<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Caution</title>
            <author>Aurelius Kolleetis Aurelius Diogenes Psaïs</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">gothenburg.apis.129</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.got;;3</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">17553</idno>
            <idno type="TM">17553</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. Got. inv. 125 recto; (Verso: Cf. got.apis.130)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>A fisherman gives security for a man who is responsible for the provision of fish products for the emperor's (Caracalla's) visit</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Gothenburg University Library</note>
                     <note type="general">Source of description: Recto</note>
                     <note type="general">20 lines with the fibres</note>
                     <note type="general">The label inside the glass frame indicates this as the recto. It is also called recto by Frisk, although he writes that this document has been written on the verso of the document published as P.Got. 113, inv.no 125 verso; he also gives an earlier date to that document than to P. Got. 3, inv. no 125 recto. TM calls this side verso.</note>
                     <note type="general">Place name mentioned: Phenek() / Phenebythis?</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>Pap.; 12 x 16 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0215" notAfter="0216">215-216 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Panopolis, Panopolite nome, Province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Kolleetis Aurelius Diogenes Psaïs</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Kolleetis Aurelius Diogenes Psaïs</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Papyri Gothoburgenses were, with the assistance of prof. Wilhelm Schubart, partly acquired from a private dealer in Germany in the 1920's, partly bought in Egypt in 1925. Cf. Chronique d'Égypte 13 - 14, 1932, p. 327</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Security</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Garum</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Fish</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>To Aurelius Diogenes, strategos of the nome of Panopolis, from Aurelius Kolleetis, son of Akes and of Senkales, mother, fisherman from Phenek. I acknowledge that I, voluntarily and independently, give security for Psaïs, son of Psaïs and the mother Sekos, who is a fisherman and has given his name as responsible for the preparation of garum, dried delicate fish and fresh fish for the renowned visit of our lord, Emperor Caesar Marcus Aurelius Severus Antoninus, great Parthian, great Britannic, great Germanic, Pius Augustus, and I swear, by the fortune of our lord, to present the aforesaid man. But if I will not present him, I will, myself, be responsible for everything that will be required from him. In the 24th year of the reign of Emperor Caesar Marcus Aurelius Severus Antoninus, great Parthicus, great Britannicus, great Germanicus, Pius Augustus.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P. Got. 3; (Verso: Cf. P. Got. 113 descr.) C.Pap.Hengstl 11 - Griechische Papyri aus Ägypten als Zeugnisse des öffentlichen und privaten Lebens, ed. J. Hengstl unter Mitarbeit von G. Häge and H. Kühnert, München 1978 Translations: Johnson, Roman Egypt, An economic survey of ancient Rome, vol. 2, (1936), p. 631; Levick, B., The government of the Roman empire, 1985, No 216, p. 219 <note>Bell, H. I., The Classical Review 43, 1929, p. 237; Schmidt, Karl Fr. W., Philologische Wochenschrift 8, 50th year of issue, 1930, c. 235; Wilcken, U., Urkunden-Referat, Archiv für Papyrusforschung 9, 1930, p. 249-250; BL II 2, 68 (lines 5, 8); BL V, 36 (line 3); BL VII, 61 (line 8); TM 17553</note>
               </bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
