<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of a Donkey</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">berenike.apis.125</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(EG-Ber)125</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">o.berenike.2.125</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">o.berenike;2;125</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">89151</idno>
            <idno type="TM">89151</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Inv. BE99 3962-uu-125, 31.cbw (west baulk trim)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract for the sale of a male donkey</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">19 lines of text; traces on back</note>
                     <note type="general">A contract between Horos son of Komaros and Nektharaus son of Haryothes, wherein the former agrees to sell a male donkey to the latter for the price of 160 silver drachmas (i.e., 40 tetradrachms).</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus, 26.0 x 21.8 cm.</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0061">26 July, A.D. 61</origDate>
                     <origPlace>This document was discovered in a Roman dump at Berenike.</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>This papyrus is currently stored in a magazine of the Supreme Council of Antiquities in Quft.</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Sale</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Contract</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Donkey</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Prices</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[In Berenike] in the Red Sea, year 7, sacred, of Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, Mesore 2.  Horos son of Komaros, grandson of Germullos to Nektharaus son of Haryothes, greetings.  I acknowledge that I have sold to you a white male donkey belonging to me, with a pack-saddle, just as it is, not subject to rejection, and that I have herewith received from you from hand to hand out of your house the price of one hundred and sixty drachmas in Ptolemaic and Imperial silver, total 160 dr.  If anyone should summon or proceed against you or your assigns on my behalf or against me or my assigns in any manner concerning the above-mentioned donkey or its price or any part thereof, I myself shall necessarily defeat the plaintiff at my own expense or I shall immediately and without delay pay in full the price that I have received from you and an equal sum to the Treasury, and whatever may have been exacted from you or expenses you may incur.  This agreement shall be authoritative and legal concerning the sale wherever it is produced as if it were registered in the public record office.  (2nd hand) I, Horos son of Komaros, grandson of Germulos, have sold and have received the price of one hundred sixty drachmas, 160 dr., price of the male donkey belonging to me, as aforesaid.  (3rd hand) Year 7, sacred, of Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, Mesore 2.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>O.Ber. II 125</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">O.Berenike:2:125</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
