<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title type="main"> HGVTITLE (DDBTITLE) </title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">hgv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="TM">gv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">hgv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.hamb;1;23</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-02-24T14:51:48-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> In the fourth year of reign and consulate of our most divine lord Flavius Iustinus, the eternal august emperor, on the seventh (day) of Thoth, of the godwilling fortunate current third indiction in the most glorious Antinoopolis. 
To gloriosissimus Flavius Philippos, exceptor of the ducal office at Thebais, son of Theodosios of the best memory, landowner at this city, from us, both present, giving mutual security and being mandatories of each other,
according to the right of the two current promising parties, Aurelii Phibios, son of Sirios and Thaesis and Ieremias, son of him and Tekrompia, vine-dressers, hailing from the village of Ibion Sesembothis in Hermopolite nome,
but residing here in Antinoopolis, greetings. We acknowledge through this written lease agreement of ours, by mutual security (and) giving mutual security, that we readily and by free choice have leased from you for the period of five years, 
counting from the mentioned above day and from the harvest of the god willing oncoming fourth indiction and current one and of continuous period each year the belonging to you and pertaining planted vine field of four arourae,
separated and surrounded by walls as is, and put in good order with a whole reservoir, a shed, a house, a little building, a barn for chaff, a vat, an orchard, a wooden saqiya furnished with all plants both fruitful and unfruitful,
date-plams and all rights and appurtenances with this entire area located in the down [...] of Antinoopolis, so that we may have it for our vine-dressing and manual work and make every care for it except for any negligence and disregard,
and water it with the orchard farmer using the farming animals there with necessary irrigations incessantly, in the winter twice a month and in the summer thrice a month, and dig it and the garden there and prune vines with appropriate vine-pruning
and re-erect using your, of course, reeds, and root up weeds in general and perform every work on it without reproach and unexceptionably, at our risk and liability to our welfare. And when the appropriate time comes, each year of the grape-crops,
what is left of the wine juice will be distributed to us per half part, for you the aforementioned one part for the taxes and rent, and for us with the farmer there another part for the troubles. You, the landowners, are allowed to take from the shared
winejuice before the division eighty jars, for the slave-payment fifty jars and for the wine from the first vat thirty full vases. We will provide you the customary cost of the grain-crop and the expenses according to the custom and we will not be able
to step away from this work before the passing of the time as though having overlooked the help of the laws, and if we do it, we will willingly supply the fisc with the penalty of twelve golden solidi. May the lease be secure and valid with the signature
of the one writing for us and having been asked the formal question about everything we consented.
(Translation by Law in Social Networks Project)
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
