<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title type="main"> HGVTITLE (DDBTITLE) </title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">hgv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="TM">gv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">hgv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.cair.masp;2;67167</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-25T13:58:22-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> of Antinoopolis, to Flavius Constantinus, son of Kallinikos of excellent memory, grandson of Alexander, singularis of the ducal office, hailing from the city of A?…, 
but now residing in this city of Antinoopolis, greetings.
<milestone n="5" unit="line"/> And I acknowledge the following stated terms: Long ago, your father (kept) in blessed memory, named Kallinikos, contracted through a written document a debt with me 
for thirty three gold solidi of full weight, having mortgaged this for the security and repayment of them and their interest, as this document encompasses, in real pledges, 
of whatever weight they are, that is one medium size silver cup and two gold small rostra for five candles.
<milestone n="11" unit="line"/> And after the time of the ransoming of these passed, and your father, the initiator of this, died, before their recuperation and return of this debt, I pursued the repayment from you, 
the above-mentioned Constantinus, regarding the said debt and its interest, that ought to be paid according to what is proper, 
and to return to you my securities mortgaged by your father when he was still alive.
<milestone n="18" unit="line"/> And since your clarity was unable to ransom them, you brought me a request so that I keep the aforementioned objects of pledge for the aforesaid debt and its interest, 
to have and possess and appropriate them with the rights of ownership, from now on and forever and for the time to come, 
and so that I have the power and be able to use the aforesaid objects of pledge with the rights of ownership, in any manner I may wish, 
without hindrance or impediment or question indisputably.
<milestone n="27" unit="line"/> And after the written quitclaim of these made for me by you today, you sought  from me the document, that is the security concerning them which your father had made for me, 
and despite the pressing issue I have not found it to return it to you.
<milestone n="32" rend="break" unit="line"/> Accordingly, I have come to this settlement agreement, in the type of cancellation, through which I acknowledge that I am ready to give you back the document signed by your father, 
whenever I search and investigate all my deeds and I identify it (among them), or if I see that it is lost among my documents, then I also acknowledge that, in any way and from this point on, neither I nor my heirs or successors or bonorum possessors have any claim against you or your heirs at this point or in the future concerning this hand-written document.

Because I have not found this hand-written document in my papers and have already received the pledged objects through your written waiver, 
and I appropriated them for the said debt and its interest having paid off the amount of debt in full, both capital and interest.

And if it be found on any occasion or time by either me or my heirs or any other person, it shall be invalid and ineffective wherever it is produced, before an office or authority, 
so that you, the aforementioned Constantinus, and your heirs, are not in any way accused or hindered or requested on account of this hand-written document or its interest, on any occasion or at any time, because I have discharged and paid off both the capital specified here and its interest, and I have settled with you through its encompassing power.

For all my present wealth, that is ancestral and my own, is liable and mortgaged to you and the successors of your inheritance each time, on account of pledge and by the law of hypotheke, 
in any shape and kind, to prevent and ward of from you each time any person who will make claim against you concerning this.

And for your security I executed this settlement agreement which is valid and secure wherever it is produced, subscribed both by me and the customary witnesses, 
by whom having been asked the formal question, I gave my consent. <note>Translation: Law in Social Networks Project (Warsaw)</note>

            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
