<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
           <title>Magical and astrological texts</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
           <idno type="apisid">leidenpapinst.apis.0021</idno>
           <idno type="TM">64079</idno>
           <idno type="HGV">64079</idno>
           <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.warr;;21</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                 <idno type="invNo">Leiden Pap. Inst. inv. Warren 21</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                 <summary>The contents of this papyrus are mainly of a magic character; the first column of the verso is astrological. On the verso we read first an amatory spell, to which are added some directions if the god delays to appear, and the words necessary to procure his dismissal. There follows a method to ascertain through reckoning whether a certain person lives or is dead, but this part is very unclear. Along the bottom a row of magical signs. The verso first gives four horoscopes, then an incantation directed against a woman, with magic words and a magic figure. The third column begins with a new spell.</summary>
                 <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Editio princeps: A.S. Hunt in Studies presented to F. Ll. Griffith (1932) 233-239</note>
                     <note type="general">Republished as [PGM III 42 (1941)] PGM (2nd ed.) II 62 (excluding the horoscopes lines 52-75).
                                                                                                                                                                                                                                    For lines 52-75 cf. Neugebauer - van Hoesen, Greek Horoscopes, p. 53, 56-57</note>
                     <note type="general">Printed plates: P.L.Bat. I, plates VI-VII; JJ.Aubert, GRBS 30 (1989), after p. 432</note>
                     <note type="general">Corrections: BL VII 93; BL X 111; see also D. Cohen, Museum 52 (1947) col. 34-35; H.I. Bell, Class.Rev. 60 (1946) 83; J.J. Aubert, GRBS 30 (1989) 421-449, esp. 430 n. 14; W. Fauth, ZPE 98 (1993), p. 57-75</note>
                     <note type="general">Translations: P.L.Bat. I  21 (see below); (German) PGM III 42 and II 62; Betz, The Greek magical papyri in translation (1997) 292-294 no. PGM 62</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Acquired in 1935 (legacy E.P. Warren) </note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Ancient Greek</textLang>
                 </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                       <support>Papyrus; H. 18.9 x W. 30.6 cm</support>
                       <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Papyrus with several holes; ten vertical foldings; recto complete, verso broken off at the right side: the papyrus has been cut from a larger one by a reader who was especially interested in the two columns of the recto</ab>
                       </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                          <ab type="lines">A total of 154 lines: on the recto 2 columns with 23 + 26 lines along the fibers; on the verso 3 columns with 24 + 28 + 27 lines across the fibers</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                 <handDesc>
                     <p>Recto lines 1 and 23-51 of (seemingly) a second hand; verso of a third hand and (seemingly) a fourth in lines 76ff.</p>
                 </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                    <origDate notBefore="0219-02-01" notAfter="0244-07-02">after AD 244, July 2</origDate>
                    <origPlace>unknown</origPlace>
                    <persName type="asn">Didymos</persName>
                    <persName type="asn">Dionysia</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                    <p>unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
              <term>Magic</term>
              <term>Horoscopes</term>
              <term>
                  <rs type="genre_form">Semi-literary</rs>
              </term>
              <term>
                  <rs type="genre_form">Papyrus</rs>
              </term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2019-04-26T03:54:44-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Finalized - ready; hopefully the images will be visible now</change>
         <change when="2019-04-26T03:32:12-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Vote - yes - ok</change>
         <change when="2019-04-26T03:30:49-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Submit - corrected URL of images</change>
         <change when="2019-04-25T12:06:05-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2019-04-25T12:04:28-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Vote - yes - ok</change>
         <change when="2019-04-25T12:03:52-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Submit - corrected URL of images</change>
         <change when="2019-01-03T09:14:47-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Finalized - ok</change>
         <change when="2019-01-03T09:09:53-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Vote - yes - ok</change>
         <change when="2019-01-03T09:08:41-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Submit - changed a typo</change>
         <change when="2016-01-07T11:22:40-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/joshuad.sosin">Finalized - Looks ok to me; was previous trouble finalizing.</change>
         <change when="2016-01-07T10:39:12-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Vote - yes - o.k.</change>
         <change when="2016-01-07T10:38:29-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Submit - seems I did not submit it well</change>
         <change when="2016-01-07T08:49:31-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Finalized - </change>
         <change when="2016-01-07T08:49:13-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Commit - added idnos (also for DDBDP, where this magical text does not figure yet)</change>
         <change when="2016-01-07T05:48:24-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Vote - yes - o.k.</change>
        <change when="2013-12-30T09:49:12-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
  <facsimile>
      <surfaceGrp n="P.Warren 21">
         <surface type="recto">
            <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/e3/leidenpapinst.apis.pwarren21.r"/>
         </surface>
         <surface type="verso">
            <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/6a/leidenpapinst.apis.pwarren21.v"/>
         </surface>
      </surfaceGrp>
  </facsimile>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
              <bibl>M. David - B.A. van Groningen - J.C. van Oven, The Warren Papyri (P. Warren) (Papyrologica Lugduno-Batava 1, Leiden 1941), p.  52-64          <note>P.Warren 21 is also cited as P.L.Bat. I  21</note>
               </bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
        <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Translation from P.L.Bat. I  21)
	                                                                                A hanging lamp, not miniated. Burn it with good olive-oil and ceder-oil. 'Thou art the fire unquenchable that is set beside the great god Osornophris Osor --. Thou didst minister to him when he fell in love with his own (5) sister Senephtys and didst run six times sixty leagues and didst encompass six times sixty mountains. Even so minister to me, NN, in regard to NN. Else I will utter the eight letters of the moon (10) which have been fixed on the heart of the sun, and if I am about to speak and you have not yet departed, I will go within the seven gates round Dardaniel and will shake the foundation of the earth and (15) the four elements of the world shall be merged together in order that their product may become nought. Be thou dissolved into thine own nature and mix with the air and go to NN daughter of NN – ordinary speech – and bring her to me with thy thunderous fire. I adjure you, the great god, (20) set in the pure earth, by whom the fire is set unquenchable for ever. Athouin thrice, (magic words), ordinary speech.'
	                                                                                A safeguard: wrap 3 peonies round your left arm and wear them.
	                                                                                'Come to me, god of gods, manifestation from fire and spirit, (25) who alone wearest thruth on thy head, who cleavest the darkness, lord of spirits, (magic words). Hail lord (magic words)'. Say this many times, and if you proceed, the phantom delays: 'Open, heaven; open, Olympus; open, Hades; open, abyss; (30) let the darkness be divided at the command of the most high god and let the sacred light come forth from the infinite into the abyss.'
	                                                                                If it again delays, speak thus again aloud, enchanting the boy: (Magic words). 'Approach, o lord god; hail, sacred light; hail, eye of the world; hail, ray of dawn upon the world; (35) and give me an answer concerning the things I beg of thee.' And ask what you wish. 
	                                                                                Release: 'I thank you that you have come at the god's command. I beg you to keep me whole, unaffrighted, un-spectre-struck (magic words). Betake yourselves to your hallowed seats.'
	                                                                                With a cup, into which you put a cotyle of good oil, and which you place on a brick; (40) and you shall inscribe these characters on a live magnet. These characters are made. And you shall set the stone outside on the left of the cup and, grasping it (?) with both hands, recite as it was explained to you. Throw (the magnet?) into the cup. Plunge in it the afterbirth of a bitch called White, viz. of a pup white when born, or a --- membrane (?). (45) And write with myrrh on the boy's breast Karbaoth.
	                                                                                A method to find by a number whether one is living or dead, thus: having made, with reference to him, a counting ---, let him complete --- in the number 612, which is the name of a god, viz. Zeus, and from the greater number let him subtract 353, which is (50) Hermes. If then pairs are found in the number, he lives, but if ---.
	                                                                                (verso) 2nd year of Antoninus – Mecheir 6th to 7th, 7th hour of the night: (55) Saturnus, horoskopos in Scorpio; Jupiter, Sun in Aquarius; Mars in Aries; Venus, Moon, Mercurius in Capricorn.
	                                                                                2nd year of the same, (60) Mecheir 17th to 18th, 11th hour of the night: Saturnus in Scorpio; Jupiter, Sun in Aquarius; Mars in Aries; (65) Venus, horoskopos, Mercurius in Capricorn; Moon in Gemini.
	                                                                                Didymos: Saturnus in Libra; Jupiter, Moon in Capricorn; Venus in Aries; (70) Sun in Taurus; Mercurius, Mars in Gemini; horoskopos in Leo.
	                                                                                Dionysia: 1st year of Philippus, Epeiph 8th, 2nd hour of the day: Saturnus, Mars in Virgo; Jupiter, Venus in Taurus; (75) Mercurius in Gemini;  horoskopos (?), Sun (?) in Cancer; Moon in Libra.
	                                                                                (Magic words and figure).
	                                                                                (123) 'Let the body and the womb of NN open and let her bleed by night (125) and by day', and ordinary speech. Write with soiled blood and recite -- when the night has come: 'she injured me first,' and bury near a ….

                                                                                </ab>
        </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
