<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
           <title>Agreement for payment of arrears</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
           <idno type="apisid">leidenpapinst.apis.0008</idno>
           <idno type="TM">13704</idno>
           <idno type="HGV">13704</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                 <idno type="invNo">Leiden Pap. Inst. inv. Warren 8</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                 <summary>The brothers Aunes and Papontos, styled Persians of the epigone, agree to pay to the Roman citizen M. Antonius Aper certain arrears of rent for arable land</summary>
                 <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Editio princeps: A.S. Hunt, in: Mélanges Maspero II (1935 - 1937) 9f. = SB V 7663</note>
                     <note type="general">Corrections: BL III 101; BL IX 150</note>
                     <note type="general">Printed Plates: P.L. Bat. I, plate II; David - van Groningen, Papyrological Primer (1965), plate II (l. 1 - 24); Boswinkel - Sijpesteijn, Greek Papyri (1968) plate 14;  Pestman, New Primer (1990,1994) 117 (l. 15 - 34); Hoogendijk - Muhs, Handschrift op papyrus (2005) 42, Afb. 16</note>
                     <note type="general">Translations: A.S. Hunt, in: Mélanges Maspero II (1935 - 1937), S. 11-12; P.L.Bat. I  8 (see below);(Dutch) Hoogendijk - Muhs, Handschrift op papyrus (2005) 55f.</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Acquired in 1935 (legacy E.P. Warren) </note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Ancient Greek</textLang>
                 </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                       <support>Papyrus, H. 23 x W. 19.7 cm</support>
                       <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Complete, good quality</ab>
                       </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                          <ab type="lines">41 lines along the fibers on the recto, 2 lines along the fibers on the verso</ab>
                          <ab type="recto-verso">Verso has docket of 2 lines</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                 <handDesc>
                     <p>L. 24 start of 2nd hand (writer on behalf on Aunes and Papontos), l. 38 start of 3rd hand (of M. Antonius Aper), l. 39 start of 4th hand (date); verso in 1st hand (professional writer)</p>
                 </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                    <origDate when="0086-12-21">AD 86, December 21</origDate>
                    <origPlace>Philadelphia</origPlace>
                    <persName type="asn">Aunes son of Petermouthis</persName>
                    <persName type="asn">Papontos son of Petermouthis</persName>
                    <persName type="asn">M. Antonius Aper</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                    <p>unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
              <term>Agreement</term>
              <term>Arrears</term>
              <term>Perses tes epigones</term>
              <term>Roman citizen</term>
              <term>Rent</term>
              <term>
                  <rs type="genre_form">Documentary</rs>
              </term>
              <term>
                  <rs type="genre_form">Papyrus</rs>
              </term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
        <change when="2013-12-28T07:02:35-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
  <facsimile>
      <surfaceGrp n="P. Warren 8">
         <surface type="recto">
            <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/08/leidenpapinst.apis.pwarren08.r"/>
         </surface>
         <surface type="verso">
            <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/cd/leidenpapinst.apis.pwarren08.v"/>
         </surface>
      </surfaceGrp>
  </facsimile>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
              <bibl>Citation: M. David - B.A. van Groningen - J.C. van Oven, The Warren Papyri (P. Warren) (Papyrologica Lugduno-Batava 1, Leiden 1941), p.  23-25       <note>= P.Warren 8, also cited as P.L.Bat. I  8</note>
               </bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
        <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Translation from P.L.Bat I  8)
	                                                   The sixth year of Imperator Caesar Domitianus Augustus Germanicus, the twenty-fifth of the month Peritios, being the twenty-fifth of Choiak, at Philadelphia in the division of Herakleides of the Arsinoite nome. Aunes, aged about fifty-two, having a scar on the little finger of the left hand, and Papontos, aged about (5) fifty, having a scar on the left thumb, both sons of Petermouthis, inhabitants of the hamlet of Nestos in the said division, Persians of the epigone and mutual sureties for payment, acknowledge to Marcus Antonius Aper of the tribe Quirina, son of Marcus, aged about twenty-three, with no distinguishing mark, that they the acknowledging parties will perforce pay to Marcus Antonius Aper of the tribe Quirina or to his agents the arrears debited (10) to them on account of rent up to and including the past fifth year of Imperator Caesar Domitianus Augustus Germanicus for the twenty-four arurae in the holding of M. Antonius at the aforesaid village of Philadelphia, namely (15) 181 ½ artabae of wheat by the quarter measure of Philippus belonging to M. Antonius and 87 artabae of barley, in five years from the present year in the month Payni annually in equal parts, together with the rent measured out by them, with no delay or subterfuge; and if the acknowledging parties do not pay as herein written, they shall forfeit to M. Antonius the amount increased by one half and (20) M. Antonius shall have the right of execution on the acknowledging parties individually and upon whichever of them he may choose and upon all their property as if in accordance with a legal decision, irrespective of what is further due from Papontos separately to the same creditor, namely three arurae of fodder for the pasturage of sheep, the leases of holdings from them to Marcus remaining in force. The subscriber for the acknowledging parties is Dioskoros son of Kephalion, aged about 63, having a scar on his left wrist. (24) (Signatures of the contracting parties and the subscriber; note of registration; title on the verso)

                                                  </ab>
        </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
