<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Private Letter</title>
            <author>Apollinarius</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2221</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2221</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.8.- 49</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">27101</idno>
            <idno type="TM">27101</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;8;491</idno>
            <idno type="filename">27101-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4528</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.570023-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Apollinarius to Taesis, his mother and lady, many greetings. Before all else I pray for your health. I myself am well, and I make obeisance on your behalf before the gods of this place. I wish you to know, mother, that I arrived in Rome in good health on the 25th of the month Pachon and was assigned to Misenum. But I have not yet learned my century, for I had not gone to Misenum when I wrote you this letter. I beg you then, mother, take care of yourself, and do not worry about me, for I have come into a fine place. Please write to me about your welfare and that of my brothers and all your kinsfolk. And for my part, if I find someone &lt;to carry the letters&gt;, I will write to you; I will not delay to write to you. I salute my brothers often, and Apollinarius and his children, and Karalas and his children. I salute Ptolemaios, and Ptolemais and her children, and Heraklous and her children. I salute all your friends, each by name. I pray for your health.;;(Verso) Deliver to Karanis, to Taesis, from Apollinarius, her son, of Misenum.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep_editor - Winter JG-Youtie HC;    Rep_ser. - PMich VIII;    Rep_Year - 1951;     Rep_Pg_No - 491;;Rep_editor - White JL;    Rep_Ser - Light from Ancient Letters;    Rep_Year 1986;   Rep_No. 104 B, with plate. Winter JG, CP 22, 243-5, 1927, Plate -- SB IV 7353 Edgar CC-Hunt AS, Select Papyry I, 111, 1932</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
