<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">leidenpapinst.apis.0014</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.warr;;14</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">27220</idno>
            <idno type="TM">27220</idno>
            <idno type="filename">27220-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Leiden Pap. Inst. inv. Warren 14</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-01-07T08:14:56-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Finalized - </change>
         <change when="2016-01-07T08:14:37-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Commit - added idnos</change>
         <change when="2016-01-07T05:43:57-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Vote - yes - o.k.</change>
         <change when="2013-12-30T07:09:10-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:31.904356-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
  
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>M. David - B.A. van Groningen - J.C. van Oven, The Warren Papyri (P. Warren) (Papyrologica Lugduno-Batava 1, Leiden 1941), p.  40-43    <note>= P.Warren 14, also cited as P.L.Bat. I  14</note>
               </bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Translation from P.L.Bat. I  14)
	                                        Osorapis and his son Phatres to the most reverend Theon many greetings. Before all we wish you (5) good health. As we instructed your sister Arsous concerning the one hundred and twenty drachmae, we know that she will not neglect to give them (10) to Apollon's wife and remind her that the interests for Hathyr have been paid(?). Also concerning the capital itself, you ought to know (15) that when we intended sending it to her through a friend, we thought of you, considering you the best we have. And so we have transferred the money (20) to Harthonios the brother of your wife through a bank, in order that you should remit it to Apollon's wife and that, together with her (Arsous?), you should trouble yourself with (25) the woman; (we mean) that you should in this way get back from the wife of Apollon our bonds undersigned by me Osorapis, (30) and get them back in this way and send them immediately to me; and that, as soon as the woman herself has seen my subscription, you should send (35) my bonds also. For we have ordered the banker to remit the money to the account of Harthonios, in expectation of the recovering of (40) our bonds. So do not neglect this, my brother, lest the interest of Choiak also come to our charge. We wish you lasting good health.
                                        (Verso:) (46) From the stolistes Osorapis. Deliver to the priest Theon in the Argeu..
                                        </ab>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
