<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Cession of Catoecic Land</title>
            <author>Aristopous [- - -]</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2941</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2941</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">22192</idno>
            <idno type="TM">22192</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;18;784</idno>
            <idno type="filename">22192-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 68</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.389262-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Copy.;The fourth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, 'Phamenoth' 8, in the city of the Oxyrhynchi of the Thebaid. Aristopous, [- - -], acknowledges to Hermophilos, son of Harthoonis, and Didymos, son of Sarapion, that he has ceded to them, in the street, in accordance with the administrative arrangements of those controllong cavalry affairs and on the basis of a memorandum that he, Aristopous, submitted to Eudaimon who was appointed by his brother Theon, the official in charge of the registry of military settlers' land grants, to each of them equally the six arourai by rectangular measurement of corn-bearing sowable land  purchased, (paying) twelve drachmai for the assignment (syntaxis) of the catoeci, belonging to him near Kerkemounis of the Upper Toparchy in the holding of Philon(?), with their yearly rent, in accordance with the contract of lease made with the lessee (of this land), [all the public dues] being to whom the cession is made [- - -;(several lines missing) - - -] in accordance with the ordinances and instructions concerning these things, in return for the cession fee that Aristopous received in pressing times, to pay the public dues, from those to whom the cession is made; and (he acknowledges to them) that he, Aristopous, won't make any violation nor resort to fraud regarding the cession of the land in any way, but that he must deliver to whom the cession is made and to their representatives the six arourai guaranteed for ever and free from all taxes and payments of previous times up to the past third year and including the past third year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus. If Aristopous violates any of the conditions, his action shall be invalid and he shall pay in addition to whom the cession is made or to their representatives for any kind of violation both the damages and a fine of one thousand drachmai of money and to the treasury the same amount and nevertheless &lt;the provisions agreed shall be binding&gt;, the rights of those to whom the cession is made being undiminished with respect to the obligation of guarantee falling  for ever on Aristopous for the other thirteen arourai of a . . . allotment which he ceded to them . . . [- - -]</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Huebner R, PMich XVIII, 784, 1996, Pl. XXII-XXIII</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
