<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Agreement Concerning an Inheritance</title>
            <author>Calpurnia and Apia alias Theodora, daughters of Gai[- - -] and of Theodora</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1618</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1618</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">22196</idno>
            <idno type="TM">22196</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;18;789</idno>
            <idno type="filename">22196-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 274</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.449355-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Calpurnia and Apia also called Theodora, both daughters of Gai[- - -], their mother being Theodora, from the city of Oxyrhynchus, each with her husband as guardian, Calpurnia with Apion, son of Apollonios, son of Sarapion, his mother being Saraeus, by adoption daughter of Diogenes, son of Sarapion, from the same city, and Apia also called Theodora with Chosion, son of [- - -]on, also called Chosion, his mother being Thaisous, from the same city, to our maternal uncle Dioskourides, son of Zoilos, son of Dioskourides, of the Hadrianic phyle and the Olympian deme, one of the class of victors at the sacred games who are exempt from taxation, former gymnasiarch and former high priest of the lords Augusti and of all the gods of the same city of the Oxyrhynchites, neokoros of the great Sarapis of the Hellenic Sarapeium in the same city, greeting.;Since your father, who is our maternal grandfather, Zoilos, son of Dioskourides, son of Hermes, his mother being Theodora, from the same city of Oxyrhynchus, by means of the sealed testament which he drew up through the office of the public notary in the same city in the 27th year, Tybi, which was unchanged when he died and (then) opened, in addition to the other things that he stipulated for us, wished, upon the condition that you set aside the income from the property belonging to us as indicated by this testament until we marry husbands and that after our marriage for another two(?) years you pay to us, whatever husbands we marry, instead of [- - - and of - - -</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Daniel RW, PMich XVIII, 789, 1996, Pl. XXXV --   -- From the writing on the Recto, it is unlikely that fragment b belonged to this piece. (PH)</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
