<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter [174-192 AD]</title>
            <author>Hermias, son of Sotas, kosmetes and bouleutes of Oxyrhynchos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p298</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1222</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.10.265</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;10;265</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;10;265</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">22266</idno>
            <idno type="TM">22266</idno>
            <idno type="filename">22266-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 440</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:24.50622-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>To Harpalos, tax-farmer with others of the xenike praktoria of the Heptanomia and the Thebaid, from Hermias son of Sotas, of the deme, on the side of his maternal grandfather Hermias, of the Sosikosmian tribe and the Althaean deme, kosmetes-designate and councilor of Oxyrhynchos. In the month of Phamenoth of the fourteenth year, Lolliane also known as Kyrilla, daughter of Dorion, from Oxyrhynchos, through her mother Sarapias also known as Tha?iusous, daughter of Sarapion also known as Theogenes, from the same city, distrained through you, from her debtor Alkimos son of Hermias, grandson of Apollonios, belonging to the Phylaxi~thalassian tribe and the Althaean deme, who later obtained Roman citizenship and was known as Marcus Aurelius Alkimos also known as Hermias, in Iseion Panga, . . . in the western parts of the village, a house and an atrium and a courtyard and all its appurtenances, of which the entrance leads to the street by the new bath . . .  vacant lots . . . to the east . . .</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. X 265 <note>Plate 19 in P.Col. X; on the date see BL XI p. 65</note>
               </bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
