<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Offer to lease an orchard</title>
            <author>Aurelios Taurinos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3255</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3255</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.8.9907</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;8;9907</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;8;9907</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">22929</idno>
            <idno type="TM">22929</idno>
            <idno type="filename">22929-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Corn. Inv. II 38</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.605691-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Consulship of our master Theodosius the eternal Augustus and Flavius Cynegius, vir clarissimus.;To Aurelios Taurinos, son of Akylaos, councilman of most illustrious Hermopolis, from Aurelius Onnophris son of Nilos, residing in your hamlet near Timonthis. I desire of my own free will and choice to lease from you for cultivation for a three-year period reckoned from the next month, Thoth, from the fruits of the fortunate third new indiction, the orchard belonging to you in your hamlet, containing date palms and citron trees, on condition that I demonstrate all the work of good cultivation in the said orchard and furnish to you, the landowner, on account of rent I will pay you each year without delay, and of course I, the farmer, am to make all water-pumping provision and keep the whole orchard flourishing (?)The lease is valid, and on formal interrogation I acknowledged it. The aforesaid consulship, Thoth 22nd. I, Aurelius Onnophris, the aforesaid, have leased as aforesaid.I, Aurelius Kopreas, upon request wrote for him, who is illiterate.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Lewis N, RechPap 3, 33, 1964, planche I -- SB VIII, 9907 Cavallo G - Maehler H, Greek Bookhands of the Early Byzantine Period, 26-27, 1987, 9a</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
