<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of a Donkey</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">berenike.apis.125</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(EG-Ber)125</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">o.berenike.2.125</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">o.berenike;2;125</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">89151</idno>
            <idno type="TM">89151</idno>
            <idno type="filename">89151-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Inv. BE99 3962-uu-125, 31.cbw (west baulk trim)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:22.265505-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>[In Berenike] in the Red Sea, year 7, sacred, of Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, Mesore 2.  Horos son of Komaros, grandson of Germullos to Nektharaus son of Haryothes, greetings.  I acknowledge that I have sold to you a white male donkey belonging to me, with a pack-saddle, just as it is, not subject to rejection, and that I have herewith received from you from hand to hand out of your house the price of one hundred and sixty drachmas in Ptolemaic and Imperial silver, total 160 dr.  If anyone should summon or proceed against you or your assigns on my behalf or against me or my assigns in any manner concerning the above-mentioned donkey or its price or any part thereof, I myself shall necessarily defeat the plaintiff at my own expense or I shall immediately and without delay pay in full the price that I have received from you and an equal sum to the Treasury, and whatever may have been exacted from you or expenses you may incur.  This agreement shall be authoritative and legal concerning the sale wherever it is produced as if it were registered in the public record office.  (2nd hand) I, Horos son of Komaros, grandson of Germulos, have sold and have received the price of one hundred sixty drachmas, 160 dr., price of the male donkey belonging to me, as aforesaid.  (3rd hand) Year 7, sacred, of Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, Mesore 2.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>O.Ber. II 125</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
