<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Petition to a Strategos</title>
            <author>Stotoetis, son of Panephremmis, &amp; Stotoetis, son of Stotoetis the elder</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2634</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2634</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">41600</idno>
            <idno type="TM">41600</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;24;16257</idno>
            <idno type="filename">41600-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 6060</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.846605-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>To Eudemos, strategos of the Arsinoite (nome), Herakleides division, from Stotoetis, son of Panephremmis, and Stotoetis, son of Stotoetis the elder, two priests from the village of Soknopaiou Nesos. Harpagathes, son of Panomgeus(?) and Taarpagathis, grandson of Petepsais(?), a priest from the same village, having duped two slaves, Horion(?), belonging to Stotoetis, son of Panephremmis, and Soteris, belonging to the other Stotoetis, caused them to disappear, after they also stole some things of ours. They then wrote to us by means of an officially registered document in Epeiph of the past 7th year of Hadrian Caesar our [lord] with the surety of his wife Taouetis, daughter of Stotoetis, granddaughter of Onnophris, and of Harpagathes, son of Panephremmis, grandson of Satabous, priest from the (same) village, that they would present these same slaves to us within thirty days, or pay back the price for them that was to be determined. Since, when the appointed time went by, Harpagathes did none of these things, but also disappeared together with his wife and Harpagathes the surety, we ask that they be served with a written summons in order [to retain] the claim against them; we have enclosed for you [a copy] of their document. I, ...euros, servant, have transmitted (it). Year 8 [of Hadrian Caesar] our Lord, 20 Phaophi. I, Ptolemaios, village scribe, have submitted the above sworn declaration and I declare that at present the aforementioned Harpagathes, son of Panomgeus(?), [Taouetis, daughter of Stotoetis], and Harpagathes, son of Panephremmis, have disappeared. Year 8 of Hadrian [Caesar our Lord, month and day].</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Hanson AE, ZPE 111, 175-182, 1996, Pl. III</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
