<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Account and receipts 343 AD</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p192</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1279</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.7.154</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;7;154</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;7;154</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10508</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10508</idno>
            <idno type="filename">10508-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 309</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:25.248643-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>	Shipment of grain for the second indiction . . . receivers.
	1. Pauni 22 for the pittakion of Apinos, sitologos, through Aion son of Kopres, 2 sacks, art. 5 1/2 1/3 1/12.
	2. And on the 23rd, Aion son of Kopres, 2 sacks, art. 5 1/2 1/3 1/12. On the same 23rd, Kopres son of Pannous, 4 sacks, art. 11 1/2 1/3.
	3. On the 26th, through Kopres son of Pannous, 8 sacks, art. 23 1/6.
 	4. On the 27th, for the pittakion of Ptollas and Panous, through Aion son of Kopres, 6 sacks, art. 18.
	5. On the 28th, for thepittakion of Apinos, Kopres son of Panous, 8 sacks, art. 23 1/2 1/3. On the same 28th, through Sarapamon, I sack, art. 2 1/2 1/3 1/12. On the 29th, through Aion son of Kopres, 3 sacks, 9 art. Epeiph 1, through Sarapammon, 7 sacks, art. 21.
	(M2) Mesore 9. Paianos and partners, sitologoi of Kerkesoucha, of Karanis, delivered through Ammonios son of Atisios [for the second new] indiction, for the account of villagers, [x artabas] of clean wheat . . .
	(M 1) Epeiph 20, for the pittakion of Sarapamon and. sitologos, through Aion son of Kopres, 4 sacks, art. 11 1/2 1/3 On the same 20th, for the pittakion of Venaphris and Ptollas through Aion son of Kopres, 1 sack, art. 3, divided into 10 modii. On the same 20th for the pittakion of Sarapammon, through the same Sarapammon, 4 sacks, art. 11 1/2 1/3.
	4 sacks, art. 11 1/2 1/12, (=Total of what follows)
	On the 21st for Ptolemais, of Karanis, through Kopres, art. 6 1/4. For Kerkesoucha, of Karanis, through Kopres, art. 5 1/3 1/12. On the same 21st for Ptolemais, of Karanis, through Aion son of Kopres, 4 sacks, art. 11 1/2 1/12 On the same 21 st for the pittakion of Venaphris and Ptollas through Aion son of Kopres, I sack, art. 2 1/2 1/3 1/12.
	On the 22nd for Kerkesoucha, of Karanis, through Aion son of Kopres, 4 sacks, art.11  1/2. On the same 22nd, for the pittakion of Venaphris and Ptollas through Aion son of Kopres, 1 sack, art. 3, divided into 10 modii. On the same 22nd, Sarapammon the sitologos through . . . 
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. VII 154 <note>Plate, P.Col. VII, Microfiche 1</note>
               </bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
