<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Loan 325 AD</title>
            <author>Aurelia Tamaleis, daughter of Hatres and Tapaeis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p211</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1298</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.7.176</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;7;176</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;7;176</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10529</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10529</idno>
            <idno type="filename">10529-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 315</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:24.837324-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>	Aurelia Tamaleis, daughter of Hatres and Tapaeis, from the village of Karanis, about thirty years old, with a scar on the wrist of the right hand, acknowledges that she has received and has had measured out to her from Eutropios, son of Archias, inhabitant of the city of the Arsinoites, through his agent Poeris, 38 1/2 artabas of wheat including, the additional one-half, which she, the acknowledging party, is of necessity to repay without delay on the appointed day in the month of Pauni of the present year from the crop of the 14th indiction, using the four-choinix measure, in quality fresh from the harvest free from dirt, unadulterated, and in good condition, and that upon a request for payment, [after default], Eutropios is to have the right of execution upon the acknowledgibIt party and all her possessions as in accordance with a legal decision, and upon formal interrogation she acknowledged (the above). 	In the consulate of Paulinus and Iulianus the most illustrious, Thoth 11. 
I, Aurelia Tamaleis, have received the thirty-eight and a half artabas, of wheat, and I will repay them on the proper day as aforesaid. I, Chaireas, wrote for her because she is illiterate.

Verso 
Note of hand of Tamaleis [daughter of Hatres for] 38 1/2 art. [of wheat]. 
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. VII 176 <note>Plate, P.Col. VII, Microfiche 2; related texts: P.NYU 22 and 23</note>
               </bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
