<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Loan 327 AD</title>
            <author>Aurelius Sarapion, son of Patas and Tanouphis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p213</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1300</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.7.178</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;7;178</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;7;178</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10531</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10531</idno>
            <idno type="filename">10531-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 181 (16)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:24.954139-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>	[Aurelius] Sarapion, [son of Patas and] Tanouphis, [from] the village of Karanis, about fifty years old, with a scar on his left hand, acknowledges to Antonius Sarapammon, former strategos, (acting) through his agent Heras, that he, the acknowledging party, has had measured out (to him) and has received eight artabas of wheat in kind from him, which he, the acknowledging party, is under obligation to repay without delay in the month of Pauni of the 16th indiction, in the aforesaid village, using the four-choinix measure, in quality fresh from the harvest, clean, unadulterated, and in good condition, and that upon formal demand [after a default] he is to have the right of execution both upon the acknowledging party and upon all his property, just as if in accordance with a legal judgment and on formal interrogation, he acknowledged (the above).
	In the consulate of Flavius Constantius and Valerius Maximus the most illustrious prefects, Choiak 23.
	(M2) 1, Aurelius Sarapion, son of Patas and Tanouphis, have received the seven artabas 8 metra (?) of wheat, and I will repay on the legal day as aforesaid. I, Aurelius Didymos son of Sotas, wrote for him too since he is illiterate. 
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. VII 178 <note>Plate, P.Col. VII, Microfiche 2</note>
               </bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
