<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Petition [October 11, 3 AD]</title>
            <author>Marsisouchos, son of Marres</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p244</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1168</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.8.209</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10545</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10545</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;8;209rpdupl</idno>
            <idno type="filename">10545-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 6</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:25.631222-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>
To Asklepiades, basilikos grammateus, from Marsisouchos son of Marres, a resident of Theadelphia of the Themistos Division, state farmer.  In the present 33rd year of Caesar I have received by cession from Pnepheros son of Tithoues, a state farmer, the 24 arouras of public land in his name near the village; after I had undertaken work on them and diked them and partially irrigated them for the sowing of the same year, on some pretext or other Soterichos, a scribe of the komogrammateus of the village, sent the praktor and the policeman to the fields, and they arrested me and handed me over to the ... of Soterichos, even though I owed absolutely nothing, and I was not released until I had given security.  And the same Soterichos took my cloak away and impeded me in the work connected with the sowing of the public fields which I farm, although the season was pressing, so as for no small harm to result for me.  Accordingly, since Soterichos has with him my receipt for the poll-tax of six years, I ask you to give orders to cause Soterichos to appear before you, so that he may receive orders to leave me alone and be compelled to return to me what he has of mine, so that the public revenues may suffer no harm.  Farewell.  Year 33 of Caesar, Phaophi 13.

</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. VIII 209 <note>Published by C.W. Keyes, CP 23 (1928) 25-29 (SB IV 7376); cf. Wilcken Archiv 9 (1930) 245 and 15 (1953) 119; Daris, Aegyptus 45 (1965) 158-64; BL 5.100; plate 18 in P.Col. VIII</note>
               </bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
