<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Declaration of Land for the Census of 302 A. D.</title>
            <author>Aurelios Aunes, son of Polion;</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1205</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1205</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.corn.20</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0097;;20</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.corn;;20</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10598</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10598</idno>
            <idno type="filename">10598-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Corn. Inv. I 116</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.137918-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>The translation is based on the edition's text (and not on what is actually preserved now) (NL);Col. I;In the fourth consulship of our lords Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars, to Aurelios Alexander, ex-official, ex-prytanis of the glorious city of Thmouites, measurer of the Arsinoite nome, toparchy fourth and fifth, of the Herakleides division, from Aurelios Aunes, son of Polion, from the village of Karanis of the same nome.;I declare in your presence, in accordance with an order of the most eminent catholikos Valerius Euethius following an imperial edict, the land which was found by you to be seed land, out of that recently declared by me to Sabinos, census taker, as my own private dry land and as ownerless land about the village of Ptolemais Nea of the above mentioned toparchy, and of which I have taken the measurements, the surveyors Heron and Annaeus and Apollonios having measured it in the presence of Abous, boundary official, and Aas son of Aboukis, headman of the village, and Olkanol village chief, as stated below:;9th section, royal seed land, from ownerless, four arouras: 4 ar.;Same section, royal seed land held in common with Patermouthis and worked on shares, from ownerless, six and seven-eighths arourae: 6 7/8 ar.;Same section, private seed land, one and twenty-three thirty-seconds arourae: 1 23/32 ar.;13th section, royal seed land held in common with Achillas, boundary commissioner, and worked on shares, from ownerless, two and seven sixty-fourths arourae: 2 7/64 ar.;And I swear by the fortune and victory of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Augusti, and of Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars, that I have made a true declaration.;Year 19 and 18 and 11 of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Most August, and of Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars. Thoth 26.;Total of royal seed land, from ownerless: 16 63/64 arourae;of private seed land: 1 23/32 arourae;(2nd hand). I, Aurelios Aunes, son of Polion, have declared the above mentioned arourae and have taken the measurements.;I swore the imperial oath. I, Aurelios Kopres, son of Euporos, wrote for him, he being illiterate.;(3rd hand) I, Aurelios Heron, surveyor, measured the arourae appearing above.;(4th hand) I, Aurelios Anaios, surveyor, helped in the measuring;(5th hand) I, Aurelios Apollonios, surveyor, helped in the measuring;(6th hand) I, Aurelios Abous, boundary official, pointed out the arourae set forth above and have omitted nothing. And we, Aas and Olkanol village chief, were present at the measuring. I, the scribe Anas, wrote for them, they being illiterate.;;Col. II;In the fourth consulship of our lords Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars, to Aurelios Alexander, ex-official, ex-prytanis of the glorious city of Thmouites, measurer of the Arsinoite nome, toparchy fourth and fifth, of the Herakleides division, from Aurelios Mysthes, son of Zosimos, from the amphodon of Boubastis of the Arsinoite nome.;I declare in your presence, in accordance with an order of the most eminent catholikos Valerius Euethius following an imperial edict, the land which was found by you to be seed land, out of that recently declared by me to Sabinos, census taker, as my own private dry land and as ownerless land about the village of Ptolemais Nea of the above mentioned toparchy, and of which I have taken the measurements, the surveyors Heron and Annaeos and Apollonios having measured it in the presence of Abous, boundary official, and Aas son of Aboikis, headman of the village, and Olkanol village chief, as stated below:;9th section, royal seed land, from ownerless, one half one-sixteenth arouras: 1 1/2 1/16 ar.;And I swear by the fortune and victory of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Augusti, and of Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars, that I have made a true declaration.;Year 19 and 18 and 11 of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Most August, and of Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars. Thoth 26.;Total of royal seed land, from ownerless: 1 1/2 1/16 arourae;(2nd hand). I, Aurelios Mysthes have declared the above mentioned arourae one half one-sixteenth and have taken the measurements. I swore the imperial oath. ;(3rd hand) I, Aurelios Heron, surveyor, measured the arourae appearing above.;(4th hand) I, Aurelios Anaios, surveyor, helped in the measuring;(5th hand) I, Aurelios Apollonios, surveyor, helped in the measuring;(6th hand) I, Aurelios Abous, boundary official, pointed out the arourae set forth above and have omitted nothing. And we, Aas and Olkanol village chief, were present at the measuring. I, the scribe Anas, wrote for them, they being illiterate.;;Col. III;In the fourth consulship of our lords Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars, to Aurelios Alexander, ex-official, ex-prytanis of the glorious city of Thmouites, measurer of the Arsinoite nome, toparchy fourth and fifth, of the Herakleides division, from Aurelios Anteinoos alias Sakaon, public physician, of the city of Arsinoites.;I declare in your presence, in accordance with an order of the most eminent catholikos Valerius Euethius following an imperial edict, the land which was found by you to be seed land, out of that recently declared by me to Sabinos, census taker, as my own private dry land and as ownerless land about the village of Ptolemais Nea of the above mentioned toparchy, and of which I have taken the measurements, the surveyors Heron and Apollonios having measured it in the presence of Abous, boundary official, and Aas son of Aboikis, headman of the village, and Olkanol village chief, as stated below:;9th section, private seed land, two one-eighth one sixteenth arourae: 1 1/8 1/16 ar. And I swear by the fortune and victory of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Augusti, and of Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars, that I have made a true declaration.Year 19 and 18 and 11 of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Most August, and of Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars. Thoth 26. Total of private seed land: 1 1/8 1/16 arourae;(2nd hand). I, Aurelios Antinoos alias Sakaon, have declared the above mentioned two one-eighth one sixteenth arourae and have taken the measurements. I swore the imperial oath. ;(3rd hand) I, Aurelios Heron, surveyor, measured the arourae appearing above.;(4th hand) I, Aurelios Anaios, surveyor, helped in the measuring;(5th hand) I, Aurelios Apollonios, surveyor, helped in the measuring;(6th hand) I, Aurelios Abous, boundary official, pointed out the arourae set forth above and have omitted nothing. And we, Aas and Olkanol village chief, were present at the measuring. I, the scribe Aunas, wrote for them, they being illiterate.;;Col IV;In the fourth consulship of our lords Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars, to Aurelios Alexander, ex-official, ex-prytanis of the glorious city of Thmouites, measurer of the Arsinoite nome, toparchy fourth and fifth, of the Herakleides division, from Aureliae Sychiaina, the wife of me, Eniochos,and Euporous, her sister, both daugthers of Maroninos from the amphodon of Chenoboskion Proton of the Arsinoite.;I declare in your presence, in accordance with an order of the most eminent catholikos Valerius Euethius following an imperial edict, the land which was found by you to be seed land, out of that recently declared by me to Sabinos, census taker, as my own private dry land and as ownerless land about the village of Ptolemais Nea of the above mentioned toparchy, and of which I have taken the measurements, the surveyors Heron and Annaeus and Apollonios having measured it in the presence of Abous, boundary official, and Aas son of Aboukis, headman of the village, and Olkanol village chief, as stated below:;13th section, private seed land held in common with Achillas, boundary commissioner, and worked on shares, five and one sixteenth: 5 1/16 ar.;And I swear by the fortune and victory of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Augusti, and of Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars, that I have made a true declaration.;Year 19 and 18 and 11 of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Most August, and of Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars. Thoth 26.;Total of private seed land, from ownerless: 5 1/16 arourae;of private seed land: 1 23/32 arourae;(2nd hand). I, Aureliai Souchiaina and Euporous, have declared the above mentioned arourae and have taken the measurements.;I swore the imperial oath. I, Aurelios Kopres, son of Euporos, wrote for them, they being illiterate.;(3rd hand) I, Aurelios Heron, surveyor, measured the arourae appearing above.;(4th hand) I, Aurelios Anaios, surveyor, helped in the measuring;(5th hand) I, Aurelios Apollonios, surveyor, helped in the measuring;(6th hand) I, Aurelios Abous, boundary official, pointed out the arourae set forth above and have omitted nothing. And we, Aas and Olkanol village chief, were present at the measuring. I, the scribe Anas, wrote for them, they being illiterate.;;Col. V;In the fourth consulship of our lords Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars, to Aurelios Alexander, ex-official, ex-prytanis of the glorious city of Thmouites, measurer of the Arsinoite nome, toparchy fourth and fifth, of the Herakleides division, from Aurelios Patermouthis son of Dioskoros and Atia, from the village of Karanis of the same nome.;I declare in your presence, in accordance with an order of the most eminent catholikos Valerius Euethius following an imperial edict, the land which was found by you to be seed land, out of that recently declared by me to Sabinos, census taker, as my own private dry land and as ownerless land about the village of Ptolemais Nea of the above mentioned toparchy, and of which I have taken the measurements, the surveyors Heron and Annaeus and Apollonios having measured it in the presence of Abous, boundary official, and Aas son of Aboukis, headman of the village, and Olkanol village chief, as stated below:;9th section, royal seed land, from ownerless, held in common with Aunes, son of Polion and worked on shares, from ownerless, six arouras: 6 ar.;Same section, royal seed land, from ownerless, one half arourae: 1 1/2 ar.;And I swear by the fortune and victory of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Augusti, and of Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars, that I have made a true declaration.;Year 19 and 18 and 11 of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Most August, and of Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars. Thoth 26.;Total of royal seed land, from ownerless: 7 1/2 arourae;of private seed land: 1 23/32 arourae;(2nd hand). I, Aurelios Patermouthis, son of Dioskoros, have declared the above mentioned arourae and have taken the measurements.;I swore the imperial oath. I, Aurelios Kopres, son of Euporos, wrote for him, he being illiterate.;(3rd hand) I, Aurelios Heron, surveyor, measured the arourae appearing above.;(4th hand) I, Aurelios Anaios, surveyor, helped in the measuring;(5th hand) I, Aurelios Apollonios, surveyor, helped in the measuring;(6th hand) I, Aurelios Abous, boundary official, pointed out the arourae set forth above and have omitted nothing. And we, Aas and Olkanol village chief, were present at the measuring. I, the scribe Anas, wrote for them, they being illiterate.;;Col. VI;In the fourth consulship of our lords Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars, to Aurelios Alexander, ex-official, ex-prytanis of the glorious city of Thmouites, measurer of the Arsinoite nome, toparchy fourth and fifth, of the Herakleides division, from Aurelios Ekysis, [son of NN, from ...].;I declare in your presence, in accordance with an order of the most eminent catholikos Valerius Euethius following an imperial edict, the land which was found by you to be seed land, out of that recently declared by me to Sabinos, census taker, as my own private dry land and as ownerless land about the village of Ptolemais Nea of the above mentioned toparchy, and of which I have taken the measurements, the surveyors Heron and Annaeus and Apollonios having measured it in the presence of Abous, boundary official, and Aas son of Aboukis, headman of the village, and Olkanol village chief, as stated below:;9th section, royal seed land, from ownerless, [x ...]one-sixteenthfourth arouras: [x ...] 1/64 ar.;Same section, private seed land arourae ....;And I swear by the fortune and victory of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Augusti, and of Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars, that I have made a true declaration.;Year 19 and 18 and 11 of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Most August, and of Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars. Thoth 26.;Total of royal seed land, from ownerless: x arourae;of private seed land: [x ...]1/642 arourae;(2nd hand). I, Aurelios Ekysis, son of Ph[...], have declared the above mentioned arourae and have taken the measurements.;I swore the imperial oath. I, Aurelios Kopres, son of Euporos, wrote for him, he being illiterate.;(3rd hand) I, Aurelios Heron, surveyor, measured the arourae appearing above.;(4th hand) I, Aurelios Anaios, surveyor, helped in the measuring;(5th hand) I, Aurelios Apollonios, surveyor, helped in the measuring;(6th hand) I, Aurelios Abous, boundary official, pointed out the arourae set forth above and have omitted nothing. And we, Aas and Olkanol village chief, were present at the measuring. I, the scribe Anas, wrote for them, they being illiterate.;;Col. VII;In the fourth consulship of our lords Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars, to Aurelios Alexander, ex-official, ex-prytanis of the glorious city of Thmouites, measurer of the Arsinoite nome, toparchy fourth and fifth, of the Herakleides division, from Aurelia [daughter of NN], granddaughter of Simon, from the village of Ptolemais Nea of the same nome.;I declare in your presence, in accordance with an order of the most eminent catholikos Valerius Euethius following an imperial edict, the land which was found by you to be seed land, out of that recently declared by me to Sabinos, census taker, as my own private dry land and as ownerless land about the village of Ptolemais Nea of the above mentioned toparchy, and of which I have taken the measurements, the surveyors Heron and Annaeus and Apollonios having measured it in the presence of Abous, boundary official, and Aas son of Aboukis, headman of the village, and Olkanol village chief, as stated below:;[.]section, private seed land, one and one-sixteenth: 1 1/16 ar.;And I swear by the fortune and victory of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Augusti, and of Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars, that I have made a true declaration.;Year 19 and 18 and 11 of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Most August, and of Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars. Thoth 26.;Total of royal seed land, from ownerless: 16 63/64 arourae;of private seed land: 1 1/16 arourae;(2nd hand). I, Aurelios Aunes, son of Polion, have declared the above mentioned arourae and have taken the measurements.;I swore the imperial oath. I, Aurelios Kopres, son of Euporos, wrote for him, he being illiterate.;(3rd hand) I, Aurelios Heron, surveyor, measured the arourae appearing above.;(4th hand) I, Aurelios Anaios, surveyor, helped in the measuring;(5th hand) I, Aurelios Apollonios, surveyor, helped in the measuring;(6th hand) I, Aurelios Abous, boundary official, pointed out the arourae set forth above and have omitted nothing. And we, Aas and Olkanol village chief, were present at the measuring. I, the scribe Anas, wrote for them, they being illiterate.;;Co. VIII;In the fourth consulship of our lords Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars, to Aurelios Alexander, ex-official, ex-prytanis of the glorious city of Thmouites, measurer of the Arsinoite nome, toparchy fourth and fifth, of the Herakleides division, from Aurelios Ape[..., son of NN], from the amphodon of the Arsinoite.;I declare in your presence, in accordance with an order of the most eminent catholikos Valerius Euethius following an imperial edict, the land which was found by you to be seed land, out of that recently declared by me to Sabinos, census taker, as my own private dry land and as ownerless land about the village of Ptolemais Nea of the above mentioned toparchy, and of which I have taken the measurements, the surveyors Heron and Annaeus and Apollonios having measured it in the presence of Abous, boundary official, and Aas son of Aboukis, headman of the village, and Olkanol village chief, as stated below:;5th section, [private seed land], held in common, half one-fourth one-eighth one-sixteenfourth arouras: 1/2 1/4 1/8 1/64 ar.;14th section, royal seed land held in common with [NN], from ownerless, x ar: x ar.;And I swear by the fortune and victory of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Augusti, and of Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars, that I have made a true declaration.;Year 19 and 18 and 11 of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Most August, and of Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars. Thoth 26.;Total of royal seed land, from ownerless: x arourae;of private seed land: 1/2 1/4 1/8 1/64 arourae;(2nd hand). I, Aurelios Aunes, son of Polion, have declared the above mentioned arourae and have taken the measurements.;I swore the imperial oath. I, Aurelios Kopres, son of Euporos, wrote for him, he being illiterate.;(3rd hand) I, Aurelios Heron, surveyor, measured the arourae appearing above.;(4th hand) I, Aurelios Anaios, surveyor, helped in the measuring;(5th hand) I, Aurelios Apollonios, surveyor, helped in the measuring;(6th hand) I, Aurelios Abous, boundary official, pointed out the arourae set forth above and have omitted nothing. And we, Aas and Olkanol village chief, were present at the measuring. I, the scribe Anas, wrote for them, they being illiterate.;;Col. IX;In the fourth consulship of our lords Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars, to Aurelios Alexander, ex-official, ex-prytanis of the glorious city of Thmouites, measurer of the Arsinoite nome, toparchy fourth and fifth, of the Herakleides division, from Aurelios Esouris, Stratiotes, and NN, the three from the village of Ptolemais Nea of the same nome.;I declare in your presence, in accordance with an order of the most eminent catholikos Valerius Euethius following an imperial edict, the land which was found by you to be seed land, out of that recently declared by me to Sabinos, census taker, as my own private dry land and as ownerless land about the village of Ptolemais Nea of the above mentioned toparchy, and of which I have taken the measurements, the surveyors Heron and Annaeus and Apollonios having measured it in the presence of Abous, boundary official, and Aas son of Aboukis, headman of the village, and Olkanol village chief, as stated below:;[.] section, royal seed land, from ownerless, x arouras: x ar.;And I swear by the fortune and victory of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Augusti, and of Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars, that I have made a true declaration.;Year 19 and 18 and 11 of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Most August, and of Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars. Thoth 26.;Total of [: x arourae]; (2nd hand). NN] have declared [the above mentioned arourae and have taken the measurements.I swore the] imperial oath.;(3th hand) I, Aurelios Apollonios, surveyor, helped in the measuring;(4th hand) I, the scribe Anas, wrote for them, they being illiterate.;;Col. X;In the fourth consulship of our lords Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars, to Aurelios Alexander, ex-official, ex-prytanis of the glorious city of Thmouites, measurer of the Arsinoite nome, toparchy fourth and fifth, of the Herakleides division, from Aurelios [NN] from the village of Ptolemais Nea of the same nome.;I declare in your presence, in accordance with an order of the most eminent catholikos Valerius Euethius following an imperial edict, the land which was found by you to be seed land, out of that recently declared by me to Sabinos, census taker, as my own private dry land and as ownerless land about the village of Ptolemais Nea of the above mentioned toparchy, and of which I have taken the measurements, the surveyors Heron and Annaeus and Apollonios having measured it in the presence of Abous, boundary official, and Aas son of Aboukis, headman of the village, and Olkanol village chief, as stated below:;[.] section, royal seed land, from ownerless, half one-fourth one-eighth one-thirtysecond arouras: 1/2 1/4 1/8 1/32 ar.;Same section, private seed land held in common with NN, from ownerless x arourae: x ar.;Same section, royal seed land, one one-eighth one-sixteenth arourae: 1 1/8 1/16 ar.;And I swear by the fortune and victory of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Augusti, and of Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars, that I have made a true declaration.;Year 19 and 18 and 11 of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Most August, and of Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars. Thoth 26.;Total of royal seed land, from ownerless: 1 1/2 1/16 1/32 arourae;of private seed land: x arourae;(2nd hand). I, Aurelios [NN], have declared the above mentioned arourae and have taken the measurements.;I swore the imperial oath. I, Aurelios Kopres, son of Euporos, wrote for him, he being illiterate.;(3rd hand) I, Aurelios Heron, surveyor, measured the arourae appearing above.;(4th hand) I, Aurelios Anaios, surveyor, helped in the measuring;(5th hand) I, Aurelios Apollonios, surveyor, helped in the measuring;(6th hand) I, Aurelios Abous, boundary official, pointed out the arourae set forth above and have omitted nothing. And we, Aas and Olkanol village chief, were present at the measuring. I, the scribe Anas, wrote for them, they being illiterate.;;Col. XI;In the fourth consulship of our lords Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars, to Aurelios Alexander, ex-official, ex-prytanis of the glorious city of Thmouites, measurer of the Arsinoite nome, toparchy fourth and fifth, of the Herakleides division, from Aurelios Appianos, son of Horion, from the amphodon of Hiera Pyle of the Arsinoite.;I declare in your presence, in accordance with an order of the most eminent catholikos Valerius Euethius following an imperial edict, the land which was found by you to be seed land, out of that recently declared by me to Sabinos, census taker, as my own private dry land and as ownerless land about the village of Ptolemais Nea of the above mentioned toparchy, and of which I have taken the measurements, the surveyors Heron and Annaeus and Apollonios having measured it in the presence of Abous, boundary official, and Aas son of Aboukis, headman of the village, and Olkanol village chief, as stated below:;14th section, royal seed land, held in common withAtepsenes from ownerless, one one-thirtysecond arouras: 1 1/32 ar.;And I swear by the fortune and victory of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Augusti, and of Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars, that I have made a true declaration.;Year 19 and 18 and 11 of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Most August, and of Constantius and Maximian, most renowned Caesars. Thoth 26.;Total of royal seed land, from ownerless: 1 1/32 arourae; (2nd hand). I, Aurelios Aunes, son of Polion, have declared the above mentioned arourae and have taken the measurements.;I swore the imperial oath. I, Aurelios Kopres, son of Euporos, wrote for him, he being illiterate.;(3rd hand) I, Aurelios Heron, surveyor, measured the arourae appearing above.;(4th hand) I, Aurelios Anaios, surveyor, helped in the measuring;(5th hand) I, Aurelios Apollonios, surveyor, helped in the measuring;(6th hand) I, Aurelios Abous, boundary official, pointed out the arourae set forth above and have omitted nothing. And we, Aas and Olkanol village chief, were present at the measuring. I, the scribe Anas, wrote for them, they being illiterate.;</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Westermann WL - Kraemer CJ, PCorn, 20, 1926, Pl pp114-5 -- Col. VI: ll. 104-108 one more fragment was joined on the right of the ed. princ. text and proves ed. princ. readings (NL)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
