<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lease</title>
            <author>Lucius Vettius . . .</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1287</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1287</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.corn.10</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0097;;10</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.corn;;10</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10593</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10593</idno>
            <idno type="filename">10593-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Corn. Inv. II 9</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.664711-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>"To Lucius Longinus Frontinus, through Frontinus Longinus Apella, from Luccius Vettius . . . I wish to lease from you one and a half aroura of land near Philadelphia belonging to Fronto, in which are scattered date palms whatsoever he may now be growing, the land being also an undivided portion of a three aroura plot, for four years, namely four fruit crops, four sown crops, (reckoning) the date palms on the basis that all the hanging fruits of the present 3rd year of Hadrianus Caesar our lord are included in the 4 years' crops, and the farm plot as (leased) from the coming 4 years' crop, the rent of the farm land and the date palms to be one hundred and twenty drachmas annually without deductions and without risk, the farm labors resting upon me, the lessee. And I will pay the rent as follow, in . . . forty drachmas, and the remaining eighty drachmas in the month of . . . And at the end of the time I will hand back the farm plot after the harvest, if it is agreed to make the lease. 2nd hand. I, Lucius Longinus, through Apella, have made the lease on all the foregoing conditions as laid down above. Year 3 of Hadrian our lord, Mesore 30th."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Westermann WL - Kraemer CJ, PCorn, 10, 1926 -- BL II.2,47 on lines 7-8;IV,24 on line 8;III,46 on line 12; VIII, 89 on line 10; X on the dating.</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
