<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Bail for a Prisoner</title>
            <author>Theon</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">upenn.apis.50</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(PU) 50</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.oxy.2.259</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0181;2;259</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;2;259</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20529</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20529</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Penn. Museum inv.E02798</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Main text: Copy of a declaration on oath addressed to the governor of a public prison by a surety for a man who had been arrested for debt.  Theon, the surety, had secured the temporary release of the prisoner, Sarapion, some months previously; and now he undertakes to produce Sarapion within a month or to pay the amount of the debt. (Grenfell &amp; Hunt) Secondary text: The declaration is followed by a short and rather obscure letter written by Theon, and beginning apparently with a message to Sarapion.  Theon's object doubtless was to bring to Sarapion's notice the conditions of his bond on Sarapion's behalf. (Grenfell &amp; Hunt)</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Text is on one side only, 35 lines written with the fibers.  Left and right margins are intact; top and bottom margins are visible.  Text mentions the location of Phaophi.</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Museum of Archaeology and Anthropology collection</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>17.8  x 34.4cm. Damaged along the top margin and at the bottom left.  There are numerous holes throughout.  Writing does not extend to the right margin.</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0023">23 CE</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Oxyrhynchos</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Demetrius</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tiberius Caesar Novus Augustus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Magianus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aline</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Billus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tiberius Caesar Augustus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dionysius</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heliodorus</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Excavated by Grenfell and Hunt (1896-7) on behalf of the Egyptian Exploration Fund, and donated to the University Museum in return for its support (1904, Dr. Parrish Collection).</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">declaration</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Copy of a bond. Theon, son of Ammonius, a Persian of the Epigone, to Demetrius, governor of the prison of Zeus. I swear by Tiberius Caesar Novus Augustus Imperator, that I have thirty days in which to restore to you the man whom I bailed out of the public prison in Phaophi of the present year, Sarapion, son of Sarapion, arrested through Billus, assistant to the dioecetes, on account of a note of hand for a gold bracelet weighing two minae to Magianus on behalf of Aline, citizen, daughter of Dionysius. If I do not produce him within the said number of days, I will pay the said two minae of gold without delay, and I have no power to obtain a further period of time nor to transfer myself to another prison If I swear truly, may it be well with me, but if falsely, the reverse. 9th year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, Pachon 22. (Grenfell &amp; Hunt)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P. Oxy. 2.259 <note>John R. Abercrombie, "The University Museum's Collection of Papyri and Related Materials," Expedition 20.2 (Winter 1978): 32-37.</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Oxy.:2:259</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
