<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Account of a Sitologus Receipt for Taxes on Oil</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">upenn.apis.44</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(PU) 44</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.fay.86</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0110;;86</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.fay;;86</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">28615</idno>
            <idno type="TM">28615</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Penn. Museum inv.E02792</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Side 1: Account of payments of wheat, barley, and lentils received during the month of Phaophi from various classes of persons in several villages. (Grenfell, Hunt, &amp; Hogarth) Side 2: Acknowledgement by the collectors of money-taxes at Euhemeria of a payment of 56 drachmae on account of the taxes on oil and perhaps some other tax. (Grenfell, Hunt, &amp; Hogarth)</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Text is on both sides of the papyrus; Side 1 is P Fay 86, 27 lines written with the fibers.  Top, bottom, and right margins are clearly visible. The text mentions Theadelphia, Euhemeria, Polydeucia, Dionysias, Philagris, Philoteris, Autodice and two other villages, all of which were in the division of Themistes, and Oxyrhyncha in the division of Polemo.</note>
                     <note type="general">Side 2 is P Fay 64, 9 lines written against the fibers.  Top, bottom, and left margins are intact.  Text mentions the village of Euhemeria.</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Museum of Archaeology and Anthropology collection</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>11.2 x 23.4cm. The left margin is badly broken, with some loss of writing.  Toward the  middle of the papyrus there is a row of horizontal holes (small) that may indicate a fold.</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notAfter="0201" when="0100">2nd CE 201 CE</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Harit (Fayum)</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Dioscorus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Touteos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonius</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Excavated by Grenfell and Hunt (1898-9) on behalf of the Egyptian Exploration Fund, and donated to the University Museum in return for its support (1904, Dr. Parrish Collection).</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">account</term>
               <term type="genre_form">receipt</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Side 2: The ninth year, Pachon 27, through Dioscorus and Touteos (?) and partners, collectors of money-taxes at the village of Euhemeria. You have paid and I have received on account of the payment for the oil-taxes of the eighth year...fifty-six drachmae, total 56 dr., which sum we will pay to the treasury in the name of you, Apollonius, and will hand over to you the treasury receipt. (Grenfell, Hunt &amp; Hogarth)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P. Fay. 86 P. Fay. 64 <note>John R. Abercrombie, "The University Museum's Collection of Papyri and Related Materials," Expedition 20.2 (Winter 1978): 32-37.</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Fay.:86</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
