<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter from Gemellus to Sabinus</title>
            <author>Lucius Bellenus Gemellus</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">upenn.apis.38</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(PU) 38</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.fay.119</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0110;;119</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.fay;;119</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10784</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10784</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Penn. Museum inv. E02786</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Letter from Gemellus to Sabinus with various questions and instructions.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Text is written on both sides; one side is the letter and the other side is the address.  Text mentions location of Psinachis.</note>
                     <note type="general">Side 1: Text is written almost entirely with the fibers, approximately 35 lines total.  Top, left, and bottom margins are visible.  There is text written in the left margin, perpendicular to the main body.</note>
                     <note type="general">Side 2: Text is written with the fibers, so as to be perpendicular to the text on the other side.  The address is made up of two lines of text.</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Museum of Archaeology and Anthropology collection</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>10.5 x 26.3cm. In the left margin at right angles are lines 33-35. "Iota"-shaped verticle tear on the bottom half of the papyrus.</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0103">103 CE</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Kasr el Banat (Fayum)</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aunes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dionysius</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Epagathus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gemella</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasis</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Excavated by Grenfell and Hunt (1898-9) on behalf of the Egyptian Exploration Fund, and donated to the University Museum in return for its support (1901, Dr. Parrish Collection).</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">letter</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Lucius Bellenus Gemellus to his son Sabinus, greeting. Aunes the donkey-driver has bought a rotten bundle of hay at 12 drachmae, a little bundle and rotten hay, the whole of it decayed - no better than dung. Sabinus, son of Psellus, of Psinachis, who is with you brought to the city a letter of the praefect Dionysius the strategus telling him to hear... Where did you put the notice of payment for the hay, and the contract for his loan of a mina? Send the key, and let me know where they lie, so that I may get them out in order to have them if I am about to settle accounts with him. Do not neglect these instructions. Take care of yourself. Greet Epagathus and those who love us truly. Good-bye. Choiak 12. Send ten cocks from the market for the Saturnalia, and for Gemella's birthday feast send some delicacies and...and an artaba of wheaten bread. Send the animals to carry manure at the vegetable-ground at Psinachis and the manure-carts, for Pasis is crying out that we must not allow it to be dissolved by the water, and let them fetch his hay. Send the animals at once.  (Grenfell, Hunt &amp; Hogarth)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Addressed) Deliver to Sabinus my son from Lucius Bellenus Gemellus.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P. Fay. 119 <note>John R. Abercrombie, "The University Museum's Collection of Papyri and Related Materials," Expedition 20.2 (Winter 1978): 32-37. Nicolas Hohlwein, "Le veteran Lucius Bellienus Gemellus: Gentleman-farmer au Fayoum," Etudes de Papyrologie vol. 8 (1957): 69-91.</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Fay.:119</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
