<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Application for Leave to Mortgage</title>
            <author>Achillas</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">upenn.apis.72</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(PU) 72</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.oxy.3.483</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0181;3;483</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;483</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20619</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20619</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Penn. Museum inv.E02822</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Application for a lease to mortgage.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Text is on one side only, 37 lines written with the fibers.  Evidence of the right margin; left and bottom margins are visible. Lines 7-11 are practically illegible; Grenfell and Hunt indicate "vestiges of 5 lines".  Written in three hands.</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Museum of Archaeology and Anthropology collection</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>10.7 X 24.3cm. Two tears run the length of the fragment on each side.  There is a large hole in the middle left side of the papyrus.  The upper left and bottom right corners have been torn away.  Writing in the first few lines shows apparent wear.</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0108">108 CE</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Oxyrhynchos</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Zeus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hera</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Zenodorus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Trajanus Ceasar</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Augusti</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Caesar Nerva Trajanus Augustus Germanicus Dacicus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Theon</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Excavated by Grenfell and Hunt (1903) on behalf of the Egyptian Exploration Fund, and donated to the University Museum in return for its support (1907, Dr. Parrish Collection).</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">letter</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>'To Sarapion, keeper of the public records, from Achillas. . . . Wishing to mortgage to) . . . through his . . . , priest of Zeus, Hera and . . . , the (6 arourae) of catoecic land which I own near the village of  . . . in the eastern toparchy in the holding of Zenodorus . . . (on condition that the repayment is made) by the 5th intercalary day of the month Caesareus of the 22nd year of Trajanus Caesar the lord, at the interest of 1 drachma for each mina per month dating from next month, Pharmouthi, which I will pay off at the conclusion of each twelvemonth, I present this application in order that you may instruct the agoranomi of Oxyrhynchus, who are also recorders, to execute the deed in the proper way. And I swear by the deified Augusti and by the Fortune of the Emperor Caesar Nerva Trajanus Augustus Germanicus Dacicus and my ancestral gods that the aforesaid arourae are my own property and free from all ability either public or private up to the present day. The 11th  year of the Emperor Caesar Nerva Trajanus Augustus Germanicus Dacicus, Phamenoth dies Augustus. I, Achillas son of Didymus, have presented the application and sworn the oath. Sarapion, joint keeper of the records with Theon, to the agoranomi of the metropolis, greeting. Achillas has the 6 arourae on the register. Execute the deed therefore, as is fitting.' Date. (Grenfell &amp; Hunt)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P. Oxy. 3.483 <note>John R. Abercrombie, "The University Museum's Collection of Papyri and Related Materials," Expedition 20.2 (Winter 1978): 32-37.</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Oxy.:3:483</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
