<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Registration of Property</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">upenn.apis.49</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(PU) 49</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.oxy.2.250</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0181;2;250</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;2;250</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20519 20520</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20519 20520</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Penn. Museum inv.E02797</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Side 1, Main text (column on the right):  The writer registers property from his father, deceased at the end of Nero's third year. Date is missing, but mention of praefect Vestinus (6th-8th years of Nero's reign) fixes it approximately. (Grenfell &amp; Hunt) Side 1, column on the left: It "is to all appearances a similar property return and...is dated in the month of Germanicus of the 7th year of an emperor who is almost certainly Nero" (Grenfell &amp; Hunt).</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Side 1: main text is 27+ lines written with the fibers.  Text is in two columns, with only the margin separating the two columns still intact.  The column on the left has writing perhaps in at least two more hands.  Text mentions Arsinoe and Oxyrhynchos.</note>
                     <note type="general">Side 2: one line written with the fibers so as to be perpendicular to text on the opposite side.</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Museum of Archaeology and Anthropology collection</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>16.0 x 22.3cm together; the left fragment is about 6.5cm wide and 12cm tall, and the main fragment is about 11cm wide.  The two pieces overlap at the join by about 1.5cm.  Another mutilated document (parts of 15 lines, untranscribed here) is gummed to the left margin of the main document, and is damaged at the top, left and bottom. This makes it appear that there is a vertical crease where the two pieces overlap.  One line of writing appears on the other side of the main document perpendicular to the writing on the first side. All the writing is along the fibers. The main document is damaged at the top left, top and bottom, and is missing its right side.</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0061">61 CE</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Oxyrhynchos</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonios</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Excavated by Grenfell and Hunt (1896-7) on behalf of the Egyptian Exploration Fund, and donated to the University Museum in return for its support (1904, Dr. Parrish Collection).</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">registration</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P. Oxy. 2.250 <note>John R. Abercrombie, "The University Museum's Collection of Papyri and Related Materials," Expedition 20.2 (Winter 1978): 32-37.</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Oxy.:2:250</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
