<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Calendar</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">upenn.apis.100</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(PU) 100</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Penn. Museum inv.E16251</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Mutilated section of a calendar for the solar year, according to the Syrian months, and comprises the end of the month Iyar (May) and most of the month of Haziran (June). Refers to periodic changes in the Nile.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Text is on both sides, 11 lines on the recto (with the width) and 10 lines on the verso. Writing on verso runs in inverted direction with respect to the recto. The script is an old Naskhi, with some Kufic features. Diacritical signs are used, but not consistently.</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Museum of Archaeology and Anthropology, Ellen W. Harrison Collection.</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>7.0 x 9.2cm. The last line on the recto and the first on the verso are destroyed but for feeble traces.  The upper and left margins (lower and right on the verso) are preserved, although they are broken at places; the lower side (upper on verso) is broken, with the loss of some lines, and the right (left) side is slightly damaged with the loss of a few letters.  The lower left (right) corner is lost.  Both faces of the sheet are damaged by dirst and moisture, and the writing on the verso is faded at places.  There are some holes.</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0900" notAfter="1099">10th-11th CE</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Egypt</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased from Professor Bernhard Moritz of Cairo through W.M. Mueller, 1910.</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">leather</term>
               <term type="genre_form">literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">calendar</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Recto: 1. [...] the Nile of Egypt, and waters change (in color), and 2. [app]les are good, and truffles crack, and the East wind blows 3. [and] the time of the yellow gall enters, and (lasts) [for] ty- 4. two nights. On the twenty-fourth of it 5. [the d]ay is fourteen hours and the night ten hours 6. and durra and millet are sown in Yamam and in the land of Ma[..] (Tihama ?). 7. [and the land] of the Nubians. And on the twenty-ninth of it 8. the Goat rises by God''s permission from all[ 9. [and........] is high and remains until the ris[e of the Sting of the Scorpion] 10. [and on] the twenty-ninth [Aldebaran] rises 11. ... (Della Vida)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Verso: 1. ...................................... 2. [...].............................[...] 3. [....] ... to hunt and to.....[......] 4. [to eat] meat and to drink honey. 5. [Hazir]an. Thirty days. Its symbol is dal, i.e. four, 6. [and] it is called in Persian Adarbihisht Mah and in Coptic 7. [Bu]ne. Its zodiacal sign is the Twins. On the eleventh of it 8. the "Haq''a" rises and the Sting of the Scorpion disappears, and it is 9. [the long]est day and the shortest night in the year because 10. [the d]ay becomes fifteen hours and the night 11. [n]ine hours, and it is the birthday of John [the Baptist] (Della Vida)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
