<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter from Gemellus to Sabinus</title>
            <author>Lucius Bellenus Gemellus</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">upenn.apis.37</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(PU) 37</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.fay.117</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0110;;117</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.fay;;117</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10782</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10782</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Penn. Museum inv. E02785</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Letter from Gemellus to Sabinus with instructions to send to Elouras gifts of olives and fish upon his becoming deputy to the strategus Erasus, "as we want to make use of him." (Grenfell, Hunt, &amp; Hogarth)</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Text is on predominantly one side, with the final two lines on the other side.</note>
                     <note type="general">Side 1: 29 lines written with the fibers.</note>
                     <note type="general">Side 2: approximately two lines written with the fibers, so as to be perpendicular to the writing on the other side.</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Museum of Archaeology and Anthropology collection</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>11.6 x 23.0cm. The writing in places is very faded.  The top, right and bottom margins are mostly intact.  The left margin, while straight, appears a bit torn.  Numerous holes in the middle bottom two thirds of the document.</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0108">108 CE</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Kasr el Banat (Fayum)</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Elouras</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Erasus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpocrates</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Trajanus Caesar</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Excavated by Grenfell and Hunt (1898-9) on behalf of the Egyptian Exploration Fund, and donated to the University Museum in return for its support (1901, Dr. Parrish Collection).</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">letter</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Side 1: Lucius Bellenus Gemellus to his son Sabinus, greeting and continual good health.  You must know that Elouras the royal scribe is become deputy for the strategus Erasus, in accordance with a letter of his highness the praefect.  If you think it well, send him an artaba of olives and some fish, as we want to make use of him.  Send us for the house some...and olives, for they have no fresh olives at the house.  Send the...since Erasus is going to celebrate the festival of Harpocrates so soon on the 14th, and send him the cabbages(?).  Load all the animals with cabbage and we will send him five...of cabbage and as much to the house...What you write to me about not neglecting the building you have said more than enough, and you write too often "I am thanking the village," when they have charged you with four staters.  I pray for your perpetual good health.  The 11th year of Trajanus Caesar the lord, Tubi 19. (Grenfell, Hunt, &amp; Hogarth)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Side 2: (Addressed) Deliver to Sabinus my son from Lucius Bellenus Gemellus. (Grenfell, Hunt &amp; Hogarth)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P. Fay. 117 <note>John R. Abercrombie, "The University Museum's Collection of Papyri and Related Materials," Expedition 20.2 (Winter 1978): 32-37. Nicolas Hohlwein, "Le veteran Lucius Bellienus Gemellus: Gentleman-farmer au Fayoum," Etudes de Papyrologie vol. 8 (1957): 69-91.</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Fay.:117</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
