<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Medical Prescription</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">upenn.apis.106</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(PU) 106</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Penn. Museum inv.E16258</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Side 1 (Recto): Prescriptions and recipes for the same. (Records payment of three, four, and seven dirhams. [S.L. Skoss]) Side 2 (Verso): Arabic Accounts on Paper. Index to a book of accounts (see DV, no. 55, p. 113-115).</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Text is written on both sides, 6 lines on Side 1 (Recto), 9 lines on Side 2 (Verso).</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Museum of Archaeology and Anthropology, Ellen W. Harrison Collection.</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>15.8 x 15.0cm. Paper has been folded several times according to the width, and the creases are still apparent. Otherwise in good condition. Right and left margins are even; top margin slightly torn, still very even; bottom margin slants slightly downward in a relatively straight line from left to right. Shade of paper darkens to light brown in center; dark spot at top right corner, perhaps burn mark, which however blocks no text. Sprawling black ink writing clearly visible on top half; part of last line faded.</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0900" notAfter="1099">10th-11 CE</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Egypt</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased from Professor Bernhard Moritz of Cairo through W.M. Mueller, 1910.</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">paper</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">prescription</term>
               <term type="genre_form">account</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Side 1 (Recto): 1. In the name of God, the Merciful, the Compassionate. 2. Let there be taken with God's blessing and help thirty grains of sabistan and twenty grains of jujube 3. and the weight of three drams (dirhams) of lily root the weight of four drams of violet root, 4. and the whole be boiled in two quarts (ratl) of water, until it shrinks to one third, and let be soaked in it the weight of seven 5. drams of cassia ...................................... 6. so please God. God is our sufficiency and how good a custodian is He!</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
