<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Hadiths</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">upenn.apis.101</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(PU) 101</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Penn. Museum inv.E16253</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Hadiths, or traditions (Sahih) of Bukhari, reporting the sayings of the Prophet Muhammad. Almost certainly a fragment of the book al-Mulakhkhas lima fi''l-Muwatta'' min al-hadith al-musnad, by Ali Ibn Muhammad Ibn Khalaf Al-Qabis, d. 403 A.H. (Della Vida)</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Text is on both sides, 12 lines on the front and 15 lines on the back. The script has an outspoken Maghrabi aspect. Vowel marks are profusely, if not constantly, used.</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Museum of Archaeology and Anthropology, Ellen W. Harrison Collection</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>21.8 x 16.0cm. Sheet, vertically folded through its middle, representing the first and last folios in the quire of a book.  The former folio is inscribed only on its verso, where twelve broken lines appear: the recto is blank.  The latter folio is inscribed on both faces, at 15 lines to the page.  More than half of folio 1 is lost; the whole upper side and a part of the lower side of folio 2 are destroyed.  The width of folio 2 is 12.8 cm.; the outer and inner margins measure respectively 2.6 and 1.9 cm.; the lower margin, 1.7 cm.; the upper margin, of which only the outer corner is preserved, is of the same size as the lower.  Moisture and dirt have obliterated much of the writing.</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0900" notAfter="1099">10th-11th CE</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Egypt</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased from Professor Bernhard Moritz of Cairo through W.M. Mueller, 1910.</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">leather</term>
               <term type="genre_form">literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">hadiths</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
