<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Farm Account</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">upenn.apis.103</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(PU) 103</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Penn. Museum inv.E16255</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Side 1: Accounts referring to farm produce. Some words remain unknown or unclear as to meaning. Side 2: Remnants of a private letter about which little sense can be made. (Della Vida)</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Text is on both sides. Side 1 is in two columns, the first (at right) is three lines; the second (at the left) is five lines.  Side 2, which was cut through its length, has the beginnings of 14 lines of a private letter, written perpendicular to the shorter side. Only a few letters remain from each line so no sense can be derived.</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Museum of Archaeology and Anthropology, Ellen W. Harrison Collection.</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>21.0 x 5.0cm. Relatively well-preserved piece of paper with creases and several small holes throughout.</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0900" notAfter="1099">10th-11th CE</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Egypt</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased from Professor Bernhard Moritz of Cairo through W.M. Mueller, 1910.</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">paper</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">account</term>
               <term type="genre_form">letter</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Side 1: Column 1: 1. The first (time) barley, forty ardabbs. 2. And a second time, barley, eight ardabbs less two thirds. 3. And on his debt . . . twenty ardabbs of wheat. What the tenant received: thirty-two ardabbs, a third time, wheat. Column 2: 1. Beans, the first time to . . . . . and . . . . .; wheat for the rented field. 2. nineteen ardabbs of beans 3. A second time, eleven ardabbs of beans, on the third(?) thirty-one 4. A second time, eleven ardabbs of beans. 5. Fifty-two ardabbs on the fourth. Sixty-one ardabbs and a half.  (Della Vida)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
