<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<bibl xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="b20632" type="book">
   <title level="m" type="main">Architectural Styles of Ancient Alexandria. Elements of Architectural Decoration from Polish Excavations at Kom el-Dikka (1960-1993).</title>
   <series>
      <title level="s" type="main">Centre d'Archéologie méditerranéenne de l'Académie polonaise des Sciences et Centre Kazimierz Michalowski d'Archéologie méditerranéenne de l'Université de Varsovie. Alexandrie.</title>
      <biblScope type="volume">VIII</biblScope>
   </series>
   <author n="1">
      <forename>Barbara</forename>
      <surname>Tkaczow</surname>
   </author>
   <date>2008</date>
   <pubPlace>Varsovie</pubPlace>
   <publisher>Académie polonaise des Sciences. Centre d'Archéologie méditerranéenne</publisher>
   <note type="pageCount">369</note>
   <note type="illustration">et 154 pll. + pll. A-D coul.</note>
   <note resp="#BP">Introduction. - Part I: 1. Ancient Alexandria and its buildings - historical outline; - 2. Review of architectural styles used in Alexandria from the 3rd century B.C.; - 3. Buildings of ancient Alexandria. - Part II: 1. Architectural complexes discovered on Kom el-Dikka; - 2. Elements of architectural decoration found on Kom el-Dikka (1960-1993); - 3. The Kom el-Dikka assemblage in the Alexandrian context. - Part III. Catalogue [1-1254]. - Appendix.</note>
   <idno type="pi">20632</idno>
   <idno type="bp">2008-0626</idno>
   <idno type="bp_old">09/1/194</idno>
   <idno type="isbn">83-922-3195-3</idno>
   <seg type="original" subtype="index" resp="#BP">241 Alexandrie 840</seg>
   <seg type="original" subtype="titre" resp="#BP">TKACZOW Barbara, Architectural Styles of Ancient Alexandria. Elements of Architectural Decoration from Polish Excavations at Kom el-Dikka (1960-1993). (Centre d'Archéologie méditerranéenne de l'Académie polonaise des Sciences et Centre Kazimierz Michalowski d'Archéologie méditerranéenne de l'Université de Varsovie. Alexandrie. VIII.)</seg>
   <seg type="original" subtype="publication" resp="#BP">Varsovie, Académie polonaise des Sciences. Centre d'Archéologie méditerranéenne, 2008, 4°, 369 pp. et 154 pll. + pll. A-D coul. ISBN 83-922-3195-3.</seg>
   <seg type="original" subtype="resume" resp="#BP">Introduction. - Part I: 1. Ancient Alexandria and its buildings - historical outline; - 2. Review of architectural styles used in Alexandria from the 3rd century B.C.; - 3. Buildings of ancient Alexandria. - Part II: 1. Architectural complexes discovered on Kom el-Dikka; - 2. Elements of architectural decoration found on Kom el-Dikka (1960-1993); - 3. The Kom el-Dikka assemblage in the Alexandrian context. - Part III. Catalogue [1-1254]. - Appendix.</seg>
   <seg type="original" subtype="nom" resp="#BP">Tkaczow</seg>
</bibl>
