<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml" ?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hgv1">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>...</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <idno type="filename">0000000000044638.xml</idno>
        <idno type="biblio">0000000000044638</idno>
        <idno type="bp_old">10/3/227</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl type="monograph" subtype="Editor"/>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <p>This file encoded to comply with EpiDoc Guidelines and Schema version 8
                <ref>http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/gl/5/</ref>
         </p>
    </encodingDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change who="BP" when="2011-06-14">Record created</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="bibliography">
        <bibl xml:lang="en">
          <title level="a" type="main">Archives and Dossiers.</title>
          <title level="m" type="main">The Oxford Handbook of Papyrology </title>
          <author n="1">
            <surname>VANDORPE</surname>
            <forename>Katelijn</forename>
          </author>
          <editor n="1">
            <forename>R.S.</forename>
            <surname>BAGNALL</surname>
          </editor>
          <publisher>
            <placeName>Oxford</placeName>
          </publisher>
          <date>2009</date>
          <biblScope type="page" from="216" to="255"/>
          <biblScope type="illustration">12 figg.</biblScope>
          <note type="annotation">Terminological Issues: The Term Archive in Papyrological Jargon; - Archive versus Library, Archive versus Dossier. - Intact and Mixed Archives: Archives in Their Original Deposit; - Archives Mixed Up in Antiquity; - Archives Mixed Up in Recent Times. - Reconstruction of Archives: Relying on the Archaeological Context: A Solid Method; - Studying Prosopographical Data: A Successful Approach; - Identifying Real Estate: A Method Rarely Applied; - Museum Archaeology: A New Method. - Editions, Guides, and Lists of Archives: Editions; - Guides; - Descriptions, Lists and Studies of Archives. - Types of Archives and Archive Keepers: Official Archives and Personal Archives of Official; - Personal and Family Archives of a Private Nature (Personal versus Family Archives; - Private versus Professional Papers); - Archives of Communities; - Archives Comprising a Single Type of Document. - Composition of Archives: Incoming versus Outgoing Documents; - Juridical versus Sentimental Value. - Greek, Egyptian, and Bilingual Archives. - Classifying Papers and Files. - Ostraca Groups: Archives Sui Generis. - Moments of Joy. - Archives Mentioned in This Chapter, Listed Alphabetically.</note>
        </bibl>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
