<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml" ?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hgv1">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>...</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <idno type="filename">0000000000044784.xml</idno>
        <idno type="biblio">0000000000044784</idno>
        <idno type="bp_old">10/4/134</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl type="journal"/>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <p>This file encoded to comply with EpiDoc Guidelines and Schema version 8
                <ref>http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/gl/5/</ref>
         </p>
    </encodingDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change who="BP" when="2011-06-01">Record created</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="bibliography">
        <bibl>
          <title level="a" type="main">Ostraca Upsaliensia (Part I). Avec résumé en anglais.</title>
          <author n="1">
            <surname>HICKEY</surname>
            <forename>Todd</forename>
          </author>
          <series>
            <title level="j" type="main">Archiv für Papyrusforschung und verwandte Gebiete</title>
            <title level="j" type="short">ArchPF</title>
            <biblScope type="issue">56</biblScope>
          </series>
          <date>2010</date>
          <biblScope type="page" from="258" to="273"/>
          <biblScope type="illustration">1 tabl. et pll. VIII[b] - XVI[a].</biblScope>
          <note>16 Greek ostraka from the collection of the Victoria Museum of Egyptian Antiquities at Uppsala University. - 1. Inv. 1127. A poll tax receipt from Roman Elephantine. 23.viii.79. - 2. Inv. 966. A poll tax receipt from Roman Edfu. Probably 107. - 3-16. Receipts from Roman Thebes. - 3-4. From the dossier of Nepheros and his sons. - 3. Inv. 653. Receipt for the poll and bath taxes. 12.v.88. - 4. Inv. 1589. Receipt for the bath tax. 14.vi.98. - 5-12. Receipts for payments of money taxes. - 5. Inv. 2440. Receipt for the poll and bath taxes. 15.viii.44. - 6-7. Two receipts from the dossier of Pamonthes, son of Haryothes. - 6. Inv. 1243. Receipt for the poll and bath taxes. 29.iii.50(?). - 7. Inv. 920. Receipt for the poll and bath taxes. 11.ix.56. - 8. Inv. 1383. Receipt for the dike (and bath taxes). 17.viii.113. - 9. Inv. 1361. Receipt for the dike and bath taxes. 19.ix.117. - 10. Inv. 2505. Receipt for a tax on two mummies. 15(?).vii.127. - 11. Inv. 2444. Receipt for the dike and bath taxes. 1.xii.149. - 12. Inv. 2382. Receipt for the tax on weavers. 21.ii.167. - 13-16. Receipts for tax payments in kind. - 13. Inv. 1362. Receipt for payment to the granary of the villages. 13.viii.151. - 14-16. From the dossier of Panameus, son of Pekysis. - 14. Inv. 754. Receipt for payment to the granary of the villages. 28.v.192. - 15. Inv. 1133. Receipt for payment to the granary of the villages. 194. - 16. Inv. 2555. Receipt for payment to the granary of the villages. 23.vi.195.</note>
        </bibl>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
