<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">princeton.apis.p467</idno>
            <idno type="controlno">(NjP)apis.p0467</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invno">AM 8950</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Letter which refers to a dispute concerning the payment of 5,500 drachmas</summary>
                  <msItem>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; on the verso, a eulogy</note>
                     <note type="general">20 lines + 2 lines in margin;</note>
                     <note type="general">The hand is a large, compressed upright cursive, showing influence of the chancery style</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItem>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus fragment; 16 x 13 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0200" notAfter="0299">IIIrd c. AD</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Provenance Unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>
                  <rs type="genre_form">Papyri</rs>
               </term>
               <term>
                  <rs type="genre_form">Letter</rs>
               </term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[recto] Greetings to Chairemon, most honored. I have been brought to the president of the town-council concerning the sum of the payment, since you wrote that 5,500 dr. was paid, but he had asked for the payment of the whole talent.  I am satisfied at the moment with 5,000 dr., but when [l. 5] in the presence of Horigenes, again many times a gymnasiarch, while Heliodoros paid respect to me, after Satorneilos approached him--for this friend of mine was present, when the president alone forbade me [l. 10] to listen and speak, because the decemvir has already decided and Horigenes who was present said . . .I could hardly support . . .  pay back . . . 1,000 dr. in the 13th . . . [l. 15] he went back  . . . Pompeianos . . . a talent and he still owes 5,500 dr. and it still holds . . . giving the whole . . . for the accounts posted in your name [l. 20] from which you carried out the performance of kosmeteia. [margin] I salute your children and your wife  . . . .  I pray you be well. [verso] [hand 2] Hearing from many about the good disposition of his nature and the earnestness  of his character, [l. 25] and now having learned through facts,  I was pleased and gladly agreedâ-as I was attached to my friendâ- . . . and the letters which were brought early to me, and having read the stained ones, which I have got, I suspected him, and thus now . . .</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Princ. II 71</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Princ.:2:71</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>