<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Receipts for Payment of Rent on Leased Land</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">princeton.apis.p639</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NjP)apis.p0639</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.princ.2.37</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0192;2;37</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.princ;2;37</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12832a 12832b</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12832 12832</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">GD 7624</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>The text is divided into two columns, in each of which a separate receipt is recorded.  Both receipts are for payment of rent (ekphorion)made on a parcel of land situated near Tanis a small village a few miles south of Philadelphia.  The land is part of a chleros.  Aurelious Herakleides, ex-cosmete of Alexandria appears as lessor.  The land was leased by Aurelius Patron, Aurelius Asoeis and Aurelius Atammon.  The amount of rent paid in the first receipt is not stated, but in the second it is 656 1/2 artabas</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; back blank</note>
                     <note type="general">Two columns: col. I, 12 lines, col. II, 12 lines; Col. I complete, col. II broken except at top</note>
                     <note type="general">The receipt in lines 1 to 12 is from Aug. 29, 255; that in lines 13 to 26 is from 256</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus fragment; 8.5 x 25.5 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0255" notAfter="0256">255 and 256  AD</origDate>
                     <origPlace>From Tanis</origPlace>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Receipt</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[col. I] Aurelius Herakleides, former kosmetes of the most illustrious city of Alexandria, through Amais, overseer of Tanis, to Aurelii Patron and Asoeis and Atammon, renters of the [l. 5] plot of land of Ptiap-, greetings.  I have received from you the payment of rent for the arourai of my land which you farm on shares near the village of Tanis for the current second year, the rent having been paid in full, and having been formally questioned, I have acknowledged it.  I, Aurelius Herakleides, agree as appropriate. [l. 10] The 2nd year of our Lords Valerianus and Gallienus, Augusti, the 6th added day of Mesore [sc. August 29, 255 AD]. [col. II] Aurelius Herakleides, former kosmetes of the most illustrious city of Alexandria, through Amais, [l. 15] overseer of Tanis, to Aurelii Patron and Asoeis and Atammon, renters of the plot of land of Ptiap-, greetings.  I have received from you the payment of rent for the arourai of my land which you farm  on shares [l. 20] near the village of Tanis for the current 3rd  year . . . 656 artabas of wheat, half of the full . . . total 656 artabas of wheat.  I have received through Amais 656 artabas of wheat, as has been agreed. [l. 25] The 3rd year of our Lords Valerianus and Gallienus, Augusti, [month, day].</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Princ. II 37 <note>BL III 149 and VII 168</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Princ.:2:37</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <p>
               <figure>
                  <graphic url="http://arks.princeton.edu/ark:/88435/3484zk51k"/>
               </figure>
               <figure>
                  <graphic url="http://www.columbia.edu/cgi-bin/dlo?obj=princeton.apis.p639"/>
               </figure>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
