<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">princeton.apis.p481</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NjP)apis.p0481</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.princ.2.97</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0192;2;97</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.princ;2;97</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">17374</idno>
            <idno type="TM">17374</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">GD 7619</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Letter in which the writer gives instructions to the recipient to issue receipts to certain farmers and vine-dressers who have delivered the required number of pigs in settlement of claims against them.  He is instructed to further credit these deliveries on his accounts.  In most cases one pig has been delivered.  Deliveries are creditied for the years 325/326 and 326/3227.  The letter also contains an instruction for the settlement of taxes on the estate under the supervision of the addressee</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written across the fibers; on the recto traces of an account</note>
                     <note type="general">30 lines; one line missing at the top</note>
                     <note type="general">The text s effaced in the center and at the right</note>
                     <note type="general">The hand is a fluent cursive</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus fragment; 23.5 x 9.5 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0326" notAfter="0327">326/327 AD</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Provenance Unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Letter</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Horion . . .  to . . . his brother (?), greetings.  When the pigs have been delivered by the farmers and [l. 5] vine-dressers of the estate, insure that having taking the receipts for me you give receipts to those listed below so that you credit them to the list of revenues.  [l. 10] The following are for the past year 20, year 10, year 2 // Moschos for 6 arouras of the water-guarding; 1 pig, for the newly planted vineyard; 1 pig, Euphron; [l. 15] for the mill service,1 pig, for 3 arouras of the water-guarding; and vineyard, 2 pigs, and for the current year 21, year 11, year 3; Moschos for 6 arouras of the water-guarding, 1 pig; for the vineyard, 2 pigs. Helenos for 6 arouras of the water-guarding; [l. 20] 1 pig, for the vineyard, 1 pig, for the mill service; 2 pigs, [[Helenos for 6 arouras of the water-guarding 1 pig]]; for 3 arouras of the water-guarding, 1 pig; for 7 arouras of the water-guarding, 2 pigs; Pauan; for the garden, 1 pig, for the [l. 25] newly planted . . . subject to the 1/6 tax . . .; for the vineyard, 1 pig, also make settlement; for the demosia (= public taxes) on the estate under your supervision. [l. 30] I pray you be well.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Princ. II 97</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Princ.:2:97</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <p>
               <figure>
                  <graphic url="http://arks.princeton.edu/ark:/88435/2z10ws81g"/>
               </figure>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
