<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Account</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">princeton.apis.p91</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NjP)apis.p0091</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.20.14576</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;20;14576</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;20;14576</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14887a 14887b</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14887 14887</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">AM 8917v</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Account; twenty columns of a ledger recording payments for the syntaximon</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written across the fibers; on the recto, accounts for syntaximon (P.Princ. 8)</note>
                     <note type="general">Complete</note>
                     <note type="general">The hand is a small, rapid cursive</note>
                     <note type="general">Many abbreviations used</note>
                     <note type="general">In several places, near the beginning and the end of the roll, the ink has faded</note>
                     <note type="general">Col. (i) 8 lines; col. (ii) 32 lines; col. (iii) 38 lines; col. (iv) 9 lines; col. (v) 39 lines; col. (vi) 19 lines; col. (vii) 35 lines; col. (viii) 37 lines; col. (ix) 9 lines; col. (x) 23 lines; col. (xi) 39 lines; col. (xii) 40 lines; col. (xiii) 39 lines; col. (xiv) 40 lines; col. (xv) 42 lines; col. (xvi) 36 lines; col. (xvii) 34 lines; col. (xviii) 34 lines; col. (xix) 33 lines; col. (xx) 4 lines</note>
                     <note type="general">On the other side of the papyrus is P.Princ. I 8</note>
                     <note type="local_note">AM 8917 verso. Oversize</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus fragment; 28 x 166 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0043">AD 43, Jan. 14</origDate>
                     <origPlace>From Philadelphia</origPlace>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Account</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[col. I] Mechir. Records in the bank. [col. II] Those in charge of expenses; likewise spent; Horos s. of Mysthas 4 dr.; [l. 5] to Melankomas s. of Ischyrion 2 dr.; to Platon s. of Pachnoubis 4 dr.; 19th of the month of Theogeneios, 3rd (year?), at the bank, Thermouthis s. of Psenamounis; from (?) Psammis s. of Syros, on account of wheat 29 1/4 1/16 artabas; of which 1/2 1/3 1/12. [col. III] [l. 10] expenses [drawn] at the [bank] through Nemesion; to Herakles s. of Petesouchos 4 dr.; . . .  8 dr.; . . . s. of Antiphil- 4 dr. ; in that at Hiera Ptol- 2 dr.; [l. 15] total 18 dr.; to Achillas 20 dr.; to Dionytas s. of Pe- 4 dr.; to Eisapollon, armed guard of wine, 8 ob.; to Maron . . . 4 dr.; [l. 20] for fodder 3 ob.; for the price of the sweatmeats 3 1/2 ob.; to Heron, collector, 3 ob.; to Maron and (?) Isidoros 10 ob.; for dates 3 ob.; [l. 25] account given through Papontos 10 dr.; to Didymas s. of Antiphilos 8 dr.; to Aphrodisios, armed guard, monthly total 8 dr.; likewise for wages 48 dr.; likewise for other expenses 8 dr.; [l. 30] for the price of bramble-berry shoots 3 dr. 3 ob.; to . . . 4 dr.; to Heron, armed guard 1 ob.; to the same 17 dr.; for the price of wheat 6 dr.; [l. 35] expenses for epixena; at Ptolemais Nea, for the price of meat 3 dr. 2 ob.; travel money of an armed guard 80 dr.; in Ptolemais Nea, through Maron 20 dr.; to Horion, armed guard 1 dr.; [l. 40] other expenses 100 dr.; to the same 4 dr. [col. IV] to slaves collecting claims 2 dr.; to herald 12 dr.; to servants 4 dr.; [l. 45] [[to slaves 2 dr.]]; to Papees for the price of dates 2 dr.; to Adrastos 4 ob.; for vegetables zyt- 4 ob.; for tach- chre- 8 dr.; [l. 50] to scribe 60 dr.; to Dionytas 8 dr.  to Hermes 8 dr.; for scribe’s salary 14 dr.; to Petesouchos s. of Hegemon 24 dr.; [l. 55] for the price of wine 4 dr.; for one papyrus roll 1 dr.; likewise for the price of reeds 4 dr.; for the price of dates 3 dr.  total, in silver 124 dr.; [l. 60] to Rufus 4 dr.; for the price of meat 2 dr.; for armed guards assigned to Polemon meris 40 dr.; for another expenditure; to Petesouchos s. of Hegemon, through Maron 124 dr.; [l. 65] to scribe 13 dr. 3 ob.; to the chief of armed guards 4 dr.; in Boukolon; [[to Platon s. of Pachnoubis 2 dr.]]; [[Horos s. of Morseus 6 dr.]]; [l. 70] [[Horos s. of Mysthas 13 dr. 2 ob.]]; of which expenditures; to Euboulos 13 dr. 2 ob.; to Petesouchos s. of Isoun 1 ob.; to Kephalon 1 ob.; [l. 75] to the slaves ob.; to armed guard and (?) scribe 2 dr.; to Petesouchos partner of Achillas 2 dr.; likewise for expenditures 32 dr.; to Ptolemaios, armed guard 8 dr. [col. V] [l. 80] From Maron 12 dr.; for fodder 2 ob.; for the likewise ob.; and expenses through Maron 2 dr.; to Maron who is exempt from dike tax 14 dr.; [l. 85] other to Petesouchos s. of Hegemon 28 dr.; to Ptolemaios, scribe ob.; for fodder 4 ob.; to armed guard 1 dr. [col. VI] To Maron, from which he gave; [l. 90] to the account of stone masonry 40 dr.; Onnophris, priest 7 ob.; Onnophris s. of Moueris 7 ob.; Onnophris s. of Pataas 7 ob.; Harphaesis s. of Cheousis 4 ob.; [l. 95] Petanoupis s. of Apynchis 3 ob.; Herakles s. of Horos 5 ob.; Pylades s. of Herakles 5 ob.; Panetbeus s. of Harmaios 5 ob.; Petesouchos s. of Harmaios 7 ob.; [l. 100] Laertes s. of Harphaesis 7 ob.; Apollonios s. of Anoubion 4; Apis weaver 6 ob.; Pankrates the younger s. of Haryotes 7 ob.; Herakles s. Psenamounis 7; [l. 105] Ibion s. of Marres 3 ob.; Onnophris s. of Peteamounis 7 ob.  Polyphantes s. of Polyphantes 7 ob.; Apollonios s. of Phanomgeus 7 ob.; Pasion s. of Herakles 6; [l. 110] Pnepheros s. of Petermouthis 7; Orsenouphis, weaver 2 ob.; Horion s. of Ptolemaios 6; Pomas [[s. of Akes]] 7; Petesouchos s. of Theanios 6; [l. 115] Herakles s. of Pauesis 7; likewise Herakles 7; Pankras s. of Onnophris 7; Ischis s. of Doras 14; Ischyrion s. of Kallis 7; [l. 120] Syros s. of Syros 14; Harphaesis s. of Hergeus 2; Ptolion s. of Mysthas 2; Tethautis 6 half-obols; Theon s. of Ptollis 3; [l. 125] Petermouthis s. of Peteesis 3; Esouris s. Pomsais 7; Herieus s. of Herieus, copper-smith 7. [col. VII] Petsiris Archonides 7; Panoueites [[s. of Anchor]] s. of Panchrates 7; [l. 130] Haronnophris s. of Heras 5; Athenion 7; Petermouthis s. of Phanomgeus 7; Herakles s. of Petesouchos, donkey-driver 7; Pnepheros s. of Harphaesis 7; [l. 135] Phabis s. of Straton 21; Ptermouthis s. of Phanomgeus 21; Anoubion s. of Papontos 7; Onnophris s. of Onnophris, weaver 21; Apynchis s. of Pomsais 7; [l. 140] Herakles s. of Ischyrion 7; Kallis s. of Hatres 7; Belles s. of Esouris 7; Phasis s. of Labatas 2; Herakles s. of Mysthas 7; [l. 145] Theon s. of Herakleides 4 dr.; Theon s. of Haryotes 4 dr. [col. VIII] expenses for epixena; at the epoikion of Nestos; Nemesion s. of Mysthas 6 dr.; [l. 150] his brother  6 dr.; Horion s. of Asklepiades 6 dr.; Ptollis s. of Ptollis, copper-smith 6 dr.; Sambas the son 6 dr.; total 30 dr.; [l. 155] Hieras; Hermias s. of Peteesis 6 dr.; Horion s. of Orsenouphis 6 dr.; Phasis s. of Horion 6 dr.; Petesouchos s. of Ptolemaios 6 dr.; [l. 160] Herakles s. of Herkales 6 dr.; total 30 dr.; at Ptolemais Nea; Mysthas s. of Panetbeus 6 dr.; Nekpheros s. of Harphaesis 6 dr.; [l. 165] Panetbeus s. of Mysthas 6 dr.; Herieus s. of Nekpheros 6 dr.; Abis s. of Horos 6 dr.; Horos the son 6 dr.; at the epoikion of Metrodoros 11 dr. 3 ob.; [l. 170] at Philoteris, Sambas s. of Heras 4 dr.; total 51 dr. 3 ob.; at Astar; Petermouthis s. of Psenobastis 6 dr.; Laches the son 6 dr.; [l. 175] another Psenobastis 6 dr.; Hatres weaver 6 dr.; Herakleides s. of Sambas 6 dr.; Dioskous, his brother 6 dr.; Phasis s. of Hatres and his son 12 dr.; [l. 180] Labeus s. of Onnophris 6 dr.; total 54 dr. [col. IX] [[at Astar]] at Arsinoe; Herieus s. of Harphaesis 6 dr.; Sisois s. of E- 8 dr.; [l. 185] Apollonios s. of Nekpheros 6 dr.; Nekpheros the son 6 dr.; Pachnoubis [ ] 6 dr.; Orsenouphis s. of Paneis 6 dr.; for the epixena; [l. 190] at Andrianton 13 dr. 4 ob.; at Kerkesouchon; Ptollis s. of Besas 6 dr.; Besas s. of Besas 6 dr.; Pnepheros s. of Phanomgeus 6 dr.; [l. 195] Petesouchos s. of Panomgeus 6 dr.; at Nestos, Panetbeus s. of Panetbeus 6 dr.; Papontos, his brother 6 dr.; Herakles, another brother 6 dr.; Hegemon, another 6 dr.; [l. 200] Praxias s. of Sisois 6 dr.  Heras s. of Anoubion 6 dr.; Anoubion, his brother 6 dr.; Sisois the third, s. of Psenobastis 4 dr.; at Hephaistias; [l. 205] Dionysios s. of Anoubion 6 dr.; Aunes s. of Ammonios 6 dr.; total 58 dr.; to Maron these 58 dr.; at the epoikion Straton 5 dr.; [l. 210] Sontois s. of Tithouos 6 dr.; Herieus s. of Petesouchos 6 dr.; at the epoikion of Eusebes 8 dr.; at the epoikion Phanias 12 dr.; at Sebennytos 6 dr.; [l. 215] from which to Kleon, collector 4 dr.; of the monthly total of the metropolis; total expenditures 240. [col. X] Horos s. of Mysthas 12 dr. 10 ob.; Horos s. of Morsis 6 dr.; [l. 220] Platon s. of Pachnoubis 2 dr.; total through Nemesion 67 dr., total 125 dr.; from which expenditures to Petesouchos s. of Pachnoubis 124 dr.; to armed guard 2 dr., to Euboulos 13 dr. 3 ob.; [l. 225] to Kleon collector, for an armed guard 4 dr.  total 144 dr. 1 ob. [col. XI] another Dios s. of Sambas 6 dr.; Panetbeus s. of Harmais 4 dr.; Anoubion s. of Papontos 2 dr.; [l. 230] Petesouchos s. of Nekpheros s. of Ar- 2 dr.; Romaios s. of Hergeus 1 dr.; at the metropolis; Ptollis s. of Petsiris 12 dr.; Pylades 18 dr.; [l. 235] Horos s. of Ambesis 6 dr.; Ischyrion s. of Ptolemaios 12 dr.; Sostratos s. of Apollonios 6 dr.; Psyas 18 dr.; Nikandros 12 dr.; [l. 240] Mysthas s. of Hatres 6 dr.; [ ] 3 dr.; 30th of the month of New Sebastos; Athenion s. of Harmachis 4 dr.; Apynchis s. of Apynchis s. of Did- 4 dr.; [l. 245] Petesouchos s. of Amoneus 4 dr.; Petearpsenesis s. of Petearpsenesis, fruit-buyer 4 dr.; from which for the price of wine 7 dr.; for donative 9 dr.; total, at the same, 108 dr. [col. XII] [l. 250] 10th; of the collection dr. (vacat); Horos s. of Horos s. of Harpas 7 ob.; Horos s. of s. of Horos s. Are- 7 ob.; Dionysios s. of Pamenos 7; [l. 255] Ptolion s. of Panaus 6; Phasis s. Petosiris 13; 13th [ ] 14; Ptollis s. of Besas 7; Aphrodisios s. of Phatres 7; [l. 260] Mysthas s. of Dionysios 7; Pach- s. of Dionysios 7; Psamis s. of Phasis 7; Psenobastis 21; Pomsais, weaver 4; [l. 265] Pylades s. of Apollonios 4 1/2-ob.; Panetbeus s. of Ambesis 7; Sisois, his brother 2; Phasis s. of Phasis s. of Keo- 4; Pnepheros s. of Kyl- 21; [l. 270] Orsenouphis s. of Pach- 14; Petarpochrates s. of Papontos 7; Polemon the son 7; Herakles s. of Pach- 7; Petesouchos s. of Petanoupis 7; [l. 275] Aphrodisios s. of Phratres 4; Akoris 14; Petesouchos s. of Nekpheros 7; Petesouchos s. of Phratres 7; 14th Hatres s. of Sambas 6; [l. 280] Kephalon s. of Psenobastis 6; Mysthas s. of Nekpheros 7; Panomgeus s. of Orsenouphis 7; Orsenouphis s. of Amos 6; Petermotes s. of Aulaios 5; [l. 285] Herakles s. of Amodios 6; Panomgeus s. of Amodios 10; Heras s. of Heras stepson of Koskonios 4;  283 1/2-ob. [col. XIII] Ision s. of Hegemon 2; [l. 290] Sambas s. of Thebaios 7; Petsiris s. of Kallis 8; Labeus s. of Onnophris 5; Harmiysis s. of Dionysios 2; Harphaesis s. of Harphaesis s. of Aulaios 6; [l. 295] Hatres s. of Ischyrion 7; Herakles s. of Petechon 7; Ischyrion s. of Nekpheros 7; Mithrodates s. of Pasion 6; Petesouchos s. of Ischyrion 7; [l. 300] Mysthas s. of Nekpheros; Herakles s. of Nenephis 14; Herakles s. of Horos 9; Ischyrion s. of Chrysippos 21; Thimbron s. of Harpsemis 6; [l. 305] Pouoris 3 1/2 ob.  Harphaesis s. of Paos 8; Melas s. of Tryphon 7; Heliodoros s. of Dioskous 7; Pachiris s. of Dioskous 3; [l. 310] Pnepheros s. of Akousilaos 3; Akousilaos 4; Petesouchos s. of Apollonios 4; Harmiysis s. of Horos 2; Onesimos 14; [l. 315] Haryotes s. of Thyon 21; Phasis s. of Haryotes 14; Leonteus s. of Leonteus 7; Petermouthis s. of Petesouchos 7; Petesouchos s. of Mysthas 7; [l. 320] Panaus s. of Pano- 4; Nekpheros s. of Apollonios 7; Haronnophris s. of Horos 7; Phasis s. of Petermouthis 6; Panetbeus s. of Akousilaos 15; [l. 325] Hektor  ob. 6; Pasion s. of Herakles 7; Kephalon s. of Kephalon 7; 289 1/2-ob. [col. XIV] Dios s. of Anigonos 7; [l. 330] Psenobastis 4 dr.; Nemesion s. of Stratippos 7; Praxias s. of Praxias 21; Phasis s. of Thebaios 10; Ptollas s. of Euandros 13 1/2 ob.; [l. 335] Ammonios s. of Mysthas 4 dr.; Papeis s. of Apynchis 21; Thyon s. of Haryotes 21; Petesouchos s. of Peterpsenesis 7; Petsiris s. of Orsenouphis 14; [l. 340] Pnepheros s. of Archedemos 4; Herakles s. of Ammonios 14; Polemon s. of Polemon 8; Orsenouphis s. of Orsenoupis the older 4; [[Polemon s. of Polemon 8]]; [l. 345] Patynis s. of Naaraus 14; Onnophreis s. of Petemounis 7; Harmiysis s. of Papontos 7; Pasis s. of Pasis 7; Herieus s. of Paos 14;[l. 350] Mysthas s. of Orsenouphis 4; Harphaesis s. of Cheousis 7; Petsiris s. of Harphaesis 12; Petesouchos s. of Onnophris 7; Pomsais s. of Anchorimphis 2; [l. 355] Herakles s. of Petesouchos s. of Pano- 7; Petesouchos s. of Araus 21; Anoupis s. of Sambas 14; Peterpsenesis, weaver 21; Orsenouphis s. of Petemounis 7; [l. 360] Damas s. of Ptol- 7; Horos s. of Panetbeus 14; Herieus s. of Ptollis 7; Hatres s. of Atomeus 21; Petsiris s. of Diodoros 7; [l. 365] Petesouchos s. of Panaus 7; Harphaesis s. of Dikranos 14; 389 1/2 ob.; [col. XV] Herakles s. of [ ] 2; Herakles s. of [ ] s. of Ark- 7; [l. 370] Harmiysis s. of Harmiysis 6; Iason s. of Sambas the younger 21; Psenatymeis s. of Horion 14; Aischrion 2; Panethoutes 14; [l. 375] Laertes s. of Nekpheros 7; Atomeus s. of Panomgeus 7; Kales s. of Petesouchos 7; Pachnoubis, weaver 7; Nekpheros s. of Nekpheros s. of Alekis 7; [l. 380] Panomgeus s. of Ammonios 7; Petearpsenesis s. of Petearpsenesis 21; Chairemon s. of Horion 4; Ammoneus s. of Harphaesis 7; Harmiysis s. of Mysthas 7; [l. 385] Petesouchos s. of Mysthas 8; Kephalon s. of Teos 4; Kephalon s. of Panetbeus 7; Petesouchos the older, barber 14; Apynchis s. of Pomsais 7; [l. 390] Chrysippos 6 1/2-ob.; Polemon s. of Polemon 4; Petesouchos s. of Ischyrion 7; Esoures the younger s. of Ischyrion 7; Nekpheros s. of Ischyrion 7; [l. 395] Dios s. of Sambas 7; Athenais 3 1/2-ob.; Teos s. of Panetbeus 9; Pouoris, his brother 7; Apynchis s. of Herakles 7; [l. 400] Ptolion, weaver 7; Petsiris s. of Seras 2; Hatres s. of Syros 13 1/2 ob.; Nekpheros s. of Heras 8;  Papais s. of Apynchis 4; [l. 405] Panaus s. of Ptolion 7; Ptolion s. of Mysthas 4 1/2-ob.; 296 1/2 ob. [col. XVI] Konnos s. of Apollonios 7; Ptollis s. of Sambas; [l. 410] Horos s. of Mysthas 10; Dios s. of Dios 7; Theon s. of Dios 7; Kephalon s. of Psenatymis 7; Petalos s. of Pasion 7; [l. 415] Nikanor s. of Pnepheros 7; Psenatymeis 5; Dekatos s. of E- 7; Heras s. of Areos 7; Kollythis s. of Psenatymis 6; [l. 420] Phasis s. of Praxias 7; Sambas s. of Dios 7; Mysthas s. of Herakles 9; Horos s. of Horos s. of Kobeis 7; Sambas s. of Andronikos 7; [l. 425] Dioskous s. of Dioskous 2; Ischyrion s. of Ischyrion 7; Pnepheros s. of Petesouchos 7; Dionysandros 7; Pason s. of Pason, shepherd 6; [l. 430] Onnophris s. of Harphaesis 7; Dikranes s. of Harphaesis 2; Petesouchos s. of Kottos 4; Patynis s. of Pnepheros 7; [l. 435] Sisois, weaver 4; another Sisois 7; Mysthas s. of Horos 14; Petesouchos s. of Apollonios 3; Apynchis s. of Phanomgeus 21; Stratippos s. for the shepherd 4 dr.; [l. 440] Ptolion s. of Ptolion 7; Panaus s. of Ptolion 5; Hermias s. of Antaios for the shepherd 4 dr.;  238; Thesion s. of Apollonios 8 dr.; [l. 445] another(?) Petesouchos s. of Herakles 2 dr. Dios s. of Herakles 6 dr.; total 34 dr.; Sambas s. of Panomgeus 6 dr., 10th Hermas s. of Ischyrion 8 dr.; Apynchis s. of Phanomgeus 2 dr., Peteanoupis 2 dr.; Petesouchos s. of Panomgeus 8 dr., to Kleon 5 ob.; [l. 450] Mysthas s. of Petechon 12 ob., total 9 dr. 1 ob. [col. XVII] And before the collecting for the present arithmesis; Amonneus s. of Harphaesis 9 ob.; Peteamounis s. of Peteamounis s. of Teos 10 ob.; Pouoris the younger s. of Hatres 10 ob.; [l. 455] Amonneus s. of Petalos 5; Ptolles s. of Sambathion 15; Apion and Aischyrion 10; Arronophris s. of Heras 10; Pachnoubis s. of Atomeus 5; [l. 460] Horos s. of Mysthas 11; Harphaesis s. of Harphaesis s. of Aulaios 15; Harphaesis s. of Herieus 5; Herakles s. of Harmiysis 5; Pnepheros s. of Phanomgeus 5; [l. 465] Athenais s. of Heras 10; Kephalon s. of Teos 9; Teos s. of Kephalon 5; Petsiris s. of Panetbeus 5; Dikranes s. of Harphaesis 5; [l. 470] Harphaesis s. of Pateesis 10; Dionysios s. of Pamenos 10; Harmiysis s. of Dionysios 10; 189 Harphaesis s. of Cheusis 10; Anoubas and Horos 10; [l. 475] Dioskous s. of Dioskous 5; Panetbeus s. of Harmiysis 10; Horos s. of Teos 10; Panesneus s. of Kephalon 5; Hierax s. of Onnophris, buyer of fruit 10; [l. 480] Mysthas s. of Herakles 5; Horion s. of Ptolemaios 15; Hatres s. of Atomeus 5; Orsenouphis s. of Nekpheros 5; Petermouthis s. of Harmiysis 5; [l. 485] Pomsais s. of Hesties (?) also called Ischyrion 20 ob.; Petsiris s. of Harphaesis 15 [col. XVIII] Panebeus s. of Ambesis 5; (vacat) 5; Ptollis s. of Ptollis 10; [l. 490] Phasis s. of Kokalos 10; Asklas, weaver, syntaximon; from . . . 4 dr.; Petsiris s. of Dikran- 5; Sambas s. of Chairemon 10; [l. 495] Harmiysis s. of Horos 5; Pacheiris s. of Dioskous 4; Petesouchos s. of Dikran- 5; Herakles s. of Horos 5; Apion s. of Haryotes 15; [l. 500] Sisois s. of Ambesis 5; Pnepheros s. of Akousilaos 10; Akousilaos s. of Romaios 10; Nekpheros s. of Hatres 1; Apollonios s. of Anoubion 10; [l. 505] Misiophres s. of Mysthas 3 1/2 ob.; Polemon s. of Hatres 5; Petesis s. of Petesis 10; Apollonios s. of Herakles 2 dr.; Ptollis s. of Petesouchos 2 dr.; [l. 510] Harphaesis s. of Chrates 2 dr.; Labeus s. of Hatres 4; Mysthas s. of Horos 4; Petesouchos s. of Petesouchos s. of Paraba- 4; Aunes s. of Aunes 4; [l. 515] Pankrates 4; Pharbethon 4; Hatres s. of Hatres 4; of which expenses; to Petesochos 24 dr.; [l. 520] to soldiers 23 dr. 1/2 ob. [col. XIX] to scribes 148 dr.; to Papion, a bribe 40 dr.; for conversion of copper 3 dr.; to Horion s. of Stoutouetis 2 dr.; [l. 525] to Isapollon, for wages 4 dr.; for maintenance of a scribe 13 dr. 4 ob.; to slaves 2 dr. 2 ob.; for dates 4 dr.; Monthly total for Mechir; [l. 530] at Hephaistias 13 dr.; Bakchias; Mysthas s. of Amonneus 5 dr.; Hatres s. of Patynis 5 dr.; Harmais s. of Panetbeus 5 dr.; [l. 535] Louson 4 dr.; Hiera; Anoubion s. of Meleagros 2 dr.; Horion s. of Akousilaos 2 dr.; Herakles s. of Herakles 4 dr.; [l. 540] Pharbaitha; Herakles s. of Herakles 10 ob.; Astar 9 dr.; Ptolemais Nea 10 dr.; Karanis 11 dr.;  [l. 545] Equals 80 dr.; of which, expenses for Bakchias, for wine 22 ob.; for wages 6 ob.; for fodder 4 ob.; at Pharbaitha, for wine 4 dr.; [l. 550] for wages 5 ob.; for conversion 4 ob.; in the [epoikion] of Amyntaios 4 dr.;  to . . ., armed guard 2 dr.; to Aphrodisios, armed guard 8 dr. [col. XX] [l. 555] at the epoikion Straton 6 dr.; Eusebeus 12 dr.; Phanias 12 dr.; Amyntaios 12 dr.; Nestos 10 dr.; [l. 560] Abrochos 9 dr.; Agrias 11 dr.; 66 dr.; of which expenses 6 dr.; to Maron 12 dr.; [l. 565] Zytos 6 ob.; 30th Patynis s. of Naraus 12 dr.; Thrax s. of Petesouchos 8 dr.; Sokmenis s. of Herakles 6 dr.; Ischuras 4 dr.; [l. 570] Petesouchos s. of Pason 10 dr.; Aphrodisios s. of Pol- 4 dr.; of which to Maron 98 dr.; to Petesouchos s. of Arabo- 24 ob.; to Maron; [l. 575] Hephaistiados 40 dr.; Onnophris s. of Anoubion 2 dr.; Nekpheros s. of Mysthas weaver 2 dr.; Herakles s. of Pnepheros swineherd 4 dr.; Papontos s. of Heliodooros 4 dr.; [l. 580] Petesouchos s. of Chrates 4 dr.; Pachiris s. of Dioskous 2 dr.; Apion s. of Apion vegetable-seller 4 dr.; Horos s. of Petemounis 2 dr.; Petesouchos s. of Nekpheros 2 dr.; [l. 585] Orsenouphis s. of Ammonis scribe 4 dr.; Patmouis donkey-driver 4 dr.; Petesouchos s. of Onnophris 4 dr. [col. XXI] Athenion s. of Harmachis . . . dr.; Petsiris s. of Nekpheros (1-2 dr.); [l. 590] Apychis s. of Marres (1-2 dr.); Herakles s. of Pacheiris (1-2 dr.)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Princ. I 13 SB XX 14576 CPJ III 481 b <note>A. E. Hanson "P. Princeton I 13: Text and Context revised," Miscellanea Papyrologica in occasione del bicentenario dell' edizione della Charta Borgiana (1990): 259-283; A. Hanson, "Lists of Taxpayers from Philadelphia (P.Mich. inv. 879 and P.Princ. I 14)," ZPE 15 (1974): 231 n.9</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB:20:14576</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
