<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Register</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">princeton.apis.p697</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NjP)apis.p0697</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.princ.1.8</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0192;1;8</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.princ;1;8</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12823</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12823</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">AM 8917 recto: oversize</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register for payments for the syntaximon; entries include name, patromymic, metronymic and age;  usually twelve names were entered in each column and a space of about 2 lines was left under the name for the record of payments, which were entered by a different clerk; names are not arranged alphabetically but family groupings suggest that the arrangement was topographical and that the register is of a quarter or tax-precinct of Philadelphia</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; verso published as P.Princ. 13 = SB XX 14576</note>
                     <note type="general">The papyrus was rolled up while the ink was still wet and many lines are blotted</note>
                     <note type="general">Some holes; col. I affected by surface peeling; col. VI has holes at the bottom</note>
                     <note type="general">The hand is a fine, rapid cursive</note>
                     <note type="general">Ten columns: col. I, 28 lines; col. II, 27 lines; col. III, 29 lines; col. IV, 21 lines; col. V, 30 lines; col. VI, 28 lines; col. VII, 13 lines; col. VIII, 24 lines; col. IX, 12 lines; col. X, 21 lines; complete</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus fragment; 28 x 166 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0046" notAfter="0047">AD 46-47, Nov. 27-July 24</origDate>
                     <origPlace>From Philadelphia</origPlace>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Register</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Taxation</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[col. I] Papontos s. of Papontos s. of Lauous whose mother is Tapelalis, aged 47; // 28th of Pharmouthi 20 dr., 21st of Pachon 12 dr., 26th 4 dr., 20th of Epiph 8 dr., 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Dios s. of Papontos whose mother is Heraklea, aged 15; // 28th of Pharmouthi 16 dr., 21st of Pachon 12 dr., 23rd 4 dr., 16th of Epiph 12 dr., 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; [l. 5] Horion s. of Dinoysios whose mother is Thaesis, aged 47; // through the agents of the village of Hiera, Mechir 24 dr., Pachon 20 dr., Pauni 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Mysthas also called Auenes s. of Anchorimphis whose mother is Taubastis, aged 24; // through the agents of the village of Hiera, Tybi 24 dr., Phamenoth 20 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; [l. 10] Satabous s. of Satabous whose mother is Thenamounis, aged 35; through the agents of the village of Kremaste, Choiak 16 dr., Pharmouthi 16 dr.; . . .; // through the agents of the village Kremaste, Choiak  16 dr., Pachon 20 dr. 1/2 ob. 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob.; Pnepheros s. of Papontos s. of Killes whose mother is Dem-, aged 44; [l. 15] through the agents of the village Pol-, Pharmouthi 20 dr.; Auxis s. of Horos whose mother is Apechis, aged 49; through the agents of the village of New Ptolemais, Mechir 20 dr.;   Pachon 16 dr.; Mysthas s. of Panetbys whose mother is Thermouthis, aged 44; [l. 20] // through the agents of the village of New Ptolemais, Phamenoth 20 dr., Pachon 12 dr., Pauni 12 dr., 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Herieus s. of Harphaesis whose mother is Stolarpis, aged 49; through the agents of the village of Arsinoe, Pauni 40 dr.; Herakles s. of Petermouthes whose mother is Tamystha, aged 60; [l. 25] 23rd of Pachon 24 dr., 23rd of Pauni 8 dr.; Petermouthes s. of Herakles whose mother is Thaesis, aged 26; (hand 2) through the agents of the village of Arsinoe (hand 3) 28th of Pachon 16 dr., 23rd of Pauni 8 dr.; (hand 2) Psamenoth 16 dr. [col. II] Sochotes s. of Herakles whose mother is the same, aged 19; (hand 2) through the agents of the village of Arsinoe, Mechir 16 dr., (hand 3) 23rd of Pachon 8 dr., 23rd of Pauni 8 dr.; (hand 2) Phamenoth 8 dr.; Phasis s. of Herakles whose mother is the same, aged 17; [l. 5] (hand 2) through the agents of the village of Arsionoe, Mechir 16 dr., (hand 3) 23rd of Pachon 8 dr., 23rd of Pauni 8 dr.; (hand 2) Phamenoth 8 dr.; Theokles s. of Ptollis whose mother is Taarmotis, aged 46; // 26th of Mechir 16 dr., 30th of Phamenoth 4 dr., Pharmouthi 8 dr.; l- 12 Phamenoth  8 dr., 30th of Pharmouthi 4 dr., 26th of Pauni 4 dr. 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob.; [l. 10] Ptollis s. of Ptollis . . .Theokles whose mother is the same, aged 35; 28th of Pharmouthi 28 dr., l- 16 Pauni 12 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Laertes s. of Ptollis whose mother is the same, aged 33; 21st of Mechir 8 dr., 28th of Phamenoth 8 dr., l- 12  4 dr.; 28th of Pharmouthi 4 dr., 30th 4 dr., 16th of Epiph 8 dr.; [l. 15] Harphaesis s. of Onnophris whose mother is Taormiysis, aged 44; // through the agents of the village of Arsinoe, Pachon 20 dr., Pauni 24 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; . . . s. of Tanameus whose mother is Tanomgeus, aged 25; // . . .  Mechir . . . 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; . . .; [l. 20] through the agents, Choiak 12 dr., Tybi 12 dr., Pachon 16 dr.; Panetbys s. of Hatres whose mother is Sambous, aged 45; // . . . Mechir 16 dr., Mechir 16 dr., Mechir 16 dr. 1/2 ob. 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob.; Pnepheros s. of Phanomgeus s. of Iseis whose mother is Thermouthis, aged 25; // through the agents of the village Kerkesoucha, Choiak 12 dr., Tybi 12 dr.; Mechir dr. 8, Pachon 12 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; [l. 25] Peteuchos s. of Phanomgeus whose mother is the same, aged 16; // through the agents of the village of Kerkesoucha, Choiak 12 dr., Tybi 12 dr., Mechir 8 dr., Pachon 12 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob. ; Panetbys s. of Mysthas whose mother is Taareos, aged 46. [col. III] Isidoros s. of Peteuchos whose mother is Tauris, aged 36; // through the agents of the village Sebennytos, Mechir 12 dr., Pauni 32 dr. 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob.; Phasis s. of Herakles whose mother is Thermouthis, aged 44; through the agents of the village of Straton, Mechir 24 dr., Pharmouthi 8 dr.; [l. 5] Pauni 12 dr.; Anoubion s. of Anoubion whose mother is Thanoubion, aged 46; Harphaesis s. of Anoubion whose mother is the same, aged 33; // through the agents of the village of Straton, Mechir 32 dr., through the agents of the village of Sebennytos, Pauni 12 dr. 1/2 ob. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Sentois s. of Tithoues whose mother is Tanemgeus, aged 53; [l. 10] // through the agents of the village of Straton, Pauni 44 dr. 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob.; Hergeus s. of Petesouchos whose mother is Teinaus, aged 19; // through the agents of the village Straton,  Mechir 24 dr., Phamenoth 12 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Pachon 8 dr.; Herakles also called Papontos stepson of Chairemon whose mother is Tapontos, aged 54; [l. 15] // through the agents of the village of New Ptolemais, Pachon 28 dr., Pauni 16 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Sisois s. of Zoilos whose mother is Herieus, aged 30; // 12th of Tybi 20 dr., Pauni 24 dr., through the agents of the village of Sebennytos, 24 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; [l. 20] Esouris s. of Hatres whose mother is Soueris, aged 30; // through the agents of the village of Sebennytos, Tybi 20 dr., Mechir 8 dr., 16th of Phamenoth 12 dr. Pauni 4 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Petermouthes also called Petsiris . . . whose mother is Tisnis, aged 30; through the agents of the village Epimachos, Mechir 20 dr., Phamenoth 12 dr.; Horion s. of  Pachnoubis whose mother is Tanoubis, aged 54; [l. 25] through the agents of the village of Boubastos, Tybi 24 dr., Pamenoth 24 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Pachnoubis s. of Pachnoubis whose mother is the same, aged 27; through the agents of the village of Psenyris, Choiak 16 dr., Pharmouthi 8 dr., l- m- 4  16 dr., Pachon 4 dr. 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob.; Haryotes s. of Harpsemis whose mother is Taryotis, aged 47; // . . . through the agents of the village of New Ptolemais Pauni 44 dr. 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob. [col. IV] Aunes s. of Harpsemis whose mother is Taryotis, aged 24; // through the agents of the village of Psenyris, Pauni 44 dr. 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob.; Diogenes s. of Sostratos whose mother is Tekosis, aged 17; // 7th of Mechir 32 dr., 12th of Pachon 12 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; [l. 5] Sostratos s. of Apoll- whose mother is Tanomgeus, aged 44; 19th of Tybi 20 dr., through the bank of the village of Psyas, Choiak 12 dr.; Titanos s. of Apoll- whose mother is the same, aged 49; // l- 4 Choiak 12 dr., 6th of Mechir 12 dr., 18th of Pharmouthi 12 dr., 12th Pachon 8 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Chanasis s. of Petermouthis whose mother is ____________, aged; [l. 10] // 18th of Pharmouthi 32 dr., through the bank of the village of Sebennytos Pauni 12 dr. 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob.; Kommon s. of Haryotes whose mother is Aunchis, aged 33; // through the agents, Pauni 44 dr. 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob.; Pebos s. of Haryotes whose mother is the same, aged 39; [l. 15] // through the agents of the village of Boubastos, Mechir 32 dr., pauni 12 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Herakles s. of Phaesis whose mother is Thanoubion, aged 46; Papontos s. of Herakles whose mother is Ptorimphis, aged 16; Phamouereus also called Apponis s. of Horos, aged 48; Nekpheros s. of Horos, aged 39; [l. 20] Horos s. of Harphaesis also called Apathes, whose mother is Tauris, aged 25; Horos s. of Harphaesis whose mother is Tauris, aged 20. [col. V] Herakles s. of Hatres whose mother is Tapeuchos, aged 29; // through the agents of the village of Arsinoe, Pauni 44 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Herakles also called Lykos s. of Lykos, aged 54; // l- 3 Pachon 20 dr., 29th of Pauni 12 dr. 1/2 ob. 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob.; [l. 5] . . . through the agents of the village  . . . 16th of Autnaios (?), 12 dr.; Lykos s. of Herakles also called Lykos whose mother is Tapous, aged 17; through the agents of the village Onniton Koitai, 24th of Tybi 20 dr.; 30th of Phamenoth 4 dr., Pauni 8 dr., l- 3  8 dr.; Dioskoros also called Psosneus s. of Petemounis whose mother is Isidora, aged 38; [l. 10] Sambas s. of Heras whose mother is Isidora, aged 38; Tybi 20 dr.; Petemouthes s. of Petemouthes whose mother is Thotoutes, aged 43; Horos s. of Morseus whose mother is Taninouth-, aged 44; // l- 4 Choiak 8 dr., 19th of Tybi 8 dr., 12th of Pachon 8 dr., 8; [l. 15] 6th of Pauni 8 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob., [[Pauni]], 11th of Epiph 4 dr.; Herakles s. of Psenatymis whose mother is Sennepheros, aged 44; Nikandros s. of Archedemos whose mother is Thermouthis, aged; // 7th of Pachon 12 dr., 12th of Epiph 32 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Chairemon s. of Archedemos whose mother is the same, aged 16; [l. 20] // 12th of Epiph 44 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Harphaesis s. of Petermouthes whose mother is Thermouthis, aged 19; // 18th of Pharmouthi 20 dr., 12th of Epiph 24 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Horos s. of Ambesis whose mother is Tapeuchos, aged 47; // 19th of Tybi 24 dr., 12th of Pachon 8 dr.; [l. 25] Epiph 12 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Platon s. of Pachnoubis whose mother is Taoutis, aged 49; // through the agents of the village of Psenyris, Pauni 20 dr.; 12th of Epiph 24 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Nekpheros s. of Apollon whose mother is Tasokis, aged; [l. 30] 12th of Epiph 24 dr. [col. VI] Pnepheros s. of Apollon whose mother is Tasokis, aged 17, 9th of Choiak 8 dr.; // 19th of Tybi 12 dr., 18th of Pharmouthi 8 dr., Pauni 12 dr., Epiph 4 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Apollonis s. of Apollon whose mother is the same, aged 15, 19th of Tybi 12 dr., 9th of Choiak 8 dr.; // 21st of Mechir 4 dr., 22nd 4 dr., l- 7 Phamenoth 4 dr., 26th of Pharmouthi 8 dr.; [l. 5] 23rd of Pachon 12 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Mysthas s. of Hatres whose mother is Thaesis, aged 43; .9th of Tybi 12 dr., 18th of Pharmouthi 8 dr., 12th of Pachon 12 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Nekpheros also called Balanos whose mother is Thaes, aged 40; // 12th of Epiph 44 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; [l. 10] Herakleides s. of Panetbys whose mother is Tausiris, aged 28; // through the agents of the village of Sebennytos, Phamenoth 24 dr., Pharmouthi 12 dr., Pauni 8 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Ischyrion s. of Ptolemaios whose mother is Berous, aged, 7th of Mechir 20 dr.,; // 12th of Pachon 16 dr., 12th of Epiph 8 dr. 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob.; Sambas also called Ischyrion s. of Ischyrion whose mother is Thatres, aged 33; [l. 15] 13th of Tybi 8 dr.; Horion also called Panomgeus s. of Panetbys whose mother is Tausiris, aged 40; Herakles s. of Ptolemaios whose mother is Berous, aged, 7th of Mechir 28 dr.; // 12th of Pachon 8 dr., 12th of Epiph 8 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Horos s. of Horos whose mother is Taapis, aged 26; [l. 20] // 12th Pachon 32 dr., 12th of Epiph  12 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Chrates s. of Petesouchos whose mother is Aplonis, aged; 23rd of Pauni 36 dr.; . . . Hektor s. of Nekpheros; Phasis s. of Phaesis whose mother is Thanoubis, aged 33; [l. 25] Heron also called Eirenaios s. of Onnophris, aged 39; Kastor s. of Onnophris, aged 47; Orion s. of Onnophris, aged 45; Sisois also called Chairemon s. of Eurion, aged 27. [col. VII] Horos s. of Mysthas, aged 62; // 12th of Epiph 44 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob; Nekpheros s. of Horos whose mother is Thenamounis, aged; Nekpheros s. of Petemounis stepson of Onesimos; [l. 5] // 9th of Choiak 16 dr., 18th of Pharmouthi 28 dr. 1/2 ob. 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob.; Dioskous s. of Sambas whose mother is Satabous; Pekos also called Patynis s. of Naaraus; Naaraus Patynis whose mother is Tamystha; Pteuchos s. of Sambas whose mother is Sambion, aged; [l. 10] Harphaesis s. of Mysthas whose mother is Tauris; Petesouchos s. of Mysthas whose mother is the same; // through the agents of the village of Boubastos, Tybi 20 dr., Mechir 8 dr., Phamenoth 8 dr.; Pauni 8 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob. [col. VIII] Peteuchos s. of Nekpheros whose mother is Thaesis, aged; // 19th of Mechir 12 dr., 25th of Choiak 8 dr; l- 10 Pharmouthi 20 dr., 16th of Choiak 8 dr., 24th of Tybi 4 dr.; 24th of Phamenoth 4 dr., 20th of Pauni 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob.; [l. 5] Zoilos s. of Herakles whose mother is Tephorsos, aged; // 28th of Pauni 44 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Herieus s. of Pnepheros whose mother is Dee-, aged; // 19th of Pachon 24 dr., 19th of Pauni 24 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Dioskous s. of Isapollon s. of Kertes whose mother is Panoubis, aged; [l. 10] 24th of Tybi 16 dr., 21st of Mechir 8 dr., Pharmouthi; 21st of Pachon 8 dr. 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob.; Heras s. of Areos whose mother is Chenousis, aged; // l- 2 Tybu 8 dr., 19th of Mechir 8 dr., 26th of Phamenoth 12 dr.; 30th of Pharmouthi 4 dr., 24th of Pachon 12 dr., 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; [l. 15] Hatres s. of Patynis, aged; Pabis s. of Haryotes, aged; // l- 3 Tybi 16 dr., l- 2 Mechir 12 dr.; 25th of Pachon 16 dr. 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob.; Pouoris s. of Harbaithos, aged; [l. 20] // 16th of Pharmouthi 44 dr. 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob.; Apynchis s. of Keras, aged; // l- m- 4 Phamenoth 44 dr. 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob.; Lagos s. of Apollonios, aged; . . . Praxias s. of Diodoros, aged. [col. IX] Psosneus s. of Praxias whose mother is Thaesis, aged; // l- m- 7 Pauni 44 dr. 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob.; Ptollis s. of Mysthas whose mother is __________, aged; // 10th of  Mechir 16 dr., 29th of Pachon 28 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; [l. 5] Herakles s. of Mysthas whose mother is, aged; // 10th of Mechir 16 dr., 29th of Pachon 28 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Herakles s. of Apollonios s. of Agron whose mother is _______, aged; // through the bank, 7th of Phamenoth 44 dr. 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob.; Sambas also called Keras s. of Harphaesis, whose mother is ________, aged; [l. 10] // through the bank, 17th of Phamenoth 44 dr. 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob.; Horos s. of Pason whose mother is Tauris, aged; // l- 2 Phamenoth 44 dr., 26th of Pauni 1/2 ob. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob. [col. X] Apynchis s. of Pnepheros; Pnepheros s. of Apynchis whose mother is Terobastis, aged 17; Kenn- 22nd of Epiph 44 dr. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Ken- Herakleides s. of Herakles whose mother is Tamystha, aged 19; [l. 5] // through the bank, 18th of Tybi 20 dr., 21st of Pauni 12 dr., 23rd 12 dr.; 24th of Pauni 1/2 ob. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Papontos s. of Leontis whose mother is Thatres, aged 17; // l- 2 Tybi 24 dr., 24th of Pharmouthi 20 dr.; 24th of Pauni 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob.; [l. 10] Horos s. of Peteamounis whose mother is Soueris, aged 40; Papontos s. of Peteamounis whose mother is the same, aged 25; // 21st of Pachon 32 dr., 23rd of Pauni 12 dr. 2 chalki, pig-tax 1 dr. 1 ob.; Petearmotes s. of Petoeris s. of Apoll- whose mother is Tamonn-, aged 47; Petsiris s. of Petsiris whose mother is Tauris, aged 52; [l. 15] Ptollides s. of Petsiris whose mother is Tasos, aged 2.; Pebos s. of Arabion whose mother is Taanno-, aged 20; // 23rd of Pachon 28 dr., 24th of Pauni 16 dr. 1/2 ob. 2 chalki, 1 dr. 1 ob.; Dikranes s. of Dikranes  whose mother is Thermouthis, aged 40; Hatres s. of Didymos whose mother is Thermouthis, aged 55; [l. 20] Dios also called Loukos s. of Nemion whose mother is Soueris, aged 29; . . . s. of Psenamounis whose mother is Thermouthis, aged 17.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Princ. I 8 <note>For the date, cf. BL VII, 165 and BL VIII, 282</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Princ.:1:8</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
