<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Account</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">princeton.apis.p145</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NjP)apis.p0145</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.princ.2.96</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0192;2;96</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.princ;2;96</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">17372</idno>
            <idno type="TM">17372</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">AM 8965</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Account for wages</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written on both sides of the papyrus</note>
                     <note type="general">Recto: col. I, 30 + 1 line written at right angles; col. II, 22 lines + 1 line written at right angles</note>
                     <note type="general">Verso: 22 lines + 6 lines written at right angles</note>
                     <note type="general">The hand is a small, upright, compact cursive</note>
                     <note type="general">Recto two columns; before each column is one line of text written at right angles to the column</note>
                     <note type="general">Verso, left side, 6 lines of text written at right angles to the text on the recto; at the right, a column of text duplicating the names in the columns on the recto</note>
                     <note type="general">Belongs to the Apion archive</note>
                     <note type="local_note">AM 8965: oversize</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus fragment; 30 x 31.5 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0551" notAfter="0567">551/552 or 566/567 AD</origDate>
                     <origPlace>From Oxyrhynchus</origPlace>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[recto] [col. I] List of the wages of the Egyptian slaves, women and others in the 15th indiction, as follows; List of the wages paid to the Egyptian slaves, as follows, paid to; Philoxenos, meizoteros, 12 art. of wheat by the cancellus measure; [l. 5]Philoxenos, meizoteros, 12 art. of wheat by the cancellus measure; the same, as a premium, 12 art. of wheat by the cancellus measure; the same, as a premium, 12 art. of wheat by the cancellus measure; his father Phoibammon, from meizoteroi, 12 art. of wheat by the cancellus measure; his father Phoibammon, from meizoteroi; [l. 10] Iakob, s. of this Phoibammon, 12 art. of wheat by the cancellus measure; Iakob, s. of this Phoibammon; Serenos, from meizoteroi, 12 art. of wheat by the cancellus measure; Serenos, from meizoteroi; his son Viktor, 6 art. of wheat by the cancellus measure; [l. 15] his son Viktor; Marinos s. of Leon, 12 art. of wheat by the cancellus measure; Marinos s. of Leon; Chryseros s. of Mauros, 4 art. of wheat by the cancellus measure; Chryseros s. of Mauros; [l. 20] his brother Annis, 6 art. of wheat by the cancellus measure; Hypatia d. of Viktor, from meizoteroi, 6 art. of wheat by the cancellus measure; her sister Arkadia, 6 art. of wheat by the cancellus measure; her sister Georgia, 6 art. of wheat by the cancellus measure; Apphouas s. of apa Sion, 12 art. of wheat by the cancellus measure; [l. 25] son of apa Sion, 12 art. of wheat by the cancellus measure; Philoxena, sister of apa Sion, 3 art. of wheat by the cancellus measure; Andreas s. of Menas s. of Rouas (?), 12 art. of wheat by the cancellus measure; his son Phoibammon, 3 art. of wheat by the cancellus measure; Papnouthios brother of Andreas, 12 art. of wheat by the cancellus measure; [l. 30] Serenos s. of Papnouthios, 12 art. of wheat by the cancellus measure; [margin] [l. 31] account of receipts and expenditures which occurred through me, Ioannes. [col. II] Isis d. of the same Papnouthios . . .; Petronia d. of the same Papnouthios . . .; Petronia daughter . . .; [l. 35] Maria wife of the same Papnouthios  . . .; Papnouthios s. of Menas s. of Andreas (?) . . . ; Georgios s. of the same . . .; Menas, cake-maker, s. of the same . . .; Christophoros, lute-player . . .; [l. 40] Serenos s. of the same Papnouthios . . .; Theodoros s. of Ioulios . . .; his wife Altina; apa Horos s. of the same Theodoros . . .;  Ioulios s. of the same Theodoros . . .; [l. 45] Serenos s. of the same Theodoros . . .; Menas s. of the same Theodoros . . .; Theodote d. of the same Theodoros . . .; Minerios s. of Euphemia . . .; his mother Euphemia, sister of Ioulios [margin] she died; [l. 50] Phib s. of apa Nakios, butcher . . .; the same, as a premium, . . .; his son Ioannes . . .; Georgios s. of Pseeios s. of Iakob . . . [margin at left, written at right angles] [l. 54] To Flavius Apion, the all-honored and most magnificent formerly consul in ordinary. [verso] [l. 55] Philoxenos, meizoteros; the same, as a premium; his father Phoibammon, from meizoteroi; Iakob s. of the same Phaibammon; Serenos, from meizoteroi; [l. 60] Viktor, his son; Marinos s. of Leon; Chryseros s. of Mauros; Annis his brother; Hypatia d. of Viktor, from meizoteroi; [l. 65] Arkadia, his daughter; Georgia, his sister; Andreas s. of Menas s. of Rouas (?); Phoibammon, his son; Isis d. of the same Papnouthios; [l. 70] Philoxenos meizoteros; the same, as a premium; his father Phoibammon, from meizoteroi; Iakob s. of the same Phaibammon; Serenos, from meizoteroi; [l. 75] Viktor, his son; Marinos s. of Leon; [at left, at right angles] [l. 77] To Flavius Apion, the all-honored and most magnificent formerly consul in ordinary landholder here also in the illustrious city of Oxyrhynchos.  Account of receipts and expenditures that occurred through me.  Receipts and expenditures of the accounted for 14th indiction. [written above the last three lines] [l. 80] To Flavius Apion.  Account of receipts and expenditures of the accounted for 14th indiction. [written upside down above the last line] [l. 81] Account of receipts and expenditures of the accounted for 14th indiction. [in lower left corner, in very large letters] [l. 83] Draft. Draft; Draft. Draft.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Princ. II 96 <note>H. Harrauer, P. J. Sijpesteijn, "P.Princeton II 96 und Schreib*bungen," ZPE 64 (1986): 115-116</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Princ.:2:96</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <p>
               <figure>
                  <graphic url="http://arks.princeton.edu/ark:/88435/5m60qv503"/>
               </figure>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
