<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Declarations Concerning the Delivery of Garments</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">princeton.apis.p250</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NjP)apis.p0250</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.princ.2.27</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0192;2;27</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.princ;2;27</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">17354a 17354b</idno>
            <idno type="TM">17354 17354</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">AM 8947</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Declaration addressed under oath to the strategos of the Oxyrhynchite nome by some official connected with the juridicus; concerns a shipment of garments destined for Alexandria which the strategos urges him to dispatch promptly; the text supplies the name of a juridicus, Suillius Julius; on the verso, in a different hand, is a second declaration also addressed under oath to a strategos, informing him that the delivery of certain garments of stated value will be made in accordance with instructions received from him</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written on both sides of the papyrus</note>
                     <note type="general">Recto, 7 lines, verso, 12 lines; recto, broken at left and bottom; verso, broken at right</note>
                     <note type="general">The hand on the recto is a small, crowded cursive, sloping to the right; the hand on the verso is an upright, fluent cursive with a number of abbreviations</note>
                     <note type="general">The text on the recto dates to 191-192 AD; the text on the verso to ca. 191(?), Dec. 9</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus fragment; 10 x 11 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0191" notAfter="0192">191/192  AD</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Oxyrhynchus</origPlace>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Declaration</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[recto] . . . by Sullius Julius the most excellent juridicus to Sarapion (?), strategos of Oxyrhynchos, greetings. Consider sending with utmost care and at appropriate time the customarily sent in Alexandria clothing of those fighting in heavy arms. I pray for you to be well. The 32nd year of Emperor Caesar Aelius [l. 5] Aurelius Commodus Pius Felix Augustus Armeniacus Medicus Parthicus Sarmaticus Germanicus Maximus Bretannicus, [month, day] and I swear by the fate of Lucius Aelius Commodus Caesar the Lord.  Signed by . . . [verso, hand 2] To Sarapion, strategos. Thonis, freedman of Apollonianos, also called Dionysios (?) . . . [l. 10] both sons of Hermippos of Hadrianeion also called Sarapous from the city of Oxyrhynchos.  We swear by the fortune of Aurelius to have delivered and performed valuation of the payments furnished by the Oxyrhynchcites . . . 3 for 305 denarii, . . . of cloaks . . . for . . .  suits of clothes 34 . . . in accordance with the instructions from Sullius Julius [l. 15] and also sent by ship to Alexandreia with the boats of those ordered to go in that nome  . . .  and remain until . . . 1 himation . . . documents of the delivery, or we will be liable in accordance with the oath.  The 12th of Hadrianos.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Princ. II 27 <note>BL III, 149; VII, 168; VIII, 283; IX, 218.</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Princ.:2:27</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <p>
               <figure>
                  <graphic url="http://arks.princeton.edu/ark:/88435/bn999b070"/>
               </figure>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
