<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Odyssey [III AD]</title>
            <author>Homer</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">princeton.apis.p37</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NjP)apis.p0037</idno>
            <idno type="dclp">60873</idno>
            <idno type="TM">60873</idno>
            <idno type="dclp-hybrid">p.oxy;3;448</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Oxy. 448</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Odyssey, xxii and xxiii</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written across the fibers; on the recto are traces of a prose literary work which has been cleaned off</note>
                     <note type="general">Fragment (h) now preserves only 8 lines, not twelve as published in the ed. pr</note>
                     <note type="general">The 12 lines of column (iv) are not wholly consecutive: (f) 10 lines from the top of the column, (g) 2 lines from the bottom of a column</note>
                     <note type="general">Col. i, 16 lines; col. ii, 14 lines; col. iii, 28 lines; col. iv, 12 lines; col. v, 8 lines</note>
                     <note type="general">Cols i-iii broken except at bottom; cols iv, v broken except at top</note>
                     <note type="general">The hand is upright and rather large</note>
                     <note type="general">Marks of elision have been written by the original scribe</note>
                     <note type="general">Accents, breathings (usually acute-angled)  and high stops have been added by a second hand, which has also introduced some corrections into the text</note>
                     <note type="general">The system of accentuation is similar to that found in P.Oxy. 223</note>
                     <note type="general">Cols. (i), (ii), (iii), (iv), and (v) in Princeton; the rest are in the Cornell collection, currently housed at the University of Michigan</note>
                     <note type="general">The Princeton portions of the papyrus consist of eight fragments on which the text is preserved in the following manner: col. i, fragment (a); col. ii, fragment (b); col. iii, fragments (b), (c), (d), (e); col. iv, fragments (f), (g); col. v, fragment (h)</note>
                     <note type="local_note">AM 4422 verso; Frame 33</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>5 papyrus fragments; (a) 12 x 7.5 cm. (b) 11 x 8.3 cm. (c) 8.8 x 3.5 cm. (d) 9.5 x 7.9 cm. (e) 5.7 x 4 cm. (f) 8.1 x 8.5 cm. (g) 4.2 x 3.6 cm. (h) 8.5 x 6.2 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0200" notAfter="0299">200 CE – 299 CE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Given to Princeton University by the Egypt Exploration Society, 1907</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Oxy. III 448</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Oxy.:3:448</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <p>
               <figure>
                  <graphic url="http://www.columbia.edu/cgi-bin/dlo?obj=princeton.apis.p37"/>
               </figure>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
