<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Dialysis</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">princeton.apis.p258</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NjP)apis.p0258</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.princ.2.82</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0192;2;82</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.princ;2;82</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">17370</idno>
            <idno type="TM">17370</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">AM 8961</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Dialysis</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written across  the fibers; docket on back at top</note>
                     <note type="general">90 lines; complete</note>
                     <note type="general">Holes at top: several very large holes and a number of smaller ones</note>
                     <note type="general">The hand</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Oversize</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus fragment; 30 x 111.5 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0481">481, March 27</origDate>
                     <origPlace>From Lycopolis</origPlace>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>In the 3rd year following the consulship of our sovereign Flavius Zeno, the immortal Augustus, on the 1st day of Pharmouthi, in the fourth indiction, at Lykopolis the illustrious, this common agreement of the settlement was made for themselves by the party of the first party, the most God-beloved bishop Kyros of the church general of Holy God in Lykopolis, [5] and Danielios and Areion, most pious presbyters, three brothers of the same family, whose father was Besas of pious memory, and by the other party, Theophilos, son of Apollon, deacon of the same church of Holy God.  We agree on the following.  Greetings.  A little earlier, the foretold Theophilos went to the great officium of Augustalis (pertaining to the prefect of Egypt) and through a complaint petition accused afore mentioned [10] Kyros, the most righteous bishop, and Danielios and Areion, the most pious presbyters, on the basis of well-known topics which in fact were included in his petition, and he said that Kyros, the most God-beloved bishop, should go to that great court and set forth for him additional arguments (pleas of justification), unless he (Kyros) should choose  to resolve (dismiss) the charges before the case is taken, while Danielios and Areion, [15] his most pious brothers, through a debate to receive judgment from Makarios the most honorable advocate of the Theban tax.  After this was stated, an agreement was reached between the above-mentioned deacon Theophilos and Danielios and Areion, the most pious, in the same day  . . . in Lykopolis, according to which they have agreed with each other within specified time to come before the same most honorable Makarios and set forth their claims (arguments), or else pay a definite forfeit in accordance with the agreement.  Thereupon, however, Kyros, the most righteous bishop, after enduring the simple reminders from Theophilos and without awaiting the laborious process of accounting (legal fight in court), constrained himself to agree to do what any persons acting as intermediaries between them should judge to be right.  And thus Makarios and Sabinos, the most honorable, being agreed upon (being wanted) by both sides in oral statements, became the intermediaries between them, and having listened to their whole case, they gave judgment that Kyros, the most pious bishop, should pay to Theophilos sixteen gold pieces, total 16, in acquittal of every charge and claim and dispute, while Danielios and Areion should likewise hand over to Theophilos the hereinafter mentioned items, to wit: one man’s short cloak, one Egyptian cloak, one Egyptian cape, one rose-white tunic, two damask (sc. in which several threads were taken for the woof) pillows, one striped cover (or mattress), one Dalmation honey-colored cloak, one blanket with purple border, two small coarse curtains, five tunics with vertical design, one mallow-colored cloak, one simple man’s tunic, two man’s linen shirts, seven napkins and towels from Skinepoeus, one small mattress from Skinepoeus, one Damaskian shirt, ten scarfs, two portmanteaux, one table-cloth from Skinepoeus, one garment (?) from Skinepoeus, one napkin, one woven  portmanteaux, three new linen shirts with purple border, one woolen garment with purple border, two other linens shirt mixed, with wool, one woman’s embroidered turban.  And they gave judgment that after this, every basis for legal action by Theophilos as against three brothers above-mentioned should be done away.  Consequently, when these things had been done in deed and in fact, the above-mentioned most pious Theophilos, having received from the most God-beloved bishop the above-mentioned sixteen gold pieces, total 16, and from the pious Danielios and Areion the above-mentioned garments and various articles, agrees that hereafter he has no claim against them, nor even the slightest reproach, either out of court or in court, large or small, local or beyond the boundary, either against the three in common or against one of them individually, nor yet as touching the imposition of a fine, since the above-mentioned most God-beloved bishop, prompted only by the reverence and the piety that is in him, has awarded an additional sum to those who originally held the garments of Theophilos and has actually paid this sum.  Also the pious bishop himself and Danielios and Areion, his pious brothers, agree that they have no claim against Theophilos himself, either in courts or outside of courts, small or large, local or beyond the boundary, or based on expenditures or penalties ostensibly incurred by them on his account.  And they further agree with each other, upon being questioned, that neither as regards the above-mentioned issues or concerning any other matter, either related to this case or not related to it, either imagined or not imagined, or brought into court or not brought into court, have they any claim or reproach or liability affecting one another up to the above mentioned date which is the new moon of Pharmouthi of the current fourth indiction, but that on the contrary, every trace of claim or prosecution or liability, in person and in fact, has been done away; and further that they will abide by this agreement of settlement and will in no way transgress it or a part of it. They agree that if anyone should dare to act in opposition to it, he shall give as a fine to the party which abides it thirty six, total 36, solidi of gold for the mere attempt, while this agreement shall remain no whit the less unbroken and undisturbed on the basis of the conditions which it contains.  And finally, in addition to all this, after questioning  each other and being questioned by each other, they acknowledged the truth of this statement and to live up to it and to defend it in all respects. I, the bishop Kyros, above mentioned, entered into this agreement assenting to all that is written therein, and I shall abide by it forever and shall not protest against it as it stands; and, upon being questioned, I acknowledged it, and after reading and signing it, I released it. I, Danielios s. of Besas, a presbyter, above mentioned, entered into this agreement on the basis of all the conditions specified therein, and I am permanently satisfied, and give my consent to all the terms agreed upon; and, upon being questioned, I acknowledged it, and after reading and signing it, I released it. I, Areion s. of Besas, a presbyter, above mentioned, entered into this agreement on the basis of all the conditions specified therein, and I am permanently satisfied, and give my consent to all the terms agreed upon; and, upon being questioned, I acknowledged it, and after reading and signing it, I released it. I, Theophilos s. of Apollon, a deacon above mentioned, entered into this agreement consenting to all that is written therein, and I shall abide by it forever, and shall not protest against it as it stands; and, upon being questioned, I acknowledged it and released it. I, Claudius Heraklides s. of Alexander, councilor of Lykopolis, at his request, wrote for him in his presence and at his dictation, since he is illiterate. I, Aurelius Kollouthos s. of Besas, from Diado, witness the agreement, having heard it from the contracting parties. I, Aurelius Dionysios s. of Sois, witness the agreement, having heard it from the contracting parties. I, Aurelius Ioubinos s. of Akoris, witness the agreement, having heard it from the contracting parties. I, Aurelius Besas . . . , witness the agreement, having heard it from the contracting parties. [verso] The common agreement between Kyros, the most pious bishop, and his brothers, on the one side, and Theophilos, on the other.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Princ. II 82 SB III 7033 <note>H. B. Dewing, "A Dyalysis of the Fifth Century A.D. in the Princeton Collections of Papyri," TAPA 53 (1922): 113-127 W. Ensslin, Rheinisches Museum f*r Philologie LXXV (1926): 422-446 P. J. Sijpesteijn, "Corrections on Some Princeton Papyri," ZPE 68 (1987): 143-148</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Princ.:2:82</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <p>
               <figure>
                  <graphic url="https://dpul.princeton.edu/papyri/catalog/dv140258x"/>
               </figure>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
