<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Loan of Money</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">princeton.apis.p572</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NjP)apis.p0572</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.princ.3.144</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0192;3;144</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.princ;3;144</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12848</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12848</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">AM 8940</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Aurelius Diogenes acknowledges to Aurelius Serenus also called Isidoros, son of Olympus, that he has receive a loan of 200 silver drachmas.  In lieu of interest Serenus has the rightto inhabit the half part of a house belonging to Diogenes near the village of Philadelphia.  If the loan is not repaid within a specific period, Serenus will have ownership of the half portion of the house</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; trace of docket on back</note>
                     <note type="general">26 lines; complete</note>
                     <note type="general">Many holes and top right corner missing</note>
                     <note type="general">The hand is a small, rapid cursive</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus fragment; 18.5 x 12 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0219" notAfter="0220">219-220(?) AD</origDate>
                     <origPlace>From Ptolemais Euergetis</origPlace>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Loan</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Contract</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>In the third year of the Emperor Pius Felix Augustus, Pauni, at Ptolemais Euergetis in the Arsinoite nome.  Aurelios Diogenes aged about seventy and with a scar, acknowledges to [l. 5] Aurelios Serenos, also called Isidoros, son of Olympos, that he has received from him a loan of two hundred drachmas in silver and in lieu of interest Serenos has the right to inhabit the [l. 10] half part of a house belonging to Diogenes near the village of Philadelphia  . . . .  from the current month Epeiph of the current year.  If the aforesaid sum is not paid back  . . .  Serenos [l. 15] will have the ownership of the aforesaid half portion of the house  . . .  nor shall Diogenes alienate this property until he pays back the aforesaid loan.  Whenever he wishes Serenos may register this contract in [l. 20] the record-office of Apollinarios. . . .  Aurelios Serenos has the right of exaction from Aurelios Diogenes in person and from the half part of the house and from all his possessions as if legal decision had been given. Aurelios Diogenes, veteran, . . .  acknowledges that he has [l. 25] borrowed two hundred drachmas with the right of habitation in lieu of interest on the aforesaid principal as stated above.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Princ. III 144 <note>BL X, 165</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Princ.:3:144</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <p>
               <figure>
                  <graphic url="http://arks.princeton.edu/ark:/88435/j098zd70n"/>
               </figure>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
