<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Register of Taxes</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">princeton.apis.p696</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NjP)apis.p0696</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.princ.1.14</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0192;1;14</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.princ;1;14</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12816</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12816</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">AM 8910: oversize</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, possibly for the poll tax; entries consist of a name, patronymic  and a payment in the amount of 45 drachmas, 2 obols, the combined total paid for the laographia and pig tax;  the arrangement of the list is topographical and entries refer to estates; the register is a record of Philadelphians residing outside the village; two systems of checking are found a single stroke is drawn under the name at the left of the entry in most cases but in others a stroke resembling a quarter circle is found at the left of the name</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; back blank</note>
                     <note type="general">Five columns: col. I, 29 lines; col. II, 29 lines; col. III, 35 lines; col. IV, 29 lines; col. V, 23 lines; complete</note>
                     <note type="general">Quite a few holes, especially in the bottom half</note>
                     <note type="general">The hand is a small, rapid cursive</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus fragment; 27.5 x 47 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0048" notAfter="0063">After AD 48-49 or 62-63</origDate>
                     <origPlace>From Philadelphia</origPlace>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Register</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Taxation</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[col. I] The epoikion of Severus near Perseon; Onnophris s. of Pouoris 45 dr. 2 ob.; Arienis s. of Onnophris 45 dr. 2 ob.; Herakles, his brother 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 5] Apynchis s. of Apynchis 45 dr. 2 ob.; Herakles s. of Petesouchos 45 dr. 2 ob.; total 226 dr. 4 ob.; The epoikion of Antonia, daughter (of Claudius); formerly of Pamphilos, near Boubastos; [l. 10] Nekpheros s. of Teos 45 dr. 2 ob.; Panesneus s. of Mysthas 45 dr. 2 ob.; total 90 dr. 4 ob.; and by the village; Kephalon s. of Kephalon 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 15] Phasis s. of Petearmotes 45 dr. 2 ob.; Aphrodisios s. of Phaes 45 dr. 2 ob.; Satbois s. of Kephalon 45 dr. 2 ob.; Psenobastis s. of Nenephis 45 dr. 2 ob.; Nemion s. of Strattios 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 20] Horion s. of Horion s. of Koll- 45 dr. 2 ob.; Petermouthes s. of Petermouthes, copper-smith 45 dr. 2 ob.; Panomgeus s. of Ammonios 45 dr. 2 ob.; Apollonis s. of Herakles 45 dr. 2 ob.; Arontotes s. of Psenobastis 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 25] Labeus s. of Psenobastis 45 dr. 2 ob.; Pachnoubis s. of Pachnoubis 45 dr. 2 ob.; Apynchis s. of Keras 45 dr. 2 ob.; Peton s. of Mysthas 45 dr. 2 ob.; Apion s. of Maron 45 dr. 2 ob. [col. II] Leon s. of Nekpheros 45 dr. 2 ob.; Papontos stepson of Chairemon 45 dr. 2 ob.; Herakles s. of Mysthas s. of Paabos 45 dr. 2 ob.; Herakles s. of Papontos 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 5] Apollonis s. of Andro- 45 dr. 2 ob.; Dios the son 45 dr. 2 ob.; Herakles s. of Thyogeiton 45 dr. 2 ob.; Labeus the younger s. Onnophris 45 dr. 2 ob.; Labeus s. of Psenamounis 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 10] Peteuchos s. of Nekpheros 45 dr. 2 ob.; Nekpheros s. of Polyphantos 45 dr. 2 ob.; Onnophris s. of Kephalon 45 dr. 2 ob.; Mysthas s. of Seras 45 dr. 2 ob.; Ischis s. of Ischis 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 15] Ischyrion s. of Nekpheros 45 dr. 2 ob.; Neenephis s. of Herakles 45 dr. 2 ob.; Peeris s. of Herakles 45 dr. 2 ob.; Anoubion s. of Anoubion 45 dr. 2 ob.; Nekpheros s. of Apollonios 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 20] Haryotes s. of Harpsemis 45 dr. 2 ob.; Herakles s. of Herakles, copper-smith 45 dr. 2 ob.; Herakles s. of Horos, cowherd 45 dr. 2 ob.; Asklas s. of Menon 45 dr. 2 ob.; Anchorimphis s. of Petesouchos 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 25] Antis s. of Apollonios 45 dr. 2 ob.; Paesis, his brother 45 dr. 2 ob.; Dioskoros s. of Petemounis 45 dr. 2 ob.; Horos s. of Apollonios 45 dr. 2 ob.; Onnophris s. of Apollonios 45 dr. 2 ob. [col. III] Keras s. of Harphaesis 45 dr. 2 ob.; Mysthas s. of Mysthas 45 dr. 2 ob.; Ptollis s. of Mysthas 45 dr. 2 ob.; Kalaus s. of Harphaesis 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 5] Herakles s. of Marres, shepherd 45 dr. 2 ob.; Hatres s. of Didymos 45 dr. 2 ob.; Aphrodisios s. of Phatres 45 dr. 2 ob.; Petermouthis s. of Amos 45 dr. 2 ob.; Nekpheros s. of Polyphantos 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 10] Sisois s. of Zoilos 45 dr. 2 ob.; Herakles s. of Dios 45 dr. 2 ob.; Ibion s. of Marres 45 dr. 2 ob.; Esouris s. of Hektor 45 dr. 2 ob.; Peteuchos s. of Kephalon 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 15] Nekpheros also called Pano- s. of Panes 45 dr. 2 ob.; Hatres s. of Patynis 45 dr. 2 ob.; Herakles s. of Pteuchos 45 dr. 2 ob.; Paninouthis s. of Pante- 45 dr. 2 ob.; Herakles s. of Harmiousis 45 dr. 2 ob.; total 2901 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 20] and in Alexandria; Mandrobes s. of Akamon 45 dr. 2 ob.; Petermouthis s. of Harphaesis 45 dr. 2 ob.; Diodoros s. of Antiochos 45 dr. 2 ob.; Sosneus s. of Diodoros 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 25] Aunes s. of Anchorimphis 45 dr. 2 ob.; Apollon s. of Mandrobes 45 dr. 2 ob.; Asklas s. of Zoilos 45 dr. 2 ob.; Herakles s. of Pete- 45 dr. 2 ob.; Horion s. of Leo- 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 30] Horos s. of Sambas 45 dr. 2 ob.; Papontos s. of Heliodoros 45 dr. 2 ob.; Melinas s. of Ano- 45 dr. 2 ob.; Lykos s. of Lykos 45 dr. 2 ob.; Peteuchos s. of Hatres 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 35] Petsiris s. of Petsiris 45 dr. 2 ob. [col. IV] Ptolion s. of Petsiris 45 dr. 2 ob.; Euemeros s. of Amonios 45 dr. 2 ob.; Nanion s. of Apollonios 45 dr. 2 ob.; Phaesis s. of Apollonios 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 5] Sontois s. of Horion 45 dr. 2 ob.; Pebos s. of Arabion 45 dr. 2 ob.; Petoeris s. of Pnepheros 45 dr. 2 ob.; Mysthas s. of Mysthas 45 dr. 2 ob.; Petermotes s. of Petsiris 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 10] Paseis s. of Paseis 45 dr. 2 ob.; Phaseis s. of Phanomgeus 45 dr. 2 ob.; Panetbys s. of Mysthas 45 dr. 2 ob.; Psosneus s. of Praxias 45 dr. 2 ob.; Kallis s. of Hatres 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 15] Peteanos s. of Apynchis 45 dr. 2 ob.; Dikranes s. of Dikran- 45 dr. 2 ob.; Paspes s. of Pomsais 45 dr. 2 ob.; Hatres, his brother 45 dr. 2 ob.; Zoilos s. of Herakles 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 20] Pnepheros s. of Apollonios 45 dr. 2 ob.; Pilkon s. of Damas 45 dr. 2 ob.; Nemes- s. of Pnepheros 45 dr. 2 ob.; Thyon s. of Haryotes 45 dr. 2 ob.; Petermouthis s. of Apynchis 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 25] Horos s. of Merres 45 dr. 2 ob.; Phaesis s. of Phaesis 45 dr. 2 ob.; Herakles s. of Horos 45 dr. 2 ob.; Peteuchos s. of Peteuchos 45 dr. 2 ob.; Horos s. of Horos 45 dr. 2 ob. [col. V] Seras s. of Horion 45 dr. 2 ob.; Asklepiades s. of Petermotes 45 dr. 2 ob.; Sambas s. of Dios 45 dr. 2 ob.; Zoilos s. of Petearmotes 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 5] Herakleides s. of Panetbys 45 dr. 2 ob.; Herakles s. of Apollonios 45 dr. 2 ob.; Horos s. of Petkam- 45 dr. 2 ob.; Horion s. of Nemesion 45 dr. 2 ob.; Melankomas s. of Herakles 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 10] Peteuchos s. of Nekpheros 45 dr. 2 ob.; Neschatym- s. of Petan- 45 dr. 2 ob.; Herakles s. of Apollonios 45 dr. 2 ob.; Panaus s. of Ptolion 45 dr. 2 ob.; Pnepheros s. of Apynchis 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 15] L- s. of Apollonios 45 dr. 2 ob.; Pnepheros s. of Thyon 45 dr. 2 ob.; P-os the older s. of Haryotes 45 dr. 2 ob.; Ischyras s. of Ischis 45 dr. 2 ob.; Arsames s. of Pnepheros 45 dr. 2 ob.; [l. 20] Iason s. of Sambas 45 dr. 2 ob.; total 2901 dr. 2 ob.; total, in silver 2 talents 2733 dr. 4 ob.; 807 dr. 4 ob.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Princ. I 14 <note>A. E. Hanson, "Lists of Taxpayers from Philadelphia (P.Mich. inv. 879 and P.Princ. I 14)," ZPE 15 (1974): 229-248; BL VII, 166</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Princ.:1:14</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <p>
               <figure>
                  <graphic url="http://arks.princeton.edu/ark:/88435/g158bk88r"/>
               </figure>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
