<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Royal decree</title>
            <author>Athenodoros</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3035</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3035</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">7883</idno>
            <idno type="TM">7883</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.sijp;;45</idno>
            <idno type="filename">7883-2</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 6947</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:31.004362-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>"Athenodoros to the agoranomoi, greetings. Attached is a copy of the memorandum of Pyrrhos, the praktor. Set up a katahgraphe in accordance herewith. Farewell, year 8, Hathyr 28. ;To Athenodoros, the dioiketes, from Pyrrhos. It has been declared, according to the decree posted from year 8, Phaophi 2, in relation to everybody who owns Egyptian slaves originating from the rebellion in the country, Thaybastis, daughter of Socrates, Syrian with Apollonios as her guardian, one of the people of Anthemidos, Cretan, and one of the members of the elite armoured  forced, Thasion, approximately 18 years old, who says (or: of whom she says) that she is an Egyptian. And Thaybastis has made the payment at the bank of Phillipos into the account of the king in year 8, Xandikos 15. In copper 500 drachmas and an agio [(drachmas)]52 and 4 obols and the resulting tax for the purchase of of slaves in copper 110 &lt;drachmas&gt; and 5 (obols) . . . When it suits you, see to it that the deed of purchase is resgistered to Thaybastis, approximately 30 years old,  short, with honey-coloured complexion, round faced with a scar on the right cheeks, with Apollonios, with the guardian Apollonios, son of Apollonios, approximately 40 years, of medium size, of honey-colored complexion, smooth head, with ears standing out, scar on the left forehead, from the street of Arsinoe Euergetis, purchase of Thasion, approxiamtely 18 years old, short, of dark hair with a roun face and easily recognisable by several scars. Year 8, Hathyr 26, Daisios 4."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Koenen L, Atti XVII Congr Int 3, 915-6, 1983 Scholl R, C.Ptol.Sklav. I, 9, 1990 -- SB XX 14659 -- BL XI, 231</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
