<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Register of Documents Prepared at the Grapheion</title>
            <author>Kronion son of Apion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3198</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3198</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.123</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;123</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;123</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11967a 11967b 11968</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11967 11967 11968</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11967b-7</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 966</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:26.903551-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>On the 2nd. Agreement guaranteeing immunity (concerning) 104 drachmai, (made) by Orseus and others to Psenkebkis. [(Fee:) - -];Loan of 100 silver drachmai, (made) by Papnebtynis to Mieus and his wife. (Fee:) 14 obols.;Agreement of lease of 1/2 aroura for planting reeds &lt;or: of lease, by way of payment in advance, of 1/2 aroura of reeds&gt;, (made) by Hatres to Harsiesis. (Fee:) 12 obols.;Lease of 2 arourai of green fodder, (made) by Mesoueris to Sosas. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Payment of works by a carpenter, (made) by Nekpheraus. (Fee:) 4 obols.;Agreement of lease, by way of payment in advance, of a half-share of a plain, (made) by Onnophris and another to Haryotes. (Fee:) . . drachmai, of which he owes 14 obols.;Lease of vacant pasture lands, (made) by Nepheros and others to Mieus. (Fee:) . . drachmai.;On the 3rd. Agreement of lease of a half-share of a plain, (made) by Orsenouphis and another to Haryotes. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Agreement of cession of 3 3/4 arourai, (made) by Thaeisarion also called Thaesis to her brother Maron. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Lease of 3 arourai, (made) by Tasigeris to Eutychos. (Fee:) 24 obols.;On the 4th. Loan of 28 silver drachmai, (made) by Orseus to Ptolemaios and his wife. (Fee:) 8 obols.;Lease of 5 arourai of green arakos, (made) by Herodes to Orseus. (Fee:) 10 obols.;Loan of 500 silver drachmai, (made) by Herodion to Psyphis and Thaubastis. (Fee:) 8 drachmai.;Petition of Chrates against the son of Tapellichis. Gratis, through both (grapheion officials).;Agreement of receipt of wages and of farming, (made) by Eus, 'a gardener', to Didymos. (Fee:) 7 obols.;Lease of 4 arourai of fodder, (made) by Eus to Herakles. He owes the scribe's fee.;Agreement for nursing (a slave child), (made) by Thaesis and her husband to Mystharion of Tristomos, (and);on the 5th, loan of 100 silver drachmai, (made) by Mystharion to Harmiysis and his wife. (Fee) for both (documents): 6 drachmai.;Payment of a rent in kind, (made) by Labesis to Herakleides, a gardener, and another. (Fee:) 7 drachmai 8 obols.;Petition of Pastoous son of Taltis. (Fee:) 1 obol.;Total up to the 5th of Phaophi: 292 drachmai, of which 182 drachmai for the (monthly) transfer (diagraphe), 9 drachmai for expenses, 16 drachmai 3 obols on debt, remain 82 drachmai 3 obols.;Acknowledgment of receipt of a maintenance, (made) by Thenpetsoykis and her husband to Anoubion. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Acknowledgment of deposit of 40 silver drachmai and 5 artabai of barley, (made) by Herakles to Herakles. Gratis, for Eutychas.;Agreement of a lease pertaining to gardening, for wages of 148 drachmai, (made) by Orseus to Apollonios and Dioskourides. (Fee:) 11 obols.;Eutychas has by himself the copy of that agreement for the lessor.;Acknowledgment of receipt of a maintenance, (made) by Heraklea and her husband Heronas to Kronion. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Agreement of lease of 5 arourai of green fodder, (made) by Tenouphis to Orseus. (Fee:) 7 obols.;On the 8th, Augustan day. Agreement of division of building-sites, (made) by Taonnophris to Herodes. (Fee:) 8 drachmai.;Loan of 28 silver drachmai, (made) by Lysimachos to Peteesis and his wife. (Fee:) 7 obols.;Lease of 8 1/2 arourai, (made) by Herakleides to Lysimachos. (Fee:) 9 obols.;On the 9th. Acknowledgment of receipt of 80 drachmai for pasture lands, (made) by Leonides to Mysthas and another. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Petition (made) by Psenkebkis, son of Laches, against Hatres, son of Panesis. (Fee:) 1 obol.;Lease of 3 arourai of green fodder, (made) by Orsenouphis also called Herodes to Peteeus. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Lease of 2 1/2 arourai of fodder, (made) by Thenatymis to Herodes. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Lease of 2 arourai of fodder, (made) by Panesis to Kronion. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Lease of 2 1/2 arourai of green fodder, (made) by Orseus to Maron. [(Fee:) . . obols], which he owes.;On the 10th. Agreement (of - - -) of 24 keramia of wine, (made) by Psenkebkis and his wife to Marsisouchos. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Lease of 12 1/2 arourai of green fodder, (made) by Herakleides and another to Mieus. (Fee:) 8 obols.;Lease [of - - -], (made) by Kronion to Herakleides. (Fee:) 2 drachmai 1 obol.;2 petitions [- - -], (made) by Herodion [- - -];On the 11th. Agreement [- - -], (made) by Herakledes(?) to Pyrrhichos(?) [- - -];(Traces of 5 more lines).</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 123, Recto, col. IV, 1933 -- BL VI, 80 (l. 18); BL VII, 108 (l. 33)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
