<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Register of Documents Prepared at the Grapheion</title>
            <author>Kronion son of Apion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3215</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3215</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.123</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;123</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;123</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11967a 11967b 11968</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11967 11967 11968</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11967b-15</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 966</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.29722-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>[For] reports of the tax on transfer (. . .) Orsenouphis [- - -]:;[- - -] son of Akousilaos: [. .] silver [drachmai];;[- - -]mnis, greengrocer: [. .] silver [drachmai];;[- - -]tkisos, freedman: 10(?) obols;;[- - -]enephies, dyer: 15 obols;Eutychos, son of Takolleeinis: 4 silver drachmai;;Pausis, maker of thick garments: 10 silver drachmai;;Haryotes, interpreter: 4 silver drachmai;;Sarapias, teacher: 4 silver drachmai;;Harpaesis, of Areos kome(?): 12 silver drachmai;;Papnebtynis, stone-cutter: 4 silver drachmai;;Orsenouphis, son of Anchious: 4 silver drachmai.;Acknowledgment of receipt of 400 drachmai, (made) by Kollauthis to Heraklas. (Fee:) 18 obols.;Acknowledgment of receipt of 24 drachmai, (made) by Thenapynchis to Kronion. (Fee:) 7 obols.;Sale of a house, (made) by Thotsythmis, son of Chales, to Didymos. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Sale [of - - -], (made) by Kronion the dyer, and Kronion, his brother, to Kronion, son of Pet[- - -];Agreement of . . . of 4 places (totalling?) 4 arourai, (made) by Petsiris and others to Harmiysis. (Fee:) 8 drachmai.;Contract (for) a dowry of 420 silver drachmai, (made) by Pachis and his wife to Taorsenouphis. (Fee:) 50 silver drachmai.;Contract (concerning) 100 silver drachmai, (made) by Herakles and his wife to Heron. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Contract (for a dowry of) 60 silver drachmai, (made) by Marepsemis, son of Osis, and his wife to Heraklous. (Fee:) 10 obols.;Contract (for a dowry of) 180 silver drachmai, (made) by Chrates to Heraklous. (Fee:) 16 silver drachmai.;Loan of 180 silver drachmai, (made) by Marsisouchos to Harpaesis and another. [- - -];Contract (concerning) 100 silver drachmai, (made) by Kollouthos and his wife to Tepheros. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;On the 9th. Contract for a dowry of 28 silver drachmai, (made) by Chomenis to Panther. (Fee:) 10 obols.;Agreement of division (of property), (made) by Mestoys to his sons. (Fee:) 8 drachmai.;Contract (for a dowry of) 80 drachmai, (made) by Nepheros and his wife to Thenphemnasis. (Fee:) . . drachmai.;Agreement to furnish lodging for the sum of 300 silver drachmai, (made) by Petsiris to Paeus. (Fee:) 8 silver drachmai.;Loan of 112 silver drachmai, (made) by Harsiesis to Patynis. (Fee:) 2 silver drachmai.;Lease of 13 1/2 arourai . . ., (made) by Orsenouphis to Papontos. (Fee:) . . drachmai.;Sale of . . . bikoi, (made) by Galates to Didymas the son of Lysas, the village secretary [- - -];Written declaration of the president (of the guild) of weavers for the coming 7th year on [- - -]. He owes the fee.;Petition, (made) by Kollouthos, son of Papnebtynis. Gratis.;(Received) through Thouonis, son of Onnophris, (for?) reports of the tax on transfer [- - -];On the . . . Lease of 4 arourai, (made) by Sotas to Papontos. (Fee:) . . obols.;Acknowledgment of receipt of a dowry of 300(?) silver drachmai, (made) by Thenarkeeis to Orseus. (Fee:) 10 [obols].;Sale of a house and small court, (made) by Orseus to Apias. (Fee:) 4 [silver] drachmai.;Lease of [. . arourai] of fodder, (made) by Marsisouchos to Patron and Petesis. [- - -];Lease of 3 arourai, (made) by Kronion to {to} Pallaous. (Fee:) 16 silver drachmai.;Lease of 4 arourai of fodder, (made) by Marsisouchos to Patynis. (Fee:) 14 [obols].;Payment, (made) by Heraklas and other dealers in salt of Talei and Th[- - -];Acknowledgment (of receipt) of a dowry of [. .] silver [drachmai], (made) by Lysas to Thenpsosneus. [- - -];Petition, (made) by Orsenouphis, son of Horos. (Fee:) [. .] obol(s).;Agreement of deposit of [. .] silver [drachmai], (made) by Kronion to Pallaous. [- - -].;Loan of [. .] silver [drachmai], (made) by Heros to Stotoetis and his wife. [- - -].;On the 23rd. Agreement [- - -], (made) by Thentitois to Akousilaos and [another(?). - - -].;Agreement [- - -], (made) by Heras and his wife to Herodion. [- - -].;Loan of [. .] silver [drachmai], (made) by Maron to Kollouthos. [- - -].;Lease of 10(?) arourai, (made) by Heron to Pastoous. [- - -];Loan [- - -], (made) by Marepsemis, son of Patareis, to Psyphis. [- - -];On the 24th. Agreement to furnish lodging [- - -], (made) by Orseus to Papontos. [- - -];Loan [- - -], (made) by Galates to Psyphis and his sister. [- - -];Payment, (made) by Panechotes and other priests [- - -];Agreement [- - -], (made) by A---tis, son of Ktestis, to his sons(?). [- - -];[- - -], (made) by Harmiysis(?) and others to [- - -];[- - -], (made) by Onnophris and others to [- - -]</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 123, Recto, col. XXI, 1933</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
