<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Collection of Abstracts of Contracts (Eiromenon)</title>
            <author>Unknown scribe</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2718</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2718</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11965-11</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 622</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.144187-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Akousilaos, son of Kastor, a Persian of the epigone, about 39 years old, with a scar on his right hand, has leased to Tamarron, daughter of Haryotes, about 40 years old, with a scar on her left instep, acting with her guardian, her son Eutychos, about 29 years old, with a scar on his left shin, the catoecic allotment belonging to him in the aforesaid village in what is called (the allotment?) of Zenon, that is five arourai out of six arourai, or however many there may be, in one parcel, for five years from the fourth year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator for a first and second sowing with whatever sorts of wheat and barly she may choose. And Akousilaos has received from Tamarron the rental of . . . and of produce and . . . of the same five-year period at once from hand to hand out of the house, all the public revenues of the five-year period, the artabia naubion and (whatever charges which are to be charged) according to the crops, being a charge upon Tamarron, but the arithmetikon being a charge on Akousilaos.;Signatory: Onnophris, son of Pakebkis, about 39 years old, with a scar on his right knee.;The rest in conformity.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 121, Recto, col. II, i, 1933, Pl. II -- BL VII, 107 (l. 1; 2; 3)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
