<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Register of Documents Prepared at the Grapheion</title>
            <author>Kronion son of Apion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3192</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3192</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.124</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;124</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;124</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11969</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11969</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11969-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 966</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.976265-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Col. I);;(Traces of 4 lines);[- - -] for Antigo(--) [- - -];(Traces of 2 lines);On the 9th. Agreement to furnish lodging for the sum of 28 silver drachmai, (made) by Peteeus to [- -]dis. (Fee:) [. .] obols.;On the 10th. Agreement for nursing a slave (child), (made) by Tetosiris and others to Mystharion, (and);on the 11th, loan of 100 drachmai, (made) by Mystharion to the same. [(Fee): 4 drachmai], of which Psenkebkis, son of Chouses, owes 2 drachmai.;. . . through Polemon [- - -]. (Fee:) 4 obols.;Lease of 1(?) 1/2 arourai, (made) by Peteeus, son of Moueis, to Peteeus. (Fee:) 8 obols.;Acknowledgment of receipt of 60 [silver] drachmai, (made) by Tarmouthis to Thaesis. (Fee:) 14 obols.;On the 13th. Agreement of obligation to remain in service (paramone) for the sum of 60(?) [silver drachmai], (made) by Thaesis to Tarmouthis. (Fee:) 7 obols.;Lease of buildings, (made) by Thouonis and others to Nepheros. (Fee:) 4 silver drachmai.;Agreement to furnish lodging for the sum of [28 silver] drachmai, (made) by Esenempis and her husband(?) to Kronion. [(Fee:) 2 drachmai].;Petition, (made) by Aunes, son of Sekonopis, to . . . [- - -];Agreement to furnish lodging for the sum of [200] silver drachmai, (made) by Orsenouphis, son of Snouphis, and his wife to Apollonios. [(Fee:) 2 drachmai].;On the 14th. Lease of 3 arourai, (made) by Kronion the interpreter and his wife to Heraklas, son of Saramo(--). (Fee:) 10(?) obols.;(Received) through Aunes, son of Sekonopis: 40 silver drachmai.;Acknowledgment of receipt of 120 silver drachmai, (made) by Tapnebtynis to Mieus and his wife. (Fee:) 4 drachmai for(?) Papnauth(--).;Acknowledgment of receipt of a maintenance, (made) by Thenpsosneus and her husband to Tapnebtynis. (Fee:) 22 obols, of which she owes 5 obols.;On the 10th &lt;Read: 16th&gt;. Agreement (of deposit) of 120 silver drachmai, (made) by Pasis and his wife to their sons Apynchis and Pasis. (Fee:) 4 drachmai 3 obols.;On the 17th. Lease of 6 arourai, (made) by Kronion, son of Polydeukes, to Karpos, son of S[- - -]. (Fee:) 20 obols.;Agreement guaranteeing immunity, (made) by Tapieus to Herodes. (Fee:) 6 silver drachmai.;;On the 17th. Lease of 9 arourai of an allotment, (made) by Herakleides, son of Hephaistion, to Petesis. (Fee:) 19 obols.;On the 18th. Acknowledgment of deposit of 84 silver drachmai, (made) by Mieus and his wife to Psosneus, son of Andronikos. (Fee:) 11 obols.;Total: 178 drachmai 10(?) 1/2 obols; of which 6 [drachmai] 5 obols are owed: remain 172 [drachmai - - -];;(Col. II);;(Traces of several lines);Written declaration, (made) by Agathopous(?) the younger(?) to [- - -].;Another written declaration - - - - -. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Acknowledgment of receipt of a maintenance, (made) by Thermouthis to Herakleides. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Acknowledgment of receipt of a dowry of 8(?) drachmai, (made) by Thasis to Harmiysis. (Fee:) 15 obols, of which Herakles(?) owes 6 obols.;Agreement of confirmation, (made) by Tamieus to Kronion, son of Ereeis. (Gratis).;Agreement of - - -, (made) by Psyphis to Orseus. (Fee:) 15 obols.;Lease of 2 1/2 arourai, (made) by Orseus and another to Herakleides(?). He owes the scribe's fee.;On the 28th. Acknowledgment of deposit of 28 drachmai, (made) by Nepheros to [Apollonios]. (Fee:) 7 obols.;Loan of 100 silver drachmai, (made) by Herakles to Orseus and his wife. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Acknowledgment of receipt of 44 drachmai, (made) by Phomseous to Tephersos. (Fee:) 2 obols.;On the 29th. Agreement (of - - -) of 360 silver drachmai, (made) by Herakleides to Apollonios. (Fee:) 4 drachmai 16 obols.;Petition, (made) by Papnebtynis. (Fee:) 2 obols.;Agreement (of receipt of - - -), (made) by Tanaaraus to Arras. He/She owes the scribe's fee.;Written declaration of the guild of the wool-dealers. (Fee:) 8 drachmai.;Agreement to furnish lodging for the sum of 124 drachmai, (made) by Thenprakis and her husband to Herakles. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;On the 30th. Agreement of obligation to remain in service (paramone) for the sum of 24 drachmai, (made) by Paris and his wife to Eutychos. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Mortgage of - - -, (made) by Naaraus to Herakles. (Fee:) 8 drachmai.;Gift (received) through the president of the guild of the weavers, for their written declaration: 4 drachmai.;Agreement of obligation to remain in service (paramone) for the sum of 24 drachmai, (made) by Orseus to Galates. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Sale of a house and a court, (made) by Papontos and others to Mar . . . (Fee:) [. .] drachmai.;On Choiak 1. Loan of 104 drachmai, (made) by Patron to Eutycheides and his wife. Gratis.;Ordinance of the association of the god [- - -] . . .;Total: 78 drachmai 11 obols; of which 6 obols are owed: remain 78 drachmai [5] obols.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 124, recto, col. I-II, 1933 -- BL III,108 (col. I, 9; 13; 17; 26; 27; col. II, 4; 7; 17). - Col. I, l. 9: read [Tet]osireo(s) instead of [Pet]osireo(s); - l. 10: read tous a[u]to(us), instead of tous allous; - col. II, l. 12: 360, not 307 drachmai. (PH)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
