<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Quadrimestrial Register of Contracts</title>
            <author>Unknown scribe</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2759</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2759</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11964-41</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 622</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.63796-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Pauni) 25. Loan of 56 drachmai, (made) by Eutychos to Marepsemis and another.;Lease of estates, (made) by Marepsemis to Marsisouchos.;On the 26th. Loan of 240 drachmai, (made) by Galates to Psyphis and others.;Lease of 11 arourai of land, (made) by Psyphis to Galates.;Loan of 44 drachmai, (made) by Herodion to Harmais and others.;On the 27th. Alimentary contract for the value of 11 gold pieces, (made) by Petesouchos to Thatres.;On the 28th. Lease of 4 arourai, (made) by Psenkebkis to Marsisouchos.;On the 29th. Acknowledgment of deposit of 60 drachmai, (made) by Orseus to Tamaron.;Agreement to furnish lodging for the sum of 100 drachmai, (made) by Panesis to Apollonios.;Acknowledgment of receipt of 32 drachmai, (made) by Demetria to Papontos.;Epeiph 2. Acknowledgment of deposit of 28 drachmai, (made) by Orseus and others to Heron.;Acknowledgment of receipt of a dowry of 200 drachmai, (made) by Thenerakleia to Herakles and another.;Agreement of obligation to remain in service (paramone) for the sum of 40 drachmai, (made) by Petesouchos to Galates.;On the 4th. Acknowledgment of receipt of 1,000 drachmai, (made) by Taopis to Haryotes.;Agreement to furnish lodging for the sum of 128 drachmai, (made) by Leon to Maron.;Lease of 6 1/2 arourai, (made) by Heron and others to Patynis and another.;On the 5th. Acknowledgment of receipt of 60 drachmai, (made) by Orsenouphis to Herakleios.;On the 7th.Loan of 72 drachmai, (made) by Lysimachos to Peskas and another.;Loan of 60 drachmai, (made) by Lysimachos to Heraklas.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 121, Verso, col. V, 1933</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
