<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Register of Documents Prepared at the Grapheion</title>
            <author>Kronion son of Apion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3197</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3197</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.123</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;123</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;123</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11967a 11967b 11968</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11967 11967 11968</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11967a-35</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 966</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.860324-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(On the 23rd?). Acknowledgment of deposit [of - - -], (made) by Thermoutharion to Diodoros [(Fee:) - -];[Acknowledgment of - - -] of 400 drachmai, (made) by Teos and his wife to Herakl[- - -]. (Fee:) 10 obols.;Lease of 4 arourai, (made) by Taorseus to Pastoous and another. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Lease of 13 arourai, (made) by Aphrodisios to Pastoous and another. (Fee:) 6 drachmai.;On the 23rd. Agreement (of - - -) of 25 artabai of barley, (made) by Herakles and his wife to Dionysios. (Fee:) 12 obols.;Lease of 8 1/2 arourai bearing green fodder, (made) by Herodes to Orseus. (Fee:) 10 obols.;(Document covering) payment of a rental of 200 silver drachmai, (made) by the fishers of Tebtynis. (Fee:) 14 obols.;Agreement of cession of 3 arourai of an allotment, (made) by Herakleides to Herodes. (Fee:) 12 drachmai.;Contract of apprenticeship, (made) by Orses to Orsenouphis, a shearer. (Fee:) 8 obols.;On the 24th. Lease of 6 1/4 arourai, (made) by Heras to Sellouris. (Fee:) 15 obols.;Agreement of obligation to remain in service (paramone) for the sum of 40 drachmai, (made) by Peteeus and his wife to Herakles. (Fee:) 12 obols.;Lease of 6 arourai (bearing) green fodder, (made) by Anchias to Eutychos. (Fee:) 13 obols.;Lease of 3 arourai, (made) by Herodes 'son of Phombos' to Herakleides. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;(Total) up to the 24th: 160 drachmai 10 obols, of which 14 drachmai 9 obols are owed. Credit balance: 154 drachmai 1 obol &lt;Read: 146 drachmai 1 obol&gt;.;On the 24th. Acknowledgment of deposit of 1,680 drachmai, (made) by Petearpsenesis and another to Horion. (Fee:) 20 drachmai.;On the 25th. Lease of 5 arourai (bearing) green fodder, (made) by Anchious and his son to Horion. (Fee:) 7 obols.;Agreement of obligation to remain in service (paramone) for the sum of 40 drachmai, (made) by Orseus to Galates. (Fee:) 7 obols.;Agreement of sale of a loom, (made) by Tephersos to Mieus. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Acknowledgment of receipt of wages of 12 drachmai, (made) by Heras to Petheus. (Fee:) 4 obols.;Loan of 148 silver drachmai, (made) by Peteeus to Paas. (Fee:) 14 obols.;Agreement of (lease of) a garden, (made) by Mieus to Galates. (Fee:) 10 obols.;    Total: 112 drachmai 3 obols &lt;Read182 drachmai 3 obols, for 183 dr. 2 ob.?&gt;;On the 26th. Lease {Lease} of 10 arourai (bearing) green fodder, (made) by Herakles and another to Herakles. He owes the scribe's fee.;Lease of 4 1/2 arourai (bearing) green fodder, (made) by Chairiaios and another to Herakles. He owes the scribe's fee.;I have received 4 drachmai from the account of the secretarial fees owed by Didymos.;Return for a third of a half-share(?) of pasture lands, (made) by Papontos to the other Papontos. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Written declaration of receiving a rental of 500 drachmai, (made) by Marepkemis and another. (Fee:) 15 obols.;Another written declaration of receiving a rental of 52 drachmai, (made) by Psenkebkis and another. (Fee:) 7 obols.;On the 27th. Sale of a vacant plot of 2 cubits, (made) by Kronion to Haryotes son of Belles. (Fee:) 4 drachmai, which he owes.;Lease of 4 arourai (bearing) green fodder, (made) by Herakles to Horion. (Fee:) 5 obols.;    Total: 180 &lt;drachmai&lt; 5 obols.;Agreement to nurse (a slave girl named) Thaeisarion, (made) by Thaubastis and her husband to Tesenouphis, (and);on the 28th, loan of 80 silver drachmai, (made) by Tesenouphis to Marepsemis and his wife. (Fee) for both (documents): 4 drachmai.;Lease of fishers' (services?), (made) by Galates and another to Psenobastis and another. (Fee:) 21 obols.;Payment of a rental of 360 drachmai, (made) by Leon and his son to the inspector of the fisheries tax of Kerkeesis. (Fee:) 14 obols.;    Total: 210 drachmai.;On the 29th. Lease of 5 arourai, (made) by Kollouthos to Herakles. He owes the scribe's fee.;Lease of 3 3/4 arourai, (made) by Mysthas to Herakles. He owes the scribe's fee.;For the signatory, 1 obol.;On the 30th. (For) written declarations and the list of people free from duty and of cattle graziers. (Fee:) 11 drachmai.;Written declaration of the guild of the weavers to the inspectors. (Fee:) 8 drachmai.;Acknowledgment of deposit of 212 drachmai, (made) by Heron and another to Kronion. (Fee:) 5 drachmai.;Lease of 3 1/2 arourai of revenue land, (made) by Pastoous to Papontos and another. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Petition (made) by Orsenouphis, son of Diodoros(?), against Onnophris(?), son of Petepmoueis(?). (Fee:) 1 obol.;Total up to [the 30th of Sebastos:] 228 [silver] drachmai 234 obols.;On Phaophi 1. Lease of 7 arourai, (made) by Pn[- - -] to [- - -] and another. [(Fee:) - -];Agreement [- - -] Tapnebtynis [- - -];(Traces of 3 more lines).</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 123, Recto, col. III, 1933 -- BL III, 108 (l. 22)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
