<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Accounts of Expenditures</title>
            <author>Kronion son of Apion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3230</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3230</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.123</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;123</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;123</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11967a 11967b 11968</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11967 11967 11968</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11967b-25</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 966</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.224685-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>In Neos Sebastos:;On the 11th. For Heraklas the swordsman, who went with the other for the sake of the paper tax, as travel money: 4 drachmai 8 obols.;For beer: [. .] obols.;For breads and fishes (thrissai): 3 obols.;On the 18th. For a certain Horion who came from Ephebos with a letter:  for the price of breads and oil and a fish (thrissa) and beer: 3 obols.;On the 20th, Augustan day. Through Kronion, son of Soterichos, for the price of one papyrus (roll): 4 silver drachmai . . .;On the 22nd. Through Eutychas, for the price of turnips: 12 obols.;On the 29th. For interest on what Eutychas owes: 16 drachmai . . obols.;;On Choiak 1. For the monthly payment (diagraphe): 210 silver drachmai 6 obols.;'Expenses for this': as travel money and for beer: 8 obols.;On the 4th. For us, for beer: 1 obol.;On the 10th. For Kronion, son of Krados, for the price of one papyrus (roll): 4 drachmai 2 obols.;On the 14th.For the price of a dressed meat: 5 obols.;For Herodes, son of Soterichos, for what we borrowed of him for the payment (diagraphe) of Hathyr: 12 drachmai.;For Apias, similarly, for what we borrowed of her for the payment (diagraphe) of Hathyr: 4 drachmai.;On the 16th. Loan to Eutychas, through his wife Thermo(--), for him to give to (some people) of Talei . . .: 4 drachmai.;On the 20th. For the price of beer (bought) from Eutychas the brewer at the avenue of Tristomos: 1 5/6 artabai of wheat, (of the value) of 16 silver drachmai.;For the price of a papyrus (roll?) in the city: 2 drachmai.;On the 22nd. A loan to Eutychas, similarly, through me: 12 silver drachmai.;On the 24th. For the monthly payment (diagraphe) to Heron: 102 silver drachmai.;As travel money and for expenses: 6 obols.;;On Hathyr 23. A loan to Eutychas: 3 obols.;[- - -] in the city: 4 drachmai.;On the 28th. [- - -] 16 silver drachmai. As interest: 3 obols.;[- - -] a loan to [- - ] the thresher [- - -].</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 123, Verso, col. XI, 1933</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
