<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Collection of Abstracts of Contracts (Eiromenon)</title>
            <author>Unknown scribe</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2728</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2728</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11965-50</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 622</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.25104-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Alimentary contract for money of the value of 11 pieces of gold, and the contract of surrender and preliminary sale in respect of my share inherited from my mother of a house and court with all their appurtenances in Talei in the division of Polemon, and also in respect of (whatever property) I may acquire from the present time, both allotments and slaves and movables and household furnishings, in any way whatsoever.;And the dowry is 60 silver drachmai, and as parapherna without valuation a pair of gold ear-rings of 3 quarters, and a lunette of gold of 1 1/2 quarters, and silver armlets of a weight of 8 drachmai of uncoined metal, and a bronze bowl, and two bronze water jars, and (women's utensils) of tin of a weight of 2 minai.;Which contract Patynis, son of Kronion, his mother being Soueris, about 40 years old, with a scar on the left cheek, makes with his wife Thatres, daughter of Nikomedes(?), her mother being Thomsais, about 26 years old, with a scar in the middle of the forehead below the hair.;Signatory: Ptolemaios, son of Chairemon, about 75 years old, with a scar above the left elbow, and for the other party Heraklides, son of Horion, about 60 years old, with a scar on the left instep.;The rest in conformity.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, JEA 12, 100-109, 1926 -- SB III 7260, col. IIIa Boak AER, PMich II, 121, Recto, col. III, i, 1933 -- L. 1: read Tali, instead of Tebt(yni); l. 3: read Thomsaio(s), instead of Thome(neos) Olio(u). (PH)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
