<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Collection of Abstracts of Contracts (Eiromenon)</title>
            <author>Unknown scribe</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2750</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2750</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11964-32</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 622</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.506306-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Petheus, son of Petheus, a weaver, a Persian of the epigone, about 35 years old, with a scar on the right eyebrow, president and secretary of the weavers of the village of Kerkesoucha Orous in the division of Polemon for the current year, acknowledges to Papontos, son of Herak(l--), about 36 years old, with a scar in the middle of the forehead, and Harpa . . ., son of Papontos, about 35 years old, with a scar on the left eyebrow, and Ptollis(?), son of Ptollis, about 30 years old, with a scar on the left knee, and Papontos, son of Papontos, about 30 years old, with a scar on the left eyebrow, and Ptollis, son of Herak(l--), about 40 years old, with a scar on the left cheek, the 5 being weavers belonging to the corporation of those of the same village, that he, Petheus, the president, shall be obliged to pay to those aforesaid in the month Kaisareios of the current year 92 drachmai, the outlay for beer.;Signatory: Alkimos, about 30 years old, with a scar on the left cheek.;The rest in conformity.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 121, Recto, col. IV, vi, 1933</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
