<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Forms for Grapheion Reports</title>
            <author>Unknown scribe (Kronion son of Apion?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3094</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3094</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.122</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;122</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;122</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11966</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11966</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11966-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 725</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.594743-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Recto, col. I);;[- - -] of the record office of the villages of Tebtynis and Kerkesoucha Orous in the division of Polemon. (These) are the cessions and mortgages and sales and contracts of security prepared by me from the month Sebastos of the 6th year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator to the month Pharmouthi of the present 9th year, of which a detailed list follows:;Year 6, month Sebaste, the Nth day(?).;Agreement by A son of B with &lt;C son of D(?)&gt; to cede an allotment of x arourai at such-and-such a village.;Mortgage by A son of B with C son of D of an allotment of x arourai at such-and-such a village in consideration of x silver drachmai.;Sale by A son of B with C son of D of a house and courtyard and some other possessions(?).;Agreement by A son of B to sell to C son of D . . .;. . . the 3rd year of Claudius, Phamenoth 6.;A loan by Kronion, son of Herodes, to . . .  of 160 drachmai.;I, the aforesaid A son of B, swear by Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator that I in sound health and in accordance with the truth have recorded the cessions and mortgages and sales and contracts of security drawn up by me from the month Sebastos of the 6th year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, to the 30th of Pharmouthi of the present 9th year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, and have falsified nothing. If I swear truly may it be with me, but if falsely may the opposite happen.;(After a space:);On the 13th. Cession of a catoecic allotment of 3 arourai near Tebtynis by Orseus . . . 'to A son of B' to Apollonios son of Apollonios.;On the 14th. Mortgage.;;(Recto, col. II);Cession of a catoecic allotment of x arourai at such-and-such a village by A son of B to C son of D.;&lt;Sale&gt; of a half-share of a house and courtyard and all the appurtenances in such-and-such a village by A son of B and C son of D.;Mortgage of a house or something else and the appurtenances in such-and-such a village by A son of B to C son of D in consideration of x silver drachmai.;Mortgage of a catoecic allotment of so many arourai at such-and-such a village by A son of B to c son of D in consideration of x silver drachmai.;;(At the bottom, 3 more lines, too uncertain to be translated).;;(Verso: text too fragmentary to be translated).</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 122, 1933 -- BL III, 107 (Col. I, l. 28); BL VIII, 108 (Col. I, l. 7-8, 20-22, 24-26, 28, 32, 35; col. II, l. 5, 8, 11)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
