<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Quadrimestrial Register of Contracts</title>
            <author>Unknown scribe</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2764</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2764</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11964-43</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 622</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.743707-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Kaisareios 23, continued).;Loan of 224 drachmai, (made) by Lysimachos to Pnasis.;Lease of an oil-press, (made) by Apsemis to Nepheros.;Agreement of obligation to remain in service (paramone) for the sum of 100 drachmai, (made) by Phasis to Orseus.;Agreement of sale of a donkey, (made) by Herakleios to Orseus.;Acknowledgment of deposit of 360 drachmai, (made) by Kronion to Herakleios.;On the 24th. Lease of 4 1/2 arourai, (made) by Pasys and others to Orseus.;On the 25th. Lease of 9 arourai, (made) by Harmiysis to Patynis and another.;Agreement of sale of a donkey, (made) by Herakleios to Kronion.;Loan of 24 drachmai, (made) by Marous to Harpaesis.;Agreement to furnish lodging for 48 drachmai, (made) by Herodes to Harpaesis.;Acknowledgment of receipt of 224 drachmai, (made) by Taorseus to Taarmiysis.;On the 27th. Alimentary contract for the value of 11 gold pieces, (made) by Naaraus to Tepheros.;(Contract by which) Heras gave (his son) in apprenticeship to Papontos.;Acknowledgment (of receipt) of a dowry of 36 drachmai, (made) by Petearpsenesis to Aures.;Acknowledgment of receipt of 16 drachmai, (made) by Nekpheraus to Pakebkis.;On the 28th. Acknowledgment (of receipt) of a dowry of 1,000 drachmai, (made) by Lysas to Heraklous.;Alimentary contract for the value of 11 gold pieces, (made) by Kronion to Taorseus.;Alimentary contract for the value of 41 gold pieces, (made) by Areios to Ptollous.;On the 29th. Agreement of division (of property), (made) by Patynis to Tetekas.;First intercalary day. Acknowledgment of deposit of 48 drachms, made by the Romans and others to Pastoous.;[[. . Alimentary contract]]</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 121, Verso, col. XI, 1933 -- BL III, 107 (l. 13)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
