<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Register of Documents Prepared at the Grapheion</title>
            <author>Kronion son of Apion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3199</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3199</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.123</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;123</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;123</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11967a 11967b 11968</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11967 11967 11968</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11968-8</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 966</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:26.91877-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>[Agreement] of division [of property, (made) by - - -] to Dionysios and Taorseus. [(Fee:) - - -];[Acknowledgment (of receipt)] of a dowry of 160 silver drachmai, [(made) by - - -] to Taorseus. (Fee:) 1 drachme . . .;[Agreement] concerning (- - -) of a president, [(made) by - - -] to Petesouchos. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;[- - -] through Kronion, son of Soterichos: 6 drachmai, of which he owes [- - -];Equal for Choiak 192 silver drachmai 23 obols.;And loan from Orsenouphis, son of Belphis: 4 &lt;read 40&gt; drachmai;;and (loan) from Eutychos, son of Philous: 20 drachmai;;and (loan) from Soterichos, son of Herodes: 20 drachmai;;Equals a loan of 80 silver drachmai.;Equal 272 silver drachmai 23 obols as total (income) of the month.;Of these, expenses: 36 drachmai 24 obols;;and (monthly) transfer (diagraphe): 192 drachmai;;Equal 228 silver drachmai 24 obols (as expenses);Credit balance: 44 drachmai.;Of these, (held) by (me,) Kronion: 28 drachmai;;and 2 drachmai which I have received from Eutychas;;Equal 30 silver drachmai.;And (held) by Eutychas: 16 silver drachmai;;And similarly (held) by Eutychas for an old account: 16 drachmai;;Equal 32 silver drachmai.;Of these I have received from him: 2 silver drachmai;;And (held) by the same Eutychas: 30 silver drachmai, equal (to what I have).;(The account is) equally balanced.; ;On the 30th. Acknowledgement of a deposit of 502 silver drachmai, (made) by Petesouchos and another to Orsenouphis. (Fee:) 4 obols.;On Tybi 2. Agreement of confirmation, (made) by Orsenouphis to Kronion. (Fee:) 21 obols.;Similarly through Kronion and another for Horion. (Fee:) 14 obols.;Petition, (made) by Papontos, a repairer. (Fee:) 2 obols.;Loan of 28 drachmai, (made) by Apollonios to Harmiysis and others. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Lease of 1 aroura of fodder, (made) by Peritas to Orsenouphis. (Fee:) 3 obols.;Agreement of mortgage on a half-share of a house, (made) by Tamarres and her husband to Tanesneus. (Fee:) . . .;Loan of 316 silver drachmai, (made) by Ammonios to Zenon and his wife. (Fee:) 7 drachmai.;Written declaration of the seeds of the public farmers of the village. (Fee:) 8 drachmai.;Undertaking, (made) by the goldsmiths. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;On the 4th. Agreement of mortgage on a half-share of a house for 124 silver drachmai, (made) by Thenkebkis by Papnebtynis, son of Petamon. (Fee:) 9 drachmai.;On the 5th. Agreement of sale of 3 bikoi, (made) by Didymos to Haryotes. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Lease of 2 1/4 arourai of green fodder, (made) by Apynchis to Maron. (Fee:) . . obols.;On the 7th. Acknowledgment of receipt of 21 artabai of wheat, (made) by Souchion to Harmiys. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Acknowledgment of deposit of 80 drachmai, (made) by Miysis and his wife to Orseus. (Fee:) 24 obols.;Agreement of sale of 45 sheeps, 4 lambs and 1 goat, (made) by Pausiris to Herakles. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;(Received) through Herakles, son of Aphrodisios: 24 silver drachmai.;Guild ordinance, (made) by Kron[- - -];[- - -], (made) by(?) Eirene to Taor[- - -];;(Traces of several lines)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 123, Recto, col. IX, 1933 -- BL VII, 108 (l. 5; 9; 10; 13; 16; 20; 21; 22; 24); BL X, 123 (l. 3). - L. 6: 4 drachmai is probably a mistake for 40 drachmai, see l. 9 and Verso, col. II, 6. (PH)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
