<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Register of Documents Prepared at the Grapheion</title>
            <author>Kronion son of Apion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3207</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3207</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.123</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;123</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;123</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11967a 11967b 11968</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11967 11967 11968</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11967a-3</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 966</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:26.674604-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Col. XIII);;[- - -] (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;[- - -] (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;[- - -] (Fee:) . . obols.;[- - -] (Fee:) 9 obols.;[- - -] (Fee:) 10 obols. And(?) lease to Mytharion. (Fee:) . . silver drachmai.;[- - -] 280 silver drachmai [- - -]. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;On the 16th (of Phamenoth). [- - -] 24 silver drachmai [- - -]. (Fee:) 7 obols.;[- - -] (Fee:) 16 drachmai.;Acknowledgment of receipt of a dowry of 60 drachmai, [(made) by - - - to - - -] and another. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;[- - -] concerning a shipment. (Fee:) 18 obols.;Agreement of sale of 7 arourai of fodder, (made) by [- - -] and his son to Maron. He owes the fee.;On the 20th. Agreement of obligation to remain in service for the sum of 40 silver drachmai, (made) by Heronas to Orseus. (Fee:) 14 obols.;Agreement of lease, by way of payment in advance, of 10 arourai, (made) by Herodes to Maron. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Agreement of lease, by way of payment in advance, of 10 arourai, (made) by Herodes to Herakl(--). (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;On the 22nd. Agreement (of - - -) of 15 artabai of barley, (made) by Polykrates and his son to Seras. (Fee:) 8 obols.;On the 23rd. Acknowledgment of deposit of 12 drachmai and - - -, (made) by Orseus to Tkyphis. (Fee:) 8 obols.;On the 24th.Agreement of sale of a donkey, (made) by Apollonios to Eutychos. Gratis.;On the 26th. Acknowledgment of receipt of 380 drachmai, (made) by Mieus and another to Horos and another. (Fee:) 3 drachmai.;Petition, (made) by Mieus, son of Harmiysis. (Fee:) 2 obols.;Acknowledgment of deposit of 48 drachmai, (made) by Orseus and his wife to Eutychos. [(Fee:) - -];Agreement of lease of 11 3/4 arourai, (made) by Psenamounis to Psyphis. (Fee:) 15 1/2 obols.;Agreement of lease of 2 arourai, (made) by Sekonopis to Psyphis. (Fee:) 10 obols.;Lease of 2 shares of pasture lands and of . . . for a rental of 764 silver drachmai, (made) by Horos and others to . . . mis. (Fee:) 6 drachmai.;On the 27th. Agreement of sale of a slave (called) Heraklous, (made) by Taaryos to Petesouchos. (Fee:) 12 silver drachmai.;Similarly (received) through Patynis [- - -] records of the tax on transfer (enkyklion): 4 drachmai.;Agreement for mowing 52 1/2 arourai for a salary of 210 silver drachmai, (made) by Peteesis and another to Didymos. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Lease of 3 shares of a bath for 525 silver drachmai, (made) by Didymos and others to Psosneus. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;On the 29th. Lease of 4 arourai, (made) by Apollonios to Plosis. (Fee:) 2 silver drachmai.;Total (of the fees paid in copper): 180 1/2 obols, which (equal) 24 silver drachmai 6 1/2 obols; and 121 silver drachmai: total for the Mecheir: 145 silver drachmai 20 1/2 obols.;On the 1st of Pharmouthi. Agreement (of - - -) of lentils for 52 drachmai, (made) by Papontos to Herakles. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Acknowledgment of receipt of a maintenance, (made) by Thenmarsisouchos and her husband to Zoilos. (Fee:) 21 obols.;Agreement for nursing a slave, (made) by Thaesis and her husband to Demarion.;'Payment of the shearings of 140 sheep, (made) by P- - - and another to Phabas. (Fee:) 11 obols.';Loan of 120 silver drachmai, (made) by Demarion to Apynchis and his wife. (Fee) of the two (documents drawn for these persons): 4 drachmai.;Agreement to furnish lodging for the sum of 52 silver drachmai, (made) by Apynchis and his wife to Tephersos. (Fee:) 12 obols.;Agreement (of - - -) of 20 silver drachmai, (made) by Orseus to Kronion, son of Games. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Agreement for nursing (a slave) and loan of 120 silver drachmai, (made) by Heraklea and others to Tamystha. (Fee:) 2 silver drachmai.;Agreement of lease, by way of payment in advance, of 5 arourai, (made) by Galates to Didyme. (Fee:) 3 drachmai.;On the 4th. Agreement for nursing a slave, (made) by Thentitois and her husband to Lysas, (and),;on the 5th, loan of 120 silver drachmai, (made) by Lysas to Phason and his wife Thentitois. (Fee) for the two (documents): 2 drachmai.;'Agreement of deposit of 240 silver drachmai and 8 artabai of wheat, (made) by Phenias to Peteeus. (Fee:) 14 obols, of which he owes [- -]';Lease of 6 arourai, [(made) by - - - to (- - -)] son(?) of Kantauros. (Fee:) 9 obols.;[- - -] both (sons/daughters) of Phynix. (Fee:) 4 silver drachmai.;[Total] up to the 8th of Pharmouthi;;(Traces of 5 more lines.);;(Col. XIIIa);;(Traces of 5 lines);;[- - ] and for a division (of property) of Anoubas: 4 drachmai.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 123, Recto, col. XIII-XIIIa, 1933 -- BL III, 108 (l. 30)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
