<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Quadrimestrial Register of Contracts</title>
            <author>Unknown scribe</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2762</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2762</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11964-40</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 622</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.176421-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Epeiph) 30. Acknowledgment of receipt of 60 drachmai, (made) by Tatepheros to Orseus.;Lease of estates, (made) by Lysimachos to Onnophris. [[Sale]];Sale of a half part of a house, (made) by Harmais to Petesouchos.;Sale of a half part of a house, (made) by Orsenouphis to Cheus.;Sale of parts of a house, (made) by Psosneus to Kastor.;Sale of a third part of a house, (made) by Marepkaimis to Pakebkis.;Sale of parts of a house, (made) by Herakleia and others to Sadalas and another.;Lease of estates, (made) by Marepsemis [[and others]] to Psyphis.;Agreement of division (of property), (made) by Orseus and his brothers.;Agreement (of - - -) of 60 silver drachmai, (made) by Pakebkis and others to Sigeris.;Agreement (of - - -) of 60 drachmai, (made) by Thaubastis to Orseus and another.;Mutual agreement of partnership between Orseus and others.;Mutual agreement of division of a house between Tapholemis and others.;Agreement of release of claims, (made) by Thaesis to Onnophris and another.;Month of Kaisareios 4.;Agreement of sale of a donkey, (made) by Herodes to Marcus.;Agreement (of - - -) of 28 artabai of barley, (made) by Orsenouphis to Maron.;Sale of a third part of a vacant plot, (made) by Herodes to Eutychos.;Agreement of sale of a donkey, (made) by Eutychos to Gaius.;Acknowledgment of deposit of 1250 drachmai, (made) by Orsenouphis and others to Herakleios.;On the 5th. Agreement of sale of a half part of a donkey, (made) by Lysimachos to Akousilaos.;Agreement of partnership in farming, (made) by Akousilaos to his sons.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 121, Verso, col. VIII, 1933</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
