<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Register of Documents Prepared at the Grapheion</title>
            <author>Kronion son of Apion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3202</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3202</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.123</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;123</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;123</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11967a 11967b 11968</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11967 11967 11968</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11967a-19</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 966</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.574227-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Agreement [of - - -] of 88 silver drachmai and 5 1/2 artabai of wheat, (made) by Kronion [to - - -]. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;On the 16th (of Neos Sebastos). Agreement [of - - -] of 24 silver drachmai, (made) by Psosneus [to - - -]. (Fee:) 5 obols.;Lease of 3 arourai, (made) by Onnophris to [- - -]. Gratis, through both (grapheion officials).;Lease of 12 arourai, (made) by Iucundus to Hermas. (Fee:) 14 obols.;Lease of 9 1/2 arourai, (made) by Hatres and other priests to Maron. Maron owes the scribe's fee.;[[Agreement (of - - -) of 4 arourai, (made) by Galates and Lysas to Didyme. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Agreement of nursing (a slave child) and (agreement) of loan of 110 silver drachmai, (made) by Tasoykis and her husband Harmaeis to Komon. (Fee) for both (documents): 4 drachmai.;On the 17th. Lease of as many arourai as there may be, (made) by Galates to Harmiysis. (Fee:) 18 obols.;On the 18th. Agreement of sale of an anvil, (made) by Heronas to Harmiysis. (Fee:) 9 obols.;Lease of 10 arourai, (made) by Horion to Onnophris. (Fee:) 21 obols.;Acknowledgment (of receipt) of a dowry of 40 silver drachmai, (made) by Orsenouphis to Terepsaeis. (Fee:) 14 obols.;Contract for a dowry of 200 silver drachmai, (made) by Tephersos and her parents to Tatephersos. (Fee:) 8 drachmai.;Agreement of sale of a donkey foal, (made) by Orseus to Herakleides. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Contract for a dowry of 400 silver drachmai, (made) by Herodes to Kollauthis. (Fee:) 12 silver drachmai.;(Total) up to the 18th: 145 silver drachmai.;On the 19th. Lease of cattle for a rental of 240 drachmai, (made) by Modestus to Petesouchos. (Fee:) 14 obols.;Agreement of sale of a loom, (made) by Papnebtynis to his son Apynchis. (Fee:) 8 obols.;Acknowledgment of receipt of a dowry as cancellation (of a debt) of 100 drachmai, (made) by Thenmaron to Mieus. (Fee:) 20 obols.;Agreement to furnish lodging and of a loan of 80 silver drachmai, (made) by Cheos and his wife to Herakles. (Fee:) 18 obols.;Agreement of division (of property), (made) by Kollouthos to his sons and his wife. (Fee:) 8 drachmai.;Lease of 9 arourai of fodder, (made) by Pakebkis to Maron. Maron owes the scribe's fee.;Agreement (of - - -) of 8 1/2 artabai of wheat, (made) by Heraklas to Seras. (Fee:) 7 obols.;Agreement of release of claims, (made) by Tapetsoykis to Psosneus. (Fee:) 8 obols.;Lease of an orchard and of another (land), (made) by Eutychides to Psosneus and Mieus. (Fee:) 18 obols.;Payment of a rental of 208 drachmai, (made) by Peteeus and another, dealers in salt. (Fee:) 14 obols.;On the 21st. Acknowledgment of receipt of a dowry of 60 silver drachmai, (made) by Taopis to Pasis. (Fee:) 17 obols.;Lease of 1 1/2 arourai of green fodder, (made) by Orseus, son of Phasos, to Maron. Maron owes the scribe's fee through Orseus, son of Phasos. (Fee:) 1 obol.;On the 24th. Alimentary contract for a dowry of 140 silver drachmai, (made) by Herakles to Didyme. (Fee:) 4 drachmai 9 obols.;Petition of Heraklas. (Fee:) 1 obol.;On the 25th. Written declaration, (made) by Kronion also called Lucius, son of Artemidoros, to the strategos, concerning a tribute of 1,204 drachmai (from the collection) of the beer tax at Kerkesis. (Fee:) 14 obols.;Written declaration, (made) by Kronides and his son to the strategos, concerning a tribute of eight-thousand two-hundred drachmai, which is 1 talent 2,200 drachmai, (from the collection) of the beer tax at Tebtynis. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Agreement to furnish lodging and of a loan of 120 silver drachmai, (made) by Tamieus and her husband Petesouchos to Mieus. (Fee:) 5 drachmai.;To Maeis, a shepherd, the price of an hemikollion (of writing material?), unwritten. (Price:) 1/2 obol.;Lease of 2 1/2 arourai of fodder, (made) by Pynchis to Maron. Maron owes the scribe's fee.;On the 27th. Agreement to furnish lodging and of a loan of 100 drachmai, (made) by Papnebtynis and his wife to Patynis. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Written declaration of the seeds of Kerkesoucha Orous. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;(Total) 49 drachmai 1 1/2 obols. Equals 194 drachmai.;On the 28th. Agreement of division of part of a house and of slaves, (made) by Kronion to his brothers. (Fee:) 16 drachmai.;Agreement concerning an offer of bearsfoot (akanthos), (made) by Kronion to . . . and Issyamis. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Agreement for nursing a slave child (named) Thenamounis, (made) by Taaryos [to - - -]sito(--), (and);on the 29th, loan of 120 silver drachmai, (made) by Asou[- - - to - - -]. (Fee) for both (documents): [- - -];Agreement of sale of the slave Heraklas, (made) by Herak[- - - ];;(Traces of 3 more lines)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 123, Recto, col. VII, 1933 -- BL III, 108 (l. 36); BL X, 122 (l. 45). - L. 25: read ekstase(os) instead of ekthese(os). (PH)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
