<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Register of Documents Prepared at the Grapheion</title>
            <author>Kronion son of Apion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3210</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3210</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.123</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;123</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;123</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11967a 11967b 11968</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11967 11967 11968</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11968-9</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 966</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:26.999823-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>On the 25th (of Pharmouthi). Written declaration [- - -]. (Fee:) 14 obols.;Agreement of mortgage(?) for 20 drachmai, (made) by Panas [- - -]. (Fee:) 8 obols.;On the 29th. For Epaphroditos [- - -] 4 drachmai.;Petition, (made) by Haryos [- - -] Gratis.;[[On the 30th]]. Agreement of deposit of 28 drachmai, (made) by Marsisouchos and his wife to Harmiysis. (Fee:) 10 obols.;(Received) through Apollonios, son of Labesis, as scribe's fee: 28 drachmai.;On the 29th. Agreement for nursing a slave, (made) by Tamarres and her husband to Paopis, (and);on the 30th, loan, (made) by Paopis to Psenkebkis, son of Benipes, and his wife. (Fee) for both (documents): 4 drachmai.;Agreement to furnish lodging for the sum of 240 silver drachmai, (made) by Papnebtynis and his wife to their son. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Agreement (of - - -) of 8 artabai of barley, (made) by Cheos to Ophelion and Herakles. (Fee:) 6 obols.;On Pachon 4. Agreement of deposit of 100 drachmai, (made) by Patynis to Kronion. (Fee:) 12 obols.;Agreement of concession of seven arourai of a seven-arourai allotment, (made) by Herakleides to Sotas. (Fee:) 8 drachmai, of which he owes 4 drachmai.;On the 5th. Agreement of sale of a loom, (made) by Orseus to Pomsochis. (Fee:) 5 obols.;Agreement concerning the list of persons, (made) by Nepheros and another to Herakles, a brewer. (Fee:) 20 silver drachmai.;Loan of 156 silver drachmai, (made) by Soterichos to Apollonios and his wife. (Fee:) 4 drachmai 7 obols.;On the 6th. Agreement (of - - -) of 152 silver drachmai, (made) by Apollonios to Pnesis and Thenpetsoykis. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Sale of a half-share of a house and court, (made) by Tausis and Thenpetsoykis and Pnesis to Apollonios. (fee:) 8 drachmai.;On the 7th. Agreement of sale of a donkey, (made) by Marepkemis to Heraklas. (Fee:) 7 obols.;Acknowledgment of receipt of a dowry of 40 silver drachmai, (made) by Thenpetsoykis to Orsenouphis. (Fee:) 7 obols.;Agreement of mortgage on a house and court for the sum of 140 silver drachmai, (made) by Patynis to Sambas. (Fee:) 6 drachmai.;On the 9th. Agreement to furnish lodging for the sum of 20 silver drachmai, (made) by Herodes to Narkissos. (Fee:) 8 obols.;Petition, (made) by Chairis, son of Papnebtynis, a shepherd. (Fee:) 1 obol.;On the 12th. Contract for a dowry of 60 silver drachmai, (made) by Paopis to Thaubastis. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Agreement of sale of a loom, (made) by Sambas to Petesouchos. (Fee:) 5 obols.;Loan of 48 silver drachmai, (made) by Harmiysis to Orseus. (Fee:) 8 obols.;Written declaration, (made) by priests and pastophoroi. (Fee:) 4 obols.;Written declaration, (made) by Herakles, son of Herakles the younger. Gratis.;On the 13th. Loan of 120 silver drachmai, (made) by Herodes to Orseus and another. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Lease of 2 arourai of green fodder, (made) by Orseus to Apollonios.;Agreement of division of a building-site, (made) by Orseus, son of Kachos, to his brothers. (fee:) 20 drachmai.;On the 14th. Loan of 160 silver drachmai, (made) by Patynis to Kamas and his wife. (Fee:) 4 drachmai 7 obols.;Sale of a house, (made) by Kames to Eutychos, son of Takolleeinis. (Fee:) 6 drachmai, of which he owes 1 1/2 obols.;On the 15th. Acknowledgment of receipt of wages, (made) by Orseus to Herakleides. (Fee:) 8 obols.;Lease of 5 1/2 arourai, (made) by Pallaous to Orsenouphis. (Fee:) 14 obols.;Agreement to furnish lodging for the sum of 40 silver drachmai, (made) by Tithenxis to [- - -]. (Fee:) 8 obols.;On the 16th. Agreement (of - - -) of 200 silver drachmai, (made) by Petermouthis [to - - -] the younger(?), son of Papnebtynis, and Heron. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;On the 17th. Lease [- - -], (made) by Akoutos [- - -]. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Contract [- - -], (made) by Akoutos(?) [- - -]. (Fee:) 6 drachmai.;Lease [- - -], (made) by Orsenouphis [- - -]. (Fee:) 10 obols.;On the 18th. Lease [- - -], (made) by Mo[- - - to Mieus]. (Fee:) 7 1/2 obols, which he/she owes.;On the 19th. Lease [- - -], (made) by Pn[- - -]. (Fee:) 12 obols.;;(Remains of 3 more lines).</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 123, Recto, col. XV, 1933</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
