<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Register of Documents Prepared at the Grapheion</title>
            <author>Kronion son of Apion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3211</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3211</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.123</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;123</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;123</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11967a 11967b 11968</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11967 11967 11968</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11968-6</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 966</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:26.811368-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>[- - -] arourai of green fodder [- - -];[Agreement] to furnish lodging for the sum of 40 silver drachmai. (Fee:) 6 obols.;[Sale] of a house &lt;or: building-site&gt;, [(made) by - - - and] others(?) to Orseus. (Fee:) 6 drachmai.;[- - -] to Psyphis, son of Psosnoeris. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;[- - -] of a dowry of 80 drachmai, (made) by [- - -] to Thenpsyphis. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;On the 26th. [- - -] concerning the tax on transfer(?), to Heraklas of Talei . . . (Fee:) 6 drachmai.;[- - -]concerning the tax on transfer. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Agreement (- - -) of 50 artabai of wheat, (made) by Ischyrion also called [- - -] to [- - -]. (Fee:) 22 obols.;On the 28th. Lease of 6 arourai, (made) by Orseus to Paleus. (Fee:) 8 obols.;Agreement of sale of a loom, (made) by Kronion [to] Psosneus. (Fee:) 9 obols.;Agreement of cession of a third-share of 15 arourai, (made) by Lysas to Galates. (Fee:) 16 drachmai.;(Guild) ordinance of the shepherds. (Fee:) 8 obols.;(Received) through Didis, daughter of Haryotes: 20 silver drachmai.;Agreement of concession of a bath(?) towards the village of Talei. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Acknowledgment of receipt of [. .] artabai of wheat, (made) by Psentamieus to Lysas. (Fee:) 10 obols.;Memoranda, (made) by Kollouthos, son of - - -, (concerning) a renunciation of claim(?) on . . arourai. Gratis, for Heraklas.;On the 29th. Agreement of cession of six(?) arourai a quarter(?), (made) by Mysthas to [- - -] also called Maximus. . . .;Petition, (made) by Orseus son of Sbebus. (Fee:) 4 obols.;On Pauni 2. Loan of 100 silver drachmai, (made) by Herodion to Lysimachos and his wife. Gratis.;Acknowledgment of receipt of 500 silver drachmai, (made) by Apynchis and others to Maron, (and);loan of 500 [silver] drachmai, (made) by Maron to Apynchis and others. (fee) of both (documents): 4 drachmai.;Agreement guaranteeing immunity (concerning) 100 drachmai, (made) by Apynchis and his wife to their son. (Fee:) 12 obols.;Acknowledgment of receipt of a maintenance, (made) by Thenarkeeis and her husband to Mieus. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Agreement of lease of 8 arourai, (made) by Marepkemis to Thaubastis. (Fee:) 16 1/2 obols.;Acknowledgment of receipt of a dowry of 80 silver drachmai, (made) by Tetosiris to Marepkemis. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;On the 3rd. Loan of 100 silver drachmai, (made) by Herakles to Papontos. (Fee:) 14 obols.;Sale of a vacant plot, (made) by Herodes to Narkissos. (Fee:)  [. .] silver drachmai.;Agreement for nursing a slave child, (made) by Taorseus and her husband to Orsenouphis, (and);on the 4th, loan of 140 silver drachmai, (made) by Orsenouphis to Harmaeis and her wife. (Fee) of both (documents): 4 drachmai.;[[Petition, (made) by Orseus son of Sbebus. (Fee:) 4 obols.]];On the 5th. Loan of 124 silver drachmai, (made) by Herodion to Horos and his wife and (his?) mother. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Petition, (made) by Harmiysis, son of Phasos. (Fee:) 4 obols.;On the 7th. [Acknowledgment] of receipt of . . . as earnest money, (made) by - - -, son of Mieus, and another to Herodion. . . .;[Lease] of 4 arourai, (made) by Marsisouchos to Paopis. (Fee:) . . .;[Lease] of [. .] arourai, (made) by Kronion to the other Kronion. [(Fee:) - -];[- - -] of a vacant plot, (made) by Epetes(?) to Petesouchos. [(Fee:) - -];[Total] from Mecheir . . to Pauni [7 - - -] . . . silver drachmai 4 1/2 obols.;;(Traces of 2 more lines)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 123, Recto, col. XVI, 1933 -- BL III, 108 (l. 17); BL VIII, 211 (l. 36). - L. 7: read [e]nkykliako(--) instead of . nkyeko(--); the presence of the same word on l. 6 is very uncertain. (PH)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
