<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Collection of Abstracts of Contracts (Eiromenon)</title>
            <author>Unknown scribe</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2751</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2751</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11965-35</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 622</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.590882-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>On the 27th. Herodes, son of Heraklides, a Persian of the epigone, about 35 years old, with a scar in the middle of the forehead, acknowledges to his wife, who is living in wedlock with him, Apias, daughter of Sokrates, about 37 years old, with a scar on the forehead to the right, together with her guardian Ptol(--), son of her full brother Petesouchos, about 30 years old, with a scar on the left wrist, that he has received from the two of them in cash from hand to hand out of the house 700 silver drachmai; apart from the other 560 silver drachmai which the contracting party Herodes owes Apias in accordance with another alimentary contract executed through the same grapheion in the 9th year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus on the 11th of the month Choiak; and the parapherna enumerated in the contract; and the 14 arourai, or however many there may be, in one parcel, of a catoecic allotment near the same village of Tebtynis formerly the property of Patynis the carpenter &lt;or: son of Tekton&gt;, which the said Apias has bestowed upon Herodes according to the same alimentary contract with Herodes; and the house-born slave girl named Heraklous whom &lt;. . .&gt; has given to the same Apias. And all that is in accordance with the aforesaid alimentary contract shall also be valid.;The rest in conformity.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 121, Recto, col. IV, vii, 1933 -- BL III, 107 (l. 4); BL VI, 80 (l. 4); BLVII , 107 (l. 3)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
