<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Collection of Abstracts of Contracts (Eiromenon)</title>
            <author>Unknown scribe</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2731</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2731</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11964-15</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 622</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.258792-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Alimentary contract for money of the value of 11 pieces &lt;of gold&gt; and the contract of surrender and preliminary sale concerning the catoecic allotment of 2 arourai which belongs to me near Tebtynis, and near Kerkesoucha Orous the police allotment of 3 arourai which belongs to me, and near the same village of Kerksoucha Orous 3 3/4 arourai of an allotment of 7 arourai, and in the same village the half-share(?) of a house inherited from my father and an unroofed  court, and of the other parcels in the same village the stable inherited from my father, and concerning whatever other property I may acquire from the present time, both movables and household furnishings and all that is owing to me in any way whatsoever.;And the dowry given is 60 drachmai of silver, including a robe, and as gifts (prosphorai) without valuation a golden ear-ring of 2 quarters and a golden lunette of 5 quarters and {a pair of ear-rings} silver armlets of a weight of 8 drachmai of uncoined metal.;Which contract Herodes, also called Orsenouphis, son of Herodes, about 38 years old, with a scar on the thumb of the left hand, makes with his wife Thenchorephis, daughter of Orseus, her mother being Tapnebtynis, about 30 years old, with a scar  in the middle of the forehead.;Signatories: Diodoros, about 47 years old, with a scar in the middle of the forehead, and for the other party Pyrrhos, about 40 years old, with a scar on the forefinger of the right hand.;The rest in conformity.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, JEA 12, 100-109, 1926 -- SB III 7260, col. IV (sic) Boak AER, PMich II, 121, Recto, col. III, xii, 1933</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
