<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Collection of Abstracts of Contracts (Eiromenon)</title>
            <author>Unknown scribe</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2739</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2739</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11965-53</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 622</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.527236-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>On the 24th. Alimentary contract for money of the value of 21 pieces of gold and the contract of surrender and preliminary sale, concerning the whole house which belongs to me and the court and the plot of ground in Tebtynis in one parcel formerly belonging to Orsenouphis, son of Horouanchis, and concerning the shares which came to me from my father of another house and court likewise in Tebtynis, and concerning whatever property I may acquire from the present time, allotments and vineyards and groves and building sites and cattle of all sorts and slaves and movables and household furnishings and all that is owing to me in any way whatsoever, or may come to me from any source whatsoever.;And the dowry given is 300 silver drachmai, and as parapherna without valuation a gold ear-ring of 3 1/2 quarters and a golden lunette of 2 quarters and silver armlets of a weight of 12 drachmai of uncoined metal and a bronze bowl and women's utensils of tin of a weight of 5 minai. And concerning what is held under gift we have contracts.;Which contract Petesouchos, son of Harmiysis, his mother being Teros, about 46 years old, with a scar on the right shin.;Signatory: Er(--), son of Ptolemaios(?), about 32 years old, with a scar on the right side of the neck.;The rest in conformity.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, JEA 12, 100-109, 1926 -- SB III 7260, col. IIIg Boak AER, PMich II, 121, Recto, col. III, vii, 1933</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
