<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Collection of Abstracts of Contracts (Eiromenon)</title>
            <author>Unknown scribe</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2742</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2742</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11964-24</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 622</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.96607-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Herakleides, son of Harmiysis, about 22 yers old, with a scar on the left eyeborw, and his parents, Harmiysis, son of Orseus, about 45 years old, with a scar on the left shin, both Persians of the epigone, being mutual sureties, and the latter's wife, who is the mother of Herakleides, Heraklea, daughter of Andronikos, a Persian woman, about 40 years old, with a scar in the middle of her forehead, (acting) with Harmiysis himself as guardian, inhabitants of the village of Phenameni in the Herakleopolite nome, which is above Memphis, acknowledge to Klesis, son of Psosneus, about 65 years old, with a scar on the upper lip on the right side, that they have received from him for his daughter Tamarres a dowry . . . of 200 silver drachmai, including a robe valued at 60 silver drachmai, and among her parapherna without valuation a pair of gold ear-rings of 3 quarters, and a  golden lunette of 1 1/2 quarters, and silver armlets of a weight of 12 drachmai of uncoined silver, and a bronze bowl, and a bronze mirror, and 2 bronze water-jars, and a tin water-jar of a weight of 5 minai, and a chiton with flowers of gold, and 2 cloaks, and a white wrap. Let the married parties live together. (?There is) a dowry of 200 silver drachmai.;Signatories: Eutychos, son of Eutychos, about 32 years old with a scar on the right knee, and for the other, Soterichos, son of Herodes, about 32 years old, with a scar on the ankle-bone of the right foot.;The rest in conformity.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 121, Recto, col. IV, i, 1933 -- BL VI, 80 (l. 2)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
