<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Collection of Abstracts of Contracts (Eiromenon)</title>
            <author>Unknown scribe</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2746</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2746</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11964-29</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 622</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.336308-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Herodes, son of Heraklides, about 35 years old, with a scar in the middle of the forehead, has leased to Onnophris, son of Kollouthos, a Persian of the epigone, about 36 years old, with a scar on the left knee, the catoecic allotment of 7 1/2 1/11 arourai which he has near Tebtynis, and from his property near the same village 2 1/2 arourai of land from which olive grove has been cut down, making a total of 10 1/11 arourai or as many as there may be, in two parcels. The annual rental of the whole for the 1st and 3rd years of the lease of the aforesaid 10 1/11 arourai, together with the seed which the lessee shall receive from Herodes for his seed account for the whole each year, namely, 10 artabai of wheat, shall be 110 artabai of wheat by the standard measure of the granary of Thion, as with the other tenants, and for the 2nd and final years of the lease the rental of the whole of the aforesaid arourai without seed shall be 72 drachmai in silver. And let Onnophris pay the rental for all these years in the month Drousilleios, without any prejudice to his rights arising from the purchase of vacant plots which he has made from Herodes and his brothers.;Signatory.;The rest in conformity.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 121, Recto, col. IV, ii, 1933</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
