<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Quadrimestrial Register of Contracts</title>
            <author>Unknown scribe</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2756</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2756</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11965-25</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 622</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.957902-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>On the 24th. Alimentary contract for the value of 21 gold pieces, (made) by Petesouchos to Thaubastis.;Lease of 4 arourai, (made) by Psenkebkis to Marsisouchos.;On the 25th. Acknowledgment of receipt of 60 drachmai, (made) by Kronion to Orsenouphis.;Lease of 5 arourai, (made) by Nikomedes to Apollonios.;Lease of 4 arourai, (made) by Petesouchos to Petesouchos.;Alimentary contract for the value of 11 gold pieces, (made) by Herodes to Thenchonephis.;Acknowledgment of receipt of 13 1/2 artabai of wheat, (made) by Nikomedes to Herakles.;Acknowledgment of receipt of a dowry of 200 drachmai, (made) by Herakleios and others to Klesis.;Lease of 10 arourai, (made) by Herodes to Onnophris.;Acknowledgment of receipt of a dowry of 32 drachmai, (made) by Orseus to Thenanchious.;&lt;Alimentary&gt; contract for the value of 11 gold pieces, (made) by Patynis to Tapeseus.;Lease of pasture land, (made) by Orsenouphis and another to Orseus.;Agreement &lt;to pay&gt; 92 silver drachmai, (made) by Petheus to Papontos.;Acknowledgment &lt;of deposit&gt; of 700 drachmai, (made) by Herodes to Apias.;On the 28th. Agreement to furnish lodging for 40 drachmai, (made) by Klesis and others to Papontos.;Acknowledgment of receipt for rent, (made) by Herodes &lt;Read: Herakleides&gt; to Haryotes.;Pauni 1. Agreement to furnish lodging for 28 drachmai, (made) by Leon to Pallaus.;On the 3rd. Agreement of confirmation, (made) by Orsenouphis and others to Herakles and another.;Loan of 48 drachmai, (made) by Didymos to Harmais.;On the 4th. Agreement to furnish lodging for 60 drachmai, (made) by Orseus to Kollouthos.;Agreement to furnish a part of lodging for 60 drachmai, (made) by Orseus to Kollouthos.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 121, Verso, col. III, 1933</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
