<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Quadrimestrial Register of Contracts</title>
            <author>Unknown scribe</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2763</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2763</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11964-39</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 622</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.046757-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Kaisareion 16, continued).;Acknowledgment (of receipt) of a dowry of 40 drachmai, (made) by Harmaissemis and others to Naaraus.;Alimentary contract for the value of 11 gold pieces, (made) by Psosneus to Thenerakleia.;Alimentary contract for the value of 21 gold pieces, (made) by Trophaneous to Tephersos.;Loan of 320 drachmai, (made) by Lysimachos to Aunes and another.;Lease of estates, (made) by Psosneus to Heron.;Agreement of division (of property), (made) by Papnebtynis to Teteon.;Acknowledgment of deposit of 123 drachmai, (made) by Aunes to Herakleides.;Lease of 6 arourai, (made) by Panesis to Herakleides.;Lease of pasture land, (made) by Sotas to Herodes.;Acknowledgment (of receipt) of a dowry of 50 drachmai, (made) by Hatres to Thatres daughter of Petesouchos.;Alimentary contract for the value of 11 gold pieces, (made) by Apynchis to Thatres.;Acknowledgment of deposit of 182 drachmai, (made) by Herakleios to Orseous.;On the 19th. Agreement to furnish lodging for 7 silver drachmai, (made) by Papontos to Pekysis.;Agreement of cession of . . ., (made) by Kronion to Herakleides.;Loan of 90 drachmai, (made) by Herakleides to Kronion.;Lease of 6 arourai of an allotment, (made) by Heron to Herakleides.;Acknowledgment of receipt of 52 drachmai, (made) by Orseus to Petesouchos.;Lease of 4 arourai of grass, (made) by Anchious to Patron.;On the 23rd. Loan of 160 drachmai, (made) by Didymos to Orsenouphis.;Acknowledgment of deposit of 16 drachmai, (made) by Orseus to Orseous.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 121, Verso, col. X, 1933</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
