<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Register of Documents Prepared at the Grapheion</title>
            <author>Unknown scribe of the grapheion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2923</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2923</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.125</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;125</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;125</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11970</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11970</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11970-2</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 668</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.625113-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(L. 14-28);;Month of Sebastos, the 8th.;Agreement of obligation to remain in service (paramone), (made) by Herakleides, son of Pateroous to Stotoetis, son of Petearpsenesis. (Fee:) 6 oboloi.;On the 9th. Acknowledgment of deposit of 4,000(?) drachmai, (made) by Ptolemaios, son of Diodoros, and his wife to Herodion, son of Lysimachos. (Fee:) 4 obols.  &lt;or: Acknowledgment of deposit, (made) by Ptolemaios, son of Diodoros, and his wife to Herodion, son of Lysimachos. (Fee:) 4 drachmai 14 obols.&gt;;Acknowledgment of receipt of a maintenance, '(made) by [- - -]onopis and her husband' Kollouthos {and his wife} to Orseus. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;On the 10th. Acknowledgment of receipt of rent for 3 1/2 arourai, (made) by Soueris to Kronion. (Fee:) 10 obols.;Agreement of sale of cattle, (made) by Kronion to Horion. (Fee:) 6 drachmai, of which he owes 2 drachmai.;On the 19th &lt;read: 12th&gt;. Acknowledgment (of receipt) of a dowry of 32 drachmai, (made) by Papontos to Didyme. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Acknowledgment (of receipt) of a dowry of 28 drachmai, (made) by Phemnasis to Menemachos. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Written declaration concerning a copy of a letter, (made) by Paas and [others] to Venustus, (slave) of Primigenes. (Fee:) 10 obols.;Another written declaration to the same, (made) by Harpheesis and others concerning the grain delivered to the sitologos Apion. (Fee:) 10 obols.;Another written declaration, (made) by Papnebtynis and others to the same, concerning the [guarding] of feeding-places. [(Fee:) 3 obols.];[- - -];[Memorandum] (concerning) the receipt of a dowry [of 16 silver drachmai, (made) by Onnophris] to Sisenxis. [(Fee:) 7 obols.];;(L. 10-13);;(2nd hand) Of the same (month), the 14th. Agreement of sale of looms, (made) by Orseus and another to Ptollis and another. (Fee:) 20 obols.;On the 17th. Lease of pasture lands, (for a rental paid) on account(?), (made) by Leonides to Mysthas and another. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Written declaration, (made) by Kastor. (Fee:) 6 obols. (Kastor) the retail-dealer.;Petition, (made) by Orsenouphis and others to Epainetos. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 125, l. 10-28, 1933 -- BL X, 123 (l. 26). - L. 20: read 32, not 302 drachmai. (PH)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
