<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Account of Expenditures</title>
            <author>Kronion son of Apion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3031</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3031</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.127</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;127</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;127</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11972</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11972</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11972-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 693</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.843602-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Col. I);;Account of (my) private expenditures of the 6th year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus the Emperor, month of Sebastos.;On the 4th. For the price(?) for the sake of 5 stathmia of wool: 8 silver drachmai.;On the 10th. For the price of 1 keramion of wine for Heronas the notary: 17 obols;;for petty expenses: 2 drachmai;;similarly, for us, for expenses: 4 drachmai.;For Marsisouchos the priest, for the price of 1 5/6 artaba of wheat: 8 drachmai.;On the 14th. For the price of 1 1/3 artaba of lentils, for Chrates: 4 drachmai.;On the 16th. For Eutychos the son of Takolleeinos, for 1 artaba: 4 drachmai.;On the 19th. For Eutychos, son of Chrates, for 1 3/10 artaba: 4 drachmai.;On the 24th. For Orsenouphis, son of Phombos, for the price of 3 1/2 artabai of wheat: 20 drachmai.;On the 27th. For Onnophris the granary guard, for the price of 2 artabai of wheat: 16 drachmai.;For Aphrodisios, (son of) Teris &lt;Or: Aphrodisios (also called) Teris&gt;, for the price of 1 artaba of wheat: 8 drachmai.;Similarly, through me, Kronion, for the dealers in corn, in the granaries, for 3 artabai of wheat: 24 drachmai.;On the 29th. For Herodion, son of Kephalas, for the price of 1 1/10 artaba of wheat: 8 drachmai.;For the price of 2 stathmia of wool, for Papontos, son of Marames: 4 drachmai.;On the 30th. For the price of 1 keramion of wine and 1 keramion of oil, for Eutychos: 4 drachmai.;For Patron, president of the association of the god for the 5th year: 4 drachmai.;For Posis, of Theogonis, for the price of 1 keramion of wine: 4 drachmai.;In the city for the wife, Mommous, and the maidservant of Chrates, son of Harpeesis, as travel money: 4 drachmai.;On Phaophi 1. Through Onnophris the pteraphoros and Harmaeis the weaver and another, to (be paid to) P[- - -], for what he sent to Kanariates: 8 drachmai.;On the 4th. For the price of 1 keramion of wine: 18 obols; for a made dish: 4 obols; for oil: 3 obols.;Similarly, for [- - -], the &lt;administrator&gt; of the (catoecic) registers, for 1 keramion of wine: 18 obols;;for the price of . . .: 10 obols;;[- - -]: 3 obols.;For the association of Harpochrates, for 2 keramia: 36 obols.;[For the price of oil] and a made dish: 5 obols.;[For the price of oil(?)]: 3 obols.;[For the price] of oil and a made dish: 5 obols.;[For the price] of oil(?): 3 obols.;[For - - -] and oil and a made dish: 9 obols.;[For - - -] and oil: 6 obols.;[- - - for(?)] Aphrodisios, for the price of 2 1/10 artabai of wheat: 16 drachmai.;For the price of 1 1/2 artaba of wheat: 12 drachmai.;[For the price of oil] and a made dish: 6 obols.;[For the price of oil] and a made dish: 6 obols. Similarly 3 obols.;[For(?)] Tabas, for his son:;[for the price] of 1 keramion of wine: 18 obols;;[for the price] of eggs: 1 obol;;[for the price of oil]: 3 obols.;For petty expenses: 19 obol.;On Neos Sebastos 1. For the price of a made dish and oil: 3 obols.;[- - -]: 3 obols.;[For the price] of a made dish: 1 obol. For the price of oil: 3 obols.;For Eutychas, for the price of breads baked in a pan and of a made dish: 3 obols.;For the same, for the price of breads baked in a pan: 1 obol.;[- - -] for the price of breads: 4 obols.;[- - - for] a made dish: [. .] obols.;[For - - -], for the price of [- - - and] oil(?): 4 obols.;;(In the left margin, opposite l. 14-20);. . . and the robes of Apias for 32 drachmai, on the 7th of Phaophi.;;(In the left margin, opposite l. 25-27);On the 21. For us . . . Synesios.;;(Coll. II);;For Eutychas, son of Eutychos, for the price of 12 measures of barley: 4 drachmai.;[For the price] of 4 1/2 stathmia of [wool], for Orsenouphis, son of Belphis: 8 drachmai.;. . . of 4 stathmia of wool . . .: 7 obols.;For Orsenouphis(?), as salary for a half-stathmion of thread: 10 obols.;On the 10th. [For the price] of oil: 3 obols.;On the 13th. [For the price] of oil and a made dish: 5 obols.;[For the price] of oil: 3 obols; for a made dish: 2 obols.;[For the price] of 1 keramion [of wine]: 14 obols.;[- - -] and (for) beer: 10 obols.;On the 17th. For the price [- - -]: 2 obols.;On the 18th. Through Orsenouphis, son of Tabas, (who works) in the workshop of Hatres, for the price of wool: 4 drachmai.;On the 19h.  [- - -]: 2 obols.;On the 20th. For Patron, son of Tyrannos: 10 obols.;For the price of 1 keramion of wine from Talei, (for) entertaining Eutychas: 22 obols.;On the . . For the price of a half-artaba of turnips: 6 obols.;For the price of a made dish and of oil: 6 obols.;On the . . For the price of oil: 3 obols.;On the 28th. For the price of oil and of a made dish: 5 obols.;On the 29th. For the price of oil: 3 obols.;Entertaining Kastoras: 10 obols.;For the price of the thread to complete the outer garment and of the tunics: 4 drachmai.;On Choiak 2. [- - -] of the robe and of the tunics: 16 obols;;for the price of purple dye: 3 1/2 obols.;For the price of oil: 3 obols.;On the 4th. For the price of oil and a made dish: 5 obols.;For the price of oil: 3 obols.;On the 7th. For the price of oil: 3 obols.;For the price of 10 artabai and 8 measures of dates: 28 drachmai.;For the fare of one donkey and for expenses: 19 1/2 obols.;For Satyros, for the price of 3 measures of dates: 8 obols.;For Orsenouphis the (cloth-)beater, for the price of fishes (salachia): 4 drachmai.;On the . . For Patron, son of Tyrannos, for contributions for the 6th year: 4 drachmai.;On the 9th(?). For the price of oil and of a made dish: 5 obols.;On the 13th. Entertaining Maron and Soterichos, son of Kronides: a contribution of 4 drachmai.;On the 14th. For the workers cutting the wood, and for the freight charges in the same matter, for 6 loads of wood: 34 obols.;For a made dish and for oil: 5 obols.;For Lysas, son of Kephalas, what I deducted (from his account) as a loan for the scribe's fee for Horos and Herakleides, both sons of Plesis: 8 drachmai.;On the 16th. Through Tabas the (cloth-)beater, for the price of oil: 4 drachmai.;To Tenesrois, daughter(?) of Apias, for the price of 1 keramion of wine: 20 obols.;On the 17th. For the price of a made dish: 2 obols.;For Tateeus, for the price of 2 artabai of barley: 8 silver drachmai.;On the 19th. For the price of a made dish: 1 obol.;For Pnesis, for the price of 4 stathmia of wool: 8 drachmai.;On the 20th. For the price of a made dish: 2 obols.;On the . . For the price of a made dish: 2 obols.;On the . . For the price of a made dish and vegetables: 3 obols.;Entertaining Herakles and Didymas with Pnesis: for each, a keramion of wine: 20 obols; and a made dish: 3 obols.;On the . . Entertaining Sagatos and Horos and Apetes, (his/their?) father: 10 obols.;[- - -] and eggs: 10 obols.;;(Col. III);;And for the receipt that Gaius made for Onnophris the granary guard: 14 obols;;and for (Eutychos) the son of Chrates and (Eutychos) the son of Takolleeinis, for payments: 2 obols.;On the 30th. Entertaining Onnophris the granary guard: for 2 keramia of wine, 42 obols.;On Tybi 1. For the price of a made dish and oil: 5 obols.;On the 3rd. For the price of a made dish and oil: 6 obols.;On the 5th. For the price of a made dish and oil: 5 obols.;Entertaining Apollonies &lt;read: Apollonides?&gt; 'with Eutychas and Tabos': a contribution of 12 obols.;On the 9th. For the price of a made dish and oil: 6 obols.;On the 11th. For the price of oil: 5 obols.;On the 14th. For the price of oil and of a made dish: 6 obols.;Entertaining Kastoras and his brothers as a favor to Helenos: a participation of 5 drachmai.;On the 19th. For the price of vegetables and oil and a made dish: 6 1/2 obols.;On the 21st. For the price of oil: 4 obols.;On the 22nd. For Kronion, son of Belles grandson of Kalas, for the price of wool: 4 drachmai.;For the price of vegetables in the city: 6 1/2 obols.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 127, 1933</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
