<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Census Declaration</title>
            <author>Peteuris, son of Horos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1304</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1304</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.3.176</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;3;176</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;3;176</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11982</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11982</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11982-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 104</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.637354-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>To Horos, son of Haryotes, [registration officer] of Bacchias, and Apynchis, son of Onnophris, and the other elders.;From Peteuris, son of Horos, a resident of the village of Bacchias.;There belongs to me in the village 3/4 of a house in which I dwell, and I register both myself and those of my household for the census of the past ninth year of the Emperor Caesar Domitian Augustus Germanicus.;I am Peteuris, son of Horos, the son of Horos, my mother being Herieus, the daughter of Menches, a cultivator of state land, about 30 years old without identification marks, and (I register):;my wife Tapeine, the daughter of Apkois, 25 years old, and my full brothers:;Horos, about 20 years old, and;Horion, another, about 7 years old.;And there belongs to my brother the remaining fourth part of the aforesaid house and courtyard in which we live.;I, Peteuris, the aforesaid, have submitted the declaration, and I swear by the Emperor Caesar Domitian Augustus Germanicus that the foregoing statements are true and that I have falsified nothing. Aphrodisios, secretary of the village, wrote for him as he is illiterate.;The tenth year of the Emperor Caesar Domitian Augustus Germanicus, Pachon 15.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich III, 176, 1936 -- BL III, 110 (l. 17); BL VII, 108 (l. 5, 11, 12, 15, 16, 17)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
