<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lease of Grain Land</title>
            <author>Horos, son of Horos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1318</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1318</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.3.185</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;3;185</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;3;185</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11988</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11988</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11988-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 110</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.61746-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>To Marcus Anthestius Gemellus, former cavalryman.;From Horos, the son of Horos, of the village Bacchias, a Persian of the epigone.;I wish to lease from you for four years from the present sixth year of Hadrian Caesar our lord the five arourai, or however many there may be, in one parcel belonging to you near the same village, at an annual rental for the whole, including five artabai of barley which I shall receive as seed, of twenty-five artabai of barley all(?) according to the six-choinx measure of the village interpreter; and I shall perform the annual labors, the sowing and cleaning and removal of wild oats, sowing for the first three years as I may please, but in the fourth year with grass for cutting and drying; and I shall deliver to you the annual rental new, clean, free from blemish, in the month Pauni on the threshing floor of the arourai, the annual charges for transporting state grain resting upon me, Horos; and after the expiration of the lease I shall hand over the arourai after the hay harvest free from rushes, reeds, coarse grass and all rubbish, if you decide to grant the lease on the foregoing terms, and free from public taxes.;(2nd hand) I, Marcus Anthestius Gemellus, have made the lease as aforesaid. The sixth year of the Emperor Caesar Trajan Hadrian Augustus, on the . . . supplementary day of the month Mesore.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich III, 185, 1936 -- BL VI, 80 (bibliography); BL IX, 159 (l. 2, 24-25).</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
