<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Petition to the Prefect</title>
            <author>Ptolemaios son of Diodoros alias Dioskoros</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1449</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1449</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11980</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11980</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;3;174</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11980-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 147</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.376276-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>To Lucius Valerius Proculus, prefect of Egypt.;From Ptolemaios, son of Diodoros, also called Dioskoros, an inhabitant of the Arsinoite nome.;Since your inbred kindness, my lord prefect, extends to all, I too ask to share it. There is in the nome a certain class of men who are called sailor-divers. These, being public officers and in the service of the water administration and in attendance on the shore-guards and cultivation inspectors for the time being, are therefore relieved of all head-taxes and all public services and are also fed at the public expense; and accordingly they are absolutely forbidden to take up any other employment. One of these, a certain Isidoros, son of Mareis, a man of very bold and reckless character who, by means of suborned agents, counterfeits royal leases for the sake of extortion and gain - as I shall prove also on the day of trial - made an attack on me through one of his suborned agents, a certain Ammonios, surnamed Kaboi, a culpable fellow who had been proscribed on account of his lawless life. Notwithstanding that I am a lessee of domain land who pay considerable revenues to the imperial treasury and offered considerable security for the lease, he refused to let me enjoy my lease and even excluded me from my house and insulted me until he extorted money from me. I have therefore had recourse to you, the helper of all, and beg you, since you have for the present renounced your visit to the nome, to give orders for a letter to be written to the strategos of the division of Themistes and Polemon to hear me against him, since I can bring proofs on the spot concerning my being insulted and subjected to extortion, so that I may be able to live unmolested in my home during the most happy times of our exalted emperor, and your delightful prefecture, and may obtain relief. Farewell.;(2nd hand) I, Ptolemaios, son of Diodoros, have presented the petition, as aforesaid.;(3rd hand) The strategos of the nome will do what is proper.;(4th hand) Return it.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich III, 174, 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
