<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Census Declaration </title>
            <author>Peteuris, son of Horos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1309</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1309</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.3.177</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;3;177</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;3;177</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11983</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11983</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11983-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 105</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.744057-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>To Lucretius Cerialis, strategos, and Pasion, royal secretary of the division of Herakleides of the Arsinoite nome, and Areios, village secretary, and Apollonios and Patron, registration officers of the village of Bacchias.;From Peteuris, son of Horos, the son of Horos, his mother being Herieus, daughter of Menches, a resident of the aforesaid village. There belongs to me and to my brothers in the village a fourth part of a house and courtyard in which we dwell, and I register myself and those of my household for the house-by-house census of the past seventh year of the Emperor Caesar Nerva Trajan Augustus Germanicus Dacicus. I am Peteuris, the aforesaid, a cultivator of state land, about 44 years old, and (I register):;my brother Horos, about 34 years old, with no identification marks, and;Horion, another brother, about 21 years old, with no identification marks, and;his wife Thenatymis, daughter of Chariton, her mother being Tapetosiris, about 25 years old,;and in the same village a share of building sites.;(2nd hand) We, Apollonios, registration officer of the village of Bacchias, and Patron, registration officer, have entered (the declaration) through Epimachos, secretary. The 8th year of the Emperor Caesar Nerva Trajan Augustus Germanicus Dacicus, Choiak 5.;(3rd hand) I, Areios, village secretary for the 8th year, have signed it.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich III, 177, 1936 -- BL VII, 108 (l. 19, 20, 21, 23, 25); BL X, 123 (l. 13). - L. 27: read Epimachou, instead of Petesouchou. (PH)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
