<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Application for a Lease of Grain Land</title>
            <author>Horos, son of Horos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1313</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1313</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.3.184</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;3;184</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;3;184</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11987</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11987</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11987-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 107</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.387833-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>[To Haryotes, son of Alexas.];From Horos, son of Horos, the son of Horos, an inhabitant of the village of Bacchias, a Persian of the epigone.;I wish to lease from you for four years, four sowings, from the present fifth year of Hadrian Caesar, our lord, the four and one-half arourai of an allotment, or however many there may be in one parcel, which you own in the neighborhood of the aforesaid village of Bacchias, at an annual rental for the whole of twenty artabai of wheat, including the four and one-half artabai of seed wheat which I shall receive from you, measured with the six-choinix measure of your brother Alexas, by which payments are measured, subject to no charges and guaranteed against risk.;And I shall perform all the yearly farm labors which are proper, each at the necessary time at my own expense without damage to the property. And I shall deliver in the month Pauni in the village the annual rental in grain, new, clean, without blemish, and free from barley. And after the expiration of the lease I shall hand over the arourai free from rushes, reeds, coarse grass and all rubbish, with one half lying fallow in grass and the other half after the stubble harvest. The transport charges for moving grain shall rest upon me, Horos, if the lease is approved on the aforesaid terms.;Haryotes, about 59 years old, with a scar on the ankle bone of his left food.;The fifth year of the Emperor Caesar Trajan Hadrian Augustus, Tybi 22.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich III, 184, 1936 -- BL VI, 80 (bibliography); BL VIII, 212 (bibliography). - L. 26: read Tybi 22, rather than 23. (PH)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
