<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Receipt for Rent</title>
            <author>Haryotes, son of Alexas</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1320</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1320</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.3.199</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;3;199</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;3;199</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11997</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11997</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11997-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 112</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.893467-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Recto);;The tenth year of the Emperor Caesar Trajan Hadrian Augustus, the second of the month Gorpiaios, Epeiph 2, in Bacchias of the division of Herakleides of the Arsinoite nome.;Haryotes, son of Alexas, the son of Alexas, about 64 years old with a mark on his forehead to the right and on his left foot, acknowledges to Horos, son of Horos, the son of Horos, about 52 years old with a scar on his left eyebrow that he, the party of the first part, has received from him the rent for the present tenth year of Hadrian Caesar, our lord, of the four and one-half arourai, or however many there may be, of an allotment of his in the plain called . . . which he is cultivating near the aforesaid village of Bacchias, Horos having retained by him the seed for the sowing of the coming eleventh year of Hadrian Caesar, our lord, and that he, the party of the first part, has no accusation to bring against Horos about any matter whatsoever up to the present day in any way on any pretext, while the lease remains valid in all its existing terms.;Signatory: for the party of the first part, Heliodoros, son of Heliodoros, about 50 years old with a scar on his right cheek.;(2nd hand) I, Haryotes, son of Alexas, the son of Alexas, acknowledge that I have received from Horos, son of Horos, the rent for the present tenth year of Hadrian, our lord,  for the four and one-half arourai of an allotment of mine which he is cultivating near Bacchias, Horos having retained by him the seed of the coming year, and the lease remaining in force as aforesaid. I, Heliodoros, son of Heliodoros, wrote for him as he is illiterate.;(1st hand) Recorded through the record office in Bacchias.;;(Verso);;Acknowledgment of receipt of rental, (made) by Hareotes to Horos.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich III, 199, 1936 -- BL VI, 81 (bibliography). - Verso was unpublished. (PH)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
