<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Receipt for Rent</title>
            <author>Haryotes, son of Alexas</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1322</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1322</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.3.196</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;3;196</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;3;196</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11994</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11994</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11994-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 114</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.028779-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Recto);;The sixth year of the Emperor Caesar Trajan Hadrian Augustus, the twenty-third of the month Germanikeios, Pachon 23, in Bacchias of the division of Herakleides of the Arsinoite nome.;Haryotes, son of Alexas, about 60 years old with a scar on the left foot, acknowledges to Horos, son of Horos, surnamed Imesbailis, a cultivator, about 48 years old with a scar on his left eyebrow, that he, the party of the first part, has received from him the rent of the present sixth year of Hadrian Caesar, our lord, for the four and one-half arourai of an allotment belonging to him, Haryotes, which Horos is cultivating near the aforesaid village, namely sixteen artabai of wheat by the six-choinix measure, he, Horos, having deducted in his keeping the seed for the sowing of the coming seventh year, namely, four artabai of wheat, and the lease remains in force.;Signatories: for the party of the first part Heliodoros, son of Heliodoros, about 49 years old with a scar on his right cheek, and for the other, Ammonios, son of Dioskoros, about 45 years old with a scar on his forehead to the right.;(2nd hand) I, Haryotes, son of Alexas, acknowledge that I have received from Horos the rent of the current year for the the four and one-half arourai of mine which he is cultivating near the village, namely sixteen artabai of wheat, while he retains the seed for the sowing of the coming seventh year, namely four artabai of wheat, and the lease remains in force as aforesaid. Heliodoros, son of Heliodoros, wrote for him as he is illiterate.;(3rd hand) I, Horos, son of Horos, have received the receipt as aforesaid. Ammonios, son of Dioskoros, wrote for him as he is illiterate.;(1st hand) Recorded through the grapheion in Bacchias.;;(Verso);;Acknowledgment of receipt of rental, (made) by Hareotes to Horos.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich III, 196, 1936 -- BL VI, 81 (bibliography). - L . 26-27: read kath(os) prokitai. Egra(psen) hyp(er) ; autou, instead of klerou. Egrapsen hyper ; autou. Verso was unpublished. (PH)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
