<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Receipt for Rent </title>
            <author>Haryotes, son of Alexas</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1323</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1323</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.3.197</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;3;197</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;3;197</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11995</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11995</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11995-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 115</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.199711-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Recto);;The seventh year of the Emperor Caesar Trajan Hadrian Augustus, the twenty-seventh of the month Germanikeios, Pachon 27, in Bacchias of the division of Herakleides of the Arsinoite nome.;Hareotes, son of Alexas, about 62(?) years old with a scar on his left foot, acknowledges to Horos, son of Horos, a cultivator, about [49] years old with a scar on his right eyebrow, that he, the party of the first part, has received from him the rent and the seed of the present seventh year of Hadrian Caesar, our lord, for the four and one-half arourai of an allotment of his, which he cultivates near Bacchias, namely twenty artabai of wheat by the measure specified in the lease, which remains in force in all its existing terms.;Signatories: for the party of the first part Petsiris, son of Papeis, about 52 years old with a scar on his nose to the left, and for the other, Souchas, son of Sochotes, about 43 years old with a scar on his right forearm.;(2nd hand) I, Haryotes, son of Alexas, acknowledge that I have received from Horos the rent and the seed of the present seventh year of Hadrian Caesar, our lord, for the four and one-half arourai of mine which he cultivates near Bacchias, namely twenty artabai of wheat by the measure specified in the lease, which remains in force as aforesaid. Petsiris, son of Papeis, wrote for him as he is illiterate.;(3rd hand) I, Horos, son of Horos, have received the receipt as aforesaid. I, Souchas, son of Sochotes, wrote for him as he is illiterate.;(1st hand) Recorded through the grapheion in Bacchias.;;(Verso);;Acknowledgment of receipt of rental, (made) by Hareotes to Horos.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich III, 197, 1936;;; -- BL VI, 81 (bibliography). - L . 6: read Horoi Horo[u] georg[oi hos eton 49, oule], instead of: Horoi Horo[u ho]s eto[n 49, oule]; l. 7: read: hom[o]l[o]gounta, instead of homo[logounta]. Verso was unpublished. (PH)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
