<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3787</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3787</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11999-60</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.696375-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 40.;(Pharmouthi) 2 likewise:;Petheus, son of Pasoknopaios through the agency of Ptolemais, daughter of Apollonios (Kalalas);;(left margin: drachmas 4, obols 17) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 2, obols 3, tax on the produce of oil obols 2, chalki 2, naubion obol 1.5, surcharges obols 3.5, chalki 2;;eparourion drachma 1, obols 4, surcharges kollybos obol 0.5, chalki 2, in total drachmas drachmas 5, obols 4, chalki 2;;Isidoros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Isidoros, mother Thaisarion, drachmas 20;;Helena, daughter of Aunes (Petheus, son of Titiale);;(left margin: drachmas 24, obols 12) orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 5, naubion obols 3, surcharges drachma 1, obol 0.5, chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 3, obols 2, surcharges obol 1.5, chalki 2, kollybos obol 1, chalki 2, in total drachmas 10, obols 2.5, chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 12, obols 3, surcharges obols 4.5, chalki 2, in total drachmas 13, obol 1.5, chalki 2;;Thaesis, daughter of Sokrates;;naubion for the katoikoi obols 4, surcharges obol 0.5, kollybos chalki 2, in total obols 4.5, chalki 2;;Melitous, daughter of Apollonios;;(left margin: drachmas 24, obols 12) orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 2, obols 3, tax on the produce of olives obols 2, chalki 2, naubion obol 1.5, surcharges obols 3.5, chalki 2;;eparourion drachma 1, obols 4, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5, chalki 2, in total drachmas 5, obols 4, chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 6, obol 1.5, surcharges obols 2.5, in total drachmas 6, obols 4;;and Serapous, daughter of Pasoxis;;orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 2, obols 3, tax on the produce of olives obols 2, chalki 2, naubion obol 1.5, surcharge obols 3.5, chalki 2;;eparourion drachma 1, obols 4, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5, in total drachmas 5, obols 4, chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 6, obol 1, surcharges obols 2.5, in total drachmas 6, obols 4;;Psenesis, son of Parmenion, grandson of Psenesis, mother Tkonnos, drachmas 4;;Didyme, daughter of Heras (Hellen);;(in left margin: drachmas 20, obols 8) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 5, obols 5.5, chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives drachmas 5, chalki 2, naubion drachmas 3, chalki 2, surcharges drachma 1, obols 2.5, chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 3, obols 5, chalki 2, surcharges obol 1.5, chalki 2, kollybos obol 1.5, in total drachmas 13, obol 1.5;;Ptolemaios, son of Ptolemaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219);;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 3, tax on the produce of olives obols 2.5, chalki 2, naubion obols 2, surcharges obols 5;;eparourion drachmas 2, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5, chalki 2, in total drachmas 6, obols 5.5;;Heras, son of Petsiris, grandson of Heras, mother Isidora, drachmas 8;;Psenesis, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Komonis, drachmas 4;;Marcus Sempronius Vales (Heron, son of Akaikiotis);;(in left margin: drachmas 12, obols 14) orchard taxes apomoira drachmas 2, obols 3, tax on the produce of olives obols 2, chalki 2, naubion obol 1.5, surcharges obols 3,5, chalki 2;;eparourion drachma 1, obols 4, surcharge obol 1, kollybos obols 0.5, chalki 2, in total drachmas 5, obols 4, chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 6, obol 1.5, surcharges obols 2.5, in total drachmas 6, obols 4;;naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year obols 2, surcharges chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total obols 2.5;;Soeris, daughter of Petheus (Psansabtis);;(in left margin: drachmas 24, obols 21) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 5, obol 1, tax on the produce of olives drachma 1, obol 1.5, naubion obols 3, chalki 2, surcharges drachma 1, obols 2.5;;eparourion drachmas 3, obols 2.5, chalki 2, surcharges obol 1.5, chalki 2, kollybosobol 1, chalki 2, in total drachmas 12, obols 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 12, obols 5.5, surcharges obols 5, in total drachmas 13, obols 4.5."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
