<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Receipt for Rent </title>
            <author>Haryotes, son of Alexas</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1319</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1319</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.3.195</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;3;195</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;3;195</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11993</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11993</idno>
            <idno type="filename">11993-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 111</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.774579-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Recto);;The fifth year of the Emperor Caesar Trajan Hadrian Augustus, the seventeenth of the month Gorpiaios, Epeiph 17, in Bacchias of the division of Herakleides of the Arsinoite nome.;Haryotes, son of Alexas, about 60 years old with a scar on the left foot, acknowledges to Horos, son of Horos, about 48 years old with a scar on the right eyebrow, that he, the party of the first part, has received from him sixteen artabai of wheat by the six-choinix measure which are the rental of the present fifth year of Hadrian Caesar, our lord, for the four and one-half arourai of an allotment of his which he cultivates near the aforesaid village, while Horos retains in his possession the seed for the sowing of the coming sixth year of Hadrian Caesar, our lord, four artabai of wheat by the aforesaid measure, and the lease of the allotment remains in force in all its existing terms.;Signatories: for the party of the first part Isidoros, son of Eubios, 45 years old with a scar on his neck on the right, and for the other, Maron, son of Maron, 24 years old with a scar on his left foot.;(2nd hand) I, Haryotes, son of Alexas, acknowledge that I have received from Horos sixteen artabai of wheat by the six-choinix measure which are the rental for the present year of the allotment of mine of four and one-half arourai which you cultivate &lt;read: he cultivates&gt; near Bacchias, whil he retains the seed for the sowing of the coming year, and the lease remains in force as aforesaid. Isidoros, son of Eubios, wrote for him as he is illiterate.;(3rd hand) I, Horos, son of Horos, have received the receipt as aforesaid. Maron, son of Maron, wrote for him as he is illiterate.;(1st hand?) Recorded through the grapheion in Bacchias.;;(Verso);;Acknowledgment of receipt of rental, (made) by Haryotes to Horos.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich III, 195, 1936, Pl VI -- BL VI, 81 (bibliography). - L.3-4: read Bakchiadi tes Herak(leidou) ; meridos, instead of Bakchiadi Herakleidou ; meridos. Verso was unpublished. (PH)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
