<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Census-declaration</title>
            <author>Serempios, son of Patermouthis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1241</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1241</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.20.14304</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;20;14304</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;20;14304</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">23714</idno>
            <idno type="TM">23714</idno>
            <idno type="filename">23714-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Corn. Inv. II 11</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.780701-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>" . . . from Serempis, son of Patermouthis, son of Siris, his mother being Thenp . . .on, resident of the village Ancyron. I declare myself according to the orders given by Valerius Proculus, the former prefect, for the census of the 9th year of Antoninus Caesar our lord, in the part of the house belonging to me.;I am Serempis, aged 50, scar on the left cheek. My wife, Thenosiris daughter of Psenosiris, aged 54. Patermouthis, my son, aged 2., and his wife Thenamounis, daughter of Psenamounis, aged 16. Taas, my daughter, whose mother was Tetemouthis, registered by her husband. Nouris, son of my dead brother Pnephoros, his mother Thennoupis, aged 30, scar on the right leg. Patermouthis, his brother, aged 26, without distinguishing mark. Pnephoros, son of Pnephoros, his mother being Thenosiris, son of my wife mentioned above, aged 26 without distinguishing marks. His wife Tamounis, daughter of Ameneus, aged 18. Taphorsois, his sister, registered by her husband. Another Taas, sister of the same, likewise registered by her husband.;There belongs to me in the same village various buildings; also to Thenosiris my wife, from her parents; to Nouris and Patermouthis likewise, from their parents; and likewise to Pnephoros son of Pnephoros and his sisters. (Belonging to) these same in the same village another group.;And on request I swear by the fortune of Imperator Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrian Antoninus Augustus Pius . . . that I have handed in the house declaration and have made no false statements. Otherwise may I be subject to the consequences of the oath.;Year 10 of Imperator Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrian Antoninus Augustus Pius, Phamenoth 14.;(2nd hd) I, Horis,  have certified this through my friend Aphynchios.;(3rd hd) We, Harpsemis and Pachnoubis, have certified this through our friend Sarapion.;4th hand) I, Isidorus, village scribe, have certified this through Ptolemaios.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Westermann WL - Kraemer CJ, PCorn, 17, 1926 -- SB XX, 14304 -- BL XI, 229 (l. 6) Bagnall RS, BASP 28, 27-29, 1991 -- SB XX 14304 -- BL XI, 229 (l. 6)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
