<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Nomination to a liturby</title>
            <author>Aurelius Victor; Aurelius N. N.; Aurelius N. N. &amp; Aurelius Victor.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2107</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2107</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.20.114964</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">23838</idno>
            <idno type="TM">23838</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;20;14964</idno>
            <idno type="filename">23838-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 3780</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.403492-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>"; In the year after the consulship of Flavius Petrus, the most illustrious, Phamenoth 29, indiction 10. To the tax division of the estate of Timagenes of noble memory through you the most magnificent comites, Phoibammon and Samuelios who obtained the functions of logistai and fathers of the city and prohedroi of this illustrious city of the Oxyrhinchites through Serenos, your representative, the board of the guild of the sausage butchers here through us its secretaries and treasurers being present and signing below by all that is herein written - - - from - - - of the present indiction we nominate - - - N. N., son of Julianos and of the mother N. N. from the same city, a person of property and qualified who is able to fulfill and accomplish the function of sausage-butcher and we pledge him before your magnificy that he will appear and stay if he is required of us we will deliver him up in the public jail of this city. The above written nomination written in one copy is enforceable and in reply to the formal question we have so declared. (2nd. hd.). We, Aurelius Victor, son of N. N., and Aurelius N. N., son of Johannes, and Aurelius Victor, son of Martyritos pledge and nominate and we agree with what is written above as stated above. I, N. N., son of N. N., have written it for them, because they do not know letters. (3rd. hd.). ; Through me, N. N., has it been completed."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn PJ, ZPE 62, 133-7, 1986, Pl. VII -- In l.1 read -tro- for -pho- (D. Hagedorn). Sijpesteijn PJ, ZPE 71 (1988), 123-6, 1988, Pl VII -- SB XX 14964 -- BL XI, 233 (l. 18, 23)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
