<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Loan of wheat</title>
            <author>Heraklas, son of Heraklas &amp; Kroniaina, daughter of Athenion and mother of Heraklas</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">oslo.apis.72</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NoOU)72</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.14.12023</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;14;12023</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;14;12023</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">26578</idno>
            <idno type="TM">26578</idno>
            <idno type="filename">26578-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Oslo inv. 1029</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:31.265356-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Heraklas, son of Heraklas, (... aged about ... years ...) and Kroniaina, daughter of Athenion, aged about (...) years, (...) of the village of Tebtynis, with her guardian, her own son Heraklas, acknowledge to Patron, son of Hera(...), aged about thirty years, having a scar on (...) his forehead, that they have received from him, Patron, a loan of four artabas of wheat, measured by the four-choinikes measure (of Tebtynis?) owned by him, Patron, and that the acknowledging parties will repay (the loan) on mutual security in the month of Payni of the current year, without delay, Patron having the right of execution on the acknowledging persons and upon whichsoever of them he may choose, and upon all their property, as if in accordance with a legal decision, and in answer to the formal question they have given their consent. (2nd hand) We, Heraklas, son of Heraklas, and my mother Kroniaina, daughter of Athenion, with me as her guardian, have received from Patron a loan of four artabas of wheat, which we will repay as aforesaid.;Heras, son of Herak(...), has written for them, the parties being illiterate. ;Docket of the record-office at Tebtynis.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
