<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title type="main"> HGVTITLE (DDBTITLE) </title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">hgv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="TM">gv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">hgv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sosol;2023;0507</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2023-07-14T07:40:23-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> ‘... for the sowing and planting of crops [in] flax. I have now received from you and been paid
the rent of this (land) in advance … I acknowledge that I am ready to plough and fill up the
same arouras twice <milestone n="5" unit="line"/> and to water them thrice with my animals and to guard its (read their) crops
in the fields until their transport, and I agree to transport the flax to your basin (koilas) with
my animals and at my expense without wages, receiving from you, however, one jar of wine
and one (day’s) maintenance. The contract of this wage-receipt (misthapoche) is normative and
secure, and upon being asked the formal question I gave my assent.
<milestone n="10" rend="break" unit="line"/> I, Aurelius Pkylis, son of Petrus, the aforementioned, made this wage-receipt, as written
above. I, Aurelius Theodosius, son of Triadelphus, from Hermopolis, wrote on his behalf at his
request, since he does not know letters’
(Second hand) ‘Aurelius Pkylis.’
(Third hand) ‘I, Aurelius Ioannes, son of Iosephius, from Hermopolis, am witness to the
wage-receipt and to the payment of the rent of two solidi of gold.’
(Fourth hand) ‘I, Aurelius Georgius, son of …, from Hermopolis, am witness to the receipt
of wages <milestone n="15" unit="line"/> and to the payment of the rent of two solidi of gold.’
(First or fifth hand) ‘Was written by [me], Theodo-.’
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
