<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title type="main"> HGVTITLE (DDBTITLE) </title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">hgv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="TM">gv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">hgv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.cair.masp;1;67118</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2023-11-11T07:43:12-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> In the twenty-first year of the reign of our most divine lord Flavius Justinian the Eternal Augustus and Emperor, in the postconsulate of famosissimus Flavius Basileius, eleventh indiction, Phaophi x.
(Addressed) To the Public Treasury of the village of Aphrodite of the Antaiopolite nome, through Abraham (pap.: Abraamios), son of Ioseph (pap.: Iosephios), boethos from the same village, (From) Flavius Dioskoros, son of Apollos, syntelestes (responsible for the taxes of the village) from the same village, greetings. 
7. Put down in a document and transfer to my name, from the name of Ieremias, son of Iakob (pap.: Iakubios) the priest, who is also the father of Psates the lector, the tax contribution of half of the estate of Pisraeliou Topos, in joint tax liability with the monastery called of Cleopatra of 
17. the holy topos of Abba Michael, for the half, that is for sowable land of one and a half, a fourth, a sixteenth, and a sixtieth part of an aroura, and a sixteenth and sixtieth part of an aroura planted with rush, and a thirty-second part of an aroura planted with trees. Total: sowable land 3 arourae, land planted with rush of aroura, land planted with trees  of aroura. 
22. And for this land I am ready to pay the imperial taxes to the Public Treasury blamelessly and unaccusably each year, through both you and the boethos to be appointed at the time and I shall pay the taxes for this grain, the ones in gold coins, the freight-charges and expenses, according to the cadastral records of the said village, based on the census made by Ioannes of erudite memory, the late scholasticus and censitor, starting with the tax assessment of twelfth indiction included, and throughout succeeding time forever, 
33. by virtue of the cession presently made to me by the aforementioned Psates, lector of the holy southern church, of the barren and sandy part of the arourae, which is abandoned (en aphesei). And for your security and of the Public Treasury, I have produced in two identical copies this application as above, written entirely by my own hand … /Tr. Law in Social Networks Project (Warsaw)/
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
