<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>o.heid.449</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">o.heid.449</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">o.heid;;449</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">80647</idno>
            <idno type="TM">80647</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Duke Databank of Documentary Papyri. This work is licensed under a
          <ref type="license" target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">Creative 
          Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>
               <bibl>O.Heid. 449</bibl>
            </p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <handNotes>
            <handNote xml:id="m2"/>
            <handNote xml:id="m3"/>
         </handNotes>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
          <change when="2011-12-21T12:41:02.22-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/joshuad.sosin">Finalized - ready</change>
          <change when="2011-12-21T12:41:02.199-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/simoeis">Vote - AcceptText - Accept</change>
          <change when="2011-12-21T12:41:02.186-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Vote - AcceptText - Reports from Senior Editors Dieter Hagedorn, Andrea Jördens, Klaas Worp. Notes also from J. Cowey, R. Ast, T. Hickey, P.Heilporn.&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;DIETER HAGEDORN, on scrutiny of hi-resolution digital image, from which the plate in ed pr. was generated: "Mir scheint, daß Alain Delattres Vorschlag eine gute Chance hat, den richtigen Weg zu weisen. Wenn ich--wie Joshua Sosin schreibt--das Gamma von διαγρά(φου) in Z. 3 vergleiche und die dortige Anbindung an das folgende Rho wegdenke, leuchtet mir Λογγ- in Z. 2 sehr gut ein. Zu Ny gibt es in dem Text zwar keine sichere Parallele (vgl. immerhin μ̣ί̣α̣ν̣ in Z. 4), aber was man an der Stelle sieht, wo wir bisher ου gelesen haben, entspricht der Grundform eines Ny, ist also letzten Endes unproblematisch. Ein vollständiges hochgestelltes ου kann ich danach allerdings nicht sehen, wohl ein sehr kleines, punktförmiges Omikron allein, welches am Ende des letzten Aufstrichs des Ny sitzt. Ich komme also zu dem Schluß, daß mich Paul Heilporns Version Λογγίν\ο(υ)/ am meisten überzeugt, bei der ich sogar auf jeden Punkt der Unsicherheit verzichten könnte.&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;ANDREA JÖRDENS, on autopsy of original (with R. AST; J. COWEY, on autopsy, concurring): Abweichend von Herrn Hagedorn würde ich den Punkt am Ende des Ny nicht als Omikron deuten, sondern nur als Klecks am Buchstabenende. Dagegen wird man bei den derzeit ausgezeichneten Lichtverhältnissen oberhalb des Ny sowohl ein Omikron wie auch Ypsilon erkennen wollen. Zwischen dem - nach links drehenden - Abkürzungsstrich des  εσχ(ον) in Z. 1 und dem gespaltenen Ypsilon besteht keine Verbindung, die einen entsprechenden Bezug erlauben würde. &#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Aus meiner Sicht wird man daher Λογγινου transkribieren wollen, wobei ich, da es sich lediglich um eine Schreibvariante und nicht um eine nachträgliche Einfügung handeln dürfte, auf Einfügezeichen verzichten würde.&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Was die Schreibung bzw. Kombination Ny + Omikron anbelangt, erinnert sie mich übrigens sehr an die häufiger begegnende Abkürzung für νο(μισματιον). Dies könnte auch erklären, warum Omikron und Ypsilon offenbar nicht in einem Zug geschrieben wurden, wie es ja ebenfalls in dieser Zeit anzutreffen ist. &#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;KLAAS WORP, on review of image in ed pr: "I would subscribe to the reading suggested by Paul Heilporn, though with a slight modification in that (1) I would dot the first gamma (on the photo it seems to be damaged and does not come out really crystal clear) and (2) I would not print those \  / around the ending in *-(o)u*. After all, the omikron was apparently written in ligature with the ny, slightly higher--of course--than the endstroke of that ny in order to mark the abbreviation-by-superposition, but it was not added afterwards as if one is dealing  with an addition-in-afterthought, vel. sim." Also that the photo *might* suggest 'diastolê' between the two gammas. And by second email, that, "the dot underneath the first gamma [is] only 'periculi evitandi causa'."&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;TODD HICKEY, on review of image in ed pr: "I agree (strongly) with Alain. What is deceptive is the point of ink at the end of the nu; at first glance, this suggests omicron (and is, I assume, what Paul was reading). In a text of this period, however, we would expect the omicron-upsilon ligature that Alain suggests--it is quite common--and I see it rather clearly above the nu on the plate (no dots needed imo). (Initially I thought that the upsilon was part of the abbreviation stroke following chi, but on closer inspection this seems to terminate just below the pi of para)."&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;In the light of the reports I suggest emending to: Λογ̣γίνου, no supralinear addition (\.../): the -ου ligature appears above, as is common (DDbDP does not encode such with supralinear addition).&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;:Λογ̣γίνου|SoSOL:A. Delattre (plate)|&lt;:Λουκίου|reg|Λουγ̣ίου:&gt;:&gt;&#xD;
&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Apologies that this has taken so long to be processed.&#xD;
</change>
          <change when="2011-12-21T12:41:02.174-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/joshuad.sosin">Vote - Defer - A. Delattre proposes at O.Heid. 449.2 to read Λογ̣γίν\ου/ for ed pr's Λουγ̣ιου; if I read the plate correctly, this posits (1) that ed pr's -ου (at the end of Λουγ̣ιου) is to be read as ν and (2) that the traces visible above ed pr's -ου (at the end of Λουγ̣ιου) are in fact to be construed as -ου above the proposed ν; hence, correct to Λογ̣γίν\ου/. Again if I read the plate right, the γ in διαγρά(φου) (lin3) is not outright incompatible with the first γ (which ed pr reads as υ) in Λογ̣γίν\ου/. This is in my view an excellent candidate for sending out for review by a Senior Editor.</change>
          <change when="2011-01-06T10:11:43.489-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/Alain%20D.">Entered correction l. 2</change>
          <change when="2010-06-15T10:16:49.179-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/Alain%20D.">Entered O.Heid. 449</change>
          <change when="2010-06-15T09:16:40-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <head xml:lang="en"/>
         <div xml:lang="grc" type="edition" xml:space="preserve">
<ab>
<lb n="1"/><g type="stauros"/> <expan>ἔσχ<ex>ον</ex></expan> π<unclear>α</unclear>ρὰ σοῦ
<lb n="2"/><app type="editorial"><lem resp="PN A. Delattre (plate)">Λο<unclear>γ</unclear>γίνου</lem><rdg><choice><reg>Λουκίου</reg><orig>Λου<unclear>γ</unclear>ίου</orig></choice></rdg></app> Ἠλ<unclear>ί</unclear>α
<lb n="3"/><expan><ex>ὑπὲρ</ex></expan> <app type="alternative"><lem><expan>μέρ<unclear>ο</unclear><ex>υς</ex></expan></lem><rdg><expan>μέρ<ex>ο</ex><unclear>υ</unclear><ex>ς</ex></expan></rdg></app> <expan>διαγρά<ex>φου</ex></expan> <num value="14">ι<unclear>δ</unclear></num> <expan>ἰ<ex>ν</ex>δ<ex>ικτίωνος</ex></expan>
<lb n="4"/><expan>μ<unclear>υ</unclear><ex cert="low">ριάδα</ex></expan> <app type="alternative"><lem><num value="1"><unclear>α</unclear></num> <num value="1"><unclear>μίαν</unclear></num></lem><rdg><num value="2"><unclear>β</unclear></num> <num value="2"><unclear>δυο</unclear></num></rdg></app>. <expan><unclear>ἐ</unclear>γρ<ex>άφη</ex></expan> <expan><unclear>μ</unclear><ex>ηνὶ</ex></expan> <expan>Μ<unclear>εσο</unclear><ex>ρὴ</ex></expan> <num value="8"><unclear>η</unclear></num>
<lb n="5"/><expan>ἰ<ex>ν</ex>δ<ex>ικτίωνος</ex></expan> <num value="1">α</num>. ὁ <expan><unclear>στρ</unclear><ex>ατηγός</ex></expan>, <abbr><unclear>Ελε</unclear></abbr> <expan>στ<ex>οι</ex>χ<ex>εῖ</ex></expan>.
<lb n="6"/><handShift new="m2"/><expan>Κυριακ<ex>ὸς</ex></expan> <expan>στ<ex>οι</ex>χ<ex>εῖ</ex></expan>.
<lb n="7"/><handShift new="m3"/><unclear>Δαυὶδ</unclear> <expan>ἔγρ<ex>αψα</ex></expan>. 
</ab></div>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
