<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.16/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>sosol.2023.0114</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">sosol.2023.0114</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sosol;2023;0114</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">869410</idno>
            <idno type="TM">869410</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Duke Databank of Documentary Papyri. This work is licensed under a
          <ref type="license" target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">Creative 
          Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p/>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
          <change when="2023-03-03T15:51:37-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <head xml:lang="en"/>
         <div xml:lang="grc" type="edition" xml:space="preserve">
<ab>
<lb n="1" xml:id="lb1"/>ἔτους <num value="12">ιβ</num> Μεχειρ <num value="25">κ̅ε̅</num>
<lb n="2" xml:id="lb2"/><expan>ὑπ<ex>ὲρ</ex></expan> <expan><gap reason="illegible" quantity="2" unit="character"/> <unclear>ω</unclear><ex>  </ex></expan> <expan>θ <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="character"/> <ex>  </ex></expan> τοῦ <expan>αὐ<ex>τοῦ</ex></expan> <expan><ex>ἔτους</ex></expan>
<lb n="3" xml:id="lb3"/><expan>Ψενπόρ<ex>ις</ex></expan> <expan>Ἁρπβήκι<ex>ος</ex></expan> <expan><ex>διώβολον</ex></expan>
<lb n="4" xml:id="lb4"/>σ<unclear>υ</unclear>νπ<unclear>αντ</unclear><gap reason="illegible" quantity="3" unit="character"/> <unclear>ἑπτὰ</unclear><gap reason="illegible" quantity="2" unit="character"/> <unclear>ὀ</unclear>κτώ, <expan><ex>γίνονται</ex></expan> η.
<lb n="5" xml:id="lb5"/><space extent="unknown" unit="character"/> <gap reason="illegible" quantity="3" unit="character"/>
</ab>
  </div>
         <div type="commentary" subtype="linebyline">
            <list>
               <item corresp="#lb1" xml:space="preserve"><ref>1</ref> <p>This receipt and 8 date to a year 12 and 13, which can be dated to either the reign of Augustus or Tiberius. A dating under Augustus would allow us to identify Psenpoeris son of Harpbekis in the present text with Tkales’ father Psenpo(u)eris in the receipts of years 40–42 (cf. introduction on the taxpayers).</p></item>
               <item corresp="#lb2" xml:space="preserve"><ref>2</ref> <p>The name of the tax remains a riddle. Amounts of 8 dr. are paid for the poll-tax in this archive, but it seems impossible to read λαογραφίας. The tax name has two parts: a first group with a final raised letter probably representing omega; and a second group consisting of a theta or badly made epsilon with an abbreviation stroke. The first letter of the first group may be lambda or chi, but a mu in which the first upstroke goes beyond the line of the following downstroke is not impossible, either. One could suppose the sequences χμω- or μευ-, but neither leads us to a tax name, unless one supposes χμω- to be a metathesis for χωμ-. Alternatively, one might read μέ(ρισμος), but the abbreviation stroke does not seem to suggest that the writer had rho in mind as the abbreviated third letter. For γεω(μετρίας), the first letter does not work. We have no plausible suggestions for the second group. χωμ(ατικῶν) ἔργ(ων) seems unlikely.</p></item>
               <item corresp="#lb3" xml:space="preserve"><ref>3</ref> <p>The end of the patronymic is faint. Ἁρπβήκιος is probably abbreviated with the iota below the kappa, joining the left leg of the kappa of ὀ̣κτώ in the next line. Alternatively, it might be abbreviated with a prolonged right leg of kappa, and a small omicron high above the line.</p></item>
               <item corresp="#lb4" xml:space="preserve"><ref>4</ref> <p>Everything between the patronymic and ὀ̣κτώ poses problems. Our best guess is to read something like (διώβολον) σύνπαντος (?) (δραχμὰς) ἑπτὰ (τετρώβολον), (γίνονται) ὀκτώ, (γίνονται) η, which would allow us to connect the apparent 2 ob. with the 8 dr. in the next line. We hesitate to adopt Youtie’s reading σύνπαντος (which can perhaps also be read σύνπαντι), however, because we do not grasp the meaning of the phrase in this context, and because the traces preceding ἑ̣π̣τ̣ά̣ are not at all clear (they almost look like another διώβολον symbol, but more probably belong to another abbreviation). Alternatively, a metronymic could be read fol- lowing the patronymic, with a very flat μη(τρός) abbreviation instead of (διώβολον) in l. 3, and the rare name Σενπαήσιος followed by something else in l. 4. Yet this seems even more far-fetched, and moreover metronymics in tax receipts only became more common in the second half of the first century CE (cf. Depauw 2010).</p></item>
               <item corresp="#lb5" xml:space="preserve"><ref>5</ref> <p>The signature is too faint to offer a secure reading. Possibly, the signature read in 8, Πλε̣ ̣ ( ), can be read in this receipt as well. On the original, pi and lambda look possible.</p></item>
            </list>
         </div>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
