<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Private Letter </title>
            <author>Antimenes</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1813</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1813</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.1.10</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;1;10</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;1;10</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">1916</idno>
            <idno type="TM">1916</idno>
            <idno type="filename">1916-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 3124</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.481563-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Recto);;Antimenes to Zenon greeting. If you are well, it would be excellent. [I too am in good health]. I have written for you below [a copy of the letter] which came to me from Sosipatros, in order that you may take note and enter to the account of Apollonios [- - -] no travelling allowance was delivered to them . . . [- - -] were driven in by the stormy weather [- - -] to Arsinoe. [Farewell. Year] 28, Peritios 28.;   Sosipatros to Antimenes greeting. If [you are well] in body and everything else is to your mind, it would be excellent. We too are well. Ariston and the sister arrived here, reporting that they had been handsomely treated by you in every way. You do well then to show yourself friendly towards us; for we too will try to pay you all attention in any matter that you are keen about and write to us about. Know that they were driven in to Patara by the storms; from there they hired a boat and sailed along to Arsinoe to join us. The fare has been paid . . . amounting to 35 drachmai. I have therefore written to let you know. Farewell. Year 28, Apellaios 26.;;(Verso);;To Zenon.;;(2nd hand: docket) Antimenes about Doris, with a copy of the letter from Antipatros &lt;Read: Sosipatros&gt;. (Received) year 28, Dystros 17, in Mendes.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep_editor White JL;    Rep_Ser Light from Ancient Letters;     Rep_Year 1986;     Rep_No. 11 -- A small fragment, filling up most of the central lacuna for lines 7-15, was apparently found some time after Edgar's reedition. His restitutions are confirmed, except that in line 10 the text reads: peirasometha gar kai hemeis, instead of: peirasometha gar kai autoi. (PH) Edgar CC, P.Cair.Zen. I, 59052 (left fragment only), 1925 Edgar CC, PMich I, 10, 1931 -- BL VIII, 220 (bibliography); BL X, 127 (bibliography)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
