<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Account concerning Land </title>
            <author>Mys; unknown (Pasis son of Pais?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1824</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1824</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.1.31</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;1;31</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;1;31</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">1931</idno>
            <idno type="TM">1931</idno>
            <idno type="filename">1931-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 3134</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.592972-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Year(?) 30. A balancing of the accounts of Apollonios's land, cultivator by cultivator, presented by Mys . . . Pasis son of Pais, native of Moithymis, has 880 arourai at 5 5/8 artabai of wheat per aroura, making 4950 artabai. Of this area has been allotted, according to the letters received from Apollonios, to Sarapis and Asklepios 240 arourai, to Zeus Labraudaios 120 arourai, to Agesagoras father of Iason 100 arourai, to Horos the ibis-feeder 5 arourai, at 5 5/8 artabai of wheat each, making 2615 5/8 artabai of wheat. There remain 415 arourai at 5 5/8 artabai of wheat each, making 2334 3/8 artabai. He has also received seed from Addaios [- - -] And of hay he has delivered to us 29,800 two-mina sheaves, equal to 149 artabai of wheat. And from pastures sold we have received 134 drachmai, 1 1/2 obols; from refuse sold at the threshing floor 27 drachmai; for dry arakos 20 drachmai [- - -];Copy &lt;OR: Checking?&gt; of the account which Mys has made out against me for the land of the hekatontarourai. Land of Iason, 100 arourai: Of these there are 13 arourai of hay-producing land; for this, half an artab of seed was used for each aroura, making 6 1/2 artabai; and to the sowers was given one obol for each aroura, making 2 drachmai, 1 obol. Of arakos-producing land 16 1/2 arourai, which Mys had previously sold for 7 drachmai the aroura, making a total price of 116 drachmai, 3 obols (which Mys has received); for this, 1 1/2 artabai of arakos seed for the aroura . . . Amount of money which he has exacted from me and has not entered in the account of Apollonios: for the labourers' wages . . drachmai, 5 obols; and for the dykes 20 drachmai; for the arakos 20 drachmai, 2 obols; price of the barley . . drachmai, 5 1/2 obols. There remains what . . . the guard of the pastures has received . . .</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Edgar CC, PMich I, 31, 1931 -- L. 24: read thi a(rourai) instead of ten a(rouran). (PH)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
