<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Account of Woodwork for a House</title>
            <author>Unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1822</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1822</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.1.38</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;1;38</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;1;38</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">1938</idno>
            <idno type="TM">1938</idno>
            <idno type="filename">1938-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 3133</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.024797-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>In account with Semtheus and Apollonios. You are entitled to be paid as follows in accordance with the contract given out by Hedylos the architect. In the dining-room with seven couches and the exedra, for 10 windows with bars and panelled sides, shutting on the inside, and having fillets, at 2 drachmai each, 20 drachmai; and for these windows ten sets of panels at 4 drachmai each, 40 drachmai. Also 2 side-doors with two faces, the height of each being 3 cubits and the breadth in proportion, at 6 drachmai each, 12 drachmai. Also a door with panelled sides, 6 cubits high and proportionately broad, 12 drachmai. In the bedroom, 8 latticed windows, . . cubits high and proportionately broad, at 2 drachmaieach, 16 drachmai; and for these, panelled sides shutting on the inside, at 4 drachmai each, 32 drachmai. A door with panelled sides, height 4 2/3 cubits, breadth in proportion, 8 drachmai. Also for the concealed door leading to the exedra, height 3 2/3 cubits, breadth 10 palms, 4 drachmai. Single doors of 3 cubits, one to the stairway, 4 drachmai, and one for the privy, likewise 4 drachmai. For the bath-house 4 sham-double doors with solid jambs, at 4 drachmai each, 16 drachmai. For 12 minas of glue, 12 drachmai. Total 180 drachmai. Towards this you have received the following sums. Through the bank of Artemidoros: on Pachons . . .; on Pauni 4, . . .; on the 7th, . . .; on the 19th, 20 drachmai. On the 27th throuh Charmos, 8 drachmai. Total 155 drachmai. Remainder 25 drachmai. Also from Theopompos in Krokodilopolis, 12 drachmai. From Sosos, 10 drachmai. Through Ephesos on Mesore 19 towards the execution, as contracted for, of the woodwork, pending settlement of account, 40 drachmai. On Thoth 30, through the bank, 8 drachmai. On Phaophi 8, through the bank, . . . To Semphtheus contractor for the exedra attached to the bath-house, in accordance with his accepted tender, 18 drachmai. To the same, for the doors, 8 drachmai.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Edgar CC, PMich I, 38, 1931 -- BL VIII, 220 (bibliography)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
