<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter of Reproach</title>
            <author>Lysanias</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1803</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1803</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.1.57</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;1;57</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;1;57</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">1957</idno>
            <idno type="TM">1957</idno>
            <idno type="filename">1957-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 3114</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.414169-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Recto);;Lysanias to Theophilos greeting. I think you are not ignorant of our keenness and zeal to serve you and how from the first we protected you; and when we saw you calumniated by Demeas and how the members of the association co-operated to have you condemned unjustly and Alketas my brother became surety for you and put himself to trouble along with his friends, engaging by written bond to produce you for trial within five days (of summons) or else pay the sum claimed, and yet you were so faint-hearted as to slip away without telling us, did you not know that, if nevertheless you wished to go down the river, we would have provided funds for the journey and enabled you to return with . . . counsellors to meet your adversaries and the members of the association; for we would have given you arguments that would have made your adversaries wail. Even now, then, if you can manage to present a petition by your own efforts, do so; for it was not expedient that we should write, and we have heard it is possible for you too procure decrees that will enable us to exact vengeance from them. Know then that Demeas has made a petition to Phanias against Alketas, saying that after guaranteeing by written bond to produce Theophilos for trial he is not producing him, and that Phanias has written to Eperatos to hold the crops of Alketas until he comes himself on the occasion of the review and hears the case. Try therefore, before Phanias sails up, to sail up yourself and be here before him; otherwise, if you do not appear, Alketas will be condemned and will be in danger of having to pay the 300 drachmai. But if it is possible to get a decree, do so; if not, sail up yourself, in order that you and Alketas may be acquitted and that, through not producing you at the trial, Alketas may not have to pay the sum claimed, which has been stated above. Please come in haste. Farewell. Year 38, Pachons 14.;;(Verso);To Theophilos.;(Upside down) To the agent of Epistratos.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Edgar CC, PMich I, 57, 1931 -- BL V, 70 (bibliography); BL VI, 84 (line 4)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
