<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Business Letter</title>
            <author>Pais, kybernetes</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1889</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1889</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.1.60</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;1;60</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;1;60</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">1960</idno>
            <idno type="TM">1960</idno>
            <idno type="filename">1960-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 3225</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.72265-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Recto);;To Zenon greeting from Pais. I sailed up in the boat and we are being pestered by the man who collects the twelve-drachmai tax and we have not yet . . . We brought for Artemidoros to Memphis 500 artabai of wheat 'from Tephi' and he gave me 8 drachmai, which I spent on the boat. The sailors are not inclined to sail on the terms of a third share. Inquire at home on what terms they sail for monopoly trading and you will find that they sail on a half share. Now if you approve, write to me to repair the boat; for the opportunity has come and the boat-builders are free. The boat will then find work; for at present, as she is old, no one comes to deal with us; and if you wish, you will be able to let her for hire. I myself undertake to pay you 800 drachmai for her, on condition that she will be assigned in writing to monopoly trading. Write to me then if we are to begin work, in order that I may not sit idle in the boat with two other men. For we are getting nothing and are without the necessaries of life. Farewell.;;(Verso);;To Zenon.;(Docket) Year 38, Phamenoth 20. Pais the boat-captain.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Edgar CC, PMich I, 60, 1931 -- BL III, 116 (lines 8-10); Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 136 (date);  BL X, 128 (bibliography)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
