<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Memorandum</title>
            <author>Menodoros</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1869</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1869</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.1.67</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;1;67</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;1;67</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">1967</idno>
            <idno type="TM">1967</idno>
            <idno type="filename">1967-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 3205</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.118776-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Memorandum from Menodoros to Zenon. I was to pay you rent from Pauni [of year 4] to Pachons of year 5, being 12 months, on 120 goats at the rate of 1 1/4 kids for each, making 150 kids. [I have also] 30 young she-goats which I received in addition in the fourth year, not taxed for rent; and from Zabdis I have had from Phamenoth to Pauni, being 4 months, 63 goats from which Epharmostos has 2, leaving 61, and I have also 43 kids; and on the 30th of Mecheir I had from [[Dionysios]] 'Pyrrhos' 55 goats [and] 17 kids, apart from the 10 kids which [. . .] took over; [from] Hermias 90 goats, 60 kids. That makes 356 goats. Of these you have received the goats which you gave out on contract to the Arabs, 100 to Xenokles from Epeiph and 146 others to the 3 Arabs, making 246.  There remain in my hand 110 goats, including 30 young she-goats. And of the  kids the total is 270, without counting tje 10 new-born. Of these Iason has received 40 kids, which he sold to the retailers, and Nikon 149 which he took over from Ammonia, and there died [[12]] '2 of the kids of Hermias, 5 of those of Zabdis, and 5 of those of Pyrrhos, making 12', whose skins have been received by Doxaios. You yourself have received another 12. To Glaukias we gave 2 on a written order, another 1 to Glaukias, and the son of Glaukias has received 1 and Sostratos another 1, and in Epeiph you have received 32. That makes 250, and there remain 20.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Edgar CC, PMich I, 67, 1931 -- Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 136 (on Epharmostos)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
