<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Petition to the King</title>
            <author>Attalos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1828</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1828</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.1.71</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;1;71</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;1;71</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">1970</idno>
            <idno type="TM">1970</idno>
            <idno type="filename">1970-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich. inv. 3138</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.137779-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>To King Ptolemaios greeting from Attalos. I am being wronged by Ptolemaios, younger son of Ptolemaios, exactor of private debts. For though Serambos, strategos appointed by Aristomachos, wrote an order to Ptolemaios to the effect that since Apollonios had not even yet produced Apollonia, if he should not even now produce her in ten days, Ptolemaios was to exact 43 drachmai from Apollonios the horse-breaker and pay them to me, and though he received the order and though Apollonios has not produced Apollonia and the term has expired, and on top of that a further period has elapsed, in spite of my demands 'he will not pay' me the 43 drachmai. I beg you therefore, if so it please you, not to suffer me to be wronged by him, but to order Aphthonetos the strategos to write to Serambos that, if my story be true, he is to exact from Ptolemaios according to the edict three times the sum which should have been exacted, or 129 drachmai, and pay this to me; and so through you may I obtain justice. May you prosper.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Edgar CC, JEA 14, 289-291, 1928 -- SB IV 7446 Edgar CC, PMich I, 71, 1931</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
