<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Receipt for repayment of a loan</title>
            <author>Ischyriaina, daughter of Geminus</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">oslo.apis.100</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NoOU)100</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.8.9923</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;8;9923</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;8;9923</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14299</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14299</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Oslo inv. 1046</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Receipt from Ischyriaina to Hero, acknowledging that she has received repayment of a loan.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto, the Verso is blank</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 19.8 x 5.5 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The papyrus is rather mutilated, almost half of the left part being lost. Of the five vertical foldings, four of which are visible, the break is mainly at the middle one, occasionally at the inner left. Along the only horizontal folding, at l.27, it is broken in two. This folding probably marked the middle. Below the last line there is one cm of open space before the papyrus breaks off irregularly.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">40</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The document is written in a clear scribe hand.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0175" notAfter="0176">175-176 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Ptolemais Euergetis, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Caesar Marcus Aurelius Antoninus Augustus Armeniacus Medicus Parthicus Gemanicus Sarmaticus Maximus, emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ischyriaina, daughter of Geminus son of Ischyrion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hero, also called Aia, daughter of Herus, father unknown</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Eutychus, son of Soterichos son of Soterichos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thenapynchis, mother of Ischyriaina</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Ptolemais Euergetis; Arsinoite nome; Herakleopolite nome; Berenikis Aigialou; Themistou meris</term>
               <term>Receipt</term>
               <term>Repayment</term>
               <term>Loan</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>The 16th year of Imperator Caesar Marcus Aurelius Antoninus Augustus Armeniacus Medicus Parthicus Germanicus Sarmaticus Maximus, the ... of the month ... at Ptolemais Euergetis in the Arsinoite nome. Ischyriaina daughter of Geminus son of Ischyrion from the village ... in the Herakleopolite nome, aged about 28, having a scar ... acting with her guardian her husband ... son of the other Geminus son of Herm... aged about 38, having a scar on the little finger of his left hand, acknowledges to Hero also called Aia whose father is unknown, her mother being Herus daughter of ... son of Mallion, aged about 46, having a scar on her left knee, acting with her guardian Eutychus son of Soterichus son of Soterichus, aged about 52(?), with a scar near his right knee, that she has received from her, Hero, from hand to hand 1,800 silver drachmae, of which being for the capital 1,700 dr. which she owed to Ischyriaina and her mother ... also called Thenapynchis, who is dead, in accordance with a contract of loan made through the record office of Berenicis Aigialou in the division of Themistes in the 12th year of Titus Aelius Antoninus, the 8th of the month Payni, which Ischyriaina acknowledges is invalid in every respect, of which the remaining one hundred drachmas are the remaining (sc.drachmas) of the interest, and neither Ischyriaina herself nor another on her behalf shall proceed against Hero or her heirs about the sum which she has received in the aforesaid way or about anything at all up to the present day. ....</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>
               <ref target="http://ub-media.uio.no/OPES/jpg/1046r.jpg">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://ub-media.uio.no/OPES/thumb/1046r.gif"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://ub-media.uio.no/OPES/jpg/1046r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
