<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Wage Account</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">princeton.apis.p95</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NjP)apis.p0095</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.princ.2.54</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0192;2;54</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.princ;2;54</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">25166</idno>
            <idno type="TM">25166</idno>
            <idno type="filename">25166-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">GD 7679</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:26.135223-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>[col. I] . . . Harmieis; . . .; . . .; Hathyr . . .; [l. 5] Harmieis,  fruit-buyer, 2 art. of wheat; Esouris, fruit-buyer, 2 art. of wheat; Athenotoros Kari-, 2 art. of wheat; Mysthas s. of Balanios in; Phaophi and Hathyr, 4 art. of wheat; [l. 10] Aniketos, 6 art. of wheat; for the bread to Phryn-; so that . . . 2 art of wheat; Horion, for irrigation, 2 art. of wheat; Total 20 art. of wheat; [l. 15] Choiak; Harmieis, fruit-buyer, 2 art. of wheat; Esouris, fruit-buyer, 2 art. of wheat; Athenotoros Kar-, 2 art. of wheat; Mysthas s. of Balanios, 2 art. of wheat; [l. 20] Horion, for irrigation, 2 art. of wheat; Total 10 art. of wheat; Tybi;   Harmieis, fruit-buyer, 2 art. of wheat; Esouris, fruit-buyer, 2 art. of wheat; [l. 25] Athenotoros Kari-, 2 art. of wheat; Mysthas s. of Balanios, 2 art. of wheat; Horion, for irrigation, 2 art. of wheat; Total 10 art. of wheat.; Mechir; [l. 30] Harmieis, fruit-buyer, 2 art. of wheat; Esouris, fruit-buyer, 2 art. of wheat; Athenotoros, 2 art. of wheat; Mysthas s. of Balanios, 2 art. of wheat; Total 8 art. of wheat; [l. 35] Phamenoth; Harmieis, fruit-buyer, 2 art. of wheat; Athenotoros Kari-, 2 art. of wheat; Esouris, fruit-buyer; 2 art. of wheat; Mysthas s. of Balanios, 2 art. of wheat; [l. 40] Total 8 art. of wheat. [col. II] Pharmouthi; Harmieis, fruit-buyer, 2 art. of wheat; Esouris, fruit-buyer, 2 art. of wheat; Athenotoros, 2 art. of wheat; [l. 45] Mysthas, s. of Balanios, 2 art. of wheat; to Horion, 1 1/2 1/4 art. of wheat; Total 9 1/2 1/4 art. of wheat; Pachon; for the bread; [l. 50] to Pryn-, 7 art. of wheat; to Horion, 1 1/2 1/4 art. of wheat; Total 8 1/2 1/4 of wheat; from the deposit which [l. 55] Heras gave to me by . . . measurement . . . Total 24 1/2 art. of wheat by the 1/10 measurement for commercial tax equally [l. 60] . . . 94 1/2 1/4 art. of wheat in bronze measured by the administrators.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Princ. II 54 <note>P. J. Sijpesteijn, "Corrections on Some Princeton Papyri," ZPE 68 (1987): 143-148. BL IX, 219-220</note>
               </bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
