<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of a House</title>
            <author>Haryotes, Herodes, and Eutychos, sons of Haryotes; and Haryotes, son of Haryotes alias Sakbelis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1357</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1357</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.288</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">25182</idno>
            <idno type="TM">25182</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;288/289dupl</idno>
            <idno type="filename">25182-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1272</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.110346-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>I, Haryotes, son of Haryotes the elder, my mother being Tapnebtynis, have joined in selling the aforesaid shares, that belong to me, of the aforesaid house and yard and gate with the room above it; and I have received my share of the price and join in the guarantee. And I ordered the document to be drawn up as aforesaid. My wife Tapontos, daughter of Mieus, consents to the sale and agrees not to proceed against it or to bring any claim as aforesaid. I, Haryotes, wrote also for my wife, who is illiterate.;(2nd hand) I, Herodes, also called Orseus, son of Haryotes, my mother being Tapnebtynis, have joined in selling my aforesaid shares of the property and in receiving the price and making the guarantee. And I ordered the document to be drawn up as aforesaid.;(3rd hand) I, Haryotes, son of Haryotes also called Sakbelis, have joined in the sale and in receiving the price and making the guarantee as aforesaid.;(4th hand) I, Eutychos, son of Haryotes, my mother being Tapnebtynis, have joined in selling my aforesaid shares of the aforesaid property and in receiving the price {and in receiving the price} and making the guarantee. And I ordered the document to be drawn up as aforesaid.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 288, 1944</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
