<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of Property</title>
            <author>Onnophris, son of Psenkebkis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1368</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1368</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.307</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">25199</idno>
            <idno type="TM">25199</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;307dupl</idno>
            <idno type="filename">25199-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1283</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.405926-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>I, Onnophris, son of Psenkebkis, my mother being Tamarres, acknowledge that I have sold to Psyphis, son of Psyphis, his mother being Tetosiris, in acordance with this sale from the present day forever, the two shares that belong to me from five shares of house property inherited from my father, consisting of a house that has fallen down and the adjacent courtyards and the old lots and the gate building and the rooms above it and all the appurtenances in Tebtynis near the temple of Isis, common and undivided with respect to my brothers by the same father and to Psyphis, son of Marepkamis, and to Nebtynis, son of Psyphis. The neighbors of the old house that has fallen down are on the south the house of the sons of Psyphis, son of Thothis, on the north the house of the aforesaid Psyphis, son of Marepkamis, on the west the aforesaid adjacent lots, on the east the lots of Lysimachos, son of Lysimachos. And the neighbors of the adjacent courtyards and lots are on the south and north and west the royal roads, on the east the aforesaid old house and in part the house and court of Psyphis, son of Marepkamis, and in part the house and court and lots of the aforesaid sons of Psyphis, son of Thothis. And I have received from Psyphis the entire price agreed upon, in full, immediately, from hand to hand, out of the house, and I guarantee the sale with every guarantee from both public and private debts and from every claim forever. My wife Tetosiris, daughter of Psyphis, her mother being Thaubastis, consents to the sale and agrees not to proceed against it forever or bring any claim and that no one else shall in her behalf as aforesaid. Dionysios, son of Mares, wrote for them because they are illiterate.;(2nd hand) Psyphis, son of Psyphis, my mother being Tetosiris. The sale was made to me as aforesaid.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 307, 1944</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
