<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of Part of a Building Site</title>
            <author>Mieus and Herakles, sons of Harmiysis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1359</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1359</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.301</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">25194</idno>
            <idno type="TM">25194</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;301_302dupl</idno>
            <idno type="filename">25194-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1274</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.123011-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>We, Mieus and Herakles, both sons of Harmiysis, our mother being Taarpaesis, and the wife of Mieus, Tapnebtynis, daughter of Psonsneus, her mother being Taarmiysis, acknowledge that we, Mieus and Herakles, have sold, in accordance with the Egyptian contracts, to Psonsneus, son of Orseus, his mother being Tapesouris, the share that belongs to us by inheritance from our father, of the vacant lot, that is partly walled in, and all the appurtenances common and undivided, in Tebtynis in the division of Polemon. The measurements of the whole vacant lot are from south to north eight ells, from west to east five ells, up to as many as there may be. The neighbors are on the south the open space of the temple of the god Herakles Kallinikos, on the north the house of Mieus, son of Kouthis, on the west the house of the purchaser Psonsneus, on the east the house of Panther and in part the common entrance and exit. And we have received from the purchaser, at once, from hand to hand, out of the house, the entire price agreed upon, in full, and we guarantee with every guarantee forever. I, Tapnebtynis, the aforesaid wife of Mieus, consent to the sale and agree not to proceed against it and that no one else shall in my behalf forever, and that I shall not bring any claim. And we shall do the other things and agree to them as aforesaid. Marepsemis, son of Marepsemis, wrote for them because they are illiterate.;;;Mieus, about 48 years old, with a scar on his face to the right. Herakles, about 30 years old, with a scar on his left cheek. Tapnebtynis, about 45 years old, with a scar on his face to the left, under the hair.;Psosneus, about 50 years old, with a scar on the small finger of his left hand.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 301, 1944 -- L. 1: read Tapneoitoinis instead of Tabneoitoinis (PH)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
