<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of Part of a Courtyard</title>
            <author>Psenobastis alias Chales, son of Thebaios</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1366</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1366</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.306</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;306</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;306</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">25198</idno>
            <idno type="TM">25198</idno>
            <idno type="filename">25198-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1281</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.376825-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>I, Psenobastis, also called Chales, son of Thebaios, my mother being Tageleus, acknowledge that I have sold to Labesis, son of Labesis, his mother being Arsinoe, from the courtyard that belongs to me, three cubits on the east side of the court, within the wall that is in it, extending ten cubits five palaistai from south to north, and on the south side of the same court an area six and two-thirds cubits from south to north, eight cubits five palaistai from west to east, to the total number of cubits, measured with the carpenter's standard wooden cubit; the neighbors being on the south the house of Herakles, son of Aphrodisios, and in part the house of Papnebtynis, son of Paanouphis, on the north the lots of the seller, Chales, on the west the house of Papnebtynis, son of Paanouphis, and in part the lots of the said Chales, on the east the lots of the purchaser, Labesis. And I have received from Labesis the total price agreed upon, in full, from hand to hand, out of the house, and I guarantee the sale with every guarantee from public debts and every impost. My wife Taarmiysis, daughter of Harmiysis, and Orsenouphis(?), son of Orsenouphis, and his wife Thermouthis, daughter of Mersis, consent to the sale and agree not to proceed against it or bring any claim, ad that no one else shall in their behalf, as aforesaid. Eutychos the elder, son of Eutychos, wrote for them because they are illiterate.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 306, 1944</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
