<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of a House and Courtyard</title>
            <author>Phasos, son of Phasos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3100</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3100</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.300</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;300</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;300</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">25193</idno>
            <idno type="TM">25193</idno>
            <idno type="filename">25193-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 731</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.312901-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>I, Phasos, son of Phasos, son of Pious, my mother being Thasos, acknowledge that I have sold, in accordance with the Egyptian contracts, to Orsenouphis, son of Horouanchious, his mother being Tacheos, the one-story house that belongs to me, and the courtyard and all the appurtenances, in Tebtynis, the measurements of which are from south to north seventeen cubits, from west to east nine cubits, to the total number of cubits, as many as there may be, more or less. The neighbors of the house and court are on the south the house of Nepheros the tinsmith, on the north the royal road, on the west the house of Orsenouphis, son of Pios, on the east the house of Anesouris, son of Phasos, and in part the house of Harmiysis, son of Alimes. And I have received from Orsenouphis the entire price agreed upon, in full, from hand to hand, out of the house, and I guarantee the sale with every guarantee. My children, Harmiysis and Thaesis and Thenpasos, the three children of Phasos, with the guardian of Thaesis, the aforesaid Harmiysis, and of Thenpasos, her husband Apsemis, son of Psonsneus, and the wife of my dead son Phasos, Thaubastis, daughter of . . ., with her guardian, her own son, Orsenouphis, son of Phasos, consent to the sale and agree not to proceed against it forever, and not to bring any claim, and that no one else shall in their behalf forever. Harmiysis, [son of - - -], wrote for them [because] they are illiterate.;(2nd hand?) Orsenouphis, son of Horouanchious, my mother being Tacheos. [The sale] was made to me [as aforesaid].  Mar[- - -, son of - - -,] wrote for him [- - -].</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 300, 1944</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
