<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>petition</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2917</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2917</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.5.8010</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;5;8010</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;5;8010</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">25305</idno>
            <idno type="TM">25305</idno>
            <idno type="filename">25305-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 6659</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.160864-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>"To Tiberius Claudius Kronios, the Neokoroi of the great Sarapis of Tiberius Claudius . . . , to the priest,  the exegetes  and to the Caesarians and the other prytaneis.;From A..., daughter of Ptolemaios . . . acting with the assistance of Apollonios, son of Theonites . . .  of Ammonios . . . against my husband Aristeas, son of Isidoros from the phyle of Eirenophylakeia and the deme Eusebios; . . . about the fact that I have completed the divorce from my husband with him according to a settlement through the record office in Mecheir of the present year. [I am also . . .about the fact] that I am to receive the dowry which I brought along to him in the shape of clothes evaluated at around 300 silver drachmas and gold jewelry of the weight of 10.5 tetartoi as well as the other objects brought as dowry and named in the settlement after proportion of the other agreements, which according to normal procedure are to be added; that I, apart from the fact that I acquire these objects, so that I can keep them with me until I marry  another man. Furthernore, it has also been written in the settlement, which I attach, concerning my son Aristeas, who is still a baby, that he remains with me but acquires clothing and provisions from Aristeas: I am now prevented [to enjoy my rights of the settlement], since I cannot use Arsiteas as my guardian, because I have divorced him, since my son is a minor, since I do not have other children, and I simply do not have any other [male] relatives. Therefore I beg of You, that the legal guardian will be appointed . . . ."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Wolff HJ, Aegyptus 17, 463-70, 1937 -- SB V 8010 -- BL III, 197 on lines 2,19; BL X, 189 (l. 2; 3; 4); BL XI, 202 (l. 6, 7-8, 29-30) David M-Groningen BA, Papyr Primer 4, 29, 1965</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
