<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Memorandum of Instructions Dealing with Distribution of Oil in Pelousion</title>
            <author>A scribe of the scrinium canonum of the sacrae largitiones</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1550</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1550</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">35626</idno>
            <idno type="TM">35626</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;18;795</idno>
            <idno type="filename">35626-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1936</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.91898-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Recto);;To write a letter to Hypatios, the curialis of the metropolis of Pelousion, to take on as associates Theodosios, the curialis and father (of the city), and Photios, the curialis and n charge of the oil tax, and the supervisors of the taxes(?), and the Tyrians who are currently staying in the metropolis of Pelousion and the village Thylax,; and in the designated place of the city an exact decision should be made on how the oil ought to be distributed to those inhabiting the metropolis of Pelousion, in order that they hold blamelessly the goods for their prosperity and . . . make this clear to the court, because a threat is being stipulated against him and an officer is being dispatched.;;To write a letter to Theodosios, the curialis and father of the metropolis of Pelousion, to fetch all the Tyrians who are currently staying in the metropolis of Pelousion and the village Thylax, to Hypatios the curialis so that in the presence of all those who have been ordered, an eact decision should be made for the sale of the oil, how it ought to be distributed to those inhabiting the metropolis of Pelousion, in order that they hold blamelessly the goods for their prosperity, because a threat is being stipulated against him.;;Revenue department (Scrinium canonum).;;(Verso);;Memorandum.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Gagos T - Burns BE - MacKay C, PMich XVIII, 795, 1996, Pl. XLI --   -- BL XI, 135 (bibliography)</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
