<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Description of document</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <idno type="filename">hgvTEMP</idno>
            <idno type="TM">hgvTEMP</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid"/>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <placeName>
                     <settlement>Alexandria</settlement>
                  </placeName>
                  <collection>The Bishop Payne Library at Virginia Theological Seminary for the General Theological Seminary</collection>
               </msIdentifier>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>
                           <material>Papyrus</material>
                        </support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origPlace>unbekannt</origPlace>
                     <origDate>unbekannt</origDate>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <p>This file encoded to comply with EpiDoc Guidelines and Schema version 8</p>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-05-14T10:37:37-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="principalEdition">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="principal">
                  <title level="s" type="abbreviated">SoSOL</title>
                  <!-- provide meaningful data -->
                  <!-- provide meaningful data -->
                  <!-- provide meaningful data -->
                  <biblScope n="1" type="volume">1</biblScope>
                  <biblScope n="2" type="numbers">2</biblScope>
               </bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="otherPublications">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="1">Aland, Kurt. Repertorium Der Griechischen Christlichen Papyri I: Biblische Papyri Altes Testament, Neues Testament Varia, Apokyrphen. Patristische Texte und Studien, edited by K. Aland and W. Schneemelcher, vol. 18. Berlin: de Gruyter, 1976. Grenfell, Bernard P., and Arthur S. Hunt. The Oxyrhynchus Papyri:Part III. London: Egypt Exporation Fund, 1903.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="2">Becker, Adam H. “2 Baruch.” In Outside the Bible: Ancient Jewish Writings Related to Scripture, edited by Louis H. Feldman, James L. Kugel, and Lawrence H. Schiffman, 1565-1585. Philadelphia: The Jewish Publication Society, 2013.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="3">Boccaccini, Gabriele, and Jason M. Zurawski, eds. Interpreting 4 Ezra and 2 Baruch: International Studies. The Library of Second Temple Studies, edited by Lester L. Grabbe, vol. 87. London: Bloomsbury T&amp;T Clark, 2014.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="4">Bogaert, Pierre-Maurice. Apocalypse de Baruch. Sources Chrétiennes, vol. 144-145. Paris: Éditions du Cerf, 1969.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="5">Brockington, L. H. “The Syriac Apocalypse of Baruch.” In The Apocryphal Old Testament, edited by H. F. D. Sparks, 835–95. Oxford: Oxford University Press, 1984.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="6">Ceriania, Antonius Maria. “Apocalypsis Baruch, olim de graeco in syriacum, et nunc de graeco in latinum translata.” In Monumenta sacra et profana ex codicibus praesertim Bibliothecae Ambrosianae. Milan: Biblotheca Ambrosiana, 1866.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="7">Ceriania, Antonius Maria. “Apocalysis Baruch Syriace.” In Momenta sacra et profana ex codicibus praesertim Bibliothecae Ambrosianae. Milan: Biblotheca Ambrosiana, 1871.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="8">Charlesworth, James Hamilton. “4 Ezra and 2 Baruch: Archaeology and Elusive Answers to Our Perennial Questions.” In Interpreting 4 Ezra and 2 Baruch: International Studies, edited by Gabriele Boccaccini and Jason M. Zurawski, 155-172. The Library of Second Temple Studies, edited by Lester L. Grabbe, vol. 87. London: Bloomsbury T&amp;T Clark, 2014.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="9">Charles, R. H. The Apocalypse of Baruch: Translated from Syriac. London: Adam and Charles Black, 1896.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="10">Dedering, S. “Apocalypse of Baruch.” In The Old Testament in Syriac According to the Peshitta Version, edited by R. J. Bidawid. Leiden: Brill, 1966.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="11">Fabricius, Johan Alberto. Codex Pseudepigraphus Veteris Testamenti. 2nd ed. 2 vols. Hamburg, 1722-1723.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="12">Gurtner, Daniel M. Second Baruch: A Critical Edition of the Syriac Text with Greek and Latin Fragments, English Translation, Introduction, and Concordance. T&amp;T Clark Jewish Christian Texts Series, vol. 5. New York: T&amp;T Clark, 2009.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="13">Haelst, Joseph van. Catalogue des Papyrus Littéraires Juifs et Chrétiens. Śerie Papyrologie, vol. 1. Paris: Publications de la Sorbonne, 1976.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="14">Henze, Matthias. Jewish Apocalypticism in Late First Century Israel: Reading “Second Baruch” in Context. Texte und Studien zum Antiken, vol. 142. Tubingen: Mohr Siebeck, 2011.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="15">Henze, Matthias, and Frank Feder, eds. The Deuterocanonical Scriptures. Textual History of the Bible, edited by Armin Lange, vol. 2B. Leiden: Brill 2019.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="16">Henze, Matthias, and Gabriele Boccaccini, eds. Fourth Ezra and Second Baruch: Reconstruction after the Fall. Supplements to the Journal for the Study of Judaism, edited by Benjamin G. Wright III, vol. 164. Leiden: Brill, 2013.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="17">Henze, Matthias, and Liv Ingeborg Lied. “Jeremiah, Baruch, and Their Books: Three Phases in a Changing Relationship.” In Jeremiah’s Scriptures: Production, Reception, Interaction, and Transformation, edited by Hindy Najman and Konrad Schmid, 330-353. Supplements to the Journal for the Study of Judaism, edited by Benjamin G. Wright III. Leiden: Brill, 2016.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="18">Hobbins, John F. “The Summing Up of History in 2 Baruch.” The Jewish Quarterly Review 89, no. 1-2 (1998): 45-79.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="19">Klijn, A. F. J. “2 (Syriac Apocalypse of) Baruch: A New Translation and Introduction.” In The Old Testament Pseudepigrapha: Apocalyptic Literature and Testaments, edited by James H. Charlesworth, vol. 1, 615-652. Garden City: Doubleday, 1983.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="20">Klijn, A. F. J. “The Syriac Apocalypse of Baruch.” In Outside the Old Testament, edited by M. De Jong., 193-212. Cambridge Commentaries on Writings of the Jewish and Christian World, vol. 4. Cambridge: Cambridge University Press, 1986.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="21">Kmosko, M. “Liber Apocalyseos Baruch filii Neriae translatus de Graeco in Syriacum.” In Patrologia Syriaca, edited by R. L. Graffin, vol. 1.2. Paris: Firmin-Didot, 1907.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="22">Korsvoll, Nils Hallvard, and Liv Ingeborg Lied. “Enoch and Baruch: Unusual Suspects in a Syriac Amulet.” Journal of Near Eastern Studies 75, no. 2 (2016): 349-360.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="23">Korsvoll, Nils Hallvard, Liv Ingeborg Lied, and Jerome Alan Lund. “British Library Additional 14,686: Introduction, List of Readings, and Translations of Colophon and Notes.” Hugoye: Journal of Syriac Studies 19, no. 2 (2016): 385-402.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="24">Leemhuis, Fred. “The Arabic Version of the Apocalypse of Baruch: A Christian Text?” Journal for the Study of Pseudepigrapha 2, no. 4 (1989): 19-26.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="25">Leemhuis, F., A. F. J. Klijn, and G. J. H. Van Gelder, eds. and trans. The Arabic Text of the Apocalypse of Baruch. Leiden: Brill, 1986.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="26">Lied, Liv Ingeborg. “2 Baruch and the Syriac Codex Ambrosianus (7a1): Studying Old Testament Psuedepigrapha in Their Manuscript Context.” Journal for the Study of Pseudepigrapha 26, no. 2. (2016): 67-107.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="27">Lied, Liv Ingeborg. “Baruch, Second Book of.” In T&amp;T Clark Encyclopedia of Second Temple Judaism, edited by Daniel M. Gurtner and Loren T. Stuckenbruck, vol. 1, 121-125. London: T&amp;T Clark, 2020.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="28">Lied, Liv Ingeborg. “Between ‘Text Witness’ and ‘Text on the page’: Trajectories in the History of Editing the Epistle of Baruch.” In Snapshots of Evolving Traditions: Jewish and Christian Manuscript Culture, Textual Fluidity, and New Philology, edited by Liv Ingeborg Lied and Hugo Lundhaug. Texte und Untersuchungen zur Geschichte der altchristlichen Literatur, edited by O. von Gebhardt and A. von Harnack, vol. 175. Berlin: de Gruyter, 2017.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="29">Lied, Liv Ingeborg. “Epistles from Jerusalem: The Paratexts of Syriac 2 Baruch and the Peshitta Jeremiah Corpus.” Religions 13, no. 7 (2022): 591.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="30">Leid, Liv Ingeborg. Invisible Manuscripts: Textual Scholarship and the Survival of 2 Baruch. Studien und Texte zu Antike und Christentum, edited by Liv Ingeborg Lied, Christoph Markschies, Martin Wallraff, and Christian Wildberg, vol. 128. Tübingen: Mohr Siebeck, 2021.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="31">Lied, Liv Ingeborg. The Other Lands of Israel: Imaginations of the Land in 2 Baruch. Supplements to the Journal for the Study of Judaism, edited by John J. Collins, vol. 129. Leiden: Brill, 2008.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="32">Lied, Liv Ingeborg. “Recent Scholarship on 2 Baruch: 2000-2009.” Currents in Biblical Research 9, n. 2 (2011): 238-276.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="33">Lied, Liv Ingeborg. “Response to the Respondents.” Ancient Jew Review (2016), accessed March 20, 2025, https://ancient-jewreview.squarespace.com/read/2022/3/14/response-to-the-respondents?rq=response%20to%20the%20respondents.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="34">Lied, Liv Ingeborg. “What Happened to the Heavenly World When the Righteous Finally Arrived? Transformation, Space and Redemption in 2 Baruch 51.” In Constructions of Space III: Biblical Spatiality and the Sacred, edited by Jorunn Økland, J. Cornelis De Vos, and Karen J. Wenell, 107-122. Library of Hebrew Bible/Old Testament Studies, edited by Claudia V. Camp and Andrew Mein, vol. 540. New York: Bloomsbury T&amp;T Clark, 2016.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="35">Murphy, Frederick James. “The Structure and Meaning of Second Baruch.” PhD dissertation, Harvard University. Atlanta: Scholars Press, 1985.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="36">Nir, Rivkah. The Destruction of Jerusalem and the Idea of Redemption in the Syriac Apocalypse of Baruch. Early Judaism and Its Literature, vol. 20. Atlanta: Society of Biblical Literature, 2003.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="37">Sayler, Gwendolyn Beth. “Covenant in Crisis: Have the Promises Failed? A Literary Analysis of 2 Baruch in Comparison with Related Documents.” PhD dissertation, University of Iowa, 1982.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="38">Stone, Michael E., and Matthias Henze. 4 Ezra and 2 Baruch: Translations, Introductions, and Notes. Minneapolis: Fortress Press, 2013.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="39">Violet, Bruno. Apokalypsen des Esra und des Baruch in deutscher Gestalt: Mit Textvorschlagen fur Esra und Baruch von H. Gressman. GCS, vol. 32. Leipzig: Hinrichs, 1924.</bibl>
               <bibl type="publication" subtype="other" n="40">Whiston, William. A Collection of Authentick Records Belonging to the Old and New Testament Translated into English. London: 1727-1728.</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
