<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Declarations of grain revenue</title>
            <author>Antes</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">berkeley.apis.282</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(CU)282</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.tebt.2.340</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0206;2;340</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.tebt;2;340</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20818 20819</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20818 20819</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Tebt.0340</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Three declarations of grain revenue (in this case, specifically, wheat) from Antes and Thoteos, addressed to Flavius Heracleon, pasted together (tomos sunkollesimos).</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Verso published</note>
                     <note type="general">Part of a tomos sunkollesimos.</note>
                     <note type="general">15th year of the Emperors Septimius Severus and Caracalla, the 6th resp. 9th of the Egyptian month Thoth.</note>
                     <note type="related">Similar, but with different formula and technical vocabulary, to P.Tebt.339.</note>
                     <note type="local_note">3001</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Bancroft Library, Univ. of Calif., Berkeley</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc material="Papyri">
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 33 x 26 cm.</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">3 cols. (ca. 78 lines) on recto along the fibers.</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">On verso, Dictys, Cretensis. Trojan War. Book 4, 9-15.</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Regular much-ligatured cursive.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0206">3 resp. 6 Sept. 206 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Mendesian Nome</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Flavius Heracleon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thoteos</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>House at Tebtunis T341</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Wheat</term>
               <term>Mendesios nomos</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Declarations, Roman Period</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <facsimile>
      <surfaceGrp n="1">
         <surface n="verso">
            <desc>UC 3001 Recto.</desc>
            <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/9d/AP01196a"/>
         </surface>
      </surfaceGrp>
   </facsimile>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>To Flavius Herakleon, strategos of the Mendesian nome, from Antes and Thoteus, grain-receivers of Hermopolis in the Hermopolite toparchy. The summary of the wheat measured to us from the produce of the past 14th year in accordance with the monthly account of Mesore by the collectors of Kellis for the village-dues is eight and a half artabas of unsifted wheat, total 8 1/2 art., which are stored at the granary under the seal of Ammonios, the sealer. Of this summary there are two copies, to be considered as one (?). The 15th year of Imperatores Caesares Lucius Septimius Severus Pius Pertinax Arabicus Adiabenicus Parthicus Optimus and Marcus Aurelius Antoninus Pius Augusti, Thoth 6. We, Antes and Thoteus, grain-receivers, have signed through me, Ammonios, scribe, (for) the eight and a half artabas of wheat, total 8 1/2 art. of wheat. (2nd hand) To Flavius Herakleon, strategos of the Mendesian nome, from Isidoros the younger, designated sitologos of the village of Thchenuth in the Lukopolite toparchy. The summary of the wheat measured to me from the produce of the past 14th year by the collectors of the village of Thchemis of the Lukopolite toparchy, for the village dues through the presbuteroi is fifty four and a quarter artabas of unsifted wheat, total 54 1/4 art. of wheat, which are stored at the granary under the seal of N.N. the sealer. Of this summary there are two copies, to be considered as one (?). The 15th year of Imperatores Caesares Lucius Septimius Severus Pius Pertinax Arabicus Adiabenicus Parthicus Optimus and Marcus Aurelius Antoninus Pius Augusti, Thoth 9. I, Isidoros the younger, have signed (for) the fifty four and a quarter artabas of wheat, total 54 1/4 art. of wheat.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Tebt., II.340</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Tebt.:2:340</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://sunsite.berkeley.edu/cgi-bin/apisdb/record/282">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>