<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter to the Dead</title>
            <author>Heni</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">berkeley.apis.12356</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(CU)12356</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">1966 w. k. simpson, the letter to the dead from the tomb of meru (n3737) at nag' ed-deir. jea 52 (39-52)</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Hearst.1282</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>A letter addressed to the deceased Meru by his son Heni. The letter to Meru contains a complaint that a person named Seni has a malicious influence upon Heni. Heni begs his dead father to prevent Seni from inflicting bad dreams upon him.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Published</note>
                     <note type="general">9th or 10th Egyptian Dynasty. First Imntermediate Period.</note>
                     <note type="general">Verso also bears titles and names written upside down in relation to final line of letter. Folded packet would thus bear Meru's name on one side and Heni's name on the other side. Scene in decorative relief of west wall of tomb chapel of Meru (also known there as ly the Long) shows Meru, his son Heni, and the servant Seni ( see Parkinso 1991: 144). Per Simpson (p. 48), Heni probably father of woman on a stela from Nag' ed-Deir (D.Dunham, Naga ed Der Stelae, 44, no. 31).</note>
                     <note type="local_note">P.Hearst 1282 = 38.2121</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Bancroft Library, Univ. of Calif., Berkeley</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyh">Hieratic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc material="Papyri">
                        <support>papyri ; 24 x 8 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Embrittlement, soiling, discoloration, stains, breaks, losses, and abrasions. Previous and now inactive insect damage.</ab>
                           <ab type="preservation">Needs new label.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">5 columns, on recto. 1 column also bears titles and names, on verso.</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">On recto, writing. On verso, writing.</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Black ink</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="-2160" notAfter="-2025">Between 2160 and 2025 B.C.</origDate>
                     <persName type="asn">Heni, Meru and Seni.</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Nag' ed-Deir N3737, tomb of Meru</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyh">Hieratic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Dreams</term>
               <term>Nag' ed-Deir</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>A servant speaks before his lord; [his son] Heni says: 'Attention a million times! Excellent is (giving) attention to him who makes (funerary) provision for you, about these things which your servant Seni has done, and to this humble servant's being made to see him (Seni) in a dream, in the same city as you. For, look, it was his character which carried himself off. For, look, the things which happened to him could not have happened through the action of this humble servant - that (action) wasn't the sum of all that happened. For, look, it wasn't I who har[med] him]. Others did it before this humble servant. Pray, may his lord be protective, may he be not evil-minded, may one beware of him, until he has failed to watch this humble servant, for eternity! alternative translation of last lines (Szpakowska 2003: 25 [she's an expert on dreams in ancient egypt) ... Please, may his lord be protective, and do not allow him to do harm. May he be guarded in order that he may be done with looking at me, your servant, forever!</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>1958 C. Peck, Some Decorated Tombs of the First Intermediate Period at Naga ed-Der. Dissertation, Brown University. Ann Arbor, MI: University Microfilms. Pl. 13 1966 W. K. Simpson, The Letter to the Dead from the Tomb of Meru (N3737) at Nag' ed-Deir. JEA 52 (39-52) 1969 G. Fecht, Der Totenbrief von Nag' ed-Deir, MDAIK 24: 25-28. 1990 E. Wente, Letters from Ancient Egypt. No. 343 "A Son to his Deceased Father," 212-213. 1991 R. B. Parkinson, Voices from Ancient Egypt. No. 57 "A denial of murder," pp. 143-145. (includes line drawing of scene from Meru's tomb) 2003. K. Szpakowska, Behind Closed Eyes: Dreams &amp; Nightmares in Ancient Egypt. Pp. 24-27. 2010 K. Szpakowska, Nightmares in Ancient Egypt. In J.-M. Husser et R. Mouton (eds), Le Cauchemar dans les Societes Antiques. 24-25.</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">1966 W. K. Simpson, The Letter to the Dead from the Tomb of Meru (N3737) at Nag' ed-Deir. JEA 52 (39-52)</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://sunsite.berkeley.edu/cgi-bin/apisdb/record/12356">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>