<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Settlement of a debt</title>
            <author>Tyrannis, daughter of Sarapion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">berkeley.apis.226</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(CU)226</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.tebt.2.397</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0206;2;397</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.tebt;2;397</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">13553</idno>
            <idno type="TM">13553</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Tebt.0397</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tyrannis acknowledges the repayment of a loan plus interest, by six persons; both Tyrannis and the six persons repaying the debt are in fact heirs of the persons who made the loan in 150 A.D.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Margins: top, 2 cm.; left, 2.2 cm.; bottom, 2.6 cm.; on verso, in black ink: T 703.</note>
                     <note type="general">On verso, two impressions in red of a seal measuring 9 cm. in diameter with portrait heads (of Severus and Caracalla) surrounded by an inscription ("6th year of Lucius Septimius Severus Pertinax Augustus Arabicus Adiabenicus")</note>
                     <note type="general">6th year of the Emperors Septimius Severus and Caracalla, 29th of the Egyptian month Mecheir</note>
                     <note type="related">The text was found in the same pot as P.Tebt.639</note>
                     <note type="local_note">3002</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Bancroft Library, Univ. of Calif., Berkeley</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc material="Papyri">
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 22.8 x 44.8 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">OUT TO PHOTOLAB 10/28/04 PJR</ab>
                           <ab type="preservation">The document is written in lines of great length, and is excellently preserved.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">34 lines, on recto along the fibers.</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">On verso, two impressions in red of a seal</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Five different hands</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0198">23 Feb. 198 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Ptolemais Euergetis</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>House at Tebtunis T703</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Debtor and creditor</term>
               <term>Women, 30 B.C.-640 A.D.</term>
               <term>Arsinoiton polis</term>
               <term>Ptolemais Euergetis</term>
               <term>Tebtunis</term>
               <term>Polemonos meris</term>
               <term>Euhemeria</term>
               <term>Themistou meris</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Contracts, Roman period; Seals (Numismatics)</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <facsimile>
      <surfaceGrp n="1">
         <surface n="recto">
            <desc>Recto</desc>
            <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/bd/AP04399a"/>
            <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/84/AP04399_11_a"/>
            <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/98/AP04399_12_a"/>
         </surface>
      </surfaceGrp>
      <surfaceGrp n="2">
         <surface n="verso">
            <desc>Verso</desc>
         </surface>
      </surfaceGrp>
   </facsimile>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(5th h.) Registered in the 6th year, Mecheir 29: 5 copies were issued, one to each one. (1st h.) The sixth year of Imperator Caesar Lucius Septimius Severus Pius Pertinax Augustus Arabicus Adiabenicus and Marcus Aurelius Antoninus Caesar Augustus Imperator-elect, on the 29th of the month Xandikos or Mecheir, at Ptolemais Euergetis in the Arsinoite nome. Tyrannis daughter of Sarapion, ex-exegetes of Arsinoiton polis, aged about 28 years, with no scar, acting with the guardian whom she has voluntarily chosen through Serenus also called Harpokration, priest and exegetes, according to the notification issued by him, appended to which is the request presented by her, copies of all of which documents are added below,--namely Kronion son of Heron son of Zosimos, of the Treasuries' quarter, aged about 50 years, having a cataract in the left eye, acknowledges to Turbon son of Harpokration son of Herakleides, of the metropolis, aged about 55, having a bent little finger on the left hand, and to Melanous daughter of Harpokration son of Chairemon, of the Syrian quarter, aged about 19, with no distinguishing mark, and to Taopis daughter of Heron son of Paopis, aged about 40, with no distinguishing mark, and to Polion son of Herakleos son of Sarapas, aged about 40, with no distinguishing mark, and to Heraklia, aged about 20, with no distinguishing mark, and to Serenus, aged about 30, with no distinguishing mark, both of them children of Satorneilos son of Tyrannos, all four being from the village of Tebtunis in the division of Polemon, and the women acting each with her guardian, Taopis with Pansoulatis son of Kronion son of Zoilos, aged about 50, with no distinguishing mark, Heraklia with her aforesaid brother Serenus, and Melanous with Kronion son of Heron son of Heron, aged about 35, with no distinguishing mark, that she, the acknowledging party Tyrannis, has received from them from hand to hand 1040 drachmas of silver, being the equivalent of the sum owed by Tourbon's father Harpokration son of Herakleides, and by Satorneilos son of Tyrannos, the father of both Herakleia and Serenus, and by Heron son of Pakysis, the father of Taopis, and by Sarapas, paternal grandfather of Polion, and by Poueris son of Paopis, maternal grandfather of Melanous, together with Orsenouphis, without legal father, his mother being Taorsenouphis, and Protas son of Amis, and Hatres son of Sarapas, and Apynchis son of Orsenouphis, to Tyrannis' deceased father Sarapion, ex-exegetes, in accordance with an agreement made in the 13th year of the deified Aelius Antoninus, on the 8th of the month Mesore, through the record-office of the village of Euhemeria in the division of Themistos; which agreement she has surrendered to them to be annulled and cancelled, because she has forthwith received from hand to hand on account of interest, instead of a larger amount, a sum equal to that above-mentioned, that is, 1040 drachmas, together making 2080 drachmas of silver, paid to the public treasury as price of wheat during the superintendence of supply which Tyrannos also called Diogenes, ex-kosmetes, father of Ptolemaios the husband of the acknowledging party, held in the 17th year of the deified Aelius Antoninus; and that neither Tyrannis herself, who makes the acknowledgement, nor her representatives will proceed against Tourbon and his associates, nor against any one of them, nor against their representatives, nor against those who were joint borrowers with the individuals who have been succeeded by Tourbon and his associates, namely Orsenouphis and the others, because Tourbon and his associates have paid their (Orsenouphis' and the others') share on their own account, or for any other matter whatever, on the basis of any claim, bond or other agreement, written or unwritten, dating from the past down to the present day, in any wise; and that Tyrannis shall herself at her own cost repel any person so proceeding, the fee fixed for the notification (?) having been paid. The copy of the official response is as follows:-- Serenus also called Harpokration, priest, exegetes and archiprytanis, superintendent of the distribution of seed and of supplies, to those in charge of the archives, greeting. A copy of the petition presented to me in the name of Tyrannis is forwarded to you through Demetrios, assistant to the office, in order that if there be no obstacle of any kind you may act with her in the transaction below written, Kronion son of Heron being assigned as her guardian in accordance with her request. Give proper attention to this matter. I pray for your health. The 6th year of Lucius Septimius Severus Pius Pertinax Augustus and Marcus Aurelius Antoninus Caesar Augustus Imperator-elect, Mecheir 27. Copy of the petition:--To Serenus also called Harpokration, priest, exegetes, from Tyrannis daughter of Sarapion, late exegetes of Arsinoiton polis, acting with her guardian, whom I choose voluntarily through you, namely Kronion son of Heron son of Zosimos, from the Treasuries' quarter. I am to receive from Taophis daughter of Heron son of Paopis, and from Polion son of Herakleios son of Sarapas, and from Tourbon son of Harpokration son of Herakleides, and from Herakleia and Serenus, both children of Satorneilos son of Tyrannos, and from Melanous daughter of Harpokration son of Chairemon, from the Syrian quarter, 1040 drachmas of silver from hand to hand, being the equivalent of the sum owed by those whose heirs they are to my father Sarapion aforesaid, and, instead of a larger sum, the like amount as interest, together making 2080 drachmas of silver, and I wish to issue to them a complete discharge, but am prevented through having no assignable guardian, as my husband Ptolemaios with whom I live is away, and my father is no longer living, nor is my grandfather, and I have no brother or son. I therefore choose through you the aforesaid Kronion, and present this petition asking you to instruct those in charge of the archives to act with me in issuing to them the receipt, that so I may obtain relief. The drachmas are being paid to the treasury as the price of what during the superintendence of supply in the seventeenth year held by Tyrannos also called Diogenes, ex-kosmetes of the city of Arsinoe, father of my husband Ptolemaios aforesaid. Read by me (sc. the exegetes). I, Demetrios, assistant of the prytanis and the exegetes, have brought the letter; the same date. (2nd h.) The signatory for the acknowledging party and her guardian, who profess to be illiterate, is Herakleides son of Ptolemaios, aged about 45, having a scar on the left shin. (then follow the signatures)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Tebt., II.397; Lines 1-10; 18-28; 34: Chrest. Mitt., no. 321 <note>On line 11 see BL v. 6, p. 198; on line 18 see BL v. 4, p. 97-98.</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Tebt.:2:397</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://sunsite.berkeley.edu/cgi-bin/apisdb/record/226">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>