<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Official letter from Horos : to the topogrammateis and komogrammateis of the Arsinoite Nome</title>
            <author>Horos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">berkeley.apis.1468</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(CU)1468</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.tebt.1.27</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0206;1;27</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.tebt;1;27</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">3663</idno>
            <idno type="TM">3663</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Tebt.0027 B</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Circular letter from the Horos, royal secretary, to the topogrammateis and komogrammateis (local and village secretaries) of the Arsinoite Nome (modern Fayyum, Egypt) containing copies of correspondence from the dioiketes (finance minister) Eirenaios and ordering the addressees to make a list of the property of a certain Protarchos, who, as apparent from the included letter of the dioiketes, had been malfunctioning.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Margins: top, 2.9 cm.; right, 0.2 cm.</note>
                     <note type="general">4th year of King Ptolemy IX Soter II, 10th of the Egyptian month Mecheir.</note>
                     <note type="general">Menches archive</note>
                     <note type="general">Tomos sunkollesimos.</note>
                     <note type="local_note">1897, 3011, and 3012</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Bancroft Library, Univ. of Calif., Berkeley</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc material="Papyri">
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 30 x 86 cm.</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1 col. (28 lines) on recto along the fibers.</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Verso empty.</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Two different hands, both regular cursives: 1, body of letter (lines 85-111); 2, notice of receipt (line 84).</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="-0113">27 Feb. 113 B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Ptolemais Euergetis?</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Eirenaios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Asklepiades</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Protarchos</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>crocodile cartonnage at Tebtunis 27.31</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Crops</term>
               <term>Tax evasion</term>
               <term>Arsinoites nomos</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Business letters, Ptolemaic period</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(2nd hand) Received in the 4th year, Mecheir 14. (1st hand) Horos to the komogrammateis, greeting. Appended is a copy of the letter from Eirenaios, the king's cousin and dioiketes. Make out therefore a return of the property in your districts belonging to Protarchos, and send it to me with full details (?) by the messenger showing this order, so that the other arrangements may be accomplished in accordance with the instructions. Good-bye. The 4th year, Mecheir 10. Eirenaios to Horos, greeting. Appended is a copy of the letter to Asklepiades. Take care therefore that its directions are followed. The 4th year, Dustros 21, Tubi 21. To Asklepiades. Appended is a copy of the letter to Apollonios. Give good heed therefore that its instructions be carried out. To Apollonios. I have read your letter concerning the case of Protarchos, how after receiving orders from Asklepiades, the overseer of the revenues, to pay down in money the amount owing for the epigraphe in his department, and to behave in a more decorous manner in his house until he should take counsel with himself and provide for the management of the revenues, instead of doing this he sailed downstream to the city in order that owing to the great confusion which would be evinced in the collection of the rest of the debts for the tax, Asklepiades might be careless concerning his affairs. I have therefore duly instructed the officials concerned with such matters so that he may be summoned by proclamation, and, if he does not appear, be proclaimed a defaulter, and I have directed Asklepiades (to seize) his property to meet the debts in his department.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Tebt., I.27, col. IV. <note>On line 89 see BL v. 2.2, p. 169; on lines 101-102 see BL v. 1, p. 423.</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Tebt.:1:27</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://sunsite.berkeley.edu/cgi-bin/apisdb/record/1468">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>