<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Contract</title>
            <author>Thommous, also called Protous, daughter of Petesouchos; granddaughter of Apollonios</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">berkeley.apis.650</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(CU)650</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.tebt.2.380</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0206;2;380</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.tebt;2;380</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">13536</idno>
            <idno type="TM">13536</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Tebt.0380</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>A contract whereby Thommous, daughter of Petesouchos, cedes to her brother Sambas all her prospective rights in the estate of their father, who is still living.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Margins: top, 2 cm.; left, 1.9 cm.; on verso, in black ink: T 524 (twice).</note>
                     <note type="general">13th year of the Emperor Nero, the 21st of the Egyptian month Mecheir.</note>
                     <note type="local_note">1401</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Bancroft Library, Univ. of Calif., Berkeley</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc material="Papyri">
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 24.2 x 10.2 cm.</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">46 lines, on recto along the fibers.</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Verso empty.</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Three different hands, all regular cursives. Hand 1 (lines 1-34), body of contract; Hand 2 (lines 35-44), subscription of first party; Hand 3 (lines 45-46), subscription of second party.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0067">15 Feb. 67 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtunis</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Orseus, Son of Pakebkis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, Son of Petesouchos, Grandson of Apollonios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Lusas, Son of Didymos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Theon, Son of Heron</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>House at Tebtunis T524</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Inheritance and succession</term>
               <term>Brothers</term>
               <term>Daughters</term>
               <term>Sisters</term>
               <term>Tebtunis</term>
               <term>Polemonos meris</term>
               <term>Arsinoites nomos</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Contracts, Roman Period</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <facsimile>
      <surfaceGrp n="1">
         <surface n="recto">
            <desc>Recto.</desc>
            <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/05/AP01772a"/>
         </surface>
      </surfaceGrp>
      <surfaceGrp n="2">
         <surface n="verso">
            <desc>Verso.</desc>
            <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/96/AP01773a"/>
         </surface>
      </surfaceGrp>
   </facsimile>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>The thirteenth year of Imperator Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus, the 21st of the month Xandikos which is the 21st Mecheir, at Tebtunis in the division of Polemon of the Arsinoite nome. Thommous also called Protous, daughter of Petesouchos, aged about 34, having a scar on the outside of her right hand, with her guardian her kinsman Orseus son of Pakebkis, aged about 32, having a scar on the left hand under the thumb, acknowledges to Sambas, her full brother on both father's and mother's side, aged about 37, having a scar at the tip of his right eyebrow, that the acknowledging party, Thommous also called Protous, resigns to Sambas all the property that shall be left by their father Petesouchos son of Apollonios, and that neither she herself, the acknowledging party, nor her representatives will proceed against Sambas on account of any of the property to be left by the aforesaid father Petesouchos. The signatories are, for the acknowledging party and for her appointed guardian, Lusas son of Didumos, aged about 47, having a scar on his left foot, and (for Sambas) Theon son of Heron, aged about 59, having a scar on his right knee. (2nd hand) I, Thommous also called Protous daughter of Petesouchos with my guardian my kinsman Orseus son of Pakebkis, acknowledge that I have resigned to my brother Sambas all property that will be left by our father Petesouchos, son of Apollonios, and that I will not proceed on account of anything and in no ways, like is written above. Lusas, son of Didumos, has written for them because they do not know letters. (3rd hand) I, Sambas son of Petesouchos, the agreement happened for me. (Here the papyrus breaks off.)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Tebt., II.380; Sel. Pap., v. 1, no. 54 <note>On line 31 see BL, v. 8, p. 492.</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Tebt.:2:380</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://sunsite.berkeley.edu/cgi-bin/apisdb/record/650">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>