<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Official letter from Onnophris to Menches</title>
            <author>Onnophris</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">berkeley.apis.6</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(CU)6</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.tebt.1.30</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0206;1;30</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.tebt;1;30</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">3666</idno>
            <idno type="TM">3666</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Tebt.0030</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Onnophris orders Menches to comply with the instructions contained in the included copy of a letter from the Basilikos Grammateus, regarding the administrative processing of a change of ownership of a plot of cleruchic land. The copy of the letter from the Basilikos Grammateus contains copies of all the preceding correspondence.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Margins: top, 2.5 cm.; left, 2.7 cm.; bottom, 4 cm. In the margin, in different hand, notice of receipt. In the top left corner, no. "30" is written in red ink. On verso, along the fibers: Address</note>
                     <note type="general">2nd year of Ptolemy IX Soter II, 28th of the Egyptian month Tybi</note>
                     <note type="general">Menches archive</note>
                     <note type="local_note">3041</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Bancroft Library, Univ. of Calif., Berkeley</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc material="Papyri">
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 22.7 x 31.7 cm.</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1 col. (29 lines) on recto across the fibers.</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Verso, along the fibers: Address</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>2 different hands; 1, memorandum (line 1); 2, body of text (lines 2-29)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="-0115">15 Feb. 115 B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Kerkeosiris?</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonios, son of Poseidonios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymarchos, son of Apollonios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hestieios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menches</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petron, Son of Theon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Polemon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Crocodile cartonnage at Tebtunis 27.21</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Cleruchic land</term>
               <term>Land tenure</term>
               <term>Kerkeosiris</term>
               <term>Polemonos meris</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Business letters, Ptolemaic period</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <facsimile>
      <surfaceGrp n="1">
         <surface n="recto">
            <desc>Recto.</desc>
            <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/b7/AP00469a"/>
            <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/9c/AP00469_11_a"/>
            <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/6f/AP00469_12_a"/>
         </surface>
      </surfaceGrp>
      <surfaceGrp n="2">
         <surface n="verso">
            <desc>Verso.</desc>
            <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/68/AP00920a"/>
            <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/9e/AP00920_11_a"/>
            <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/14/AP00920_12_a"/>
         </surface>
      </surfaceGrp>
   </facsimile>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(2nd h.) Onnophris, 24 arouras, total 24. The 2nd year, Tybi 29. Received in the 2nd year, Tybi 29. (1st h.) Onnophris to Menches, greeting. A copy is appended of the letter of Apollonios son of Poseidonios, Basilikos Grammateus, about the 24 arouras near Kerkeosiris stated to have been ceded to Didymarchos son of Apollonios by Petron son of Theon, in order that you being informed may execute its instructions. Good-bye. 2nd year, Tybi 28. Apollonios son of Poseidonios to Polemon, greeting. Copies are appended of the letter from Ptolemaios and Hestieios, late supervisors of the arrangement of katoikoi, concerning the 24 arouras near Kerkeosiris which they state to have been ceded to Didymarchos son of Apollonios by Petron son of Theon, and of the scribes' report. 2nd year, Tybi 27. Ptolemaios and Hestieios to Apollonios greeting. We have appended a copy of the petition which has been presented to us by Didymarchos son of Apollonios, a Macedonian of the fifth hipparchy of the 100-aroura-men. Since our scribes also have reported that the cession of the 24 arouras has actually been made to him, please order the land to be entered accordingly on your list too under his name. 54th year, Pharmouthi 8. To Ptolemaios and Hestieios, first friends and supervisors of the arrangement (of katoikoi), from Didymarchos son of Apollonios, a Macedonian of the fifth hipparchy of 100-aroura-men. As Petron son of Theon, a Persian of the same hipparchy, has ceded to me his holding of 24 arouras near Kerkeosiris in the division of Polemon, but the scribes being ignorant of this transaction affecting me continue to register the holding under the name of Petron, I beg you to order a letter to be written to Apollonios the Basilikos Grammateus, so that he being informed may register the aforesaid 24 arouras under my name, and I may obtain redress. Farewell. From the scribes. A note having been inserted on the above letter from Ptolemaios and Hestieios, late supervisors of the arrangement of catoecic cavalry-soldiers, about the holding of 24 arouras near Kerkeosiris in the division of Polemon owned by Petron son of Theon, which they write has been ceded by him to Didymarchos son of Apollonios, requesting us to report upon the case, we, on examining the land-register of Kerkeosiris for the 54th year, find him entered in the cleruchy as owning 24 arouras in the land apportioned in the reign of the king's father to the ephodi and as having been transferred to the katoikoi, concerning which land we report that the agents of Hestieios also write saying that is has been ceded to Didymarchos. The 2nd year, Tybi 24.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Tebt., I.30; Chrest. Mitt., no. 24; Chrest. Wilck., no. 233 <note>On line 28 see BL v. 3, p. 240</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Tebt.:1:30</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://sunsite.berkeley.edu/cgi-bin/apisdb/record/6">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>