<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<bibl xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="b96234" type="book" xml:lang="en">
  <pubPlace n="1">Leuven</pubPlace>
  <title level="m" type="main">A Survey of Petitions and Related Documents from Ptolemaic Egypt</title>
  <series>
    <title level="s" type="main">Trismegistos Online Publications Special Series</title>
    <biblScope type="volume">5</biblScope>
  </series>
  <author n="1">
    <forename>Gert</forename>
    <surname>Baetens</surname>
  </author>
  <date>2020</date>
  <ptr target="https://www.trismegistos.org/dl.php?id=18"/>
  <note n="1" resp="#BP">Revised version of a Ph.D. thesis defended in 2017 at KU Leuven. - Introduction. - Chapter I: ἐντεύξεις: Introduction; - 1. Royal ἐντεύξεις with petitioning function; - 2. Non-royal ἐντεύξεις with petitioning function; - 3. Non-royal ἐντεύξεις without petitioning function. - Chapter II: ὑπομνήματα: Introduction; - 1. Early ὑπομνήματα with petitioning function; - 2. Early ὑπομνήματα without petitioning function; - 3. Later ὑπομνήματα with petitioning function; - 4. Later ὑπομνήματα without petitioning function. - Chapter III: other fragmentary Greek petitions: 1. List; - 2. Form; - 3. Content. - Chapter IV: mḳmḳ: Introduction; - 1. mḳmḳ with petitioning function; - 2. mḳmḳ without petitioning function. - Chapter V: synthesis: 1. Form; - 2. Content. - Chapter VI: capita selecta: 1. The relation between the ὑπόμνημα and the προσάγγελμα; - 2. The personal delivery of ἐντεύξεις, ὑπομνήματα and mḳmḳ to their addressee; - 3. The submission of royal ἐντεύξεις to the strategos and chrematistai. - Conclusion. - Bibliography. Sources. - Appendix 1: unpublished ἐντεύξεις and ὑπομνήματα; - Appendix 2: newly published ἐντεύξεις and ὑπομνήματα.</note>
  <idno type="pi">96234</idno>
  <idno type="isbn">978-94-9060-410-3</idno>
  <idno type="bp">2020-0307</idno>
  <seg type="original" subtype="index" resp="#BP">650    690</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="titre" resp="#BP">Gert Baetens, A Survey of Petitions and Related Documents from Ptolemaic Egypt = Trismegistos Online Publications Special Series. 5.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="publication" resp="#BP">Leuven, Trismegistos, 2020, viii-297 pp., figg. ISBN 978-94-9060-410-3.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="resume" resp="#BP">Revised version of a Ph.D. thesis defended in 2017 at KU Leuven. - Introduction. - Chapter I: ἐντεύξεις: Introduction; - 1. Royal ἐντεύξεις with petitioning function; - 2. Non-royal ἐντεύξεις with petitioning function; - 3. Non-royal ἐντεύξεις without petitioning function. - Chapter II: ὑπομνήματα: Introduction; - 1. Early ὑπομνήματα with petitioning function; - 2. Early ὑπομνήματα without petitioning function; - 3. Later ὑπομνήματα with petitioning function; - 4. Later ὑπομνήματα without petitioning function. - Chapter III: other fragmentary Greek petitions: 1. List; - 2. Form; - 3. Content. - Chapter IV: mḳmḳ: Introduction; - 1. mḳmḳ with petitioning function; - 2. mḳmḳ without petitioning function. - Chapter V: synthesis: 1. Form; - 2. Content. - Chapter VI: capita selecta: 1. The relation between the ὑπόμνημα and the προσάγγελμα; - 2. The personal delivery of ἐντεύξεις, ὑπομνήματα and mḳmḳ to their addressee; - 3. The submission of royal ἐντεύξεις to the strategos and chrematistai. - Conclusion. - Bibliography. Sources. - Appendix 1: unpublished ἐντεύξεις and ὑπομνήματα; - Appendix 2: newly published ἐντεύξεις and ὑπομνήματα.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="nom" resp="#BP">Baetens</seg>
</bibl>
