<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<bibl xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="b96333" type="article" subtype="book" xml:lang="en">
  <title level="a" type="main">Photography of papyri and ostraca</title>
  <author n="1">
    <forename>Adam</forename>
    <surname>Bülow-Jacobsen</surname>
  </author>
  <date>2020</date>
  <ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1515/9783110712902-004"/>
  <biblScope type="pp" from="59" to="86">59-86</biblScope>
  <relatedItem type="appearsIn" n="1">
    <bibl>
      <ptr target="https://papyri.info/biblio/96332"/>
      <!-- ignore - start, i.e. SoSOL users may not edit this -->
      <!-- ignore - stop -->
    </bibl>
  </relatedItem>
  <idno type="pi">96333</idno>
  <idno type="bp">2020-0184</idno>
  <seg type="original" subtype="index" resp="#BP">182</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="titre" resp="#BP">Adam Bülow-Jacobsen, Photography of Papyri and Ostraca.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="publication" resp="#BP">Clementina Caputo &amp; Julia Lougovaya (edd.), Using Ostraca in the Ancient World. New Discoveries and Methodologies = Materiale Textkulturen. 32 (Berlin - Boston, 2020) pp. 59-86, figg.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="resume" resp="#BP">1. The problem: 1.1. Types of papyri: normal brownish and carbonized; - 1.2. Types of ostraca: limestone, calcareous clay, brownish clay; - 1.3. Wood, parchment; - 1.4. Types of ink: red, carbon, "mixed", iron-gall; - 1.5. Incised texts: 1.5.1. Wax tablets. - 2. Objectives: what is it we want? - 3. Set-up: 3.1. Staging your object; - 3.2. Copy-stand; - 3.3. Hand-held. - 4. Focusing and exposure: 4.1. Focus and exposure with infrared. - 5. Light: 5.1. Co-axial or angled light; - 5.2. Flash, umbrellas or not; - 5.3. Tungsten; - 5.4. LED, fluorescent tubes, economy bulbs; - 5.5. Daylight; - 5.6. Background: 5.6.1 Light-box? - 5.7. Special Tricks: 5.7.1 Photographing Ostraca Wet or Immersed; - 5.7.2. Diffused light for carbonized papyri; - 5.7.3. RTI; - 5.7.4. DStretch. - 6. Infrared, Red, Color, Blue, UV. - 7. Multispectral. - 8. Cameras and lenses. - 9. After-treatment of IR photographs.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="nom" resp="#BP">Bülow-Jacobsen</seg>
</bibl>
