<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<bibl xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="b96336" type="book" subtype="edited" xml:lang="de">
  <title level="m" type="main">Living the End of Antiquity. Individual Histories from Byzantine to Islamic Egypt</title>
  <series>
    <title level="s" type="main">Studien zu Kultur und Geschichte des ersten Jahrtausends n.Chr. / Studies in the Culture and History of the First Millennium C.E.</title>
    <biblScope type="volume">84</biblScope>
  </series>
  <editor n="1">
    <forename>Sabine R.</forename>
    <surname>Huebner</surname>
  </editor>
  <editor n="2">
    <forename>Eugenio</forename>
    <surname>Garosi</surname>
  </editor>
  <editor n="3">
    <forename>Isabelle</forename>
    <surname>Marthot-Santaniello</surname>
  </editor>
  <editor n="4">
    <forename>Matthias</forename>
    <surname>Müller</surname>
  </editor>
  <editor n="5">
    <forename>Stefanie</forename>
    <surname>Schmidt</surname>
  </editor>
  <editor n="6">
    <forename>Matthias</forename>
    <surname>Stern</surname>
  </editor>
  <date>2020</date>
  <pubPlace>Berlin - Boston</pubPlace>
  <publisher>W. de Gruyter</publisher>
  <note type="pageCount">250</note>
  <note type="prefacePageCount">xiv</note>
  <ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1515/9783110683554"/>
  <idno type="isbn">978-3-11-068331-8</idno>
  <idno type="pi">96336</idno>
  <idno type="bp">2020-0128</idno>
  <seg type="original" subtype="index" resp="#BP">216</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="titre" resp="#BP">Sabine R. Huebner, Eugenio Garosi, Isabelle Marthot-Santaniello, Matthias Müller, Stefanie Schmidt &amp; Matthias Stern (edd.), Living the End of Antiquity. Individual Histories from Byzantine to Islamic Egypt = Studien zu Kultur und Geschichte des ersten Jahrtausends n.Chr. / Studies in the Culture and History of the First Millennium C.E. 84.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="publication" resp="#BP">Berlin - Boston, W. de Gruyter, 2020, xiv-250 pp., figg. ISBN 978-3-11-068331-8. €86,95.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="resume" resp="#BP">Originated in an international conference held at the University of Basel in May 2017. - 15 contributions. - Pp. 1-29: S.R.H., E.G., I.M.-S., M.M., S.S. &amp; M.S., Introduction: Individual Histories From Byzantine to Islamic Egypt: 1. The setting; - 2. Chronology and geography; - 3. Prospects and limitations of the evidence; - 4. Politics and administration; - 5. Social hierarchies; - 6. Law and legal practice; - 7. Religion; - 8. Economy; - 9. Language, literature, and education. - I. Servants to the Rulers, Masters of the Land: Governors, Provincial Authorities, and Great Landowners. - II. Village Authorities and Leading Families at the Intersection of State and Society. - III. Patterns of Daily Life in a Time of Change. - Index of names. Index locorum.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="nom" resp="#BP">Huebner Garosi Marthot-Santaniello Müller Schmidt Stern</seg>
</bibl>
