<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<bibl xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="b96771" type="article" xml:lang="en" subtype="journal">
  <title level="a" type="main">Capital in the Sixth Century: The Dynamics of Tax and Estate in Roman Egypt</title>
  <author n="1">
    <forename>Gilles</forename>
    <surname>Bransbourg</surname>
  </author>
  <date>2016</date>
  <biblScope type="pp" from="305" to="414">305-414</biblScope>
  <relatedItem type="appearsIn" n="1">
    <bibl>
      <ptr target="https://papyri.info/biblio/2134"/>
      <!-- ignore - start, i.e. SoSOL users may not edit this -->
      <!-- ignore - stop -->
    </bibl>
  </relatedItem>
  <biblScope type="issue">9</biblScope>
  <idno type="pi">96771</idno>
  <idno type="bp">2016-0590</idno>
  <seg type="original" subtype="index" resp="#BP">146  630  730</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="titre" resp="#BP">Gilles Bransbourg, Capital in the Sixth Century: The Dynamics of Tax and Estate in Roman Egypt.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="publication" resp="#BP">Journal of Late Antiquity 9 (2016) pp. 305-414, figg.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="resume" resp="#BP">Introduction. - Part 1. The sources: The documentary corpus and the issues at stake; - The main sources. - Part 2. Sixth-century taxation in the Antaeopolite - and possibly elsewhere in Egypt: The structure of sixth-century taxation; - Tax rates; - Further issues; - Tax rates fluctuation in the sixth century. - Part 3. The dynamics of a large estate in the sixth century - the Apiones dossier: The Apiones and the Cynopolite nome; - Embolē rates and transportation fees; - The Apiones' gardens; - The villages whose tax payments were managed by the Apiones; - The area administered by the Apiones for tax purposes; - The Apiones: a house of privilege?; - Adaeration and the Apiones; - Adaeratio and the Apiones "unwanted" grain surplus; - The Apiones' profit equation; - The size of the Apiones estate between the 540s and the 580s; - Agricultural surplus, rent, and tax on the Apiones estates; - The Apiones as (non)entrepreneurs; - Did the end of Justinian's reign witness a "Laffer curve" situation?; - The disposition of agricultural rent; - Maintaining the flow of gold from Egypt in a context of lower taxation; - The uneven rise and fall of the Apiones; - How about the plague? - Conclusion.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="nom" resp="#BP">Bransbourg</seg>
</bibl>
