<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of land</title>
            <author>Aurelia - - -, daughter of Colluthus</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2279</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2279</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.22.15619</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;22;15619</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;22;15619</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">47268</idno>
            <idno type="TM">47268</idno>
            <idno type="filename">47268-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 472</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:26.892392-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>"- - - (I declare to have sold to you) in accordance with this written agreement in one copy, consisting of private land without reed, - - - and all kinds of weeds, my sixth part of vacant lots and the appurtenances and the cistern and all the trees, which belongs to me by inheritance from my deceased Colluthus in the taxing unit of Ereithis - - -, my sixth part, (the neighbours of which are) to the east the inhabitants of Alabastrine, to the west inhabitants of Toou, to the north Apa Hatres the monk, to the south the inhabitants of Toou, (and I declare) that I have received from you on the spot the full price as we have agreed between ourselves, eight gold solidi, = 8 sol., (and I declare) that you may own it and dispose of it from now on forever, and for this reason I made this sale for your security, which is valid and guaranteed, and after formal interrogation I gave my consent.;I, Aurelia - - -, daughter of Colluthus, the aforementioned, have sold you the sixth part that belongs to me of vacant lots and I have received the full price, 8 gold solidi, and all that is written (in this contract) is satisfactory to me. I, Aurelius Aroous from Thelbonthis, have written for her at her request because she is illiterate.";verso: - - - the sixth part</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Gagos T-van Minnen P, JRA 5, 197-200, 1992, Plate -- SB XXII, 15619</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
