<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lease of room</title>
            <author>Aurelius Serenus</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2231</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2231</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.22.15620</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;22;15620</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;22;15620</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">47269</idno>
            <idno type="TM">47269</idno>
            <idno type="filename">47269-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 456</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.740079-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>"In the consulate of Flavius Asclepiodotus and Flavius Marinianus, the most magnificent praefecti of the imperial praetorium in Italy, on Mesore 4 of the present eigth indiction.;Aurelius Serenus also called Pkimis, son of Narous, sailer by profession, from the village of Alabastrine in the Antinoite nome, greets Aurelia Iuliana, daughter of Hymis, from the same village of Alabastrine.;Of my own free will I would like to lease, from the present month of Mesore of the present eighth indiction onwards, one room with two doors situated on the third floor with the appropriate entrance and exit, at an annual rent of a hundred and twenty myriads of denarii a year, which I shall hand over in accordance with this document without protest. The lease is valid and guaranteed and after a being formally interrogated I gave my consent.;I, the aforesaid Aurelius Serenus, hav rented as aforesaid. I, Aurelius - - -, gnoster of the same village of Alabastrine, have written on behalf of the illiterateSerenus at his request and I am witness to the document."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Gagos T-van Minnen P, JRA 5, 200-2, 1992, Plate -- SB XXII, 15620 -- BL XI, 240 (l.1)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
