<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Book of the Dead</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.5425</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)5425</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. OIM 9787</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Undated.  Presented by Martin A. Ryerson.  Dates follow D.B. Redford (ed.), The Oxford Encyclopedia of Ancient Egypt (2001).;Square brackets [ ] denote lost text and lines ; ; indicate uncertain text.  Braces { } denote superfluous words and parentheses ( ) indicate elements supplied, comments or emended text.;There are vignettes associated with BD 16-7, 21, 23-8, 30, 64, 31-3, 35-41, 43, 45, 47, 46, 44, 48, 53, 50, 54-5, 52, 57, 59, 56, 63, 65-6, 68, 71-87, 89, 90, 88, 91-4, 98-9, 95, 100-7, 109-10, 112-5, 119, 116-7, 124-36, 138, 137, 140, 143-62, 191.  Most, if not all, of the vignettes were evidently sketched in ahead of the text, and the latter did not always fit as the artist had planned.  (Allen p. 19);BD 16 is a vignette only; everything that preceded it is lost.  For discussions of similar scenes, see K. Sethe, ''Altaegyptische Vorstellungen vom Lauf der Sonne,'' in Preussische Akademie der Wissenschaften, Philos.-hist. Klasse, Sitzungsberichte, 1928, p. 259-84 and H. Schaefer, ZAS 71 (1935), 15-38.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyh" otherLangs="egy-Egyp">Hieratic; Hieroglyphics</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>10 papyri ; 924.0 cm x 39.0 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The manuscript now starts a little after the beginning of vignette BD 16.  Aside from the initial loss, other damage is slight.  A pointed object had been thrust into the papyrus while it was rolled.  Some seventy holes near the lower edge, gradually decreasing in size toward the end until they cease in BD 148 b, probably represent two thrusts at opposite sides of the roll.  If only one thrust were involved, the roll as we have it would have been just over 3 cm in diameter; but its 924 cm length could scarcely have been rolled into such small compass.  (P. OIM 10486 is only 1/9 as long, but formed a roll about 6.4 cm in diameter when purchased.)  But P. Ryerson could not be checked directly, for it was already mounted in ten frames.  At both beginning and end, it had also been broken across in four places each, and there are minor breaks elsewhere.  (Allen p. 16)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">On recto: 157 columns in hieratic, 3 columns in hieroglyphics</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto: Book of the Dead</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The hieratic signs, when checked against G. Moeller, Hieratische Palaeographie III (1912), show forms varying from the 20th dynasty to about A.D. 60.  In selection and arrangement of spells, P. Ryerson is most similar to L 3079 (de Rouge, 1861-76, pls. V-XX), both having unusual additions.  They share strange writings and even errors, e.g. in BD 64 (cf. especially its S 12 f. and 15).  Hence they probably go back to a common ancestral manuscript.  Similarities with T (Lepsius, 1842) are also numerous.  Hieroglyphics occur only in BD 110b, 125d, 148b, 161S, 191-2, and the final offering formulas.  A note in demotic is added below BD 140.  All of the writing is in black.  The vignettes are colored in red, light and dark blue, green, yellow, brown, and white.  R, then, differs from Ptolemaic copies of BD.  The latter, as Daressy has mentioned, are generally written in crowded hieratic, with vignettes merely sketched in black, sometimes set off by a little red.  The scribe wrote with a consistent and steady hand.  He evidently checked his work, for the corrections are largely his.  But another, more angular hand has interlined name, etc. of deceased here and there (especially col. c) and made occasional other additions (cf. col. cxlviii).  The artist who did the vignettes was presumably a different person.  His work shows a good feeling for form, yet sometimes there is squattiness of figure (cf. overlapping scepter-bearers in col. liv) or unevenness of line (cf. kilt of deceased in cols. xxxix and xli).  (Allen p. 19)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="-0525" notAfter="-0031">VIth - Ist century B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Osiris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Unnofer</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Atum</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Re</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Shu</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Min</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Isis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nephthys</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Authority</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Perception</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Seth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thoth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Imset</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hapi</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Duamutef</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Qebehsenuf</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Whom His Father Sees</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Is Under His Moringa Tree</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horus with No Eyes in His Forehead</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anubis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Asdez</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dozer</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Bull Who Gives No Glow from His Hot Breath</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Observant One in His Prime</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Sees by Night Him Whom He Carried Off by Day</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tefnut</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Geb</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Carried Off His Portion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Shezmew</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nefertem</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Bastet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khepri</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Swallower of Millions</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Keen One</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Baba</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Master of His Affairs</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sokar</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ruty</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptah</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Uto</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Amon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Suty</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Upwawet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Baby</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nut</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sekhmet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tatenen</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phoenix</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">the Disk</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menkaure</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hardedef</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Soped</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Selqet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Rerek</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Neit</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hathor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khnum</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apophis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Is Over the Colors</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Sees Millions of Years Twice</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Imperishables</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ihy</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Inundation</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Seshat</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Baby</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sothis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Rekem</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Remrem</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Akhezzef</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tayt</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khonsu</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sobk</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Bibi</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ash</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Akhkhew</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menqet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harakhte</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sesha</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hotep</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpocrates</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Akhem</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Renenutet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Truth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Fate</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Luck</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Spirit of Contentment</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Blessed One</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Magician</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khasety</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Wenty</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sutekh</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Montu</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">the Deep</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Zepa</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horus Khentekhtai</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onuris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aachbyt</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Adjen</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Adj</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ned</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Born of the Two Lips</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sound of Mouth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Opener of the Ways</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Clear</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Asb</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hurler of the Two Knives</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Feller of Fish</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">The Offering Descends</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heh</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ded</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mut</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyh">Hieratic</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyp">Hieroglyphics</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Heracleopolis; Hermopolis; Heliopolis; Maat-lake; Rosetau; Naref; Abydos; Field of Rushes; Mendes; Busiris; Letopolis; Punt; Kheraha; Pe; Dep; Washerman's Shores; Memphis; Aqa-reach; Field of Offerings; Wednet; Turah; Khemmis; Ishru; Xois; Upper Egypt; Lower Egypt; Debew; Athribis; Qenqenet; Hetepet; City of the Great One; the Peaceful; Anet-wadj-wer; the Verdant; Djefat; Hezat; the Powerful; the United; Anpet; Hierakonpolis; Matat; Akhmim; Wenes; Bubastis; Fayyum; City of the Two Truths; Pomegranate; Xoite nome; Weryt; Sais; Wenes; Nedjfet; Atef; Asyut; Antaeopolis; Egypt; Sebeg; Bahbit; Aswan; Ra-antywy; 'Apret; Zekret; the Overflow; Nedit; Pesegro; Atef-wer; Shenew; Hekenew; Shaw; Peqer; Heni; Bedshew; Tayt; Sia; Siatyw; Lake Land; Pelusium; Qawyt;Ass-region; She Keeps Silence; Adew-abode; Elephantine; Heqehqed</term>
               <term>Funerary</term>
               <term>Religion</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. OIM 9787, recto: (i) (BD 16) (ii) (BD 17)Spells for extolling the blessed one and ascending (from) and descending into the god's beautiful domain.  Being in the retinue of Osiris, being satisfied with the viands of Unnofer justified.  Going forth by day, assuming any form into which one may desire to change, playing chess, being in the twin halls, (since) the living Soul of Osiris N. is worthy in the presence of the great Ennead in the west after his mooring.  It goes well with him who has recited them on earth.  (Let) the statement be addressed (to the lord) of all mankind.  (1)To be said by N.: I am Atum, who made the sky and created what exists while I existed alone in the deep.  I am Re (2)at his dawning as Ruler at the beginning of his reign.  What is the meaning of ''{it is} Re at his dawning as Ruler'' and ''{it is} the beginning of his reign''?  It means that Re began dawning in Heracleopolis (3)as one who existed before the uplifted of Shu and the deep had come into being, while he was on the mound that is in Hermopolis, after he had annihilated the children of the feeble one?s? on the mound{s} in Hermopolis.  I am (4)the great god who came into being of himself, That means the water, i.e., the deep, the father of the gods.  What is the meaning of ''the great god who came into being of himself''?  It means Re, i.e., the deep, the father of the gods.  Variant: (5)it means Re. who created his names as lord of the Ennead.  What does that mean?  It means Re, who created his body; (thus) came into being these gods who are in the train of Re.  I am one who is not kept away from the gods.  (6)What does that mean?  It means Atum who is in the Disk, the god.  Variant: it means Re in his Disk, when he rises in the eastern horizon of the sky.  I am yesterday and I know the morrow.  (7)What does that mean?  ''Yesterday'' means Osiris, ''the morrow'' means Re, on that day wherein the transgressors against the Lord of the Universe were annihilated and he was entrusted to his son Horus--(8)variant: on that day (of) the festival (called) We Abide, i.e., when burial of Osiris was ordered by his father Re.  The fighting of the gods was done for him according to his command, (that of) Osiris the lord of the western desert.  What (9)does that mean?  It means the west.  It was made for the Souls of the gods ''according to his command, (that of) Osiris the lord of the western desert.''  Variant: it means the west, i.e., this to which Re caused every god to descend; then (10)he fought in its behalf.  I know that great god who is therein.  Who, pray, is he?  He is Osiris.  Variant: his name is Praiser of Re; his name is Soul of Re.  (11)He copulates with himself.  I am that great phoenix that is in Heliopolis; I am the examiner of what exists.  What does that mean?  ''The Phoenix'' means Osiris who is (12)in Heliopolis.  ''The examiner of what exists'' means (his) corpse.  Variant: it means endless recurrence and changelessness.  ''Endless recurrence'' means day; ''changelessness'' means night.  I am Min (13)at his goings forth.  He has put his twin plumes on his head.  What does that mean?  ''Min'' means Horus who saved his father Osiris.  ''His goings forth'' means his births.  As for ''his twin plumes on his head,'' (14)Isis and Nephthys went, they put (their wings) around him, since they were hawks, while it remained on his head.  Variant: they are the great large twin uraei that are on the brow (15)of his Father Atum.  Variant: ''his twin plumes on his head'' are his eyes.  I exist in the earth, having come from my city.  What does that mean?  It means the horizon of my Father Atum.  Removed is my (16)wrong(doing), done away with is my evil.  What does that mean?  It means that the navel cord of Osiris N. was cut.  (17)All the evil that adhered to him has been removed.  What does that mean?  Osiris N. was cleansed on the day he was born in the two great (18)large ponds that are in Heracleopolis, the day when the common folk make offerings (to) that great god who is therein.  What does that mean?  Guide of Millions is the name of one (pond); the Sea is the name of the other.  (19)Those are the natron lake and yonder ar--variant: Maa(t) lake.  Variant: Begetter of Millions is the name of one; the Sea is the name of the other.  And as for ''that great god who is therein,'' (20)that means Re himself.  I go on a road that I know toward the Pool of the Two Truths.  What does that mean?  As for Rosetau, it is the south gate (of) Naref and the (21)north gate of the abode of Osiris; and ''the Pool of the Two Truths'' is Abydos.  Variant: it means the road on which his Father Atum goes when he proceeds to the Fields of Rushes.  (22)He arrives at the horizon land and enters the gate of the sacred region.  What does that mean?  It means the Field of Rushes, which bore food for the gods around (23)the shrine.  As for ''the sacred gate,'' it is the gate of the uplifted of Shu.  As for ''the north gate,'' it is the gate of the nether world.  Variant: that means the twin leaves of the door (24)through which his Father Atum proceeds when he proceeds to the eastern horizon of the sky.  (O) Ancestors, give me your hands.  It is I, who came into being through you.  Whom (25)does that mean?  They are the drops of blood that dripped from the phallus of Re when he set about cutting himself.  Then they became gods, i.e., those that are before Re.  (26)They are Authority and Perception, who are in the train of their Father Atum daily.  Osiris this N. filled out (27)the Sound Eye after its crushing on that day when the Two Comrades fought.  What does that mean?  It means the day when Horus fought Seth, when he (28)injured the face of Horus and Horus snatched away Seth's testicles.  Now it was Thoth who did this with his own fingers.  Osiris N. (lifted) (29)the hair ?away from? the Sound Eye at (its) time of raging.  What does that mean?  That right eye of Re when it was raging against him after (30)he sent it forth.  Now it was Thoth who lifted its hair.  He brought it (back) to life, soundness, and health, (so that) it was not remiss toward its Lord.  Variant: it means that his eye was sick while it was weeping for its mate.  (31)Then Thoth spat upon it.  Osiris N. sees that Re who was born yesterday from the buttock(s) of the (32)Great Flood.  If Osiris N. prospers, he prospers, and vice versa.  What does that mean?  It means these waters (of) the sky.  (33)Variant: it means the image of the eye of Re, born early every day.  Now [as for] ''the Great Flood,'' [it is] the Sound Eye of Re.  For I am one of these gods who are in (iii) the train of Horus, one whose utterances are in behalf of all his desire.  Whom does that mean?  Imset, Hapi, Duamutef, and Qebehsenuf.  Hail to you, gods, lords of Truth, Council around (2)Osiris, who inspire terror in sinners, (ye) who are in the train of Hetep.s-khew.s.  Behold, I am come unto you that ye may remove all the evil that adheres to me, just as ye (did) (for) (3)those seven blessed ones who were in the retinue of their Lord the Examiner and whose seat(s) Anubis prepared on that day (called) Come Thou to Us.  What does that mean?  As for these ''gods, lords of truth,'' (4)they are Thoth and Asdez the lord of the west.  As for the ''Council around Osiris,'' these are Imset, Hapi, Duamutef, and Qebehsenuf, who are back of the Great Bear (5)in the northern sky.  As for them ''who inspire terror in sinners, (them) who are in the train of Hetep.s-khew.s, they are the Crocodiles that are in the water.  As for Hetep.s-khew.s, she is the eye (6)of Re.  Variant: she is the fire (that is) in the train of Osiris, consuming the souls of his enemies.  And as for ''all the evil that adheres to me,'' (that means) what he was doing (am)ong the lord(s) of endless recurrence since he descended from the womb of his mother.  (7)And as for ''those seven blessed ones,'' (they are) Imset, Hapi, Duamutef, Qebehsenuf, He Whom His Father Sees, He Who Is Under His Moringa Tree, and Horus with No Eyes in His Forehead.  Anubis made them the magical protection of the burial (8)of Osiris--variant: the magical protection of the tomb of Osiris.  Variant: as for ''those seven blessed ones,'' (they are) Nedjeh-nedjeh, Dozer, Bull Who Gives No Glow from His Hot Breath, (9)?Observant One in His Prime?, Red-eyed One in the House of Bright Red Linen, Face-afire Who Came Forth Backward, and He Who Sees by Night Him Whom He Carried Off by Day.  And as for (the head of) the Council of Naref, ?his greatness (belongs) to? (10)his Father Re.  As for ''that day (called) Come Thou to Us,'' it means that Osiris said to Re: ''Come, pray, that I may see thee,'' when Re was keeping (him) away from the west.  I am his Soul dwelling in his Twin Progeny.  Whom does that mean?  (11)It means Osiris when he entered Mendes.  He found the Soul of Re there.  Then they embraced each other there.  Then his Soul became one ''dwelling in his Twin Progeny.''  ?Now as for? ''his twin progeny,'' they are Horus who saved his Father and (12)Horus with No Eyes in His Forehead.  Variant: as for the ''Soul dwelling in his Twin Progeny,'' it means the Soul of Re, it means the Soul of Osiris, it means the Soul of Shu and the Soul of Tefnut, it means the Souls that are in Busiris.  I am (13)that big cat that split the ashed-trees beside him in Heliopolis on that night of battle and guarding the rebels, on that day wherein the enemies of the Lord of the Universe were annihilated.  What (14)does that mean?  ''That big cat'' is Re himself.  He is called Cat because Perception said: ''He is such in this that he has done.'' Thus his [name] of Cat originated.  Variant: it means when Shu was drawing (15)wills for Geb and Osiris.  And as for ''him who [split] the ashed-trees besides him in Heliopolis,'' it means when the children of the feeble ones were (trying to) justify their action.  As for ''that night of (16)battle,'' it means when they forced their way into the east of the sky.  Then a great battle took place within the whole earth.  O Re in his egg, shining in his Disk, rising in his Horizon, float(17)ing on his metallic expanse, (thou) whose abomination is sin, rowing on the uplifted of Shu, without his equal among the gods, causing a breeze by the scorching breath of his mouth, illumining the Two Lands with (18)his sunshine, mayest thou rescue Osiris N. from that great god mysterious of form whose eyebrows are the arms of the bal(19)ance on that night of reckoning with the (female) Robber, Who, pray, is he?  He is He Who ?Carried Off His Portion?.  As for ''that night of reckoning with the (female) Robber,'' that is the night (of) fire and fallen ones.  (20)who lassos sin(ner)s (and hauls them) to (his) slaughtering-block which does away with Souls.  Who, pray, is he?  He is Shezmew; he is the mutilator of Osiris.  Variant: he is the zep-serpent; he possesses one head (21)bearing truth.  Variant: he is a falcon; he possesses two heads--one bears truth, the other, falsehood--which give fal[sehood to] him who practices it and Truth (to) him who comes bearing it.  Variant: he is Horus presiding over Letopolis.  (22)Variant: (he is) Thoth.  Variant: he is Nefertem the son of Bastet.  It is the Council that punishes the enemies of the Lord of the Universe.  Rescue ye Osiris N. (23)from these ?torturers?, the Slaughterers, sharp-fingered, cruel at beheading, from whose guarding there is no escape, who are in the train (24)of Osiris.  They shall not prevail over me, I will not fall (prey) to their kettle(s), for I know him, I know the name of that Smiter who is among them (25)in the house of Osiris, who shoots (rays) with his eye while he is unseen, who surrounds the sky for himself with the flame of his mouth.  He announces the inundation while it is (still) unseen.  Osiris N. (26)was sound of utterance on earth in the presence of Re, and he shall moor auspiciously in the presence of Osiris.  Offerings shall not be made out of me [for] those in charge of their brazier(s), for he (27)is a Follower of the Lord of the Universe in the books of Khepri.  Osiris N. flies as a falcon, he honks as a sem(28)en-goose.  He shall not perish forever, like Neheb-ka.  Who, pray, is he?  He is Anubis; he is Horus with No Eyes in His Forehead--variant: he is Horus of the court.  Variant: (it is) the Council for warding off (29)the enemies of the Lord of the Universe.  Variant: he is the chief physician of the court.  They shall not rage at me, I will not fall (prey) to their kettle(s).  Whom does that mean?  It means these (30)''who are in charge of their brazier(s).'' They are the image of the eye of Re and the image of the eye of Horus.  O lord of the Great House, Sovereign of the gods, mayest thou rescue Osiris N. (31)from that god whose face is (that of) a greyhound (but) whose eyebrows are (those of) a man and he lives on sacrifices.  He is the one who is at the bend of the lake of fire, who swallows corpses, who ste(32)als hearts, who attacks corpses without his being seen.  Who, pray, is he?  Swallower of Millions is his name; he exists in the lake of Punt.  And as for ''the lake of fire,'' (it is) the one that (extends) from (iv) (1)Naref to the court.  Everyone who treads on it while unclean succumbs to the sword.  Variant: his name is the Keen One; he is the doorkeeper of (2){of} the west.  Variant: his name is Baba; it is he who guards that bend of the west.  Variant: (3)his name is Master of His Affair(s).  O lord of terror, supreme over the Two Lands, lord of blood, whose slaughtering-block thrives, who lives on viscera, Who, pray, is (4)he?  He is the heart of Osiris; it is he who is in all carnage. to whom were given the Upper Egyptian crown and gladness of heart in (5)Heracleopolis, Who, pray, is he?  He ''to whom were given the Upper Egyptian crown and gladness of heart within Heracleopolis'' (6)is Osiris. to whom was assigned rule over the gods on that day when the Two Lands were established in the presence of the Lord of the Universe, Who, pray, is he (7)''to whom was assigned rule over the gods''?  He is Horus the son of Osiris, whom he caused to rule in place of his Father Osiris.  As for (8)''that day when the Two Lands were established,'' it was when the Two Lands united to bury Osiris. blameless Soul in Heracleopolis, who gives (9)nourishment and does away with sin and to whom leads the way of endless recurrence, Who, pray, is he?  That is Re himself. mayest thou rescue Osiris N. (10)from that god who carries off Souls, who gulps down hearts, (11)who lives on carrion, who is attached to darkness and is in Sokar, of whom a feeble one is afraid.  Who, pray, is he?  He is Seth.  (12)Variant: ''the wild bull'' is Horus the son of Geb.  O Khepri dwelling in his Bark, Primeval One as to his own body--variant: (whose body is) changeless, (13)mayest thou rescue Osiris N. from these {it} Examiners (14){Baboons} to whom the lord gave the radiant eye (in) order to guard his enemies, (Examiners) who {he} cause terror in the place of execution and from (15)whose guarding there is no escape.  I shall not go down among their knive(s), I shall not come to their slaughtering-block, I shall not languish within (16)their throne, I shall not go down within their slaughtering-block, I shall not dwell within their concealment, and offerings of these (17)abominations of the gods will not be made to me, for I am the Hereditary Prince in the great broad hall.  Osiris N., (18)he is one who passes (in safety), a pure one dwelling in ?the place of smiting?, to whom are given suppers of the fayence that is in the Tchennet-sanctuary.  What (19)does that mean?  As for ''Khepri dwelling in his Bark,'' that is Re-Harakhte himself.  As for ''these Examiners,'' they are the Two Baboons, (or) (20)they are Isis and Nephthys.  As for ''these abominations of the gods,'' they are accounts, they are {his} lying.  As for ''one who passes (in safety), a pure one dwelling (21)in ?the place of smiting?,'' that is Anubis, since he is in charge of the chest that contains the viscera of Osiris.  As for him ''to whom are given suppers of fay(22)ence in the Tchennet-sanctuary,'' sky and earth are meant.  (23)Variant: it means when Shu crushed the lands as Ruler of Heracleopolis.  As for ''fayence,'' that means the eye of Horus.  As for ''the Tchennet-sanctuary,'' it is the throne (24)of Osiris.  Thy house is being built, (O) Atum; thy dwelling is being founded, (O) Ruty.  (O) Ptah, turn around, turn around, ?return?.  (25)(If) Horus becomes pure, Seth becomes divine, and vice versa.  Osiris N. has come into this land; (26)he has taken possession with his feet.  He is Atum; he is in his city.  Back, Lion w with white mouth and (flattened) head!  Yield to the might of Osiris presiding over the westerners; (27)yield to the might of Osiris N.  ''Thou who keepest watch without being seen, (28)watch (me) not,'' says Osiris N.  Isis is his.  When thou hast found him, he lets (29)his hair down (over) his face in disorder so that it is mussed at the mouth of his road--variant: his pate.  He conceives through Isis, he begets through Nephthys.  Isis does away with (30)all his evil; Nephthys puts an end to his troubles.  Dread is behind him, awe is before him.  Millions bend their arms to me, (31)the common folk appeal to me.  The herd executes for me (my) enemies; the gray-haired ones bare their arms to me.  (32)It is granted me to smell the sweetness which they who are in Kheraha and they who are in Heliopolis create for me.  Every god is afraid of me because of the greatness of (33)dread of me and the vastness of awe of me.  I have saved every god from his (de)tractor; I have shot until he escapes.  I live as I will, (for) (34)I am Uto, (lady of) the devouring (flames).  If they ascend to me, few of them (reach me).  What does that mean?  Mysterious of Form, Whom (35)Amon Gives, is (the name) of the trap.  He Who Sees at Once What He Carried Off is the name (of) the storm cloud--variant: the name of (the pit).  As for the ''Lion with white mouth and flattened (36)head,'' that is the phallus of Osiris--variant: that is the phallus of Re.  As for ''he lets his hair down (over) his face in disorder so that it is mussed at the mouth of his pate,'' (37)it means when Isis was hiding herself.  Then she wipe(d) her hair ?into? her face.  As for ''Uto, (lady of) the devouring (flames),'' that means the eye of Re.  As for ''if (38)they [ascend] (to me), {they} few of them (reach me),'' it means when Suty's gang was approaching them, since it was a ?searing? approach.  He [has been appoint]ed (39)as examiner of the inhabitants of Mendes and mutilator of the souls of his enemies.  (v - a) (i) (BD 18)O Thoth who didst vindicate Osiris against his enemies, vindicate Osiris N. against his enemies as thou didst vindicate Osiris against (5)his enemies before the great Council that includes Re, before the great Council that includes (7)Osiris, before the great Council who are in Heliopolis on that night (of) offerings on the altar, on (9)that day of fighting and of guarding the rebels, on that day wherein the enemies of the Lord of the Universe were annihilated.  As for ''the (12)great Council who are in Heliopolis,'' they are Atum, Shu, and Tefnut.  As for ''guarding (14)the rebels,'' the companions of Seth were annihilated in that (day) in requital of the harm they had done.  (vi - a) (1)O Thoth who didst vindicate Osiris against his enemies, vindicate Osiris N. against his enemies (...) before the (5)great Council who are in Mendes on that night (of) erecting the djed-pillar in Mendes.  As for (7)''the great Council who are in Mendes,'' (they are) Osiris, Isis, Nephthys, and Horus who saved (9)his Father.  As for ''erecting the djed-pillar in Mendes,'' that means the upper arm of Osiris (11)presiding over Letopolis.  They were around Osiris like a strip of clothing.  (vii - a) (1)O Thoth who didst vindicate Osiris against his enemies, vindicate Osiris N. against his enemies as thou didst vindicate (Osiris) against (6)his enemies before the great Council who are in Letopolis on (8)that night (of) altar-offerings in Letopolis.  As for ''the (10)great Council who are in Letopolis,'' they are Horus who is in Letopolis and (12)Thoth who is in the Council (of) Naref.  As for (14)''that night of altar-offerings in Letopolis,'' it was the dawn (16)of the burial of Osiris the lord of the west.  (viii - a) (1)O Thoth who didst vindicate Osiris against his enemies, vindicate Osiris N. against (5)his enemies as thou didst vindicate Osiris against his enemies before the great Council (7)who are in Pe and Dep on that night (of) erecting the sanctuary of Horus and confirming the (9)inheritance to Horus, namely the possessions of his Father Osiris.  (10)As for ''the great Council who are in Pe and Dep,'' they are Horus, Isis, (12)Imset, and Hapi.  As for ''erecting the sanctuary of Horus,'' that means when Seth said (14)to his retinue: ''Establish a sanctuary against it.''  (ix - a) (1)O Thoth who didst vindicate Osiris against his enemies, vindicate Osiris N. against (5)his enemies as thou didst vindicate Osiris against his enemies before the great Council (7)who are in Washerman's Shores on that night (when) Isis lay (9)awake, mourning over her brother Osiris.  As for (11)''the great Council who are in Washerman's Shores,'' they are Isis, Horus, (13)and Imset.  (v - b) (1)O Thoth who didst vindicate Osiris against his enemies, vindicate Osiris N. against (his) enemies as thou didst vindicate Osiris (5)against his enemies before the great Council who are in Abydos on that night of (7)the haker-feast at the counting of the dead, at the stocktaking of the blessed, when dancing took place (9)at the counting of the dead.  As for ''the great Council who are in Abydos,'' (11)they are Osiris, Isis, Nephthys, and Upwawet.  (vi - b) (1)O Thoth who didst vindicate Osiris against his enemies, vindicate Osiris N. against his enemies (5)as thou didst vindicate Osiris against his enemies before the great Council who are in (7)the roads of the dead on that night of taking stock of the nobodies.  (9)As for ''the great Council who are in the roads of the dead,'' they are Thoth, Osiris, (11)Anubis, and Asdez.  As for the ''stocktaking of the nobodies,'' (13)that was when offerings were barred from the souls of the children of the feeble ones.  (vii -b) (1)O Thoth who didst vindicate Osiris against his enemies, vindicate Osiris N. against his enemies (5)as thou didst vindicate Osiris against his enemies before the great Council who were at (7)the great earth-hoeing in Mendes on that night of earth-hoeing with blood and (9)vindicating Osiris against his enemies.  (10)As for ''the great Council who were at the great earth-hoeing in Mendes,'' they are Thoth, Osiris, Anubis, and Upwawet.  (13)It was when the companions of Seth came, having assumed the form (15)of ?goats?.  Then they were slaughtered before {these} those gods, since (17)blood would issue from them, and were assigned to the inhabitants of Mendes.  (viii - b) (1)O Thoth who didst vindicate Osiris against his enemies, vindicate Osiris N. against his enemies (...) before the (5)great Council who are in Naref on that night of the great mystery as to form.  (7)As for ''the great Council who are in Naref,'' they are Re, Osiris, (9)Shu, and Baby.  As for ''that night (of) the great mystery as to form,'' (11)they were burying the arms and thighs and chest of Osiris-Unnofer justified forever.  (ix - b) (1)O Thoth who didst vindicate Osiris against his enemies, vindicate Osiris N. against his enemies (5)as thou didst vindicate Osiris against his enemies before the great Council who are in (7)Rosetau on that night (when) Anubis put his hands on the offerings around (9)Osiris and Horus was vindicated against his enemies.  (10)As for ''the great Council who are in Rosetau,'' they are Osiris, Isis, (12)and Horus.  The heart of Osiris is happy, the heart of Horus is happy, while the two sanctuaries are (14)content therewith.  Verily Thoth comes and vindicates Osiris N. (16)against his enemies before the great Council of every god and every goddess (and) before the Lord of the Universe.  He does away with the enemy of Osiris N.; (18)[he] does away with all the evil that adheres to him.  If this purifying spell is uttered, it assures going forth by day [af]ter mooring (20)by a man and assuming any form at will.  And if this spell is read in his behalf, it means that he prospers on earth, he escapes from (22)every fire, and nothing evil befalls him.  A truly excellent spell (proved) a million times.  (x) (1)(BD 19)Spell for wreaths of vindication.  To be said by Osiris N.: (2)Thy Father Atum binds for thee this beautiful wreath of vindication on this thy brow.  Live; (for) (4)the gods desire that thou live forever.  Osiris presiding over the westerners has vindicated thee against thy enemies.  (5)Thy Father Geb assigns to thee his whole inheritance.  Come!  Praise be to thee as one vindicated, (O) Horus the son of Isis and son of Osiris on the throne of thy Father Re, overthrowing (7)thy enemies.  He assigns to thee the whole of the Two Lands; he assigns to thee the whole of the Two Lands.  Atum has assigned and the Ennead has confirmed the two regions of beauty to the vindicated one, Horus the son of Isis and son of Osiris, (9)forever and ever, (even) Osiris N.  Osiris presiding over the westerners, both sanctuaries of the gods together, and every god and (11)every goddess who is in the sky and in the earth are vindicating Horus the son of Isis and the son of Osiris against his enemies before Osiris presiding over the westerners, are vindicating Osiris N. (13)against his enemies before Osiris presiding over the westerners, Unnofer justified, the son of Nut, on that day (15)of vindicating him against Seth and his companions before the great Council who are in Heliopolis on that night of fighting and overthrowing the rebels, (17)before the great Council who are in Abydos on that night of vindicating Osiris against his enemies and vindicating Osiris N. (19)against his enemies before the great Council who are in the western horizon on that night of the haker-feast, before the (21)great Council who are in Mendes on that night of erecting the djed-pillar in Mendes, before the great Council who are in the roads of the dead on (23)that night of taking stock of the nobodies, before the great Council who are in Letopolis on that night of offerings on the altars (25)in Letopolis, before the great Council who are in Pe and Dep on that night of confirming the inheritance to Horus, namely the possessions of his Father (27)Osiris, before the great Council who are at the great earth-hoeing in Abydos on that night of dismissing grief, before the great Council (29)who are in Naref from his place on that night when Horus received the domicile of the gods, before the great Council who are in Washerman's Shores on (31)that night when Isis lay awake, mourning over her Brother, (and) before the great Council who are in Rosetau (33)on that night of vindicating Osiris against his enemies.  Horus has repeated praise four times, for (all) his enemies are fallen, overthrown and slain.  (35)Osiris N. has repeated praise four times, for all his enemies are fallen, overthrown and slain.  (37)Horus the son of Isis and the son of Osiris has repeated millions of jubilees, for all his enemies are fallen, overthrown and slain.  They have been carried off to (39)the place of execution, the slaughtering-block of the easterners.  They have been decapitated, they have been strangled, their arm(s) have been cut off, their heart(s) have been removed.  They have been given (to the Great) Annihilator (41)in the valley; they shall never escape from the custody of Geb.  If this spell is uttered over wreaths put on a man's head, after thou hast offered (43)burnt incense to Osiris N., there is brought about his vindication against his enemies, whether he be dead or alive; and he shall be {to be said} (45)a follower of Osiris, while a cake, a jar, and a loaf are given him before this god.  Say (it) over thee early, twice, (for) it is a great protection.  A truly excellent spell (proved) a million times.  (xi) (1)(BD 20)Another spell for wreaths of vindication.  (2)O Thoth, vindicate Osiris N. against his enemies as thou didst vindicate Osiris against his enemies before the (5)great Council who are in Heliopolis on that night (of) fighting and overthrowing the rebels.  (vertical) O Thoth, vindicate Osiris N. against his enemies as thou didst vindicate Osiris against his enemy before the great Council (7)that is in Mendes on that night of erecting the djed-pillar in Mendes, (9)that is in Letopolis on that night of offerings on the altars in Letopolis, (11)that is in Pe and Dep on that night of confirming the inheritance to Horus, namely the possessions of his father Osiris, (13)that is in Washerman's Shores on that night of the mourning that Isis made over her brother Osiris, (15)that is in Rosetau on that night of vindicating Osiris against his enemies, (17)that is in Abydos on that night (of) dancing (at) the counting of the dead, (19)that is in the roads of the dead on that night of taking stock of the nobodies, (21)that is at the great earth-hoeing in Mendes on that night of being content therewith (23)before the Council of Re, before the Council of Osiris, (25)before the Council that is in the sky and (the one) that is in the earth, (26)before the Council of every god and every goddess.  (27)If a man recites this spell and purifies himself with natron-water, it assures going forth after mooring (29)and assuming any form at will.  It assures escape from the fire.  A truly excellent spell (proved) a million times.  (xii) (BD 21)Spell for giving a man's mouth to him in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: Hail to thee, Osiris, lord of light, (5)presiding over the Great House, dwelling in darkness.  (7)I have come unto thee, a pure blessed one; my arms are around thee.  I am (9){I am} (come) to thee, thy doorkeeper, and thy chiefs.  May he give him his mouth, that he may speak (11)therewith.  Mayest thou guide his heart at his hour of danger.  (13)(BD 22)Another spell for giving a man's mouth to him in {in} the god's domain.  To be said by (15)Osiris N.: I rise from the egg that is in the hidden land.  (19)My mouth has been given to me, that I may speak therewith while I am before the great Council and before the great god the lord of the netherworld.  (22)I shall ?not? be kept away from before the Council of every god and (every) goddess, (for) I am (24)Osiris the lord of Rosetau, that is, this (god) who is at the top of the terrace.  (27)I have come; I accomplish my heart's desire in the day of fire.  (29)I quench the fire when it breaks out.  (xiii) (BD 23)Spell for opening a man's mouth for him in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: My mouth has been opened by Ptah; (5)the bond of my mouth has been loosed by Amon, the god in my city, since I have come from my mother's womb.  (8)Thoth comes fully equipped with his magic; he looses the bond ?for? Atum.  (10)It is Seth who comes against me as he wards off Atum, who attacks him who comes against me.  (12)My mouth has been parted by Ptah with that metal chisel of his with which the mouth(s) of the gods were parted.  I am Sekhmet; I sit (16)at the starboard side, (I) the great one of the sky.  My mouth ?(is that of)? Osiris (18)presiding over the westerners.  I am Orion, the great one dwelling among the Souls of Heliopolis.  As for all the magic and (21)all the statements which he has thought, however, to recite against me, stand, (O) Ennead, bring magic (23)against them, (O) Ennead as a whole.  (xiv) (BD 24)Spell for bringing a man('s) magic to him in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: I am Khepri, (4)who came into being of himself (on) the lap of his mother, who gave (jackals) to (6)those who are in the Deep and the Phoenix (to) those who are in the Council.  Lo, (9)this magic has been assembled for me from every place where it was, from that man (11)with whom it was, (faster) than greyhounds, quicker (than) a shadow--variant: from (13)Shu.  O ferry-bringer, may thy towline hold firm in the flood (15)when thou proceedest upstream to the Pool of Flame in the god's domain.  Lo, (17)thou hast assembled this magic (for) Osiris N., scattered, from (21)every place where it was, from this man with whom it was, (faster) than greyhounds, quicker than a shadow.  (24)As this which the gods created out of silence, (26)a cry has been given to the new-bird to warm the mouth(s) of the gods.  This magic of his has been given (to) Osiris N. from this man (32)with whom it was, (faster) than greyhounds, quicker than a shadow--(34)variant: ?from the light? of the majesty of Shu.  (xv) (BD 25)Spell for giving a man's memory to him in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: I have caused (5)a man to remember my spell in the Upper Egyptian shrine and a man to remember (7)my spell in the Lower Egyptian shrine in front of the Ennead on that night (9)of counting the years and numbering the months in the house of (11)that fashioner who sits in the great place of (13)the sky.  As for every god who shall not come in the train of Osiris N., (16)(I) will tell his name thereafter.  (xvi) (BD 26)Spell for giving a man('s) heart to him in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: I have my heart in the house of hearts; (5)I have my breast in the house of breasts.  (7)My heart has been given me; it is content with me.  I shall not eat sand beside Osiris on (10)yonder east side of the Bowl when I am gone downstream or upstream.  I do not go down (13)to the resting-place that is with thee.  My mouth has been given me to speak (with), my feet to walk (with).  (16)My hands have been given me to overthrow my enemies.  Opened (18)for me are sky and earth.  Geb the hereditary prince of the gods opens for me (20)my jaws and my mouth.  He opens for me my eyes when I am blind, (22)he straightens my crooked arms.  Anubis strengthens my knees; yea, I have arisen (25)that I may run.  I stretch as the goddess Sekhmet, and the sky is opened for me.  I perform what is commanded me in Memphis.  (28)I know with my mind, I control my breast.  (30)I control my hands, I control my feet.  I do what my Spirit desires.  (33)My Soul shall not be kept from my corpse at the gates of the west forever (35)and ever.  (xvii) (BD 27)Spell for not letting a man's heart be taken away in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: O (ye) who seize hearts and tear out (5)breasts, whose hands fashion the heart of Osiris N. for him through what is done (9)against him, lo, may he not fail to know through you of what ye are doing.  Hail to you, (11)ye lords of endless recurrence and establishers of changelessness.  (12)Seize not my heart with your fingers in this year (or) in this month; (14)seize not this heart.  May ye not make up your mind(s) on the basis of (16)any evil words (spoken) against me, for as for this heart of mine it is (18)the great heart that is in the Ogdoad.  The great god whose words are in the members (20)of him, he sends (his) heart out of his body, that my heart may become more inventive than (those of) the gods.  I have my heart; I control (23)it forever.  (It shall) not tell (what I have done).  I myself control my body.  My heart obeys me when I say: (26)''I am thy Lord while thou art in my body.  Thou shalt not oppose me, for I am (28)one whom thou hast been commanded to obey in the god's domain.''  (xviii) (BD 28)Spell for not letting a man's breast be taken away from him in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: O Lion, mine are the blossoms; (5)the god's slaughtering-block is (my) abomination.  My heart shall not be taken away from me, (O) Elders, (7)at the festival of Thoth by the fighters in Heliopolis.  O crushers (9)of Osiris the presider over the westerners, I have seen Seth, (the cutthroats)--(11)variant: he who turned aside--being in his train.  He who smote him, he causes destruction.  (13)This breast of mine sits, having wept for (it)self before Osiris.  (15)My strength is with me.  I ask it of myself, and I have granted it.  (17)Osiris presiding over the westerners has assigned Osiris N. (20)to the hot of heart in the seat of the Broad-faced Ones.  (22)Sand has been presented to me at the entrance to the Aqa-reach (of the Nile).  This heart of mine shall not be seized.  (24)I am one whose seat ye advance, (binding) breasts to him (26)in the Field of Offerings.  The years of my power are (against) all his abomination.  (28)O god, lord of necks, thou takest away food as thy possession in thy grasp because of (30)thy might.  Thy hands are with them that are in thy train.  This breast of mine pays (32)homage to Atum (when) he leads me to the den of Seth without (34)its being given to Osiris presiding over the westerners.  This breast is your Spirit--(36)this keen breast of mine.  I subjugate my heart in the Council in the god's domain.  (xix) (1)(BD 29)Spell for not letting a man's heart be taken away from him in the god's domain.  To be said (5)by Osiris N.: (10)Back, Messenger of every god!  Hast thou come to seize this (my) breast of the living?  (16)May this my heart (of) the living not be given to thee; may the gods not bar your offerings from me.  (22)(Then) they fall at my (feet) on their face(s), they themselves having ceased to exist in this land.  (xx) (BD 30)Spell for not letting a man's breast be kept away from him in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)My heart of my mother, my heart of my mother, my breast that I had on earth, rise not against me as witness, oppose me not in the Council.  (7)Weigh not (heavy) against me before the Gods; weigh not heavy against me before the great God the lord of the west.  Hail to (10)thee, thou heart of Osiris presiding over the westerners; hail to thee, viscus.  Hail to you, ye Gods who preside over (13)the tressed one(s) and grip your scepter(s).  Tell ye the good (deeds) of Osiris (15)N.; commend ye (him) to Neheb-ka.  Though (18)I have been interred (at) the west side of the sky, may I continue on earth, (20)that I die not in the west (but) become a blessed one therein unto endless recurrence.  To be said (22)on a scarab of nephrite ?set in? and adorned with gold and put in place of a man's heart.  There shall have been performed for him (24)the opening of the mouth, it (the scarab) being anointed with prime oil.  To be said on it as a charm: (25)My heart of my mother, my heart of my mother, my breast of my being, rise not against me as witness, oppose me not in the Council.  Weigh not heavy against me before the keeper of the (28)balance.  Thou art my Spirit in my body, Khnum who preserves my flesh, now that I am gone forth to the goodly place (30)whence we (have) come.  Make not my name to stink in the presence of the Council who create man in his time in the goodly place (32)of hearing gladness and of conducting trials.  Tell no lie against me in the presence of the great god.  Behold, thy reputation is (at stake).  (xxi) (1)(BD 64)Knowing the spells for going forth by day in a single spell.  To be said by Osiris N.: I am yesterday, and I know the dawn of (2)tomorrow, (being) in charge of its birth on another occasion.  (I am) the Hidden of Souls who made the gods, who puts the Westerners to rest in (3)the west of the Sky, steersman in the east, Two-faced One (seen by) his rays, cloud-lord who came forth from the twilight, (4)whose manifestation is in the house of the sky.  O (ye) falcons, the two Horuses who preside over their tribunal, who hear cases (5)?presented orally?, while the foreleg is bound on the neck, the rump on top of the head of the west, who guide the dead to (their) (6)tombs, who draw Re as (their) follower (in) his great seat, heart of the (divine) dwelling that is above the sky, the throne-owner, who stands as the reliance (7)of the earth, I am he, and vice versa.  I made the glaze which Ptah fused upon his metal.  (O) Re, thou laughest, thy heart (8)rejoicing over thy goodly (truth) of this day.  Enter into the Nether Sky, come forth from the east, (thou) whom the First-born summons and the Ancestors adore.  Make pleasant for me thy ways; make (9)broad for me thy paths.  When thou crossest the earth to the breadth of the sky, thy light is upon me, (O) sou(l of) three.  As I approach the god, say in my ears, (O thou) who hearest in the nether world, (10)(that) no sins of my mother's are (held) against me.  Rescue thou me, protect thou me, from him who closes his eyes in the evening, who ?veils? Atum in darkness.  I am the flood; (11)Great Black Water is my Name in the temple.  My outside envelops me inside it.  O thou Great One without a channel, summon those who are in the rushes at the hour of carrying (12)the god.  Say, pray, to him who is in charge of his (flood): ''Behold, the foreleg of the god is bound for him on the neck, the rump on top of the head of the west.''  (I) have had him who was in (thee, O thou) greater of the two great (goddesses), (13)put into me.  I weep at seeing you.  (When) I sail from the embankment at Abydos, (O ye) bolts, come to rest at the gate face down.  Thy arms are within thee, (14)thy face is (that of) a greyhound, as thou sniffest at the shrine whence I propel my feet (as) Anubis (when) I withdraw from the resting-place of Tatenen to (that of) Ruty.  Preserve thou me, (for) (15)I am one who has gone forth as smasher of the door, (I am) the light which his heart made.  I Know the Water-Dwellers is my name.  I provide for the {his} needs of the blessed, who number 3,(16)300,000 with 1200 of everything, (for) I am in charge of their possessions, ?so that they are sup(plied at the proper)? hour(s) on the day of investigating the bearers of Orion.  (Each bearer) is (1/12)of the passing (day) (17)as a whole, (as) one of them gives (place) to another.  (One-)six(th) preside over the nether world; they are the hour(s) of overthrowing the impious ones and of {my} returning therefrom triumphant.  Now it is these that are in (18)the aperture of the nether world; it is these that are with myself as ?twin? of Shu.  I have risen as lord of life, the goodly triumphant one of this day, in whose ascent are seven steps.  (19)My protection is the magical protection of the blessed (whose) blood is cool, (whose) wound(s) are fresh, and who have joined the earth.  The two horns have been parted by my commands, the mysterious of form by my approach.  (20)(O ye) who (crawl) upon your bellies, I have come by order of the lord of terror to do homage to Osiris.  Let the eye swallow its tear(s).  I am the (offering-)bringer in the house (21)of ?him who is abundantly supplied?.  I have come from Letopolis to Heliopolis to tell the Phoenix about the nether world.  O (silent land) wherein are mysteries, creating Form(s) like Khepri, (22)cause thou that I ascend as the Disk at the ascent of the sunshine, which I set apart in the west of the sky and which illumines the blessed in the keep, that I shine as one set free (23)at the mouth of the twin caves.  I (have) pass(ed) into the sky, I have trod upon the metallic expanse.  (I,) the Great One, hold the sunshine aloft above my eyes as the light; I soar on (24)the rays of Brilliance.  My form is (that of) Re (rather than of) common folk, and I tramp on the tails of the snakes that (dwell) in this land.  O stabber (who drivest away) (25)the shadows of the blessed who are in the sacred land, mayest thou give (me) a good road through the gates of the nether world, (for) I am acting in behalf of him who is exhausted to reconstitute him (after taking his remains) from the water.  (26)I have reconstituted him who was in tears; that is, I have rescued him from the hidden ones who are yonder, the silent one(s).  (O) realm of the dead, open for me the keep.  Mayest thou give me a good road, that I may pass.  (27)(Who, pray,) is he whom he would devour in the west?  I am the presider over Rosetau.  I entered in his name; I went forth as a favored one, lord of the millions of earth, who had made his (own) name.  (28)I became weary and have put down my burdens.  The Musicians (gave me birth before) them that walk head downward.  Sealed was the door through this wall overturned by my hand.  I have revived him who had fallen (29)on his back, the phoenix whom the dwellers in their hall adore.  To Horus his eye has been given, that his face may become bright at dawn.  His name is my name; there is none higher (30)than I.  (My) form is (that of) the Lion; the equipment of Shu is with me; I am nephrite.  (How) good it is to see the mooring of the Weary-hearted One, (when he has alighted) in the ?reedy stream?.  Behold, I have ascended; I am (31)possessor of life.  I praise the deep; I am life.  I have ascended; I have offered praise at the entrance of the sacred abode.  (O) Osiris, mayest thou protect me from want; (O) Osiris, I am thy property (32)on earth.  I have embraced the sycamores, and the sycamores (have) shelter(ed me).  Opened for me is the Nether World; I have come, I have alighted on the Sound Eye.  (O) my (Soul), where, pray, art thou (on) the first day (of the lunar month) (33)while my corpse is silent, not speaking?  I have come to see him who is in his coiled uraeus (face) to face and eye to eye.  The wind rises as he ascends, and weariness ?shows? in my face.  Headdress-(34)Wearers, give me your hands, offspring who came forth from the mouth, Dawnings of the eye of Re, that I may stand.  (O) reassemblers, may I soar to the sky, may I alight on the earth, (every day).  (35)I want--variant: I embrace--my eye yonder in (attendance on) me.  I am the Creator, the child of yesterday, who fashions form(s).  (O) earth-god, deliver (me) at the (proper) time, for I am one whom the Fighter who banished the Swathed One (has) hidden away.  (36)Follow me.  (My) magic is the preserver of my flesh; my spells are the magical protection of my limbs at this time.  It depends on (37)my advice, and the Ennead relies on what I say.  (O) Lion, even Re, who liftest up him that is in Wednet, thou art I, and I am thou.  My manifestation is thy manifestation; thy form is my form.  I am (38)the Flood; Great Black Water is my name.  My manifestation is become (that of) Khepri; the herbage of Atum (attaches) to me.  I enter into Letopolis; I go forth in blessedness.  I am truly (39)Osiris, and I behold thy human form forever.  As for the silent one who knows this spell, he ascends and descends in the god's domain, he does all that the living do.  It is the great(est) protection of (40)the great God.  This spell was found in Hermopolis on a brick of the ore of Upper Egypt, written in real lapis lazuli, under the feet of this god in the time of the Majesty of the king of Upper and Lower Egypt, Menka(u)re, (41)by the King's son Hardedef when he was going about to inspect the temples, ?a (military) force? being with him.  He obtained (it) by pouring out (largess) and brought it as a desideratum to (42)the King when he saw that it was a foreigner's secret, unseen and unheard.  One who recites this spell (must be) pure and spotless, without coming near any abomination of a pure man.  Lo, there shall have been made for him (43)a scarab of nephrite ?set (in)? and adorned with gold, and there shall have been performed for him the (ritual of) opening of the mouth, it (the scarab) being anointed with prime oil--variant: myrrh--and put inside his body on the day of interment.  To be said on it as a charm: (44)''My heart of (my) Mother, my heart of (my) Mother, my breast (...).  (xxii) (BD 31)Spell for driving off crocodiles that come to take a man's magic away from him in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)Back!  Give way!  Back, ?bloated one?!  Come not against me, (for) I live on my magic, lest I tell (5)this (thy) name to the great god who lets thee come.  Messenger is the name of one; Baboon is the name of the other.  Thy face is (turned) to the breeze--(7)variant: Truth; the sky conjures thee in its hour.  {I} My magic conjures away his lies; I have conjured (9)my mouth with my magic which (I) have eaten.  My teeth are of flint; my teeth are of the Viper Mountain.  O seated one (11)who illumines himself with the eye which is this magic of mine, mayest thou not (let) yonder crocodile who lives on his magic take it away.  (13)I am the bull presiding over his fields.  I am truly Osiris, to whom his Father Geb and his Mother Nut were sealed (15)on that day (of) making the great slaughter.  My Father is Geb, my Mother is Nut.  I am Horus the Elder on the day (17)of festival; I am Anubis on the day of the Centipede.  I am truly Osiris.  (O) Elder God, enter and tell the collector of writings, (19)the doorkeeper of Osiris, that I am come blessed, esteemed, and powerful.  I have come, (21)(for) I have saved my own body.  I have sat on that resting-place of Osiris, for I am (re)born with him.  I am a youth, (23)(I am a youth).  I bared that thigh which was under the side of Osiris, with which I opened the mouth(s) of the gods.  (25)I have sat beside him as scribe of the sound-hearted one.  1000 of bread and 1000 of beer from the offering table of (my) Father Osiris (and 1000)of spotted cow(s), (27)of longhorn(s), of red cows, of ra-geese, and of tcherep-geese (are) what (I) give (to) Horus.  (I make) offerings (to) Thoth; I sacrifice to (29)him who is over ?Turah?, the scribe of the sound-hearted one.  I have contented myself with the offering of the ruler of (Busiris), over (31)whose shores I (wander).  I smell the east wind by its (hair); I grasp the west wind by (its) tresses.  (33)I have circled the sky past its four corners; I (grasp) the south (wind) by its eyelash.  I give breath to the worthy (35)among the eater(s) of bread.  As for one who knows this spell, he goes forth by day, he walks on earth (37)among the living, he perishes not forever.  A truly excellent spell (proved) a million times.  (xxiii) (BD 32)Spell for driving off the four crocodiles that come to take a blessed one's magic away from him in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)The Great One falls on his belly--variant: on his side.  (When) his Ennead has reconstituted him, (5)the Son comes, he speaks with his Father, he rescues this Great One from those four crocodiles.  I (7)know them by their Name(s) and their live(s).  I am one who rescues his Father from them.  Back, crocodile (9)of the west, who lives on the Tireless Stars, (for) thy abomination is in my belly.  (I have) swallow(ed) the neck of Osiris; (11)I am Seth--variant: Thoth.  Back, crocodile who is in the west, (for) there is a snake in my belly.  (13)(I) will not give myself to thee; thy flame (prevails) not against me.  Back, crocodile of the east, who lives on those that are in (15)their wrappings, (for) thy abomination is in my belly.  I have proceeded; I am Osiris.  Back, crocodile who is in the east, (17)(for) there is a snake in my belly.  (I) will not give myself to thee; thy flame (prevails) not against thee.  Back, crocodile of the south, (19)who lives on dung and choking smoke, (for) thy abomination is in my belly.  What is in thy hand is not blood; I am (21)Soped.  Back, crocodile of the south, (or) I will wipe thee (dry), (for) my navel cord is of bebet-plants.  (I) will not give myself to thee.  (23)Back, crocodile of the north, who lives on that portion ?for the time being?, (for) thy abomination is in my belly.  (25)(Thy) poison is upon me; I am Atum.  Back, crocodile who is in the north, (for) Selqet is in my belly (27)without my having begotten her.  I am the green-eyed one.  What is (28)is in my grasp; what is not is in my belly.  I am clothed and equipped with (30)my magic.  This which is above me and below, completed for me, is Re.  The width of my throat increases for me in the dwelling of (32)(my) Father the great one.  He has given me that goodly west which effaces the living.  Powerful is the Lord (34)(though) doubly wearied--variant: who makes doubly pregnant--therein every day.  My face is open, my heart is (36)in its seat.  The uraeus is with me every day; I am Re, who protects himself.  Nothing (38)evil can befall me.  (xxiv) (BD 33)Spell for driving off all snakes.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (5)O every Rerek, move not; behold, Geb and Shu are risen against thee.  (8)Thou hast eaten a mouse, the abomination of Re; thou hast crunched (the bones of) (11)a putrefied cat.  (12)(BD 34)Spell for not letting a man be bitten in the god's domain by (one that is in) (15)his (tomb).  To be said by Osiris N.: O (20)cobra, headdress of Re, Osiris N. (25)(is) the tip of the flame that shines on the pate(s) of millions (and) the standard of the gespew--variant: young aat-plants.  (30)Keep away from Osiris N., (for) he is (35)a lynx.  (xxv) (BD 35)Spell for not letting a man be eaten in the god's domain by snakes.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: ''O Shu,'' (5)says Busiris, and vice versa, ''(Neit) wears the kerchief of Hathor.''  ''They rejoice (8)Osiris,'' says he who eats his bread.  Make something go downstream, (10)make something go downstream, Osiris N., (13)(and) pass thou it.  ''(O) zek-snake,'' say the sam-plants, (15)''be on thy guard against the aqrew-trees, (for) these are Osiris, who asks for his burial.''  The eyes (19)of the ?First-born? fall; his washerman ?(is) against? thee.  (20)He shares Truth (with) him who assigns standings.  (xxvi) (BD 36)Spell for driving off a cockroach in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (5)Keep away from me, (for) my lips are crooked.  (7)I am Khnum, lord of the Circuit, who brings the words of the gods (to) (10)Re; I report the message to its Lord.  (12)(BD 37)Spell for driving off the two merty-snakes.  To be said by Osiris N.: (17)Hail to you, (ye) two comrades, sisters, merty-snakes.  I have parted you by my magic.  (21)I am Re in the night bark; I am Horus the son of Isis.  I have come to see my Father Osiris.  (xxvii) (BD 38)Spell for living on air in the god's domain.  It is to be recited to drive off the two merty-snakes.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)I am Ruty, the First-born of Re-Atum in Khemmis.  (Ye) who are in (7)your pavilion(s), be my guides; (ye) who are in your hole(s), make way for me.  Wave(s) and water serve me (11)on this route of the bark of Atum.  I stand on the ?deck? of the bark (of) Re.  (I) recite (15)his words to the common folk; I repeat his words to the narrow-throated one.  I have sought (18)my Father at eventide; I have opened my mouth that I may eat of life.  I live (21)in Busiris; I live again after death like Re every day.  (xxviii) (BD 39)Spell for driving off the refref-snake in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: Back!  Stumble, (3)thou who recoilest along with Apophis.  Mayest thou swim to (4)the pool of the deep, to the place where thy Father has ordered that thou be cut to pieces.  Keep away from this birthplace (6)of Re, (thou) trembler before him.  I am Re, (thou tr)emble(r) before him.  Back!  Keen is he whom thou takest on; (8)Re has made (thy words) harmless.  Thy face has been turned upside down by the gods; (9)thy breast has been torn out by the (lynx).  Thy bonds have been commanded by (10)the scorpion; thy injury has been commanded by truth.  The wayfarers have overthrown thee.  Fall, stumble, (12)(O) Apophis, enemy of Re.  Re is gone in safety from the east of the sky at the sound of the storm (14)roaring.  The portals of the horizon have been opened before Re, that he may ascend, though he faints (from) wounds.  I do (16)thy will, I do thy will; I do good, I do good.  I do (it) when Re sets; I make rejoicing to thy bonds, (O) Re.  (18)Apophis is fallen and bound.  The southern, northern, western, and eastern gods have bound him; (20)their bond is with him.  The Earth-God (has) overthrow(n) him; He Who Is Over the Colors has bound him.  Re sets, Re sets, preserved in peace, while Apophis is fallen.  (23)O Apophis, enemy of Re, this thy sweet taste is greatly to the liking of the scorpion.  What (25)she has done against thee, so that thou art in pain because of her, persists (eternally).  May thy phallus miss its mark for thee (forever), (may) thy penis forever, (26)(O) enemy of Re.  He averts thy face, (O thou) whom Re hates, (so that) thou lookest behind thee.  (Cut off) is thy head, (O thou) whose face is cut off, (27)(who passest) along the roadsides.  Hacked off is thy head (by) those who are at (thy head; crushed are) (thy bones).  Dis(28)membered art thou by Isis; consigned art thou to the Earth-God, (O) Apophis, enemy of Re.  These are thy crew; (29)be satisfied (therewith) as one presented therewith.  He whom thou madest proceeds, proceeds to thy house, (whereas) the good (person) proceeds, proceeds (elsewhere).  No (30){no} evil harm shall go forth from thy mouth against me as what thou hast done against me.  I am the soul of Seth, who causes storm and (31)thunder when (he) goes forth from the horizon of the sky; ?like one whose heart is sad is he?.  Says Atum: (32)''Lift your face(s), goodly (youths); ward off the noxious one from the Council.''  Says Geb: ''Establish (33)your throne(s) in the middle of the bark of Khepri.  Take ye your arrows and (34)your ?shields? held for (you) before (you).''  Says Hathor: ''Take your weapons.''  (35)Says Nut: ''Come, ward off that noxious one who comes against him who is in (36)his Shrine, who crosses alone, the Lord of (the Universe)--(that noxious one) who hates his being kept from the (other) gods.''  Say the gods: ''Take (37)your cakes; traverse the turquoise pool.  Come to the great one who is in (38)his shrine, (from) whom the Ennead came forth.  Utter for him spells, give him (39)praise, yea, announce him ye.''  Says Nut, the Mother (of the gods): ''He who came forth from him, (40)he has made booty of the gods whom he received from Nut.''  Geb stands guard (41)while the Ennead is pulling, pulling; Hathor, (while) the Ennead is a(42)tremble.  Re triumphs over Apophis.  Four times.  (xxix) (BD 40)Spell for repelling the swallower of the ass.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)On thy face!  Eat (m)e not, for I am pure.  Who, then, am I?  One who has come of himself.  Thou shalt not come (7)against me; I am one who has come without his being called.  Thou knowest not (that) I am master of thy mouth; (9)give way (before) thy myrrh.  ''O Protector of his form, which Horus has pierced,'' say his creatures, (12)''thou hast been caused to suffer in (thy coils) and vice versa.''  (Thy) Ennead is in (14)Pe and Dep, (O) child of his; go forth, (thou) whom he pierced (16)there with the eye of Horus.  (I have) repulsed thee when thou wast near; I have (done away with) (18)thee by the breath from my mouth.  O swallower of {his} sin(ner)s, O seizer by force, (21)there are no sins of mine at the hand of the Scribe of evil deeds, there are no sins (of mine on record) in the Council.  (24)(Vari)ant: (If) I am repulsed, (if) I am repulsed, then the breath shall be taken away from thy mouth.  O (26)swallower of sin(ner)s, O seizer by force at the hand of the Scribe of evil deeds, (29)there are no sins of mine.  I have caused no trouble.  I am one who has him seized at his command.  Seize not (32)Osiris N., eat him not; (for) he is lord of life and Sovereign in the horizon.  (xxx) (BD 41)[Spell for] warding off a man('s) harm in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: Osiris (5)Unnofer--variant: Atum, the complete one--more blessed is he than Ruty.  (8)Opened for him are the gates ?of...?, that he may worship the mystery.  O (11)yon doorkeeper of the west, he eats, he lives on air while being led to the bark of Khepri.  (15)(I) speak to the Ennead that is in (Ishru); I go in and out.  I see, I lift (him) up; (19)I tell what the narrow-throated one spoke.  I live; I have been rescued after my death.  (23)O thou who bringest offerings, who openest his mouth, who puttest forward the writings, who spreadest out the offerings, (27)who strengthenest the right hand, he judges the Prince(s)--variant: the Elders; he enters the Council.  (xxxi) (BD 42)Spell for warding off all evil harm and warding off the mischief that is done in the god's domain--variant: in Heracleopolis.  (1)To be said by N.: The land (belongs to) the rod, the white crown to the image.  (O) standard of Osiris Unnofer justified, I am the child.  (Say) four times.  O kid of the Great One, (3)thou hast said today, twice: ''Prepared is the place of execution, even that which knows thy name.  Hast thou come to it as an ailing, aged one?''  I am Osiris, (4)excellent of favor; I am the great god amid the tamarisks.  (How) beautiful is the skin of Re, (more so) than yesterday.  (Say) (5)four times.  I am Re, who established favor, who bound the god amid the tamarisks.  If I prosper, Re prospers, and vice versa.  (6a) My well-being is (that of) the Deep and Osiris.  (7a) The hair of Osiris N. is (that of) the Deep; the face (of Osiris N. is that of) Re.  (9a) The eyes (of Osiris N. are those of) Hathor; the ears (of Osiris N. are those of) Upwawet.  (11a) The right temple (of Osiris N. is that of) the Soul of Re by day; the left temple (of Osiris N. is that of) the Soul of Atum by night.  (13a) The nose (of Osiris N. is that of) Anubis presiding over the hall of the god and over Xois; the lips (of Osiris N. are those of) Anubis.  (15a) The teeth (of Osiris N. are those of) Selqet; the neck (of Osiris N. is that of) the divine Isis.  (17a) The heart (of Osiris N. is that of) Osiris--variant: the Soul the lord of Mendes.  (18a) The breast (of Osiris N. is that of) Neit; the chest (of Osiris N. is that of) the lady of Kheraha.  (20a) The back (of Osiris N. is that of) Thoth.  (21a) The phallus (of Osiris N. is that of) the Soul the lord of Mendes--variant: of Pe; the testicles (of Osiris N. are those of) the lords of Kheraha (or) of the Great of Dignity in Heracleopolis.  (23a) The belly and backbone (of Osiris N. are those of) Sekhmet; the buttocks (of Osiris N. are those of) the eye of Horus.  (25a) The thighs (of Osiris N. are those of) Nut; the feet (of Osiris N. are those of) Ptah.  (27a) The fingers  and (toe(s)) (of Osiris N. are) live cobras.  (28a) The members of (Osiris N. are those of) the lords of Kheraha (or of) (6b) the great dignity in Heracleopolis.  Not one (7b)of his members is without a god.  Thoth is the magical protection of his whole body every day.  He shall not (be) grasp(ed) by his arms; (9b)(he) shall not be seized by his hand.  Neither men nor gods nor the blessed nor any dead nor any (patricians) nor any (common folk) nor any sun folk nor ?forsaken ones? shall do (11b)any robbing of him.  He is one who has come forth sound, (for) men know not his name.  He is yesterday; (13b)his Name is He Who Sees Millions of Years Twice, who has gone along the roads of the chief examiner(s).  Osiris N. is lord of changelessness; (16b)may he be esteemed like Khepri.  He is lord of the Coil, (for) he is one who is with the Sound Eye.  (18b)(He of) the egg, to him life with you has been given, (for) he is one who is with the Sound Eye.  (19b)His place is on his throne; he sits as ?deputy? beside it.  He is Horus presiding over millions; his throne has been assigned (to) him, that he may rule (it).  (22b)Behold, the mouth that spoke (is silent); and he who was in normal position, behold, his form is upside down.  Osiris N. is (25b)Unnofer.  Time after time his requirements are (26)with him, as one after another serves him, (for) he is one who is with the Sound Eye.  Nothing can happen to him; evil, uncleanness, and strife, (27)they cannot (prevail) against him.  He it is who has opened the gates of the sky, who rules the throne, who has parted the progeny this day.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
