<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Property Transfer</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.20</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)20</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. O.I. 10551</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: Recto and verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyd">Demotic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>papyrus ; 64.2x28.0 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto: 10 lines in Demotic; Verso: 16 lines in Demotic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto: Property transfer; On verso: Witness list</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="-0161">August 4, 161 B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Pathyris/Gebelein</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Hermocrates son of Apollonios also known as Panas son of Nakhthor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kalibes daughter of Panas and Tasherenmont</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Taminho the daughter of Panas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pathoth son of Panamoui</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pamenho son of Panas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Wonesh, son of Grour</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Zmanres son of Pamoui</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thotortaios son of Nakhtmin</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">witness list containing 16 names</persName>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyd">Demotic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Pathyris</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. O.I. 10551, recto: (1) Year 20 month 3 of summer day 7 (August 4, 161 BC) of the kings Ptolemy and Cleopatra his sister, the children of Ptolemy and Cleopatra the gods Epiphaneis, and (the year of) the priest of Alexander and the gods Soteres and the gods Adelphoi [and the gods Euergetai and the] gods [Philopatores and] (2) the gods Epiphaneis and the gods Philometores and (the year of) the athlophoros of Bernice Euergetes and the canephoros before Arsinoe Philadelphos and the priestess of Arsinoe Philometor in accordance with the one whom Pharaoh will command to act as priest (3) [in the Thebaid nome] (of) Ptolemy Soter and the priest of Pharaoh Ptolemy the god Philometor and the priest of Ptolemy Philadelphos and the priest of the queen Cleopatra [and the priestess of] Cleopatra the mother, the goddess Epiphanes and the (4) canephoros before Arsinoe Philadelphos. There has said the man who receives rations who is assigned to the camp of Pathyris, Hermocrates son of Apollonios also known as Panas son of Nakhthor to the woman Kalibes daughter of Panas whose mother is the endowed woman Tasherenmont: I have given to you the 1/2 share [of the vacant plot] (5) (and) the house whose walls are standing whose other 1/2 share belongs to the woman Taminho the daughter of Panas, your sister, the boundaries of the plot in its entirety: south - the house of Pathoth son of Panamoui, while the street of Pharaoh is between them; north - the place of adoration; east - the house of Pamenho son of Panas together with his plot which forms its west; west - the house of Wonesh, son of Grour, while the street of Pharaoh is between them together with the quarter share of the high field which equals 40 arouras of field which are among the high fields - which equals 10 arouras of field and their increase of measurement - which are upon the temple revenue lands of [Hathor]; the boundaries of the field in its entirety: south - the field of Pamenho son of Panas - which equals 35 arouras of field and their increase in measurement; north - the field of Zmanres son of Pamoui; east - the northern section (?) of the island of Hathor, while the ditch is between them; west - the addition (?) of Pharaoh. Total whose quarter share of the 40 arouras [of field - which] equals 10 arouras of field - belongs to Tamenho daughter of Panas, your sister, (and) whose other 1/2 share (8) - which equals 20 arouras of field on the south facing of the said field - belongs to [Pamenho] son of Panas. Total of the boundaries of the vacant plot (and) [the] house together with the 10 arouras of field which are above in their entirety. I have given them to you; they are yours: your vacant plot, (and) house together with the 10 arouras of field above. The son or grandson of mine [who will] come against you on account of them, let him give real silver evaluated at 20 (deben) from the shares of the treasury of Ptah in bullion (9) equalling silver (deben) 19 kite 9 5/6 1/10 1/30 1/60 1/60 equalling real silver evaluated at 20 (deben) from the shares of the treasury of Ptah in bullion again, you being after him (i.e. having a claim upon him) to cause that he act in accordance with every matter above also. While the eldest son Pamenho son of Panas, whose mother is the endowed woman Tasherenmont, says: Receive [(the) document from] Hermocrates son of Appolonios also known as Panas son of Nakhthor, my [father]. (10)  My heart is satisfied with it to act in accordance with it without a court trial or any matter on earth. Written by Thotortaios son of Nakhtmin who writes on behalf of the priests of Hathor the Lady of Gebelein (and) the gods Adelphoi, the gods Euergetai, the gods Philopatores, the gods Epiphaneis, the gods Philometores for the 5 phyles.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
