<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Book of the Dead</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.5426</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)5426</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. OIM 9787 (2)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Undated.  Presented by Martin A. Ryerson.  Dates follow D.B. Redford (ed.), The Oxford Encyclopedia of Ancient Egypt (2001).;Square brackets [ ] denote lost text and lines ; ; indicate uncertain text.  Braces { } denote superfluous words and parentheses ( ) indicate elements supplied, comments or emended text.;There are vignettes associated with BD 16-7, 21, 23-8, 30, 64, 31-3, 35-41, 43, 45, 47, 46, 44, 48, 53, 50, 54-5, 52, 57, 59, 56, 63, 65-6, 68, 71-87, 89, 90, 88, 91-4, 98-9, 95, 100-7, 109-10, 112-5, 119, 116-7, 124-36, 138, 137, 140, 143-62, 191.  Most, if not all, of the vignettes were evidently sketched in ahead of the text, and the latter did not always fit as the artist had planned.  (Allen p. 19);In BD 52 (xxxvi, 22-38), a few lines were omitted and then added at the end; they are inserted in the translation in their proper order.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyh" otherLangs="egy-Egyp">Hieratic; Hieroglyphics</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>10 papyri ; 924.0 cm x 39.0 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The manuscript now starts a little after the beginning of vignette BD 16.  Aside from the initial loss, other damage is slight.  A pointed object had been thrust into the papyrus while it was rolled.  Some seventy holes near the lower edge, gradually decreasing in size toward the end until they cease in BD 148 b, probably represent two thrusts at opposite sides of the roll.  If only one thrust were involved, the roll as we have it would have been just over 3 cm in diameter; but its 924 cm length could scarcely have been rolled into such small compass.  (P. OIM 10486 is only 1/9 as long, but formed a roll about 6.4 cm in diameter when purchased.)  But P. Ryerson could not be checked directly, for it was already mounted in ten frames.  At both beginning and end, it had also been broken across in four places each, and there are minor breaks elsewhere.  (Allen p. 16)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">On recto: 157 columns in hieratic, 3 columns in hieroglyphics</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto: Book of the Dead</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The hieratic signs, when checked against G. Moeller, Hieratische Palaeographie III (1912), show forms varying from the 20th dynasty to about A.D. 60.  In selection and arrangement of spells, P. Ryerson is most similar to L 3079 (de Rouge, 1861-76, pls. V-XX), both having unusual additions.  They share strange writings and even errors, e.g. in BD 64 (cf. especially its S 12 f. and 15).  Hence they probably go back to a common ancestral manuscript.  Similarities with T (Lepsius, 1842) are also numerous.  Hieroglyphics occur only in BD 110b, 125d, 148b, 161S, 191-2, and the final offering formulas.  A note in demotic is added below BD 140.  All of the writing is in black.  The vignettes are colored in red, light and dark blue, green, yellow, brown, and white.  R, then, differs from Ptolemaic copies of BD.  The latter, as Daressy has mentioned, are generally written in crowded hieratic, with vignettes merely sketched in black, sometimes set off by a little red.  The scribe wrote with a consistent and steady hand.  He evidently checked his work, for the corrections are largely his.  But another, more angular hand has interlined name, etc. of deceased here and there (especially col. c) and made occasional other additions (cf. col. cxlviii).  The artist who did the vignettes was presumably a different person.  His work shows a good feeling for form, yet sometimes there is squattiness of figure (cf. overlapping scepter-bearers in col. liv) or unevenness of line (cf. kilt of deceased in cols. xxxix and xli).  (Allen p. 19)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="-0525" notAfter="-0031">VIth - Ist century B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Osiris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Unnofer</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Atum</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Re</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Shu</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Min</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Isis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nephthys</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Authority</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Perception</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Seth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thoth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Imset</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hapi</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Duamutef</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Qebehsenuf</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Whom His Father Sees</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Is Under His Moringa Tree</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horus with No Eyes in His Forehead</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anubis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Asdez</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dozer</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Bull Who Gives No Glow from His Hot Breath</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Observant One in His Prime</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Sees by Night Him Whom He Carried Off by Day</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tefnut</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Geb</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Carried Off His Portion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Shezmew</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nefertem</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Bastet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khepri</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Swallower of Millions</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Keen One</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Baba</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Master of His Affairs</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sokar</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ruty</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptah</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Uto</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Amon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Suty</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Upwawet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Baby</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nut</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sekhmet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tatenen</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phoenix</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">the Disk</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menkaure</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hardedef</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Soped</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Selqet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Rerek</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Neit</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hathor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khnum</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apophis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Is Over the Colors</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Sees Millions of Years Twice</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Imperishables</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ihy</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Inundation</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Seshat</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Baby</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sothis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Rekem</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Remrem</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Akhezzef</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tayt</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khonsu</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sobk</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Bibi</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ash</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Akhkhew</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menqet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harakhte</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sesha</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hotep</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpocrates</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Akhem</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Renenutet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Truth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Fate</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Luck</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Spirit of Contentment</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Blessed One</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Magician</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khasety</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Wenty</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sutekh</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Montu</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">the Deep</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Zepa</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horus Khentekhtai</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onuris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aachbyt</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Adjen</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Adj</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ned</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Born of the Two Lips</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sound of Mouth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Opener of the Ways</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Clear</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Asb</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hurler of the Two Knives</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Feller of Fish</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">The Offering Descends</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heh</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ded</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mut</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyh">Hieratic</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyp">Hieroglyphics</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Heracleopolis; Hermopolis; Heliopolis; Maat-lake; Rosetau; Naref; Abydos; Field of Rushes; Mendes; Busiris; Letopolis; Punt; Kheraha; Pe; Dep; Washerman's Shores; Memphis; Aqa-reach; Field of Offerings; Wednet; Turah; Khemmis; Ishru; Xois; Upper Egypt; Lower Egypt; Debew; Athribis; Qenqenet; Hetepet; City of the Great One; the Peaceful; Anet-wadj-wer; the Verdant; Djefat; Hezat; the Powerful; the United; Anpet; Hierakonpolis; Matat; Akhmim; Wenes; Bubastis; Fayyum; City of the Two Truths; Pomegranate; Xoite nome; Weryt; Sais; Wenes; Nedjfet; Atef; Asyut; Antaeopolis; Egypt; Sebeg; Bahbit; Aswan; Ra-antywy; 'Apret; Zekret; the Overflow; Nedit; Pesegro; Atef-wer; Shenew; Hekenew; Shaw; Peqer; Heni; Bedshew; Tayt; Sia; Siatyw; Lake Land; Pelusium; Qawyt;Ass-region; She Keeps Silence; Adew-abode; Elephantine; Heqehqed</term>
               <term>Funerary</term>
               <term>Religion</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. OIM 9787 (2), continued:  (27)He is the Child (28)who has trodden the path of (yesterday); to him belongs to(day), {every} man by man.  He is protection for (29)millions.  Whether ye exist in Sky or earth, southerners, northerners, westerners, or easterners, fear of him is in (30)your bellie(s).  (He is one who fashions with his hand; he shall not die again.  His power is in your bellies,) (but) his forms are in him; he cannot be known.  (As for) the red ones, their face(s are) against him; but he rejoices, (for) (31)this (period of) time has not accomplished what it would do against him.  Where is the sky?  Where is the earth?  Children of misfortune, they cannot be united.  (32)His name ?shuns? everything evil.  Effective are the spells when this Osiris N. speaks to (you).  He it is who rises and illumines the walls one by one.  Not a day is with(34)out its appropriate activities as each (day) passes.  Behold, Osiris N. tells thee he is the blossom that came forth from the Deep, and Nut is his mother.  O thou who didst create him, (he is) one who strides not, the great commander within yesterday, the commander's portion being within (36)his hand.  There is none who knows Osiris N., (but) he knows him(self); his enemies shall not grasp him.  He is Horus presiding over millions.  Scorching breath is in (37)their face(s), so that they are roasted; their heart(s are) against Osiris N.  He has ruled his throne; he spends this time, the way (38)having been opened for him, delivered from all evil.  He is the golden ape of the gods, without hands or feet, presiding over Memphis.  If he prospers, the ape (39)presiding over Memphis prospers.  To be said: ?Mayest thou look to? thy place.  Variant: A man shall present offerings, his hand at his mouth.  (xxxii) (BD 43)Spell for not letting a man's head be cut off in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)I am Re, lord of the gods; I am the Great One, son of the Great One; (I am) fire, son of fire.  (7)My head has been given (back) to me after it was cut off.  The head of Osiris shall not be taken away from him; (9){I} my head shall not be taken away from me.  (10)(I) am put together in the right order with it, renewed and rejuvenated.  I am that Osiris, (13)lord of the west.  (14)(BD 44)Spell for not dying again in the god's domain.  (15)To be said by Osiris N.: (18)The pit has been opened, the pit has been opened, and the blessed ones fall within darkness; (but) (21)the eye of Horus shelters me, and Upwawet attends me.  Hide me among you, Imperishables, (for) (24)my heart is (that of) Re.  My face is open; (26)my heart is in its cavity.  My spell, I know (it).  I am Re, who protected (28)himself.  I am not unknown; I shall not be plundered.  (30)I am the Father, (O) son of Nut; I am thy (son), great of strength, (32)who sees thy secrets.  (I am) risen as King of the gods; (34)I shall not die again in the god's domain.  (xxxiii) (BD 45)Spell for not letting a man rot in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: Does the weary one weary (5)as (did) Osiris?  (Do the members weary as did those of Osiris?)  He--variant: it--shall not weary, he shall not rot, (7)he shall have no odor, he shall have no penis.  Treat ye Osiris (9)N. like him, (for) he is (12)Osiris.  As for one who knows this spell, (13)he shall not rot in the god's domain.  (14)(BD 46)Spell for not letting those who have been alive perish in the god's domain.  (16)To be said by Osiris N.: (19)O Youth in whose body is Shu, (gateway) powerful through its fillet of sun folk, (22)make the outstretched one stretch.  (xxxiv) (BD 47)Spell for not letting a man's seat be taken away from him in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)My seat, my throne, come, given to me, and serve (6)me.  I am your Lord, (O) gods; come to me as (8)(my) Followers.  I am the Son of your Lord; ye belong to me.  It was (10)my Father who made you for me while I was in the retinue of Hathor.  (12)I was the priest there, Ihy, while I was in the retinue (14)of Hathor.  (15)(BD 47)Spell for going forth in triumph.  (16)To be said by Osiris N.: (19)I have gone forth in triumph against my enemy.  (21)I have set the sky in turmoil; I have opened the earth.  (23)I have traversed the earth at (his) heels, (I have seized) the blessed ones, the First-born, (25)for (verily I am) one equipped as to millions of his magic spells.  (27)I eat with my mouth, I excrete with my anus, for (29)(verily) I am a god, lord of the nether world.  These (powers) were given me (31)from the (time of) breaking (the egg).  (xxxv) (BD 49)Spell for going forth against one's enemy in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)O eater of his portion, get out of the way, (for) I am Re.  (6)I have gone forth from the horizon against my enemy; he cannot be rescued from (8)me.  (I) have extended my arm as lord of the Coil; I (have) stretch(ed) my legs (as) (10)the Shining One stretched (hers).  (11)I do not make that enemy of mine fall by my hand, (but) he is given to me and can(not) be rescued from me.  (14)I have stood as Horus, I have sat as the Sky.  My strength (16)is (that of) a god, my power is (that of) Nefertem.  I walk with (18)my feet, I speak with my mouth, I seek (the enemy) thereby; (and) he is given to me (20)and cannot be rescued from me.  (21)(BD 50)Spell for not entering the place of execution.  (22)To be said by Osiris N.: (25)(The knot) has been tied for me around me in the sky (27)that touches the earth (by Re), ?put (in place)? on the day (of) making the knot fast to (29)him who is weary on (his) legs, that day of ?doing away with grief?.  (32)The knot has been tied around me by Seth while the Ennead was in (34)its (pristine) power, before strife (arose).  Ye keep (me) safe from him who slew my Father.  It is I (36)who have taken the Two Lands.  The knot has been tied by Nut, who saw (its) first instance, who saw Truth before the gods were fashioned in divine images.  (38)I am [?He Who Is?]; I (am) the heir of the great gods.  (xxxvi) (BD 51)[Spell] for [...] in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)(My) abomination, (my) abomination it is; I will not eat it.  (5)Dung is my abomination; I will not eat it.  Your ordure, none can harm me (8)therewith.  I will not touch it with my hands; I will not step on it (10)with the soles of my feet.  (11)(BD 52)Spell for not eating dung in the god's domain.  (13)To be said by Osiris N.: (15)My abomination is my abomination; I will not eat it.  (17)Dung is my abomination; I will not eat it, even though ordure be fallen into my belly.  (20)I will not touch it with my hands; I will not step on it with the soles of (22)my feet.  ''What, then, dost thou live on,'' (33)say (34)they (the gods), ''thou (new)comer, (in) this (place whither) thou (hast been) brought?''  ''I live (on) these seven loaves (36)of her who has brought her loaves unto Horus, (her) loaves unto Thoth.''  (38)''Where (art) thou (permitted) to eat?'' say the gods to me.  (23)''I have eaten under this sycamore of Hathor my Mistress.  I have given (25)the leavings thereof to the wayfarer.  Fields have been assigned to me in Busiris (27)and thriven for me in Heliopolis.  I have lived on bread of white wheat and beer of (29)red wheat.  (Given) to me is my family, consisting of my Father and my mother.''  (O) doorkeeper of the house of (31)speech, pure one, open to me, (open wide) to me, make way for me, that (33)I may sit wherever I will.  (xxxvii) (BD 53)[Spell for not ea]ting dung nor drinking urine in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)I am the sharp-horned bull who rules the Sky, lord of ?the feasts? of (7)the Sky, the great illuminator who goes forth as scorching flame, who ?values? (9)long (life), the Lion (to whom) the Sunshine's course is given.  (11)Dung is (my) abomination; I will not drink urine.  I will not walk upside down.  (14)I am possessor of bread in Heliopolis.  My bread is in the Sky with Re; my bread is on earth (17)with Geb.  (It is) the Night Bark that brings (it) to me from the house of the great god in Heliopolis.  (I) ?festoon? (my) intestines (20)at joining the ferryboat; I cross to the east of the Sky.  I eat (23)of what they eat (of); I live on what they live (on).  (25)I have eaten bread in the chamber of the possessor of offerings.  (xxxviii) (BD 54)Spell for giving breath (to) a man in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)O Atum, give me the sweet breath of thy nostrils.  (7)I am that egg of the Great Honker.  (9)I guarded that great egg that separated (11)Geb from the earth.  If I live, it lives, and vice versa; if (13)I grow old, (it grows old).  If I breathe air, (it breathes air).  (I am) (14)one whose purity is recognized, whose Name is about his egg, for whom time becomes pregnant, (17)the great of strength, Seth.  (18)O thou whose corpse is in Pe, and (ye) Two Lands (which) are the food and lapis lazuli of Re, (21)be on your guard (against) him who is in his nest, the {his} child, (23)when he goes forth against you.  (xxxix) (BD 56)Spell for breathing air in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)O Atum, mayest thou give me the sweet breath of thy nostrils.  I am (7)the First-born, the eldest, dwelling in Hermopolis.  (9)I guarded that egg of the Great Honker.  If I flourish, (12)it flourishes, and vice versa; if I live, it lives, and vice versa.  (14)If I breathe air, it breathes air.  (16)My Soul (belongs) to thee, my Lord Atum.  It circles about; it is holy.  (18)This (soul) falls (protectively) over the name of Osiris N., possessor (22)of worthiness before Re and before Osiris the presider over (24)the west.  (xl) (BD 57)Spell for breathing air and having water available in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)O Inundation, great one of the sky, in thy Name of Breaker-up of the Sky, mayest thou let Osiris (7)N. have water available like (10)Sekhmet who snatched away (Osiris) on that night of the (great) storm.  (12) Behold, Osiris N. escorts (15)the Elder(s) presiding over the seat of the flood, (just) as (17)that august God whose Name they know not escorts them; and they escort Osiris (19)N.  (21)Osiris (N.) (has his mouth), and his nose is open (23)in Busiris.  He rests in Heliopolis, his house which (25)Seshat builds for him and whose wall Khnum erects for him.  If (27)north winds come, he sits in the south; if (29)south winds come, he sits in the north; if (31)west winds come, he sits in the east; (32)if east winds come, he sits in the west.  (34)His eyebrows are drawn (together) above his nostrils.  Osiris N., (38)he has access to the place where he wishes to sit.  (xli) (BD 59)Spell for breathing air in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)O thou sycamore of Nut, mayest thou give me water and (6)the breath that is in thee.  It is I who occupy that seat in the midst of (8)Hermopolis.  I watched over that egg of the (10)Great Honker.  If it flourishes, I flourish, and vice versa; if I live, it lives, (12)and vice versa.  If it breathes air, (13)I breathe air.  (14)(BD 60)Another spell.  To be said by Osiris (15) N.: Opened for me {opened (18)for me} are the double doors of the Sky, parted for me are the double doors of earth and firmament, by (20)Thoth and by (Horus' son) Hapi, that is, (Hapi) of the Sky, great in his time.  (22)May ye let me have water available as when Seth snatched away (24)his enemies on that day when (the Two Lands) raged.  (26)I have escorted the Elders who present (oblations), who are in the corners (of the sky), (just) (28)as that initiate God (30)whose Name is not known escorts them; and they, (31)the elder(s), escort the oblations.  (xlii) (BD 61)Another spell.  To be said (2)by Osiris N.: (6) Verily I am one who came forth from the flood and to whom (9)the overflow has been given, that (he) may have (10)it available as the Inundation.  (11)(BD 62)Another spell.  To be said (12)by Osiris N.: (16)Opened is the great one ?(fem.) for? Osiris, parted is the firmament for Thoth.  (19)(O) inundation, Lord of the Horizon in this his Name of Divider of the Earth, (22)mayest thou let me have water available like Osiris.  (24)Four times.  (xliii) (BD 63)Spell for drinking water and not becoming parched by fire.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)O bull of the west, (I) have given myself to thee.  I am (6)that paddle of Re's wherewith he paddles his elders.  I shall not become parched; (I shall not become scorched).  (9)I am Baby, first Son of Osiris, who united to himself (every) god (11)within his eye in Heliopolis.  I {I} am the first heir of the unwrapped great one, the weary one.  There flourishes (14)for Osiris his Name; he has prevented that thou live thereby.  Variant: I am (16)that ?richly decorated? paddle wherewith Re paddles and (wherewith) (18)the elders paddle who bear (away) the efflux of Osiris and paddle for him (20)his boatless one who does not become parched.  I have (climbed the sunshine).  (O Khnum) (22)presiding over the sanctuary, (seize) (and) behead the (catch); travel (not) (24)along this road by which I have ascended.  (xxi) (BD 64)Knowing the spells for going forth by day in a single spell.  To be said by Osiris N.: I am yesterday, and I know the dawn of (2)tomorrow, (being) in charge of its birth on another occasion.  (I am) the Hidden of Souls who made the gods, who puts the Westerners to rest in (3)the west of the Sky, steersman in the east, Two-faced One (seen by) his rays, cloud-lord who came forth from the twilight, (4)whose manifestation is in the house of the sky.  O (ye) falcons, the two Horuses who preside over their tribunal, who hear cases (5)?presented orally?, while the foreleg is bound on the neck, the rump on top of the head of the west, who guide the dead to (their) (6)tombs, who draw Re as (their) follower (in) his great seat, heart of the (divine) dwelling that is above the sky, the throne-owner, who stands as the reliance (7)of the earth, I am he, and vice versa.  I made the glaze which Ptah fused upon his metal.  (O) Re, thou laughest, thy heart (8)rejoicing over thy goodly (truth) of this day.  Enter into the Nether Sky, come forth from the east, (thou) whom the First-born summons and the Ancestors adore.  Make pleasant for me thy ways; make (9)broad for me thy paths.  When thou crossest the earth to the breadth of the sky, thy light is upon me, (O) sou(l of) three.  As I approach the god, say in my ears, (O thou) who hearest in the nether world, (10)(that) no sins of my mother's are (held) against me.  Rescue thou me, protect thou me, from him who closes his eyes in the evening, who ?veils? Atum in darkness.  I am the flood; (11)Great Black Water is my Name in the temple.  My outside envelops me inside it.  O thou Great One without a channel, summon those who are in the rushes at the hour of carrying (12)the god.  Say, pray, to him who is in charge of his (flood): ''Behold, the foreleg of the god is bound for him on the neck, the rump on top of the head of the west.''  (I) have had him who was in (thee, O thou) greater of the two great (goddesses), (13)put into me.  I weep at seeing you.  (When) I sail from the embankment at Abydos, (O ye) bolts, come to rest at the gate face down.  Thy arms are within thee, (14)thy face is (that of) a greyhound, as thou sniffest at the shrine whence I propel my feet (as) Anubis (when) I withdraw from the resting-place of Tatenen to (that of) Ruty.  Preserve thou me, (for) (15)I am one who has gone forth as smasher of the door, (I am) the light which his heart made.  I Know the Water-Dwellers is my name.  I provide for the {his} needs of the blessed, who number 3(16)300,000 with 1200 of everything, (for) I am in charge of their possessions, ?so that they are sup(plied at the proper)? hour(s) on the day of investigating the bearers of Orion.  (Each bearer) is (1/12) of the passing (day) (17)as a whole, (as) one of them gives (place) to another.  (One-)six(th) preside over the nether world; they are the hour(s) of overthrowing the impious ones and of {my} returning therefrom triumphant.  Now it is these that are in (18)the aperture of the nether world; it is these that are with myself as ?twin? of Shu.  I have risen as lord of life, the goodly triumphant one of this day, in whose ascent are seven steps.  (19)My protection is the magical protection of the blessed (whose) blood is cool, (whose) wound(s) are fresh, and who have joined the earth.  The two horns have been parted by my commands, the mysterious of form by my approach.  (20)(O ye) who (crawl) upon your bellies, I have come by order of the lord of terror to do homage to Osiris.  Let the eye swallow its tear(s).  I am the (offering-)bringer in the house (21)of ?him who is abundantly supplied?.  I have come from Letopolis to Heliopolis to tell the Phoenix about the nether world.  O (silent land) wherein are mysteries, creating Form(s) like Khepri, (22)cause thou that I ascend as the Disk at the ascent of the sunshine, which I set apart in the west of the sky and which illumines the blessed in the keep, that I shine as one set free (23)at the mouth of the twin caves.  I (have) pass(ed) into the sky, I have trod upon the metallic expanse.  (I), the Great One, hold the sunshine aloft above my eyes as the light; I soar on (24)the rays of Brilliance.  My form is (that of) Re (rather than of) common folk, and I tramp on the tails of the snakes that (dwell) in this land.  O stabber (who drivest away) (25)the shadows of the blessed who are in the sacred land, mayest thou give (me) a good road through the gates of the nether world, (for) I am acting in behalf of him who is exhausted to reconstitute him (after taking his remains) from the water.  (26)I have reconstituted him who was in tears; that is, I have resurrected him from the hidden ones who are yonder, the silent one(s).  (O) realm of the dead, open for me the keep.  Mayest thou give me a good road, that I may pass.  (27)(Who, pray,) is he whom he would devour in the west?  I am the presider over Rosetau.  I entered in his name; I went forth as a favored one, lord of the millions of earth, who had made his (own) name.  (28)I became weary and have put down my burdens.  The Musicians (gave me birth before) them that walk head downward.  Sealed was the door through this wall overturned by my hand.  I have revived him who had fallen (29)on his back, the phoenix whom the dwellers in their hall adore.  To Horus his eye has been given, that his face may become bright at dawn.  His name is my name; there is none higher (30)than I.  (My) form is (that of) Lion; the equipment of Shu is with me; I am nephrite.  (How) good it is to see the mooring of the Weary-hearted One, (when he has alighted) in the ?reedy stream?.  Behold, I have ascended; I am (31)possessor of life.  I praise the deep; I am life.  I have ascended; I have offered praise at the entrance of the sacred abode.  (O) Osiris, mayest thou protect me from want; (O) Osiris, I am thy property (32)on earth.  I have embraced the sycamores, and the sycamores (have) shelter(ed me).  Opened for me is the Nether World; I have come, I have alighted on the Sound Eye.  (O) my (Soul), where, pray, art thou (on) the first day (of the lunar month) (33)while my corpse is silent, not speaking?  I have come to see him who is in his coiled uraeus (face) to face and eye to eye.  The wind rises as he ascends, and weariness ?shows? in my face.  Headdress-(34)Wearers, give me your hands, offspring who came forth from the mouth, Dawnings of the eye of Re, that I may stand.  (O) reassemblers, may I soar to the sky, may I alight on the earth, (every day).  (35)I want--variant: I embrace--my eye yonder in (attendance on) me.  I am the Creator, the child of yesterday, who fashions form(s).  (O) earth-god, deliver (me) at the (proper) time, for I am one whom the Fighter who banished the Swathed One (has) hidden away.  (36)Follow me.  (My) magic is the preserver of my flesh; my spells are the magical protection of my limbs at this time.  It depends on (37)my advice, and the Ennead relies on what I say.  (O) Lion, even Re, who liftest up him that is in Wednet, thou art I, and I am thou.  My manifestation is thy manifestation; thy form is my form.  I am (38)the Flood; Great Black Water is my name.  My manifestation is become (that of) Khepri; the herbage of Atum (attaches) to me.  I enter into Letopolis; I go forth in blessedness.  I am truly (39)Osiris, and I behold thy human form forever.  As for the silent one who knows this spell, he ascends and descends in the god's domain, he does all that the living do.  It is the great(est) protection of (40)the great God.  This spell was found in Hermopolis on a brick of the ore of Upper Egypt, written in real lapis lazuli, under the feet of this god in the time of the Majesty of the king of Upper and Lower Egypt, Menka(u)re, (41)by the King's son Hardedef when he was going about to inspect the temples, ?a (military) force? being with him.  He obtained (it) by pouring out (largess) and brought it as a desideratum to (42)the King when he saw that it was a foreigner's secret, unseen and unheard.  One who recites this spell (must be) pure and spotless, without coming near any abomination of a pure man.  Lo, there shall have been made for him (43)a scarab of nephrite ?set (in)? and adorned with gold, and there shall have been performed for him the (ritual of) opening of the mouth, it (the scarab) being anointed with prime oil--variant: myrrh--and put inside his body on the day of interment.  To be said on it as a charm: (44)''My heart of (my) Mother, my heart of (my) Mother, my breast (...).''  (xliv) (BD 65)Spell for going forth by day and overcoming one's enemies.  (1) To be said by Osiris N.: (5)O thou who risest as the Moon, who shinest as the Moon, when thou goest forth (8)with thy multitude, mayest thou free me.  (10)Ye who are among the blessed, open the nether world.  Lo, I am gone forth on this day (14)blessed; my blessed ones (deceased relatives) grant to me (16)that I live.  Brought to me are my enemies, (18)(over)thrown, in the Council.  (20)My mother's spirit is content therewith when (it) sees (m)e (22)standing on my feet with a golden staff in my hand.  (26)I cut off the body of the living one (between) the thighs (28)of Sothis, a child by their (the gods') grace.  (xlv) (BD 67)Spell for going out.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (5)Opened is the pit for those who are in the deep; (7)loosed are (the steps for) those who are in the sunlight.  Opened is (9)the pit for Shu, and I go out.  (11)I embark (in) and disembark from the bark of Re.  (13)(BD 66)Another spell (for) going forth by day.  (14)To be said by Osiris N.: (18)I know that I was conceived by Sekhmet and (born) of Neit.  (21)I am Horus who came forth from the eye of Horus, I am Uto who came forth from the falcon, (24)flying and alighting on the pate of Re, on his pate in the prow of his bark (27)in the Deep.  (xlvi) (BD 68)Spell for going forth by day.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)Opened for me are the double doors of the sky; opened for me are the double doors of the earth.  (5)Opened for me are the bolts of Geb; cleft for me is the house above (the twin lookouts).  Him who had guarded (me), it is I who free him; it is (8)(he who had bound) (his) arm to mine who releases (his grasp) of (me).  Opened for me is (10)the pelican's mouth, that I may go forth by day to any place where my heart desires to be.  (12)I control my heart, I control my breast.  I control my hands, (14)I control my feet.  I control my mouth, I control (my) whole body.  (16)I control mortuary offerings, I control water.  I control the flood, (18)I control the shores.  I control those who act (against) me in the god's domain; (20)I control him who commanded to act against me on earth.  (21)Surely it is as I say.  I do indeed live on the bread of Geb.  (But) (23)my abomination is my abomination; I will not eat (24)it.  I live on bread of red wheat of the inundation in the (26)pure place; I sip beer of red wheat of the Inundation (28)in the pure place.  I sit above ?the pillar-folk, eating of? branches (30)?such as? Hathor presiding over the broad Disk devoured.  (32)(I proceed) to Heliopolis bearing the hieroglyphic writings, the book of Thoth.  I control (33)my heart, I control my breast.  I control my mouth, I control my hands.  I control (34)my bread, I control mortuary offerings.  I control water, I control the flood, (35)I control the air.  I control the river, I control the shores.  (36)I control him who acts against me in the god's domain; I control him who commanded to act (against) me on earth.  (37)I lift (myself) from my right side, I am placed on my left side, and vice versa.  I sit, I stand.  (38)I (shake off) my dust.  My tongue--variant: my body--(remains attached to me) as a clever guide.  (xlvii) (BD 69) Another spell.  To be said by (2)Osiris N.: I am (4)the Fiery One, brother of the Fiery One; I am Osiris, brother of Isis.  (6)His Son Horus with his Mother Isis saved him from my enemies, who were doing (8)everything evil and harmful.  Their (bonds were put) on their hands and (10)their feet because of (their) doing everything harmful and evil against me.  I am Osiris, (15)Eldest of the company, Eldest of the five god(s), heir of his Father Geb.  I am (14)Osiris, lord of the living, vigorous of strength, vigorous of phallus, (16)who is in the realm of the common folk.  I am Orion, who reaches his two lands as he rows along (18)facing the brightening Stars of the Sky.  His Mother Nut, she conceived (him) (20)(as) Osiris N. (22)according to her wish, she (bore) (him) according to her heart's desire.  I am Anubis on the day of the Centipede; (24)I am the missing bull presiding over his fields.  I am truly Osiris, whose seal was (26)upon his Father Geb and his Mother Nut on that day (of) making the great slaughter.  (28)Geb is his Father; Nut is his Mother.  (I am) Horus the Eldest (30)on the day of {his} festival; I am Anubis on the day of the Centipede.  I am (truly) Osiris.  O (32)Eldest God, enter and tell the collector of writings, the doorkeeper (of) Osiris, that (34)Osiris N. (36)is come blessed, esteemed, divine, and powerful.  He has come, (for) he has saved (38)his own body.  He sits on that resting-place of Osiris (after) he has done away with (40)his suffering when he was sick.  Osiris becomes powerful and divine on that resting-place (42)of Osiris.  He has been (re)born with him; he is a youth, he is a youth.  (44)He bared that knee which was under the side of Osiris, with which he opened the mouth(s) of the gods.  He sits beside (him as Thoth) (47)the scribe of the Sound-hearted One.  1000 of bread and 1000 of beer from the offering table of his Father Osiris (and 1000) (48)of his spotted cows, of his longhorns, (of) his red cows, of his cattle, of his ra-geese, and of his tcherep-geese, (49)that he may present gifts to Horus, make offerings to Thoth, and sacrifice (to) him who is over the judgment hall.  (50)(BD 70)Another spell.  To be said by Osiris N.: I shall not die (any more) than (51){than} (shall) he who is over the judgment hall, the scribe of the sound-hearted one.  Osiris grows content (as) he rules Busiris (and) I (wander) over his (shores).  (52)I have smelled the east wind by its (hair); I have grasped the north wind by its t[ress]; I have grasped the west wind by its (hide).  (53)I have circled the sky past its corners; (I have grasped) the south (wind) by its eyelashes.  I give breath to the worthy among the eater(s) of bread.  (54)As for one who knows this roll, he goes forth by day, he walks on earth among the living, and his name shall not perish forever.  (xlviii) (BD 71)Spell for going forth by day and repulsing the robber, not letting a man's Soul be seized in the god's domain, keeping his Soul sound in the sacred land.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: O falcon (3)who came forth from the Deep, lord of the Great Flood, (4)mayest thou keep me sound just as thou keepest thyself sound.  Mayest thou loose me, (5)mayest thou free me.  Put me down.  ''Grant (his) desire,'' (6)says the one-faced Lord concerning me.  ''I am the falcon within the (7)shrine; (I) open (to) him who is upon my wall,'' (8)says Isis' son Horus.  (O Isis' son Horus,) mayest thou keep me sound just as thou keepest (9)thyself sound.  Mayest thou loose me, mayest thou free me.  Put me down.  (10)''Grant (his) desire,'' says the one-faced Lord concerning me.  ''I am (11)the falcon of the southern Sky, (Thoth in) the northern Sky, who calms (12)the rag(ing) fire, who presents truth to the lord of truth,'' (13)says Thoth.  (O Thoth,) mayest thou keep (me) sound just as thou keepest thyself sound.  (14)Mayest thou loose me, mayest thou free me.  Put (m)e down.  ''Grant (15)his desire,'' says the one-faced Lord concerning me.  ''I am the blossoms of Naref, the reeds of the hidden abode,'' (says Osiris).  O Osiris, (17)mayest thou keep me sound just as thou keepest thyself sound.  Mayest thou loose me, (18)mayest thou free me.  Put me down.  ''Grant (his) desire,'' (19)says the one-faced Lord concerning me.  (O) thou whose flame is at ?his? feet (20)constantly, Coiled One, lord of (his Twin) Souls, dwelling in (21)his Twin Progeny, mayest thou keep me sound just as thou keepest (22)thyself sound.  Mayest thou loose me, mayest thou free me.  Put me down.  (23)''Grant (his) desire,'' says the one-faced Lord concerning me.  O Re (24)in his egg, mayest thou keep me sound just as thou keepest thyself sound.  (25)Mayest thou loose me, mayest thou free me.  Put me down.  ''Grant (26)(his) desire,'' says the one-faced lord concerning me.  Stand (still) for me, Re dwelling on (27)his hill; (stand still,) Neit dwelling on her shores.  (28)Mayest thou loose me, mayest thou free me.  Put me down.  ''Grant (29)(his) desire,'' says the one-faced Lord concerning me.  O ye seven counselors who supported the balance (31)that night of accounting for the Sound Eye, who cut off heads and sever necks, who seize hearts and ravish (33)breasts, who do harm in the pool of flame, I know you, and I know your Name(s).  (May ye recognize me) just as I recognize you and (35)your number.  (May I come to you,) and may ye come to me; may I live with you, and may ye live (36)with me.  May ye assign to me the life(-symbol) that is in your hand(s), (the scepter) that is in (37)your grasp, for life at your word.  May ye give me many years in addition to my year(s) of life, may ye give many day(s) (39)in addition to (my) days of life and many nights in addition to (my) nights of life, (for) (40)my well-being.  I shine more than (do) my images; breath is at (41)my nose.  My eyes, they see like (the eyes of) these (42)Horizon-Dwellers that day of settling accounts with the robber.  (xlix) (BD 72)Spell for going forth by day and opening the underworld of the west.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)Hail to you, lords of Truth, void of falsehood, who stay alive forever and ever (for) the periods, (5)the periods of eternity.  Open ye sky and earth, (for) I am blessed with your forms and in control of your magic and esteemed as (8)ye are esteemed.  Rescue ye me from the crocodile (of) this land (of) truth.  Give ye to me my mouth, (10)(that I may speak) therewith.  Oblations are given me in your presence, (11)because I know your Name(s) and know (12){of} the Name (of) that great god at whose nose ye place provisions.  His Name is Rekem.  (14)He penetrates the eastern Horizon of the Sky; he penetrates the western Horizon of the Sky.  (16)If I go, he goes, and vice versa; if I stay sound, he stays sound, and vice versa.  Your food is in (18)your mesqet-region; transgressors shall not prevail over me.  None can keep me from your gates; none can shut (20)your door on me.  My bread is in Pe, my beer is in Dep.  As for him who knows how to plunder, his hands are within (22)his temple.  My Father Atum gives to me, he erects for me, a house that is on earth, with in(24)numerable barley and wheat therein, which thou providest for me therein at the feasts of Atum (25)by my Son of my body.  (Variant:) I have celebrated feasts therein for (26)my son of my body., Grant ye that there come forth a mortuary offering of bread and (27)beer, oxen and fowl, alabaster and clothing, (incense and) ointment, and everything good and (28)pure on which a god lives, (so that) I continue to exist forever in (whatever) form I wish.  (30)I journey downstream or upstream at will.  I journey downstream to the Field of Rushes; I journey upstream to the Field of Offering(s).  (32) I have joined the Two Truths; I am Ruty.  If this roll is recited for him (34)on earth or is put in writing on (his) coffin, he goes forth by day in whatever form he wishes and (even) enters his place of execution undeterred.  There are given to him bread and beer and a chunk of meat (38)from the altar of Osiris.  He ascends to the Field of Rushes, and barley and wheat are given to him there.  So he shall be thriving as he was on earth and shall do whatever he wishes like these (42)gods who are therein.  A truly excellent spell (proved) a million times.  (l) (BD 73)Spell for opening (the west) by day, (for) opening the underworld.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (7)O Soul great of dignity, behold, I am come.  See me; (11)I open the nether world.  (13)I see my Father Osiris; I have driven the darkness away from my Father.  I am (18)his beloved; I have come that I may see my Father Osiris.  (21)I hack out the heart of the harmful one; I make offerings to my Father Osiris.  (26)I have opened every road that is in the Sky and in the earth.  (29)I am a Son beloved of my Father; I have come as an Eminent One blessed and equipped.  O (35)every god and every goddess, make way for me.  (li) (BD 74)Spell for opening the feet and ascending from the earth.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (6)Thou doest what thou doest against him, (O) Sokar, Sokar who is in his cave, impeder in the god's domain.  (10)(But) I shine as he who is over that district of the Sky.  (13)I ascend to the Sky, I (climb) on (the sunbeams), (16)weary, weary, walking weary, weary in the god's domain on (20)the shores of him who would steal their spell in the god's domain.  (23)My Soul is triumphant in the house of Atum the lord (25)of Heliopolis.  (lii) (BD 75)Spell for going to Heliopolis and taking a seat there.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (5)I have ascended from the nether world; I have come from the realm of earth.  Illumine (8)the water, that I may understand about a baboon's entrails.  (11)I have taken the road to the sacred portals; I alight on (14)the houses of the pure one(s) who are in (their) shrouds.  (17)I have broken into the houses of Remrem; I have reached the seat of Akhezzef.  I ?gain access (to)? (21)the sacred ?precincts? on which Thoth trod when he pacified the (Two) Fighter(s).  I journey, I journey (26)to Pe; I come to Dep.  (liii) (BD 76)Spell for assuming any form one wishes.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (6)I have passed by the King's house; it is the ?fowler? who brought me.  (9)Hail to thee who hast flown to the Sky, whom the Stars illumine and the white crown protects.  (14)(I) exist with thee, united to thee.  (O) (16)great god, make way for me, that I may pass (18)by thee.  (liv) (BD 77)Spell for assuming the form of a falcon of gold.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: I am (5)risen as a great falcon who came forth from his egg.  (7)I have flown as a falcon four cubits ?(broad) (9)across? his back, (whose) wings are of the green stone of Upper Egypt, (11)who came forth from the cabin of the Night Bark.  (12)My heart has been brought to me from the eastern mountain; I have proceeded in the Day Bark.  There come (15)to me some of their Primeval Ones bowing down and kissing the earth.  They give (18)me praise, I being risen and made whole as a goodly falcon of gold, my head being that of (21)a phoenix, whose words Re enters to hear.  (When) I have sat down (23)among the great elder Gods, peasants set an offering before me (26)that I may eat thereof, that I may become a blessed one thereby, that I may have abundance (28)thereof, according to my heart's desire.  The grain-god grants to me (30)that I gain control of him who is at my head.  (lv) (BD 78)Spell for assuming the form of a divine falcon.  To be said by Osiris N.: O Eldest One, (2)come thou to Busiris.  Mayest thou clear the roads (for me), (mayest thou) encompass for me (my) throne.  Mayest thou (see me), mayest thou exalt (me).  Mayest thou implant (3)fear of me, mayest thou create respect for me.  May the gods of the Nether World be afraid of me; may their gate(s) combat them in my behalf.  (4)(Approach) me not, thou doer of harm whose eminence is in the house of darkness, who bares the weary one when he is hidden from me.  (5)''So (be it),'' say they, the gods who hear the voice(s) of the Departed that are in the retinue of Osiris.  Fall silent, ye (6)gods, as god speaks with god, (that he may hear) the Truth which I (tell) (him).  Speak, pray, to me, Osiris; may what comes forth from thy mouth turn unto me.  Thou seest thine (7)own form, which thou hast made, journeying to thy Souls.  Let thou me go forth and control my feet and exist like the Lord of the Universe on his throne.  May {thou} they who are in the Nether World be afraid of me, (8)may their gate(s) combat them in my behalf.  Let thou me be active, since I am a living one with these gods.  May I abide on my standard{s} (9)like the lord of the sky--variant: the lord of life.  I have united with (the divine) Isis; (she) preserves me from him who would do me harm.  May (he) not come to see his weary one.  (10)I go and come to the ends of the Sky.  I ask of Geb, I request food of the Lord of the Universe.  May the gods of the Nether World be afraid of me, may their gate(s) combat (11)them in my behalf, when (they) see thy catches (of fowl and fish).  I am one of those blessed ones who are with the Blessed, whom Atum created, whom he made, who became (12)the blossoms of his eye, whom he brought into being, whom he blessed, whose face(s) he uplifted (that they might be) with him, while he was alone.  They announce him when he ascends from the Horizon; they implant fear (13)(of him in) the gods and the blessed who have become his attendants.  (I am) one of the tadpole(s) which the eye of the sole lord create(d) (before) Isis gave birth to Horus.  Osiris is restored; he regains his youth.  (14)His eminence is (greater than) (that of) those  among the Blessed who have become his attendants.  Osiris is risen as a divine falcon.  Horus presents him (with) his (Soul) to take his possessions (to) Osiris (15)in the Nether World.  Ruty has said: ''(O) Osiris who is over the {his} house of the turban, (who was) in his pit, how dost thou escape to the limits of the Sky, though thou be enwrapped (16)in thy falcon form?  There is no (turban) on thee to (enable) thee to speak indeed to the limits of the Sky.''  (I am) he who is to take the possessions of Horus to Osiris in the Nether World.  (17)Horus has repeated (to me) what his Father Osiris (told him) as magical protection of Re.  ''I give a turban,'' (says) Ruty, ''that thou mayest go and come on the roads of the Sky, that they who are in the realm (18)of the Horizon may see thee.  May the gods (of) the Nether World be afraid of thee; may their gate(s) combat them in (thy) behalf.''  Be (favorably) inclined unto me, (for otherwise) there will be violence at the words of the gods, the lords of (19)the universe, (who are attached to) the shrine of the sole and only lord.  (Says) he who is high on his float{s}: ''Take him a turban''; (so) (says) (20)Ruty concerning me.  O (favorably) inclined one, make way for me, for I know about the float.  Ruty (has) brought me the turban and (given) me (my) wings.  (21)(I) have firmly fixed my heart in (its) back, my (mouth) in its long neck{s}.  I shall not fall on Shu's slaughtering-block.  I am that goodly departed one, lord of the esteemed uraei; verily (22)I am one who knows the roads of the Deep.  There is breath in my belly; the raging bulls have been repulsed.  I go (to) the place where the sleeper is, the boatless one who presides over the fields (23)of endless recurrence, he who is my guide (to) the grievous darkness of the Westerners, (even) Osiris.  I have come today from the house of Ruty; I have gone forth therefrom to the house of the divine Isis.  I have seen (24)the mysterious sanctities, having been led to the hidden sanctities just as (she) lets me see the birth of the great god.  Horus has presented me with his Soul; I have seen what is therein.  (25)If I have said ?(so) in the presence of the great ones? of Shu, they ward off ?opposition?.  (I am) he who is to take the possessions of Horus to Osiris in the Nether World.  Verily I am Horus who is with the blessed.  (26)I control my window, I control my receiving.  I go and come to the ends of the Sky.  Horus is on his Father's seat, Horus is on his throne.  (27)My face is (that of) a divine falcon, my posterior is (that of) a divine falcon.  I am one whom his Lord equips.  I go forth to the Nether World, I see Osiris.  (If) I robe myself (be(28)fore) him, Nut will robe herself for me when (she) sees me.  The gods have seen me as the very eye of Horus with No Eyes in His Forehead against those who would reach out their hands against me.  When I arise, I drive away (29)wretchedness.  They (open) for me the impassable roads when they see my form and hear what I say.  On your face(s), gods of the Nether World, repulsive of face, who approach (30)the powerful ones and pull the Unweariable Stars and traverse (the impassable roads and the ?salt region?), because of the Lord, the Soul great of Dignity.  Lift your face(s); I have espied you.  (31)I am risen as a divine falcon.  Horus has presented (me) with his Soul to take his possessions to Osiris in the Nether World.  The Gray-haired Ones have rescued me; (32)those who are attached to their place of execution move on for me.  (Ye) who are before me, make way for me.  (Then) I proceed and reach those who preside over their pit(s), who are attached to the house of Osiris.  I (introduce) to them (33)the powerful one {like}.  I inform them like him the terror of whom is great, whose horns Horus sharpens against Seth; (I) inform them that he has taken over Authority and has provided (34)Atum's symbol(s) of power.  ''Pass, (goodly one),'' say they, the gods of the Nether World, to me; and those who preside over their pit(s), who are attached to the house of Osiris, ?rise (respectfully)?.  Behold, (35)(I have) come unto you.  Take for me, unite for me, symbols of might, the Defiers of (the lower sky--(variant:) the defiant ones of the lower sky).  Clear for me, symbols of might, the impassable (roads); guard the roads of the Horizon and its (?salt region?) in (36)the Sky.  Set up their gate(s) in behalf of Osiris; clear the roads for me in his behalf.  Granted me are my commands.  I go forth to Busiris, I see Osiris.  I tell him about (37)this his Eldest Son (whom he) loved, who hacked out the heart of Seth.  I have seen the Lord (of Weariness); so (I (can)) inform them of the plans of the gods, (plans) which Horus carried out in the absence (38)of his Father Osiris.  O Soul Great of Dignity, behold, I am come; thou hast seen me exalted.  I penetrate the nether world; opened (39)for me are the roads of the sky and earth.  None (dares) approach me (as) I exalt thy seat, (O) Osiris.  Thou hearest good, (O) Osiris; thy strength endures, (O) Osiris.  I attach to thee thy head, (I) make fast (to thee) (40)thy neck, (O) Osiris.  Thy heart rejoices, since (thy wish) abides.  Thy courtiers share thy gladness of heart, since thou abidest as bull of the west, thy Son Horus having appeared on thy throne, all life being with him.  Millions work for him, Millions are afraid of him.  The Ennead works for him, (the Ennead) is afraid (41)of him.  Atum, {his} great Power of the Ennead, who changes not, has told what Authority (said) to him: ''Horus is (clever), expanding shrunken faces for his Father.  Horus is the rescuer of his Father, Horus is the rescuer of his Mother.  (42)Horus is (my) Brother, Horus is my friend.  Horus came from the seed of his Father while his body was in (process of) decomposition.  He rules Busiris, and the gods work for him.  He has rescued Millions, he (gives new) life to Millions, by means of his eye, sole one of her Lord, Lady of the Universe.  (lvi) (BD 79)Spell for becoming the Greatest in the{ir} Council.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: I am Atum, (4)who made the Sky, who created what exists, who came forth from the earth, (5)who brought seed into being, lord of what is, who begot the gods, great god who came into being of himself, lord of life, (7)who causes the Ennead to prosper.  Hail to you, Lords of Possessions, pure ones, Hidden (9)of Seat.  Hail to you, lords of eternity, concealed of form, secret (11)of sanctuary, whose place where they are is not known.  Hail to you, gods (13)who circle the Firmament in the west, namely the Ennead within (15)the Nether Sky.  Behold, (I) am come unto you, I being pure, divine, (17)blessed, powerful, (possessed of a soul,) and mighty.  I (have) brought you bed- and (19)hezmen-natron, that I may do away with the saliva from your mouth(s).  I have come; (21)I have done away with the evil that was in your heart(s); I have detached the sins (23)that adhered to you.  I (have) brought to you goodness; (24)I cause truth to ascend to you.  I know (you, I know) your Name(s), (26)(I) know your forms, which (those) who came into being through you do not know.  (I have come unto you,) appearing (28)as that god (among men) at sight of whom the gods live.  I become powerful in your presence (30)as that god, high on his Standard, to whom the gods come (32)with rejoicing and whom the goddesses acclaim when they see him.  (34)I (have) come unto you, appearing in your place.  I sit on my seat that is in (36)the Horizon; Horizon come to me with rejoicing, praise is given (to me) (by) those who are in the Nether World, in this (my) dignity (of) lord of all (42)mankind, I (being) exalted (as) that august god, lord of the Great House, whom the gods rejoice at seeing his beau[tiful] egress [from] the belly (44)of the Nether Sky when his Mother Nut has borne (him).  (lvii) (BD 80)Spell for assuming the form of a god and putting light in the way of darkness.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: I am (4)one who has put on the garment of the deep, one white of raiment who is before (him).  I have shone (7)in the twilight by means of the Two Comrades who are in my belly and of the great magic spell (that is) in my mouth.  I raise (10)him who would fall, when I come upon him.  I fell with him in the valley of Abydos (12)when I went to rest.  I am one who remembers; I seized Authority in the city (14)wherein I found (him), (and) (I) conquer(ed) the darkness by his power.  (16)I am the woman who illumines the darkness.  (I have come that I may illumine the darkness; yea,) (it) shall become light.  (17)I rescued the eye of Horus when it was nothing (before) the fifteenth day had come.  (19)(I) join(ed) Seth in the upper chamber(s) in addition to the aged one (who was) with him.  (21)I equipped Thoth in the house of the Moon (after) I had taken the Upper Egyptian crown.  His truth is (23)in my belly, (with) turquoise and fayence at its monthly feast(s).  His fields (25)yonder are (of) lapis lazuli at his feast.  (26)(I have) take(n) the darkness; I have overthrown the ignorant.  (28)Those who were in darkness praise (me); the Mourners, whose face(s) were hidden, rise for me, weary though they be.  (31)(Just) see ye me; (I am) the Deep.  (I) will not let you hear (33)about it.  (34)(BD 81)Spell for assuming the form of a lotus.  (35)To be said by Osiris N.: I am the pure lotus which came forth from the Sunshine (39)and is at the nose of Re and at the nose of Hathor.  I accomplish{ed} (41)the mission{s}; I (seek) it (for) Horus.  I am the (42)pure lotus which came forth from the fields of Re.  (lviii) (BD 82)Spell for assuming the form (of) Ptah, (eating bread,) drinking beer, excreting from the anus, and being alive in Heliopolis.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: I have flown as a falcon, I have honked as a semen-goose.  I have alighted on yonder west side on (the occasion of) the great feast.  (My) abomination is (my) abomination; (8)I will not eat it.  Dung is my abomination; (10)I will not eat it.  The abomination of my Spirit shall not enter into (12)my belly.  ''What dost thou live on?'' say they, say the gods and the blessed.  (14)I live (and thrive) on the bread ?of him who befriends (me) on? the road.  (Say) twice.  ''Whereof dost thou eat?'' (say they,) (16)the gods and the blessed.  I thrive (17)as I eat it beneath the foliage and branches of ?the date palms? (of) (19)Hathor (my) Mistress, who provides food offerings, who provides bread and beer in (21)Busiris and bounty in Heliopolis.  I {have} put on garments (23)from the hand of Tayt.  I sit wherever (25)I wish to.  My head is (that of) Re; the total (of me) is Atum.  (Here offer) the four (27)of Re and the bounty of (the earth) four times.  (28)I have ascended, my tongue being (that of) Ptah, my throat (that of) Hathor.  (30)I recall the words of my Father Atum in my utterance, (when) he was destroying (32)the Majesty (of) Geb's wife: ''Smashed is a head (at) my word.  Fear my word and (34)repeat it not, (for) trouble (would follow).''  Assign(ed) to (me) is (36)the inheritance of the earth-lord Geb, my protector yonder.  Geb cools (me); he gives me (39)his crown.  They who are in Heliopolis bow their head(s) before me.  I am (their lord, I am) (41)their bull.  I become more powerful than (the lord of) endless recurrence; I cohabit (with) and prevail{ed} (43)over Millions.  (lix) (BD 83)Spell for assuming the form of a phoenix.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (5)I have soared as the Primeval Ones (soar); I have become Khepri.  (8)I have grown as plants (grow); I have decked (myself) as a turtle.  (I am) the fruit (11)of every god, one who knows the needs of their bodie(s).  (13)I am this yesterday of the quartet of these uraei, being a form (16)in the earth, ?the face of the Elder (Horus)?, who shines ?throughout? his body, (18)even that god (opposed to) Seth, Thoth (being) between them in that trial (of) (21)the presider over Letopolis and the Souls of Heliopolis (with) Water (24)between them.  (I have) come this day, appearing--(variant:) loosed--among the gods.  (27)I am Khonsu.  (lx) (BD 84) Spell for assuming the form of a heron.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)(I am) the mighty one (who is with the sacred c)ows, the sharp (horns) that are in their head(s), the tresses that are of (7)their turquoise.  (O) elders, blessed ones, ready of might, (9)I am (assigned) to the Sky, my trouble(s) to the earth, and vice versa.  (It is) my power that has gained for me the victory.  (12)The height of the Sky was created pure (for me); (19)the breadth of the earth was created that I might stride to my cities and the settlements.  I have gone, and (15)they who are in {the Sound Eye} error let me survive.  I leave the gods (17)in their place(s); the earth embraces for me them that are in their shrine(s).  Do I not know the Deep?  (20)Do I not know Tatenen?  Do I not know the red cows?  I have dehorned them.  (23)Do I not know magic when I hear its words?  I am the red lion that is (mentioned) in the writings.  (26)To be said by the gods as they lament: ''Yesterday ?(intercedes) (for)? you.''  (28)It has come unto me; it has griefs which ye know not.  Remedies are (30)in my belly, (for) I have not told lies in place of truth.  Today {with} truth hastens, (33)and (my) eyebrows live.  At eventide the foremost one (sails upstream) to make festive her sleeper and embrace (36)the aged one whom the earth has guarded.  As for (37)him who knows this spell, he shall be an initiate in the god's domain, and nothing evil shall befall h(im).  (lxi) (BD 85) Spell for assuming the form of a Soul and not entering the place of execution.  One who {he} knows it does not perish.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)I am Re, who came forth from the Deep.  (The god) is (my) Soul.  It was I who created Authority.  (5)Sin is my abomination; I see it not.  I am lord of truth; I live thereon.  I am (7)Authority, one who perishes not, in this my Name of Soul.  I came into being of myself together with (9)the Deep and Sky and Earth in this my Name of (Khepri), as whom I have come into being (11)daily.  I am the light.  Dying is my abomination; I enter not into the execution-place of (13)the Nether World.  None of these abominations of the gods is done to me, because I am one who does useful (15)things for Osiris.  I have gladdened the heart(s) of the possessors of offerings (in order that) they may put fear of me (17)and create awe of me in those who are with their Primeval Ones, (while I am high on my standard and on these my seats).  I am the Deep; (19)sinner(s) cannot upset me.  I am {I am} the Eldest of the Primeval Ones, (21)that is, the Souls of the gods, the Souls of eternity.  I am he who created darkness, who made his seat at the ends of the sky.  (23)(When) the Souls great of age came, I made darkness at the ends of the sky.  (25)I like to reach their ends, (to) walk on my feet, to conduct my standard, to cross the (28)?flooding? sky-waters, to do away with the darkness and worms (29)of the Hidden of Name, (to) turn (my) course away from the Lord of the two regions.  My Soul{s} (31)and its body are Uraei; my form (is that of) eternity, lord of years, ruler of everlastingness.  I am (the exalted one), (33)lord of the land of Debew.  Boy in My City, Youth in the Country is (35)my Name.  It has not perished.  I am the Soul that created the Deep, that made his seat in the god's domain.  (37)I have not seen the Nest; {in} the egg has not been broken.  I am lord of the height; I make (39)my Nest at the ends of the sky.  I go forth to the land of Geb; I do away with my uncleanness.  I see (41)my Father, lord of the evening; I kiss his body which is in Heliopolis.  I ?provide for him?, (43)for those who are in his protection are not in the western abode (of) (44)the ibis.  (lxii) (BD 86)Spell for assuming the form (of) a swallow.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)I am a swallow, I am a swallow; I am the scorpion, daughter of Re.  O gods, (6)how fragrant is your odor, the flame that ascended from the Horizon.  O thou who art in the city, (8)I have brought him who guarded his bend.  (9)Give me thy hand, (for) I (have) spent the day in the pool of fire.  (11)I went on an errand; I (have) return(ed) with a report.  Open to me, (13)that I (may) tell what I have seen.  Horus is helmsman of the Bark; (15)his Father's throne has been given to him.  That Suty, son of Nut, (17)is driven back (when) he would act against me.  I have checked what is in (19)Letopolis; I have extended my hands to Osiris.  I went (21)on an errand; I have returned to tell.  (22)Let me pass, that I may report on the errand.  I am one who goes in counted (and comes out) (24)numbered through that gate of the Lord of the Universe.  (26)I ?have? purified myself in that great district.  (27)I have done away with my uncleanness, {as} I know not sin.  I cast aside (29)my uncleanness that (adhered) to me.  (30)Doorkeepers, may way for me, for I am your peer.  I go forth by day; (32)I have come walking on foot, having at my disposal the course of the blessed.  (34)I know the secret ways and the gates of the Fields (36)of Rushes.  I exist (there); behold, I am come.  (38)I have overthrown my enemies on earth; my corpse, it is buried.  (40)As for one who knows this roll, he goes forth by day from the god's domain (42)and enters (it again) after he has gone forth.  If one knows not this spell, he shall not enter (again) after (44)he has gone forth, being unable to [go forth] by day.  (lxiii) (BD 87)Spell for assuming the form of a son of earth.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (5)I am a son of earth, long of years, who sleeps and is (re)born every day.  I am a son of earth (9)in the ends of the earth.  I sleep (11)and am (re)born, renewed, rejuvenated every day.  (14)(BD 88)Spell for assuming the form (of) a crocodile.  (16)To be said by Osiris N.: (21)I am Sobk, within whom terror of him dwells; I am the crocodile (24)when his Soul returns among his people.  I am (26)Sobk, who carries off by violence; (28)I am the fish of Horus here in Athribis.  (31)I am lord of obeisance in Letopolis. (lxiv) (BD 89)Spell for causing that a man's Soul attach itself to his Corpse in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)O Bringer{s}, O (r)unner who is in his hall, great god, mayest thou make my Soul come to me from (6)any place where it may be.  If thou art slow about bringing my Soul to me from (8){from} any place where it may be, thou shalt find the eye of Horus (18)standing against thee like those.  O gods who tow the Bark (20)of the Lord of Millions, who bring the sky to the nether world, who do away with (the secrets) of the Lower Sky, (22)who cause Soul(s) to approach mummies, whose hands are full with the towropes, (24)ye shall grasp your spear(s) and drive away the enemy, and the Bark shall rejoice (26)and the great god (proceed) in peace.  (27)Lo, may ye put this Soul (of mine) under your buttocks in the eastern Horizon of the Sky to (29)follow to the {its every} place where it was yesterday in peace, in peace, unto the west.  (31)(Then) shall it see its corpse and come to rest on its mummy.  {It shall not pass away.}  (33)It shall not perish, it shall not pass away, (for)ever and ever.  As for one who knows this spell, (35)his Corpse shall not perish and his Soul shall not leave his Corpse.  (lxv) (BD 90)Spell for giving remembrance to a man.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)O thou who cuttest off heads and slashest necks, (6)who puttest remembrance in the mouth(s) of the blessed because of the magic spells (8)(that are) in their bellie(s), thou shalt not see Osiris N. (11)with these eyes of thine (with which) thou peerest from thy thighs.  (And if) (thou) turnest thy face (13)backward, (thou) shalt not espy Shu's Mutilators who are pursuing thee to cut off thy head (16)and slash thy neck at the behest of the plunderer of his Lord because of this (18)which (thou hast) said thou wouldst do against me, (namely) putting remembrance (in) my (mouth).  Thou shalt not slash my neck, (20)thou shalt not seal my mouth (because of the magic spells that are in my belly, as thou wouldst do against the blessed) because of the {my} magic spells that are in their bellie(s).  Fall back (22)before the 2{d} statement(s) which (Isis) utter(ed at) thy coming to put remembrance in the mouth of Osiris (for) the sake of (Seth), his enemy, (25)saying to thee: ''(Thy face belongs to) thy testicles; that face shall not see.''  The fire of the eye of Horus shall go forth (27)against thee out of Atum's injured eye that night (after) (it (the eye)) has swallow(ed) (29)thee.  Fall back before Osiris, for thy abomination is in him and vice versa.  (Fall back before me, for thy abomination is in me and vice versa.)  If thou comest against me, (I will say to thee,) and if thou (31)comest not against me, I will not say to thee: ''Fall back (32)before Shu's Mutilators.''  (lxvi) (BD 91)Spell for not letting a man's Soul be confined in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)O (lofty one)--may he be praised!--Great of Renown, (7)Great of Dignity, who terrorizes the gods, having appeared on his great seat, (10)thou shalt, then, make way for my Soul and my shadow, for I am (12)equipped.  I am a(n equipped) blessed one; make way for me (14)to the place where Re, Atum, Khepri, and Hathor are.  As for (17)one who knows this spell, he shall become an equipped blessed one in the god's domain.  (lxvii) (BD 92)Spell for opening the tomb for the Soul and for the shadow, going forth by day, and controlling the feet.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)(Opened is) what is to be opened, closed is what is to be closed, (O) sleeper.  (5)I open what is to be opened (for) my Soul which is therein.  (O) eye of Horus, take thou (7)Osiris Unnofer justified; fix thou (his) beauty in the pate of Re.  (O) far-(9)strider, long-stepper, make way for me, (great one), (my) flesh being firm.  (11)I am Horus who saved his Father and brought the crown of Upper Egypt before him.  (13)Open a way for my Soul, (for) I control my feet.  (Then) shall I see the great god within (15)the Bark of Re on the day of counting Souls, my Soul being there in front among (17)the counter(s) of years.  Come to me, take for me my Soul, (O) eye of Horus.  Fix (19)its adornments in the pate of Re while the twilight is before them.  (O ye) who are in the members (21)of Osiris, (ye) shall not confine my Soul, ye shall not restrain my shadow.  Open (23)a way for my Soul, for my shadow, for (my) blessed one, that I may see the great god within (25)his shrine on that day of counting Souls and repeat my words to Osiris.  (O ye) who(se seats) are hidden, (27)(attendants of) the members (of Osiris), ye restrain Souls and blessed ones and seal (29)off the dead.  (But they) who would do evil against me, they shall not do evil against me.  (31)Go (far to) thy Spirit and my Soul.  (O) my equipped blessed one, {to} (33)may they lead thee; mayest thou sit {me} before the elders of the highest rank.  (35)I shall not be confined by (the attendants of) the members of Osiris, who restrain {the members of} Souls and lock up (37)shadows and the dead.  ''Wouldst thou seize me?'' says the Sky.  As for one who knows this spell, (39)he shall go forth by day, and his Soul shall not be confined in the god's domain.  (lxviii) (BD 93)Spell for not letting a man be ferried to the east in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)O thou phallus of Re, this deserts {deserts} him, and (6)he suffers diminution by storms.  The affairs of the weary by millions become (those of) Bibi; (but) I grow more powerful thereby than the powerful, I grow mightier thereby than the mighty.  (10)As for one who may ferry me, as for one who may take me, to the east, if (12)anything evil is done against me at the feast of transgressors (by) twisting the horns (14)of Khepri, then that phallus of Re shall swallow (16)the head (of) Osiris when I am come, led to the fields (18)of him whom the gods beheaded, that they may feed therein on (me).  (20)Then the horns of Khepri shall {not} gore, and pellets shall {not} develop in (22)the eye of Atum the annihilator, because of him who deceives me and ferries me to (24)the east, because he makes the feast of transgressors off of me, because evil harm is done me.  Alternative: (27)If nothing evil is done against me at the feast of transgressors by (29)twisting the horns of Khepri, then that phallus (31)of Re shall not swallow the head of Osiris when I am come to the fields (33)of him whom the gods beheaded, that they may feed on me.  Then the horns of Khepri shall not (gore), and (36)pellets shall not develop in the eye of Atum, and he shall not annihilate.  None shall snatch me away, none shall ferry me to (39)the east to make the feast of transgressors off of me {evil}.  None shall do evil harm to me, (42)none shall ferry me to the east.  (lxix) (BD 94)Spell for obtaining the palette and water-bowl from Thoth.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)O great one who sees his Father, attendant of the book of Thoth, (6)behold, I am come blessed, possessed of a soul, mighty, (8)equipped with the writings of Thoth.  Hasten, Earth-God (10)who art ?in? Seth; bring me the palette, bring me the water-bowl and (12)that writing case.  It is your secret that is in them, (O) gods.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
