<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>History</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.38</idno>
            <idno type="controlno">(ICU)38</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invno">P. O.I. 17636</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItem>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto and verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar-Arab">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItem>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>papyrus ; 25.5 x 20.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Medium brown medium quality papyrus. Margins comparatively narow, with parts of side margins lost. Papyrus and text are on the whole fairly well preserved.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto: 17 lines in Arabic; Verso: 17 lines in Arabic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto and verso: History of the Caliphs</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Small book hand inclined to be a little angular. Despite the apparent cursiveness, the ligatures show excessive pen-lifting within words. In keeping with quite early common practice, words are sometimes divided at the ends of lines (recto 11, 14 and verso 3); it is to be noted that the first of these divided words is &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Allah.&amp;apos;&amp;apos; This practice may have originated in an effort to save space at a time when writing materials were scarce and expensive for students. The scribe is quite space conscious, as seen from the size of the script, the running of several themes together on the same line, and the comparatively narrow margins. Diacritical points are quite rare. The circle is used to separate the themes, as well as for punctuation within the themes. The marginal notations are in the same ink and hand as the text.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0700" notAfter="0799">ca. 767-791 A.D.</origDate>
                     <persName type="asn">Muhammad ibn Ishaq</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Abu Luluah</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mughirah ibn Shubah</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Umar</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ibn Umar</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ali</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Uthman</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Talhah</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sad</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Banu Abi Muait</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Suhaib</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Muawiyah</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sad ibn Abi Waqqas</persName>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar-Arab">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Medina; Syria; Basrah; Kufah; Mecca</term>
               <term>History</term>
               <term>Islam</term>
               <term>
                  <rs type="genre_form">Literary</rs>
               </term>
               <term>
                  <rs type="genre_form">papyrus</rs>
               </term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. O.I. 17636, recto:  (1) In the name of God the Merciful, the Compassionate, (2) Muhammad ibn Ishaq said: When Abu Lu&amp;apos;lu&amp;apos;ah the slave of Mughirah ibn Shu&amp;apos;bah stabbed &amp;apos;Umar, the overwhelming misfortune distracted people from (3) prayer until they quieted down.  Then &amp;apos;Abd al-Rahman ibn &amp;apos;Awf led the people in prayer.  He read, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Verily, We have given you abundance&amp;apos;&amp;apos; (4) and &amp;apos;&amp;apos;When comes the help of God.&amp;apos;&amp;apos; Then (Ibn) &amp;apos;Umar went and called out, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;(Come,) ye people of Medina, ye people of Syria, ye people of Basrah, and (5) ye people of Kufah,&amp;apos;&amp;apos; and he caused them to enter (&amp;apos;Umar&amp;apos;s presence).  The people of Kufah were the last to be called, and no one asked him (&amp;apos;Umar) (6) to give his (last) instructions excepting them.  They said to him, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Give instructions, O Commander of the Faithful.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;  He said, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Should anything befall me, the affair is for (7) these six persons, with whom, at the time of his death, the Messenger of God--may God bless him and give him peace--was well pleased.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;  (8) Ibn Ishaq reported on the authority of Abu Ishaq al-Sabi&amp;apos;i on the authority of &amp;apos;Amr ibn Maimun al-Awdi, who said: I was present the day &amp;apos;Umar was stabbed.  (9) &amp;apos;Umar said, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Bring me &amp;apos;Ali and &amp;apos;Uthman and Talhah and Sa&amp;apos;d and al-Zubair and &amp;apos;Abd al-Rahman.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;  When they came in (10) to him, he spoke to none of them except &amp;apos;Ali and &amp;apos;Uthman.  He said, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;O &amp;apos;Ali, it may be that these people will recognize your family relationship (11) to the Prophet--peace be upon him--and your knowledge and what God has granted you of understanding.  Should you be in command of affairs after me, then fear (12) God.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;  Next he said to &amp;apos;Uthman, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;O &amp;apos;Uthman, it may be that these people will honor your relationship by marriage to the Messenger of God and (honor) your (advanced) age (13) and your nobility.  Should you be in command, then fear God and do not inflict the Banu Abi Mu&amp;apos;ait (the Umayyads) on the people.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;  (14) Then he said, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Call Suhaib to me.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;  And he said (to him), &amp;apos;&amp;apos;O Suhaib, lead the people in prayer for three (days during which) let these persons (named) retire to a house (for consultation).  And when (15) they have agreed on one of themselves, strike off the head of anyone who opposes them.  Beware of overmildness, for it severs (16) bonds and exhausts solicitude.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;  Ibn Ishaq said: When &amp;apos;Umar looked at him and said, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Be humble even as God Himself has humbled you; for, by God, I will not place  P. O.I. 17636, verso:  (1) in it (the caliphate) anyone who bore arms against the Prophet--peace be upon him.  And had you not coveted it for Mu&amp;apos;awiyah it would not have been coveted by (2) anyone who was set free (after the Victory of Mecca).  Let the freed one (Mu&amp;apos;awiya) know that this affair is not fitting for those thus freed nor for the sons of those thus freed nor for those who migrated after the Victory.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;  (3) (To the rest he said,) &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Even should you disagree (among yourselves) do not encourage those (thus) set free to covet it.  And think not that &amp;apos;Abd Allah ibn Abi Rabi&amp;apos;ah ibn al-Mughirah is of what you do heed-(4)less.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;  Ibn Ishaq said: When the elective councilors entered (the house) to take council, &amp;apos;Abd Allah ibn Abi Rabi&amp;apos;ah ibn al-Mughirah said to them, (5) &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Take me in with you.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;  They replied, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;No, neither out of love nor out of respect (would we willingly include you amongst us).&amp;apos;&amp;apos;  He said, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;You (must) listen to me.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;  They asked, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;What is it you wish (to say)?&amp;apos;&amp;apos;  (6) He said, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Should you swear allegiance to &amp;apos;Ali, we hear and resist; but should you give allegiance to &amp;apos;Uthman, we hear and obey.&amp;apos;&amp;apos;  (7) Ibn Ishaq said: Miqdad ibn al-Aswad said to them, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Do not swear allegiance to one who was not present at the Oath of al-Radwan (Hudaibiyah) and (8) who did not witness the Day of al-Furqan (Battle of Badr) and who fled the Day of the Meeting of the Two Hosts (Battle of Uhud),&amp;apos;&amp;apos; meaning &amp;apos;Uthman. Then &amp;apos;Uthman said, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;As for his saying (9) &amp;apos;one who was not at the Oath of al-Radwan,&amp;apos; the Messenger of God--may God bless him and grant him peace--sent me to the people of Mecca, (10) and the oath took place after I had gone.  So, the Messenger of God--may God bless him and give him peace--took the oath for me by grasping his (own) left hand, and (furthermore) the (11) Messenger of God specified a bounty to come to me.  And as for his saying &amp;apos;he did not witness the Day of al-Furqan,&amp;apos; the Messenger of God--may God bless (12) him and give him peace--placed me in charge of his daughter, who was dying, and he assigned me my share (of the booty) and gave me my pay.  (13) And as for his saying &amp;apos;he fled the Day of the Meeting of the Two Hosts,&amp;apos; God has already forgiven me that for which he (now) reproaches (me).&amp;apos;&amp;apos;  (14) Ibn Ishaq said: Mughirah ibn Shu&amp;apos;bah and &amp;apos;Amr ibn al-&amp;apos;As came forward and sat at the door of the council house.  (15) Sa&amp;apos;d ibn Abi Waqqas approached them and said, &amp;apos;&amp;apos;Do you two wish that someone will see you both and come to think that you are among the (16) councilors?  Up (and away with you)!&amp;apos;&amp;apos;  Thus he caused them to arise (and move away from the door).  The councilors remained two days without coming to any decision.  Then &amp;apos;Abd al-Rahman ibn &amp;apos;Awf said to them, (17) &amp;apos;&amp;apos;What is the matter with you?  Does every one of you aspire to the caliphate?  Would you (rather) leave the decision up to me provided I exclude myself and my paternal cousin (from the nomination)?&amp;apos;&amp;apos</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>