<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Book of the Dead</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.5429</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)5429</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. OIM 9787 (5)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Undated.  Presented by Martin A. Ryerson.  Dates follow D.B. Redford (ed.), The Oxford Encyclopedia of Ancient Egypt (2001).;Square brackets [ ] denote lost text and lines ; ; indicate uncertain text.  Braces { } denote superfluous words and parentheses ( ) indicate elements supplied, comments or emended text.;There are vignettes associated with BD 16-7, 21, 23-8, 30, 64, 31-3, 35-41, 43, 45, 47, 46, 44, 48, 53, 50, 54-5, 52, 57, 59, 56, 63, 65-6, 68, 71-87, 89, 90, 88, 91-4, 98-9, 95, 100-7, 109-10, 112-5, 119, 116-7, 124-36, 138, 137, 140, 143-62, 191.  Most, if not all, of the vignettes were evidently sketched in ahead of the text, and the latter did not always fit as the artist had planned.  (Allen p. 19);BD 148b (column cxl) shows deceased praying to Osiris-Sokar, who is supported by the West-Goddess and attended by the seven celestial cows and their bull, the steering oars of the four cardinal points, four sound eyes, and the four sons of Horus.  BD 150 (column cxlviii) consists of vignettes further illustrating BD 149, but order, forms, designations, and even the number of abodes vary from the one spell to the other.  In documents of the 18th-21st dynasties, BD 150 tends to show 15 instead of 14 abodes, preceded by 4 snakes, which may represent the points of the compass (so Naville and Budge).  Even in 18th dynasty documents, most of the forms used in BD 150 regularly differ from those of the apparently corresponding abodes of BD 149.  Column cxlviii in P. OIM 9787 consists of 16 rectangles similar to those of T (the Turin BD published by Lepsius in 1842) in both layout and contents except for including some misplaced legends which T lacks.  The 4 times 4 rectangles are to be read as 4 vertical lines beginning at right.  In line 1 come the 4 snakes over 2 abodes; legends occur over the first 2 snakes and with each abode.  In line 2 appear 5 abodes and 4 legends.  In line 3 are 3 abodes (the snake and the form below him are parts of one whole) and 4 legends.  Line 4 has 6 abodes and 6 legends.  The legends are scattered irregularly.  The legends ''Field of Rushes,'' ''Judgment(-place) of the Gods,'' ''Underworld,'' ''Abode of the Blessed One,'' and ''Abode of the river'' suggest abodes 2, 10, 6, 5, and 15 respectively.  But the associated abode forms do not match.  Only forms 4 (at the top of line 2), 11 and 12 (at middle and bottom of line 3), and 1, 15, and 9 (1 at top, others at bottom, of line 4) are distinctive.  Of these, form 15 alone is accompanied by its proper legend.  (Allen p.272-3)  BD 151 (column cxlix) is divided into 5 parts (a-e) and contains 3 vignettes.  BD 161 (column clvi) consists of 3 registers.  The first 2 registers each contain 2 center columns (1-2 and 3-4).  On either side of these center columns are short notes (1a-2a and 3a-4a).  The third register follows the regular textual layout in this document.;The hieratic portion of P. Ryerson ends with line 40 of column clvii (BD 162).  BD 191-2 and four offering formulas have been added in hieroglyphics.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyh" otherLangs="egy-Egyp">Hieratic; Hieroglyphics</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>10 papyri ; 924.0 cm x 39.0 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The manuscript now starts a little after the beginning of vignette BD 16.  Aside from the initial loss, other damage is slight.  A pointed object had been thrust into the papyrus while it was rolled.  Some seventy holes near the lower edge, gradually decreasing in size toward the end until they cease in BD 148 b, probably represent two thrusts at opposite sides of the roll.  If only one thrust were involved, the roll as we have it would have been just over 3 cm in diameter; but its 924 cm length could scarcely have been rolled into such small compass.  (P. OIM 10486 is only 1/9 as long, but formed a roll about 6.4 cm in diameter when purchased.)  But P. Ryerson could not be checked directly, for it was already mounted in ten frames.  At both beginning and end, it had also been broken across in four places each, and there are minor breaks elsewhere.  (Allen p. 16)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">On recto: 157 columns in hieratic, 3 columns in hieroglyphics</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto: Book of the Dead</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The hieratic signs, when checked against G. Moeller, Hieratische Palaeographie III (1912), show forms varying from the 20th dynasty to about A.D. 60.  In selection and arrangement of spells, P. Ryerson is most similar to L 3079 (de Rouge, 1861-76, pls. V-XX), both having unusual additions.  They share strange writings and even errors, e.g. in BD 64 (cf. especially its S 12 f. and 15).  Hence they probably go back to a common ancestral manuscript.  Similarities with T (Lepsius, 1842) are also numerous.  Hieroglyphics occur only in BD 110b, 125d, 148b, 161S, 191-2, and the final offering formulas.  A note in demotic is added below BD 140.  All of the writing is in black.  The vignettes are colored in red, light and dark blue, green, yellow, brown, and white.  R, then, differs from Ptolemaic copies of BD.  The latter, as Daressy has mentioned, are generally written in crowded hieratic, with vignettes merely sketched in black, sometimes set off by a little red.  The scribe wrote with a consistent and steady hand.  He evidently checked his work, for the corrections are largely his.  But another, more angular hand has interlined name, etc. of deceased here and there (especially col. c) and made occasional other additions (cf. col. cxlviii).  The artist who did the vignettes was presumably a different person.  His work shows a good feeling for form, yet sometimes there is squattiness of figure (cf. overlapping scepter-bearers in col. liv) or unevenness of line (cf. kilt of deceased in cols. xxxix and xli).  (Allen p. 19)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="-0525" notAfter="-0031">VIth - Ist century B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Osiris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Unnofer</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Atum</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Re</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Shu</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Min</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Isis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nephthys</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Authority</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Perception</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Seth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thoth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Imset</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hapi</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Duamutef</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Qebehsenuf</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Whom His Father Sees</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Is Under His Moringa Tree</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horus with No Eyes in His Forehead</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anubis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Asdez</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dozer</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Bull Who Gives No Glow from His Hot Breath</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Observant One in His Prime</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Sees by Night Him Whom He Carried Off by Day</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tefnut</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Geb</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Carried Off His Portion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Shezmew</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nefertem</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Bastet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khepri</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Swallower of Millions</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Keen One</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Baba</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Master of His Affairs</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sokar</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ruty</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptah</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Uto</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Amon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Suty</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Upwawet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Baby</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nut</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sekhmet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tatenen</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phoenix</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">the Disk</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menkaure</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hardedef</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Soped</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Selqet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Rerek</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Neit</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hathor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khnum</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apophis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Is Over the Colors</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Sees Millions of Years Twice</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Imperishables</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ihy</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Inundation</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Seshat</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Baby</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sothis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Rekem</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Remrem</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Akhezzef</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tayt</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khonsu</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sobk</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Bibi</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ash</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Akhkhew</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menqet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harakhte</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sesha</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hotep</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpocrates</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Akhem</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Renenutet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Truth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Fate</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Luck</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Spirit of Contentment</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Blessed One</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Magician</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khasety</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Wenty</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sutekh</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Montu</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">the Deep</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Zepa</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horus Khentekhtai</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onuris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aachbyt</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Adjen</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Adj</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ned</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Born of the Two Lips</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sound of Mouth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Opener of the Ways</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Clear</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Asb</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hurler of the Two Knives</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Feller of Fish</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">The Offering Descends</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heh</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ded</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mut</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyh">Hieratic</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyp">Hieroglyphics</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Heracleopolis; Hermopolis; Heliopolis; Maat-lake; Rosetau; Naref; Abydos; Field of Rushes; Mendes; Busiris; Letopolis; Punt; Kheraha; Pe; Dep; Washerman's Shores; Memphis; Aqa-reach; Field of Offerings; Wednet; Turah; Khemmis; Ishru; Xois; Upper Egypt; Lower Egypt; Debew; Athribis; Qenqenet; Hetepet; City of the Great One; the Peaceful; Anet-wadj-wer; the Verdant; Djefat; Hezat; the Powerful; the United; Anpet; Hierakonpolis; Matat; Akhmim; Wenes; Bubastis; Fayyum; City of the Two Truths; Pomegranate; Xoite nome; Weryt; Sais; Wenes; Nedjfet; Atef; Asyut; Antaeopolis; Egypt; Sebeg; Bahbit; Aswan; Ra-antywy; 'Apret; Zekret; the Overflow; Nedit; Pesegro; Atef-wer; Shenew; Hekenew; Shaw; Peqer; Heni; Bedshew; Tayt; Sia; Siatyw; Lake Land; Pelusium; Qawyt;Ass-region; She Keeps Silence; Adew-abode; Elephantine; Heqehqed</term>
               <term>Funerary</term>
               <term>Religion</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. OIM 9787 (5), continued: (With the cows and bull:) (She of) the Spirit-House, Lady of the Universe; (Storm Cloud) (of the Sky), Holding Aloft the God; the Hidden One Presiding Over Her Place; (She of) Khemmis, Who Wrapped (the God); (She Whose) Love Is Great, Red-haired One; the Possessor of Life, (Bright-red)-haired One; She Whose Name Prevails (Over) the West; and the bull, male of the cows.  (With the steering oars:) O Power of the sky, opener of the disk, good steering oar of the northern sky; O circler, leader of the Two Lands, good steering oar of the eastern sky; O blessed one dwelling in the house of (the divine images), good steering oar of the western sky; O foremost one dwelling in the house of the red ones, good steering oar of the southern sky.  (With the sound eyes:) May they give bread and beer, oxen, and fowl to Osiris (N.).  May they give provisions, ?(for) he is a son of earth?.  May they give him magic power in the god's domain.  May they give him the face (of) sky and earth; may th(ey) give him sky, earth, horizon, Heliopolis, and the nether world, (for) Osiris (...).  (With the sons of Horus:) Imset; Hapi; Duamutef; Qebehsenuf.  (cxli) (BD 149)First abode.  To be said (2)by Osiris N.: (4)O thou first abode of the west, wherein one lives on pastry and garden truck, take off (8)your turban(s at my) approach just as (at that of) the first-born among you.  May he unite my bones; may he make fast my members.  (11)Fetch me Ihy, the lord of hearts, that he may assemble (my) bones and make fast the coil of Atum.  Make thou fast the head (14)of Neheb-ka, that Osiris N. may fill the (17)scales, that thou mayest rule with the Gods, O living one triumphant--variant: the altar(s) of (thy) temples with the Gods.  Min ?is the fashioner of? the spirit (20)of Osiris N.  (22)Second abode.  To be said by Osiris N.: (25)O great of possessions in that field of rushes, whose wall is of metal, the height (28)of whose barley is 7 cubits, (its) ears 2 cubits, its stalks 3 cubits.  It is a blessed one 7 (cubits) tall (31)who reaps it alongside Harakhte.  I know the gate (of) the Field{s} of Rushes through which Re comes forth in the east of (34)the Sky, south of which is the pool of the khar{em}-geese and north of which is the water of the ra-geese, the place through which Re travels by sailing (or) paddling.  (37)I am in charge of announcing in the god's ship; I am a tireless paddler in the bark of Re.  I know that sycamore of (40)turquoise from the midst of which Re comes forth, which grows on the (uplifted) of Shu at the east gate of the Sky, through which Re comes forth.  I know (43)that Field of Rushes of Re's, the height of whose wheat is 7 cubits, (its) ears 3 cubits, its stalks 2 cubits.  (44)It is a blessed one of 9 cubits who reaps it alongside the eastern Souls.  (cxlii) Third abode.  To be said by Osiris N.: (4)O thou abode of the blessed, on which none sails, while indeed the blessed one becomes silent therein, (8)(her) flame being glowing fire; (O) thou abode of the blessed.  (11)With your face(s) down(cast), purify the abode.  Behold, like what ye were ordered to do for me is (14)this, says Osiris N.  He says: I am (17)master of the red crown (that is on) the pate of the blessed one who keeps all mankind alive by the scorching breath of his mouth (20)and rescues Re from Apophis, (so that) he stays alive forever.  (22)Fourth abode.  To be said by Osiris N.: (25)O thou mysterious abode, O yon very lofty mountain in the god's domain, (28)over which the Sky hovers, whose length is 300 hundred-cubits, its breadth 30 hundred-cubits.  (31)That snake on it, his Name is Hurler of the Two Knives.  He is 70 cubits long as he hastens, and he lives by beheading (34)the blessed and the dead in the god's domain.  (35)I stand against thee.  True is my course while the bark looks--variant: (only) one looks--toward thee.  I am the (re)united one; I am (38)the male.  Veil thy head.  If I stay sound, (thou) stayest sound, and vice versa.  I am the great of magic; (39)Re gives me my eyes, that I may benefit by them.  What does that mean?  (O) goer on his belly, (40)thou attainest thy strength--variant: (thy) mountain.  Behold, I am indeed gone, thy strength being with me.  (41)It is I who have taken over strength.  I have come to dispose of the Earth-God, that I may set (42)in the evening, that I may circle the Sky with thee in the valley.  Command thy food on earth (43)before the great God in Heliopolis--variant: the god's domain.  (cxliii) Fifth abode.  To be said by Osiris N.: (4)O thou fifth abode of the blessed, through which none can pass, the blessed in whom are (7)7 cubits (broad) in their buttocks and live on the shadows of the weary; (9)O thou abode of the blessed.  O blessed ones among them, open your way that I may pass (12)through you and journey to the (beautiful) west.  (13)This is what has been decreed for me by Osiris and the blessed one{s}, lord (of the blessed), that Osiris (N.) may live by his magic power.  I am celebrant of the new-moon feast and witness (16)of the 15th-day feast.  The eye of Horus circles for me under my guidance in the retinue of Thoth.  No (18)God shall set my face--variant: (There is no god) who directs his face--against me.  As for every dead man or woman who swallows {with} his (or her) spell against me and (any) enemy male or female who comes (21)against me this day, he (or she) shall fall to the place of execution.  (22)Sixth abode.  To be said by Osiris N.: (24)O thou underworld mysterious to the Gods, hidden (from) the blessed, difficult (of access to) the dead, the God in (27)whom bears the Name Feller of Fish, hail to thee, thou mysterious underworld the Gods in whom I have come to see.  Show ye (30)your face(s), take ye off for me your turban(s) at my approach in peace.  Behold, I have come that (I) may behold your form(s).  (33)I have come to prepare your thin cakes.  The Feller of Fish shall not prevail over me.  The gods of combat shall not (36)pursue (me); the gods of combat shall not pursue (me).  I shall live on offerings with you.  (cxliv) Seventh abode.  To be said by Osiris N.: (3)O yon As(s-region), (too) distant to be seen, the scorching breath of fire is whose magic power--variant: (is among whose) blessed ones, the snake (6)in whom, named Re(re)k, with a backbone 7 cubits long, is one who lives on the blessed and destroys (9)their magic power.  Back, Re(re)k of Ass, who bites with the mouth (of) the feller of his fish and blinds--(12)variant: floods--with his eyes.  Shattered are thy teeth, weak becomes thy venom, because of it.  Thou shalt not come (15)into me; thy venom shall not penetrate me.  Fall, lie on thy ?hay?, thy fever(ed skin in) this ground, having arrived--(18)variant: thy lips--in the (hole).  (He who is) on his mountain--variant: his chamber--falls at the command forever--variant: (falls while) harming him (21)who comes--and vice versa, for he is protected.  His head is cut off by the lion.  (23)Eighth abode.  To be said by Osiris N.: (26)O thou great, vast (abode called) The Offering Descends, flood (28)to the water in whom none has access because of the greatness of fear of her, (30)because of the greatness of her dignity, and because of the loudness of her cry.  The lofty God (32)in her is (likewise) named The Offering Descends.  He is one who is chary of his love, unapproachable.  I am (35)that new-bird which is over the district of She Keeps Silence.  I have brought the things of the earth to Atum.  (O) ye who go head downward, (38)(O) Crew, in terror of thee--variant: of me--are they that are over Letopolis; I have inspired respect (for me) in the possessors (41)of offerings.  None can carry me off to the (god's) slaughtering-block; my Soul shall not be destroyed out of (me) for their sake.  I am ruler of the northern Horizon, (44)for I know the great God who is therein.  (cxlv) Ninth abode.  To be said by Osiris N.: (3)O thou secret ?hollow? of the Gods, whose Name the blessed fear to know, (6)from whom he that enters comes not forth.  That great God is there of whom the Gods--variant: the blessed--are afraid because of the terror he inspires, of whom the blessed--(9)variant: the dead--are afraid because of his roarings.  Her opening is of fire, and her air destroys the nose.  He (the god) made it (the fire) against those in (his) train (12)for the sake of the blessed therein, not letting them breathe the air therein except for that great, august God who is in (15)his egg.  He made it against all those who were with him, for he had no desire to be approached except on the day of the great ceremonies.  Hail to thee, thou (18)august God in his egg.  I have come unto thee; I am in thy retinue.  I have gone forth unto ?the hollow?.  Open for me her double doors that (I) may breathe (21)the air in her, that I may live on her offerings, that I may become a blessed one in her.  (23)Tenth abode.  To be said by Osiris N.: (25)O thou abode of the presenters (of offerings), who seizest the blessed one by force and prevailest over the shadow.  Eaters of (28)(fresh (food))--variant: writing--who (disdain) carrion because of seeing with their eyes that there is no prevailing (30)over their shadows, weary ones--a papyrus-amulet of fayence ?having been left by them to the earth?--who are in their abode, put yourselves on your bellie(s), (33)and may your foul odor become pleasant until ye pass.  No (part) of my blessed one shall be seized; none shall prevail over my shadow.  I am a divine falcon.  May (36)myrrh be brought to me; may burnt incense be offered (to me).  (37)Remove for me the burden, my burial being earthward, with Isis and Nephthys around me.  (39)Clear ye for me the path of yon Naw-snake, (for) I am the bull of Nut, Neheb-ka.  (41)I have come unto you, ye Gods, that ye may rescue me.  Give ye (me) magic power forever.  (cxlvi) Eleventh abode.  To be said by Osiris N.: (3)O thou abode that is in the god's domain--that is the body that prevails over the blessed--(5)from whom he that enters comes not forth, (so great is the fear of revealing what is in her,) so great is her dignity.  (6)The Gods see in her (by (his) purification), the dead see in her by the terror he inspires, except for the Gods (8)who exist in her forever, hidden from the blessed.  (9)O thou (Adew)(-abode) in the god's domain, may(est thou) let me pass, (for) I am that eye of Horus, the Great of Magic, (11)the keen one who escaped from Seth.  (12)My feet are mine forever, while (I) appear and am powerful through that eye that lifted up (my) heart after faintness.  I become blessed in the sky and powerful (15)in the earth.  I have flown as a falcon; (16)I have honked as a semen-goose.  It has been granted (me) to tread--variant: to alight--(17)on that field of Hetep(et), I being gone down to the (meadows) of the Gods.  I stand on (19)it, I sit on it, (I) appear as the God who is in it.  I have opened (the gate) of the righteous.  I have eaten (of) (21)food in the fields of Hetep(et), (for) I go down upon the meadows of the Star(s) That Set.  (I have) opened (23)the way of truth, opened (it) that I may cross the sky-waters.  I have set up a ladder to the Sky among the Gods.  I am (25)one of them.  I speak as a semen-goose ?until? (26)the Gods hear my cry, repeated to Sothis.  (27)Twelfth abode.  To be said by Osiris N.: (29)O thou abode of the hour, abode of him who is in Rosetau, (31)whose scorching breath is fire, and the Gods ascend not to her nor do the blessed unite with her, and (33)the uraei upon her are (each) named Destroyer of Souls.  O thou abode of the hour, (35)where (I am) the falcon that is in her, I am (36)the greatest of the blessed; I am with the Imperishable Stars, who are imperishable ?because of her?.  (I shall not perish;) (38)my name shall not perish.  O odors of the Gods who are in the abode of the hour, (40)I shall be with you, I shall live with you.  Love ye me more than your (other) Gods, (for I shall be with you forever.)  (cxlvii) Thirteenth abode.  To be said by Osiris N.: (3)O thou abode (of) water, to whom the blessed can gain no access, since her water is fire (5)and her surf is flame and her scorching breath is burning fire, that none may drink (7)her water, (so that) there is no quenching of the thirst of them who are in her because so greatly do the blessed fear her and so great is (9)her dignity.  The Gods, the blessed, and the dead see her water from afar.  There is no quenching of their thirst, (11)no contentment of their heart(s), that there may be no approaching of her.  The river is (as) full (of) reeds as (are) (13)the waters with the efflux that came forth from Osiris.  May I gain access to the water, may I have abundance of water, like (15)that God (who is in) the abode of water.  (He) is her guardian, lest the Gods drink her water while (17)they are far away from the blessed.  Hail to thee, thou God who art in the abode of water.  I have come (19)unto thee.  Mayest thou grant that I gain access to the water and drink of the water as thou didst for the God--variant: like (21)thyself.  I am that great God for whom the inundation comes, for whom herbage sprouts, and (23)for whom all plants grow.  (Thou who) give(st) offerings to the Gods, (24)thou who camest forth from him, mayest thou be gracious to me (and) grant that inundations come to me (25)and that I gain access to the fields of herbage, (for) (26)I am thy (son) of (thy) body forever.  (27)Fourteenth abode.  To be said by Osiris N.: (29)O thou abode of Kheraha, who keepest the Inundation away from (Busiris) but causest (31)that the Inundation come, measured by the bushel, ?until he has been led? to every mouth that eats, who givest divine offerings (to) the Gods (33)and mortuary offerings to the blessed, (thou) in whom (is) this snake from the twin springs of Elephantine at the mouth (of) the cave (35)of the inundation.  He has come with the water and stops at this district of Kheraha at the Council (37)that is over the waters.  May (I) eat grain, offerings, and food.  Lift thyself up, great (39)and perfect, God who is in Kheraha.  Mayest thou satisfy me and provide me with the efflux that came forth from Osiris (41)in the presence of him who has fallen therein.  (cxlviii) (BD 150)[This is a series of scenes with legends; see notes.]  Abode ?(called) The Measurers Are Festive?, Field{s} of Rushes, Pool in front of the Sky, The ?green? abode, (2)Abode of eternity, Judgment(-place) of the Gods, Abode of Heh, Abode of Him Who Is in Charge of Tribute, (3)Abode of ?the Hole-Dweller?, Underworld, Abode of the Blessed One, Abode of the Exalted One, (4)Abode of ?the Hole-Dweller?, Abode of the deep, The great pool, Abode of Ded, Abode of the Offering-Bearers, Abode of the river.  (cxlix) (c2)(BD 151)To be said by Anubis, presider over the hall of the god, who gives justification: I have laid my hands on thee, (O) Osiris N.  (c1)To be said by Isis: (I come) as the breeze; I have come to be thy magical protection.  I give breath to thy nose, (even) the north wind that came forth from Atum, (O) Osiris N.  (c3)To be said by Nephthys: Awake thou, (O) Osiris N.  (d1)To be said (by the flame): (It is I) who smite the sand that would choke the hidden one and repel (2)him who would repel him with mouth of flame from the great one of the Horizon.  Come (3)to me, (O) road, for I am the magical protection of Osiris N.  (b1)Osiris N., (2)(thou art vigilant.  Osiris who is on his mountain, (3)thy power is broken; (I have) broken thy power.  I am thy magical protection, (O) Osiris (N.).  (4)(Mayest thou) keep Re away from Osiris N.  (cl) (BD 152)Spell for building the house that is in the earth.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)Geb rejoices when Osiris N. ?overcomes? all his badness.  Men, children, (7)and their (fathers), give praise to (...) because they see Shu giving to thee the noxious one.  (9)Anubis calls upon Osiris N. (to) build his house that is in (12)the earth, with its foundation in Heliopolis and its circumference in Kheraha, (14)while the presider over Letopolis is the recorder of its renovation.  (16)Men bring (offerings to) it; (bearers) present (offerings) to it.  Osiris has said (to the gods) who are (18)in his retinue: ''Go, and (ye) shall supervise the building of that house of (20)that equipped blessed one.  He has come today new among you.  May ye inspire fear of him.  (22)Give him praise, the (most) favored one of you.  Ye are seeing my doing, say I.''  (24)Utterance by that great God: ''He has come today (new) among you,'' says Osiris.  Brought (26)to him are small cattle by the south wind, brought to him are northern barley and wheat which the earth brings to fruition, (28)announced by day by the mouth of Osiris who has passed away.  (29)He has turned over (from) his left (side); he (puts) himself on his right (side).  (30)When men and Gods and the blessed and the dead look upon me, they ?spend (their time)? in praise (32)?and in song? yonder.  To be said by Osiris N.: (34)(O) great one who art far away, eldest child of the household, (thou art) the foremost.  May Osiris N. drink (38)the water of Tefnut.  Utterance by the sycamore, lady of offerings, to Osiris: (40)''I have come to bring thee my bread.''  Utterance: O thou sycamore of Nut (42)which refreshes the presider over the westerners and extends (its) arms to its members, behold, he is warm.  (44)Mayest thou give cool water to Osiris N. (46)(while he sits) under (thy) branches, which give the north wind to the Weary-hearted One in (48)that seat forever.  (cli) (BD 153)Spell for escaping from the net.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: O (3)(lookout) (and) ye mighty ones, both children and (their) fathers--variant: their Father, net-fishermen (5)who ?hover? in the midst of the waters, ye shall not catch me (nor) the common herd (in) that net of yours.  Loose ye me, ?that (I) may go from? the earth (with) them, (since) (9)their reversionary offerings (go) to the Sky, their weight to the earth.  (I have) escaped from (its) horn; Osiris N. (has escaped from) (12)its cords.  I have escaped from Busiris; Osiris N. (has escaped) (14)from it.  Falcon ?...against me? is my name.  Make ye ?crosspieces given from? the fisher ((and) fowler) with hidden (16)(fingers).  Variant: ''I have made a flight, (O) men, from his fisher,'' says he, the Hidden One.  I know the one sound of arm who is ?in (18)my fingers?; the Great One ?who has perished? (is he).  (Variant: I know) the commander who is in (19)(Upper Egypt; the Great One), the Perished One (is he).  As for the wood which is there, it is the hand (20)of Isis.  The blade which is therein (is) that knife of Osiris--variant: The name of their fisherman is (22)he who is in charge of his nak--wherewith (the intestines) of Horus were cut.  I know the name of (the float) with (24)(its) sinkers (--variant: the name(s) of) the flaming leg (and) weights; kneecap and knees of Ruty (are they).  I (26)know the cord belonging to it ?(and) the fishermen of? him who is in charge of it; it is a sinew of Atum.  I (28)know the name of the fishermen in charge of it; they are the (Earth-Gods), ancestors of its Achby-God.  (30)Its peg (is) the ring (of) Shezmew.  I know the name of your arms--for their arms are open to him.  They are the arm(s (32)of) the great God who heard cases in Heliopolis on that night of the 15th-day feast.  To be said over an image (34)of this blessed one put into this Bark, after thou hast made the Night Bark at its right side and the Day Bark at its left side.  (36)Offer (to) them bread and beer and all (other) good things on Osiris' birthday.  If this is done for him, his Soul shall stay alive (38)forever.  It shall not die again.  (clii) (BD 154)Spell for not letting the corpse pass away.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (2)Hail to thee, Father Osiris-Atum.  I have come (3)that I may embalm this my flesh.  This (my) corpse shall not pass away, for I am complete, (4)complete, like my Father Osiris-Khepri.  He is of like nature, one (5)whose corpse passes not away.  Come thou, (for my) breath surpasses thine, Lord of Breath, (6)exalted above his peers.  May (I) be more enduring than thou; mayest thou fashion me as possessor of a burial.  (7)Mayest thou let me go forth to eternity as thou didst together with thy Father (8)Atum--variant: (as) did thy Father Atum.  His corpse has not passed away; he especially is one (9)who perishes not.  I have not done what thou hatest.  May thy Spirit, then, love (me) (10)without its rebuffing me.  Mayest thou take me in thy company, that (I) decay not (11)after the manner of what thou hast allotted to every God and every Goddess, all quadrupeds, and (12)all worms.  He who shall pass away, his Soul ascends after death; (but) he descends after he passes away.  (13)That is, he becomes bloated; badly--variant: his bones--all decay, (and) (14)his hair is gone.  {Variant:} Appear--variant: Loosed are--the limbs; (15)(softened are the bones); the flesh all becomes evil--(16)variant: an evil liquid.  He turns to dust, he smells, he decays, he becomes (17)altogether a mass of maggots.  (So) he does when he is gone to the eye of Shu, as (do) (18)every God and every Goddess, all fowl, all fish, all snakes, (19)all worms, all quadrupeds, like the dead, the whole of them altogether, (20)(be)cause (it is they) that I have caused (to grovel) on their bellie(s when) they recognize me; it is (21)fear of me that has inspired terror (in) them.  (But) {every} every creature is like one dead (22){dead}, even all the ?living? snakes--variant: (dies) likewise at his (appointed) time--the whole of them altogether: (23)all quadrupeds, all fowl, all fish, all snakes, all worms; (24)living or dead, (they) shall be yonder.  There shall not come to pass all that the worm(s) do, that (25)they may not--variant: all that ye say, that they may not--come against me in their form(s).  (26)Thou shalt not give me to that ?slayer{s}? who is in (his) (geba)--(27)variant: arm, who cuts off limbs, who bloats the hidden one, (28)who mingles--variant: mixes--with a multitude of corpses, who lives by slaying (29)the living, who carries out his mission, who does what has been commanded him.  Thou shalt not give me into (30)his clutches, none shall prevail over (me), by command of the lord of the Gods.  Hail to thee, (31)my Father Osiris.  Thy members shall be with thee.  Thou shalt not decay, thou shalt not rot, (32)thou shalt not turn to dust, thou shalt not smell, thou shalt not decompose, thou shalt not become rotten.  (33)(I) go not to the eye of Shu.  I continue to exist, I continue to exist, alive, (34)alive, enduring, enduring.  I awake in peace, untroubled.  (35)I shall not perish ?yonder, (O) uplifter of the uplifted one?.  My (skull) shall not ?suffer?, (36)my ear shall not become deaf, my head shall not (leave) (37)my neck, my tongue shall not be taken, (my hair) shall not be cut off, (38)my eyebrows shall not fall out.  No harm shall happen to my corpse.  (39)(It) shall not pass away, it shall not perish, from this land forever and ever.  (cliii) (BD 155)Spell for the pillar-amulet of gold put at the throat of the blessed one.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)Thou hast thy backbone, Weary-hearted One; lift thyself, Weary-hearted One.  Mayest thou put thyself (7)on thy side, that I may put for thee water under thee.  Behold, indeed, I (have) brought thee the Pillar-Amulet of gold strung on sycamore bast (12)and put at the throat of the blessed one.  He enters through the gates of the nether world forthwith; he speaks (15)with the silent one.  He puts himself on his side on the day of thebeginning of the year (like) those who are in the train of Osiris.  (18)As for one who knows this spell, he shall be an initiate in the god's domain, he shall not be kept away from (21)the gates of the west.  There are given to him (regularly) a cake, a jar, a loaf, and a chunk of meat (24)from the altar of Osiris-Un(nofer), and he triumphs over his enemies in (26)the god's [domain].  A truly excellent spell (proved) a million times.  (27)(BD 156)Spell for the tie-amulet of red jasper put at the throat of the blessed one.  (29)To be said by Osiris N.: (31)Thou hast (thy) blood, Isis; thou hast (thy) magic, Isis.  (33)The amulet (is) the magical protection of the Weary-hearted One, restraining whoever would do (him) harm.  To be said over (36)a tie-amulet of red jasper anointed with sap of the ankh-imy-plant, (38)strung on sycamore bast, and put at the throat of this blessed one.  If (40)this roll is used for him, he shall be a follower of Osiris-Unnofer justified, (41)the gates in the god's domain shall be opened to him, the spells of (42)Isis shall be his magical protection, and Horus the son of Osiris shall rejoice at seeing him.  (cliv) (BD 157)Spell for the vulture of gold put at the throat of the blessed one.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)Isis has returned after alighting at the cities and seeking places of concealment (for) Horus at (his) going forth (7)(from) the swamps, his heart ?perturbed?, his ?mind (troubled)?.  (Proclaimed) for him is (10)protection.  The Ruler of the shores decrees for him that there be made for him a record (of) the (12)great conflict, (for) he remembers what was being done against him.  He causes fear (14)of him, he creates respect for him.  Mut the great, she provides his magical protection, (so that) a comer (17)against her Horus trembles.  To be said over a vulture made of gold, on which this spell is inscribed, given (20)as an amulet (to) this blessed one on the day of joining the earth.  A truly excellent spell (proved) a million times.  (23)(BD 158)Spell for the broad collar of gold put at the throat of the blessed one.  (25)To be said by Osiris N.: My Father is a Heliopolitan, (29)my Mother is a Heliopolitan.  (O) hidden one, look upon me.  (31)I am one of those that are freed when Geb looks upon them.  To be said over (34)a broad collar of gold, on which this spell is inscribed, put at (36)the throat of this blessed one (on) the day of joining the earth.  (clv) (BD 159)Spell for the papyrus-amulet of feldspar put at the throat of the blessed one.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)O thou that goest forth today from the God's house, voice of the Great One, encompass her at the door (7)of the twin seats.  She has taken the magic power of her Father, that Eminent One, as (10)bull of the virgin.  Those who are in her Train receive it; (13)now some, now others, have used it.  To be said over a papyrus-amulet of feldspar, (16)on which this spell is inscribed, put at the throat of the blessed one.  (18)(BD 160)Spell for the papyrus-amulet of feldspar which Thoth gives ?upon his being (entreated)?.  (20)To be said by Osiris N.: (23)I am that papyrus-amulet (of) feldspar, ?(uncoated)?, which Thoth has given upon his being (entreated).  (26)Injuries are its abomination.  If it stays sound, I stay sound; (28)if it stays uninjured, I stay uninjured, and vice versa; if it is not smitten, I am not smitten.  (31)Thoth has said: ''Welcome in peace, Great One, from Pe, (thou) ?after? whom Shu went, in (34)this his Name of Feldspar, whose seat is with the great God and with whose eye Atum is pleased.''  (37)The limbs of Osiris N. shall not ?become inflamed?.  To be said over a papyrus-amulet (41)of feldspar, on which this spell is inscribed, put at the throat of the blessed one.  (clvi) (BD 161)Re lives, the turtle dies.  Elicit (ye) the truth for Osiris N., the Dismembered One who is (again) in his original state.  (1a)One (opening is) for the south (wind), that is, Re.  (2)Re lives, the turtle dies, ?strangled by a noose of? the flesh of Qebehsenuf.  Their comrade is Osiris (N.).  (2a)Another (opening is for) the north wind, that is, Osiris.  (3)Re lives, the turtle dies.  The corpse is united with the earth; the bones of Osiris N. are united.  (3a)Another (opening is for) the west wind, that is, Isis.  (4)Re lives, the turtle dies.  Sound stays the great one who is in the coffin.  Sound stays Osiris N. forever.  (4a)Another (opening is for) the east wind, that is, Nephthys.  (5)As for every mummy for whom the Images are made on his inner coffin, (6)the 4 openings in the Sky are opened for him: one for the north (wind), (7)that is, Osiris; another for the south (wind), that is, the Moon; another for the west (wind), (8)that is, Isis; another for the east (wind), that is, Nephthys.  As for each one of these winds (9)which is in its opening, it is its duty to enter his nose.  No (10)outsider is to know (this spell, for) it is a secret; the rabble is not to know (it).  (11)Do not use it for anyone--even thy father or thy mother--except (12)thine own self.  It is a real secret; nobody at all is to know (it).  (clvii) (BD 162)Spell for providing heat under the head of the blessed one.  (1)To be said: Hail to thee, the Lord of might, Lofty (2)of Plumes, lord of the Coil, equipped with the flagellum.  (Thou art) lord of the phallus, (3)constant as riser, shiner whose Rising is without (end).  Thou art lord of forms, numerous of outward appearances, who conceals (5)himself in the Sound Eye from his children.  Thou art he who roars loudly (6)in the midst of the Ennead, the great runner, swift of {his} step.  (7)Thou art the mighty God to whom the crier (for help) has come, who delivers the needy from distress.  So come at my call, (for) I am (9)the Heavenly Cow.  Thy Name is in my mouth, and I will tell it.  He of He(10)qeh(qed) is thy Name; ?Graven Image? is thy Name.  I have praised thy Name.  I am (13)the Heavenly Cow.  Hear my voice this day.  (Thou hast) put (14)heat under the head (of Re); and behold, he is (in) the divine nether world in Heliopolis.  (15)Mayest thou cause him to become like one who is upon earth.  He is thy Soul.  Do (not) fail to know (16)him.  Come to Osiris N.  Mayest thou provide heat under (20)his head.  (Verily) he is the Soul of the great Corpse that rests (21)in Heliopolis.  ?The Essence of the Great One Shines? is his Name; ?Blessings Hath He Com(22)manded? is his Name.  Come thou to him.  Mayest thou cause him to become like one (23)of thy retinue.  (Verily) he is thou (and vice versa).  To be said over a Figure (24)of the Heavenly Cow made of fine gold and placed at the throat of the blessed one (25)and also put into writing on a new sheet of papyrus placed under (26)his head.  (Then) much heat will envelop him like one who is upon earth.  (27)(This is) a very, very great protection which the Heavenly Cow used for her Son Re (28)at his setting, when his seat was surrounded by ?ardent? troops with kindled face(s).  If thou hast put this Goddess (30)at the throat of the King upon earth, he shall be like flame in the face of--(31)variant: in pursuit of--his enemies upon earth.  If thou hast put her at his throat--(32)variant: at a man's throat--after death, he shall be divine in the god's domain (33)and shall not be kept from the gates of the nether world.  A (34)truly excellent spell.  Thou shalt say after thou hast put this Goddess at the throat of the blessed one: O (35)Most Hidden of the Hidden Ones, thou who art in Heaven, watch over the Corpse of thy Son, that thou keep him sound in the god's domain.  (37)This roll great of mystery, do not let anyone see it, (for) that is an abomination.  He who knows it and conceals (it), he is one who attains (continued) existence.  (39)This roll, Mistress of the Hidden Seat, is its name.  (40)Finis.  (clviii) (BD 191)Spell for bringing the soul to the body.  To be said b(y N.): O thou who carriest off the souls of the living, O thou who cuttest off shadows, O all ye gods who are over the living, come, bring ye the soul (2)of Osiris N.  May it unite with his body, that his heart may be glad.  May his soul come to his body and to his heart.  Induct his soul (3)to his body and to his heart; provide his soul with his body and with (his) heart.  Bring them to him, (ye) gods, in the benben-temple in Heliopolis beside Shu the son of Atum.  He has his heart like Re; (4)he has his breast like Khepri.  Pure, pure (are the offerings) for thy Spirit, for thy body, for thy soul, for thy shadow, for thy mummy in the nether world forever.  (clix) (BD 192)Another spell.  To be said: O Osiris N., doubly alive, doubly renewed, doubly youthful, there is nothing evil in any place wherein thou art.  (2)(Thou) goest forth by day, thou enjoyest its sunshine, and the God comes to rest on the place ?where thou art?.  Thou ascendest and descendest without thy feet being repelled.  Opened for thee are the double doors of the nether world in (the silent land); unbarred (3)for {him} thee are the gates of the hidden realm.  The doorkeepers extend their arms before them unto thee, rejoicing at thy approach (and saying): ''Thou enterest favored, (4)thou goest forth loved.''  He appoints thee as first among them, he is pleased with thee, and thou ?partakest? of his offerings.  He protects thee; he does away with thy evil.  Hail to thee.  The Blameless praise (thee), they who are in the god's domain attend thee, (O) Osiris presiding over the west justified, Osiris N.  (clx) A royal offering to Anubis the embalmer, that he may give goodly burial in the god's domain to Osiris N.  (2)A royal offering to Anubis on his mountain, that (he) may give the refreshing breath of the north wind to Osiris N.  (3)A royal offering to Anubis the lord of the chest, that he may let the soul of Osiris N. go forth.  (4)A royal offering to Anubis presiding over the god's hall, that he may beautify the body of Osiris N.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
