<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Coffin texts</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.5530</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)5530</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. OIM 14064</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">See also OIM Photo 27341.  Measurements not given.  Undated.  Allen questioningly dated this papyrus to the 6th dynasty (c.2374-2191 B.C.).  (Allen, p. 31)  Gardiner preferred a First Intermediate Period date (c.2190-2061 B.C.).  (See Willems, p. 246, n. 24.)  Mathieu dates it to the end of dynasty 6 and cites other scholars' datings, as well.  (See BdE 139, p. 254 and n.59-60.)  Dates follow D.B. Redford (ed.), The Oxford Encyclopedia of Ancient Egypt (2001).  The numbers for the entire papyrus are OIM 14059-87.  See Lesko (p. 74) for a list of spell numbers in P. Gardiner III and corresponding line numbers.  P. Gardiner II in the British Museum also contains hieratic coffin texts and may be dated to the same period as this text.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyh">Hieratic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ;</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">On recto: 13 lines in hieratic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto: Coffin texts</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="-2374" notAfter="-2061">XXIVth - XXIst century B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyh">Hieratic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Funerary</term>
               <term>Religion</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. OIM 14064, recto:  (Sp.946) (217)My love is my...my kindness is my...Horus will favor me, Nut...is for my reward(?); all that [I(?)] desire is the overflowing of what I request (218)by means of my seekers and my bringers.  They will bring me [what I] desire and what my heart requests; the god's reward is in the storehouses of the nobles (219)[...the provisions] of those who provide.  My heart is determined, my foes are under my left sandal, for I am the Eye of Horus (220)[...the Eye of] Horus, the Lady of All.  The Eye of Horus has gone out after(?)...the lord.  I am a fire... (221)...under my flame.  I did not know that from this... (222)...the great rod which controls the patricians and spits out the plebes...  (223)O you who rage, the retinue of the god, O you gods, spirits and the dead who serve me and worship me, I will give you air, for I am...I am Wadjet, I have possessions(?), I am a monkey.  (Sp.947) (224)O you who lack(?)...you who are pure, you who are primeval(?), you who are enduring...I am Wadjet, (225)I am...pre-eminent in the per-wer, the fiery serpent in the per-neser, I have appeared that I may control (226)those who make offering, and my foundation is made for me among the kings.  I will not protect a misdeed(?); is there any protection by me for his misdeed?  (Sp.948) (227)...the Four, living and equipped, who went out from Dep, the supports of the sky, the company of the gods, and Bubastis...he who is worshipped and her greedy ones, who fetched her possessions.  (Sp.949) (228)I know you, I know your names, I live as you, I come into being as you, I will leap up and I will run to you.  (As for) you older gods (229)who would oppose(?) me, I will be conducted on the path of my warrant.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
