<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Qur'an</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.7842</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)7842</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">O.I. 16964</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Surah 1:1-2:58 (later addition and followed by ruled, unwritten pages sufficient to fill the gap); 2:158-12:45 (original) (The Mecca and Medinah systems are used with 5 of the 10 surah titles.  In the other 5 cases, the verse counts differ considerably from any usually accepted systems.)</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Text area measures 13.5 x 20 cm.  Aside from the surahs, the only text divisions indicated are the hizb and its quarters.  A circular, marginal ornament marks the hizb; it consists of an inner area of yellow with hizb traced in Kufic, a circular band of white with large green dots alternating with small red ones, and an outer band of yellow divided into quarters, with red dots and "finials" projecting at the division points.  The quarter-hizb divisions are marked in the text; their symbol is a small circular device similar to the marginal ornament, but without any writing and without the outer yellow band.  The Kufic surah titles are written in yellow, outlined in the brownish-black ink of the manuscript.  Except for Surah 7, each occupies not more than one line of script, and sometimes even this line is shared with the last words of the preceding surah.  The bismillah occupies a full line.  In a single instance (folio 65a, Surah 7), a panel marks the surah division, occupying the space of 4 lines of script.  The panel is rectangular and consists of a central green background on which the Kufic title is written in yellow, a twist band of black and white, and a wider twist band of black and yellow, the whole outlined in red with red "finials" placed diagonally at the corner.  A circular palmette-like ornament in yellow, surrounded by red and green dots and a green border, extends into the outer margin.  The only other decorative feature is a circular marginal ornament indicating a sajdah (folio 74a).  2 equilateral triangles intertwine to form a 6 pointed star.  In the central hexagonal area the word sajdah is left white on a background of red.  The rest of the space is filled with yellow.  An outer rim is filled with red, yellow, and green dots and finished off with yellow "finials."    The binding is western, probably English.  It consists of binder's board covered with marble paper, with a brown leather back and corners.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto and verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>paper ; 19.5 x 28.0 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Fine thin paper.  The 70 original folios were supplemented with 8 new folios at the beginning and 15 new folios at the end, with the first 16 folios interleaved.  The manuscript is in good condition, except for the binding.  Leaves are missing between folios 40-41 and 89-90.  The two leaves have been cut out, leaving only the inner margin, which bears traces of the script.  They belonged to the original manuscript, but since the present text is continuous, they may have been cut out by the original scribe because of some scribal errors.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">109 folios with 21 lines per page in Arabic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto and verso: Qur'an</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Carefully executed Qur'anic Maghribi script.  Diacritical points are fully used except those for final f, q, n, and y.  The modern vowel signs are also fully used and, with the shaddahs, are in red.  A yellow and green dot indicate hamzah and waslah respectively.  The alif of prolongation is in red.  Where it follows the lam, the scribe has written it before the lam.  The surah titles and the word hizb are written in ornamental Kufic of fair execution.  The manuscript is well-written.  Scribal errors are few, consisting chiefly of omissions, which have been carefully supplied in the margin by the original scribe.  Reading symbols are lacking, except s for silah or waslah.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="1204" notAfter="1394">VII-VIIIth century A.H.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Islam</term>
               <term>Qur'an</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">paper</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
