<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Donation document</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.6</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)6</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. O.I. 25262 (P. Chic. Haw. 4)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">It was found rolled inside of P.Chic.Haw. 9 (P. O.I. 25263)</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto and verso</note>
                     <note type="related">P. O.I. 25263 (P. Chic. Haw. 9)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyd">Demotic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>papyrus ; 108.0 x 36.5 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto: 5 plus right margin lines in Demotic; Verso: 12 lines in Demotic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto: Donation; On verso: Witness list</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="-0292">March 4-April 2, 292 B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Hawara, in the Fayum district, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Ankhmerwer, son of Patinaneterw and Ankhet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Patiwsir, son of Ankhmerwer and Naneferibptah</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Paynetweret, son of Wennefer</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pagay, son of Patiimen</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nakhthor(?) son of Patihor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ankhmerwer, son of Patiwsir(?), the elder</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">witness list with 12 names</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyd">Demotic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Sobek town, Hawara; necropolis of Pabwenyem; necropolis of Waherqer</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. O.I. 25262 (P. Chic. Haw. 4)  recto: (1) Year 13, first month of the season peret, of Pharaoh Ptolemy. The god's sealer and embalmer Ankhmerwer, son of Patinaneterw, whose mother is Ankhet, has declared to the god's sealer and embalmer Patiwsir, son of Ankhmerwer, whose mother is Naneferibptah: ''My son, I have given to you the two-thirds (of) my share of my hous[es] which are built (and) provided (with) beam and door.  Their specification: my shares of (?) this house which is (in) the temple of Sobek (precinct), (2) which measures 21 divine cubits from south to north and measures 22 divine cubits (from) west (to) east; also, the two-thirds of my house which is in the Sobek town, Hawara, which measures 18 divine cubits from south to north and 19 divine cubits (from) west (to) east; also, two-thirds of the houses which are mine(?); and the half of the houses which I shall acquire from today onward: the halves of my shares in the necropolis of Hawara and in the necropolis of Pabwenyem; also half the shares (3) which were given to me from the share of Patinaneterw, my father, in the necropolis of Hawara and the necropolis of Waherqer(?); and the half of the share which I bought from the god's sealer and embalmer Paynetweret, son of Wennefer; and the half of the share of Pagay, son of Patiimen, and the half of the shares which I shall acquire in the necropolis and the half of all and everything which I shall acquire from today onward. They are yours from today onward.  No one in the world shall (4) be able to exercise control over the aforesaid shares except you from today onward.  They are yours and the legal right to them.  As for any son of mine at all who will come against you regarding the shares, of which the specifications are written above, from today onward, he must give you 100 silver (deben) in staters, being 500 staters, being 100 silver (deben) in staters again within ten days of his coming against you regarding them, of necessity and without delay, while you will still have claim on him not to hinder you with regard to them. (5) Yours are the two-thirds of my male servants and the two-thirds of my female servants which belong to me from today onward.'' Written by Nakhthor(?) son of Patihor.  [Right Margin:] Ankhmerwer, son of Patiwsir(?), the elder.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
