<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Qur'an; a waqf for the mosque of Sultan Mu'ayyad 815-824/1412-1421</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.7833</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)7833</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">O.I. 12029 b</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Surah 15:7-16:108; 16:112-128; 36:34-40; 40:5-8, 18-22, 27-47; 47:32-37 (It is impossible to determine the verse count system, since the contents of this manuscript are surahs and verses that are counted alike in all systems.)</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">This manuscript has many points in common, in script and decoration, with O.I. 12030 a dated 840/1436.  Text areas measure 16.5 x 25 cm.  Small 8 petaled whirling gold rosettes with alternating red and blue outer dots, mark the ends of verses.  5 and 10 verse divisions are indicated by blue and gold marginal ornaments containing the words khamsah and 'ashr written in Kufic.  The 5 verse ornament is a circle surmounted by a triangular design, the 2 forming an almond.  A vertical line projects above and below.  The 10 verse division ornament is a larger circle of gold, divided into 6 or 8 equal sections surrounding the central portion, which contains the word 'ashr.  A wide blue band encircles the gold, while dots or V's mark the divisions.  At the beginning of a surah is a wide panel of gold and blue, with red dots sparingly used.  The surah title and number of verses are written on a background of gold in a close thuluth hand with free use of the mudghamaah and the muqawwarah forms of the letters.  Gold arabesques on a background of blue fill the rest of the panel.  A gold band and a key pattern complete the panel, which is then outlined in very dark blue.  A gold and blue almond filled with a delicate arabesque extends into the outer margin.  Juz' divisions are marked by 2 ornamental pages.  A sajdah is indicated by marginal ornaments of gold and blue with convex arcs at the ends and concave arcs between with that word written within, surrounded by an arabesque, on a background of gold.  The cover of Nos. 18 and 23-25 is made of layers of manuscript paper.  The leather is dark red, unevenly worn and faded and much damaged by worms, especially along the back strip.  The inside is covered with plain paper crudely covered red.  The cover design is simple and blind-tooled, consisting of a small central arabesque and corner pieces.  The flap is similarly treated except for a slight difference in the arabesque motif.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto and verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>paper ; 27.8 x 37.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Some pages are worm-eaten, others are partly torn away.  Edges are worn and marginal ornaments are much damaged.  The paint used for outlining has eaten through the paper, causing the ornaments to break away and in some cases to fall out.  Some of the ornaments seem to have been deliberately cut out.  Nos. 18 and 23-25 came to the Oriental Institute in one loose cover measuring 30 x 41.9 cm, which is too small for No. 18 and too large for the others.  The red has oxidized and so now appears brown.  The script in the panels appears to be a very dull dark blue, but was likely painted over with white, as white traces can be seen in the sajdah ornament.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">51 folios with 5 lines per page in Arabic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto and verso: Qur'an</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The thuluth is fully pointed and voweled in the same black ink.  The extended forms of the thuluth letters are the ones most frequently used.  These give the script an open and uncrowded appearance.There are no reading symbols or notations.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="1398" notAfter="1494">IXth century A.H.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Islam</term>
               <term>Qur'an</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">paper</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
