<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Coffin texts</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.5534</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)5534</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. OIM 14068</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">See also OIM Photo 27345.  Measurements not given.  Undated.  Allen questioningly dated this papyrus to the 6th dynasty (c.2374-2191 B.C.).  (Allen, p. 31)  Gardiner preferred a First Intermediate Period date (c.2190-2061 B.C.).  (See Willems, p. 246, n. 24.)  Mathieu dates it to the end of dynasty 6 and cites other scholars' datings, as well.  (See BdE 139, p. 254 and n.59-60.)  Dates follow D.B. Redford (ed.), The Oxford Encyclopedia of Ancient Egypt (2001).  The numbers for the entire papyrus are OIM 14059-87.  See Lesko (p. 74) for a list of spell numbers in P. Gardiner III and corresponding line numbers.  P. Gardiner II in the British Museum also contains hieratic coffin texts and may be dated to the same period as this text.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyh">Hieratic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ;</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">On recto: 17 lines in hieratic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto: Coffin texts</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="-2374" notAfter="-2061">XXIVth - XXIst century B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyh">Hieratic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Funerary</term>
               <term>Religion</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. OIM 14068, recto:  (Sp.957) (275)...I have...the bark of acclamation.  Shout!  I have fashioned the bark of acclamation.  I have ascended to the upper sky, and I have fashioned Nekhbet.  (276)...to the lower sky of Re, and I have fashioned Sekhmet.  I have power in the shrine, for I have nourished Re; I have traversed the middle sky.  (277)...Re-Atum for him, because I am Maat in these manifestations of hers which are upon and in the middle of Nekhbet, the entire Vulture...  (278)...Re lives thereby every day; if life...my [nose]; if he be a noble, I will be a noble, the love of him... (279)...in the midst of herself, because what is disliked is that [Seth] should see... (280)...the young Horus on the lap of Re as a protection...[so sa]ys Re of me.  If I do not place [him] (281)Heneg who is astray(?) will not place me.  May my eyes be open and may he clear my vision, so that I may not fear Apep the Wanderer(?), (282)and [he] will never see Maat or Re, so that you may not be afraid, O Re; if Horus be content, Maat will be content.  O you who are on high within the doors (283)...[of] Nekhbet, the double doors will be opened, Re will shine, the powers of Seth will be sealed off(?).  O you who are in the Suite who see the young Horus, if he be a child, I will be a child (284)...so that I may not be afraid.  (285)...I am that Maat who is in the midst of Nekhbet, who loves Re, Mistress of eternity, Mistress of the limits of [sky] and earth...be destr[oyed] because she se[es].  (286)I am within my mother the Mistress of Pe and mine is her Pe.  Re has installed me within Nekhbet, in the midst of Nekhbet, (287)...the great ones [have po]wer over me.  If I see Re, Re will see me; may Re flourish and be glad, for I myself am alive (288)[and glad(?)].  I will [reapp]ear, for I have guided my father Re, I have received his year's bread and his thrice daily beer.  O every god and every spirit (289)...my fair and true...when I appear [as] him who is in Nekhbet; may I ascend to the sky as Horus of the Netherworld, may I descend to the lower sky as Shestet (290)...his power for I am one who passes...within...(291)...sky and earth, your deserts of the nomads come to you...</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
