<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Qur'an</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.7839</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)7839</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">O.I. 12031</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Surah 16:45-93; 17:18-71</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Text area measures 37 x 55.5 cm.  A large 12 petaled whirling gold rosette with large green center and red dots around the edge marks off each verse.  These rosettes are not very well done.  Each 10 verse grouping is indicated by a large circular ornament in the outer margin.  On a small central circle with red background, the word 'ashr is written in gold in Kufic letters.  A ring of white paint separates this inner portion from the larger outer area, which is covered with gold leaf.  2 blue rings, the outer with "finials," complete the ornament.  These marginal ornaments are carefully done.  Since they differ in color scheme from the rosettes included in the text, it is not likely that they were done by the same person.  It may be that the verses were originally separated by small blank spaces and that the rosettes between them are later additions.  The hizb division scheme is apparently not used, since no note is taken of the beginning of the 28th hizb, though the sajdah which goes with it is written in the margin.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto and verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>paper ; 55.0 x 76.0 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The paper is heavy in weight, but light in color, well-smoothed, but not overly glossy.  All pages except the first, which is much rubbed and somewhat stained, are in good condition.  The 8 folios are sewn together with heavy twine, and the back still shows remnants of paste and coarse cloth used in the binding.  Bits of several leaves on either side of the bound section give evidence of hasty and violent handling and lead one to suspect that these 8 leaves were torn off and "lifted" from a larger section.  Gatherings are of 12 folios, but the inner two double folios have been removed, and with them has gone the beginning of Surah 17.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">8 folios with 11 lines per page in Arabic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto and verso: Qur'an</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Letter forms are those of the thuluth, but size of the strokes, both in width and height of the alif, is roughly twice that of the usual thuluth specimens.  The mabsut or comparatively straight and extended types of thuluth letters are used consistently, with the exception of mudghamah r, which is used only when it follows certain letters.  Embodying these two factors of size and straight strokes, this may well be a specimen of thuluthain script.  The writing is very carefully done in heavy black ink.  The text is fully pointed and voweled.  Later corrections have been made in a small hand in red ink.  The word Allah is throughout written in gold, outlined in black.  The word sajdah, occurring only once, is written the same.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="1495" notAfter="1591">IXth-Xth century A.H.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Islam</term>
               <term>Qur'an</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">paper</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
