<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Qur'an</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.7836</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)7836</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">O.I. 12033</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Surahs 4:171-5:3</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">The manuscript is undated, but paper and general decorative scheme place it with the Mameluke Qur'ans of the 9th century.  The text area measures 10.5 x 17.6 cm.  A border of two red lines inside a thicker gray-blue line encloses the 5 lines of script.  An 8 petaled whirling rosette with red and blue points marks the ends of verses.  Marginal ornaments in gold, red, and blue, with the word khamsah in Kufic, mark the 5 verse divisions.  Surah 5 is introduced by a panel of gold clouds on a blue background, framed in a gold border.  Title and number of verses are written in white (now mostly rubbed off) on gold.  The Kufan verse count of 176 verses for Surah 4 appears in the heading of Surah 5, doubtless by a scribal error.  The verse count in Surah 4, however, is not Kufan, for the manuscript has only 175 verses, which is the verse count of Basrah and the Hijaz.  The count for Surah 5:1-3 differs from any given by Spitaler and also from that of O.I. 12029 d.  The paperboard, made of layers of old manuscripts, is covered with dark brown leather.  The back strip is reinforced with coarse brown cloth, which still has some paste remnants.  The inside is lined with fine light leather with an all-over design of blind-tooled arabesques.  On the outside of the cover is a central 8 lobed circular medallion with "finials."  The medallion contains right angles, twists, and gold punches.  2 twist designs in rhomboid form with gold punches are placed one above and one below the central medallion.  The lobes of the latter are adapted for the corners.  The frame consists of several blind-tooled lines enclosing a band of intersecting arcs.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto and verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>paper ; 18.5 x 27.4 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The paper is considerably discolored, margins are roughened, and lower outer corners are much worn and patched.  The front cover and part of the back strip are all that survive of the binding.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">8 folios with 5 lines per page in Arabic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto and verso: Qur'an</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Large, open thuluth, fully dotted and voweled, all in heavy black ink.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="1398" notAfter="1494">IXth century A.H.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Islam</term>
               <term>Qur'an</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">paper</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
