<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Book of the Dead</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.5427</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)5427</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. OIM 9787 (3)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Undated.  Presented by Martin A. Ryerson.  Dates follow D.B. Redford (ed.), The Oxford Encyclopedia of Ancient Egypt (2001).;Square brackets [ ] denote lost text and lines ; ; indicate uncertain text.  Braces { } denote superfluous words and parentheses ( ) indicate elements supplied, comments or emended text.;There are vignettes associated with BD 16-7, 21, 23-8, 30, 64, 31-3, 35-41, 43, 45, 47, 46, 44, 48, 53, 50, 54-5, 52, 57, 59, 56, 63, 65-6, 68, 71-87, 89, 90, 88, 91-4, 98-9, 95, 100-7, 109-10, 112-5, 119, 116-7, 124-36, 138, 137, 140, 143-62, 191.  Most, if not all, of the vignettes were evidently sketched in ahead of the text, and the latter did not always fit as the artist had planned.  (Allen p. 19);BD 110b consists of 3 registers.  Top register: Three cities are named in ovals: ''Qen{q}qenet, (Hetepet), and the City of the Great One.''  Then follows a statement: ''Existing as Hotep, lord of the fields, with breath in (his) nose.''  The scene below shows ''Osiris N. justified'' presenting a ;round cake; to a bird-soul perched on ;tomb;, a falcon on a shrine, and three enthroned deities whose figures overlap.  The falcon is called ''Hotep, great god, lord of the sky.''  A second scene shows ''Osiris N. justified'' ''paddling in Hotep's lake.''  In the third scene Thoth serves as scribe, while ''Osiris N. justified'' followed by two associates offers incense to ''the Great Ennead.''  Middle register: At top are named four ;islets;: ''the Peaceful, Anet-wadj(-wer), the Verdant, and ....  The area is described as ''(the lake) of the hippopotamus, 1000 leagues in length and of untold breadth, containing no fish, no snakes, and no plants.''  The scene below shows deceased ''plowing'' in a region ''the length of which is (the length of) the sky.''  Then follow sowing, reaping, threshing, and two heaps of grain.  Beyond these deceased appears seated on the ground under the word ''overflow,'' then standing ''presenting the overflow'' to ''the Inundation, father of the gods.''  Bottom register: An island at upper right is labeled ''Seat of the blessed.  (The height of its barley) is 7 cubits, its stalk(s) 3 cubits.  It is the blameless mummy that reaps them.''  Another island, below, is ''the birthplace of the god.  This city is Qen(q)enet.  The God who is in it is Re.''  In another water-surrounded area below stands a flight of steps behind three seated deities, ''(they) who eat it: Shu, Tefnut, and Geb.''  In ovals at upper left are four place names: ''Djef(a)t, (Hezat), the Powerful, and the United.''  Below float two barks, each on its own canal.  That at left is ''the bark of Re-Harakhte when he crosses to the Field of Rush(es).''  That in center is described as ''the holy throne; the god who occupies it is Unnofer.''  Uncertain legends are ;zeh mw; (T: ;azehen mw; pet), possibly ''disturbing the water,'' above the pair of barks, and ;rekhyt, ''common folk,''; as name of a ;pool; at lower left.  BD 110c is a vignette only, in four registers, each under its own sky.  At top a beardless deity squats enshrined on a bark behind which stand Isis and Nephthys.  In the next panel deceased stands praying while Harpocrates presents offerings to enthroned Osiris flanked by standing Isis.  In each of the bottom two registers, deceased kneels while presenting offerings to two squatting gods.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyh" otherLangs="egy-Egyp">Hieratic; Hieroglyphics</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>10 papyri ; 924.0 cm x 39.0 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The manuscript now starts a little after the beginning of vignette BD 16.  Aside from the initial loss, other damage is slight.  A pointed object had been thrust into the papyrus while it was rolled.  Some seventy holes near the lower edge, gradually decreasing in size toward the end until they cease in BD 148 b, probably represent two thrusts at opposite sides of the roll.  If only one thrust were involved, the roll as we have it would have been just over 3 cm in diameter; but its 924 cm length could scarcely have been rolled into such small compass.  (P. OIM 10486 is only 1/9 as long, but formed a roll about 6.4 cm in diameter when purchased.)  But P. Ryerson could not be checked directly, for it was already mounted in ten frames.  At both beginning and end, it had also been broken across in four places each, and there are minor breaks elsewhere.  (Allen p. 16)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">On recto: 157 columns in hieratic, 3 columns in hieroglyphics</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto: Book of the Dead</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The hieratic signs, when checked against G. Moeller, Hieratische Palaeographie III (1912), show forms varying from the 20th dynasty to about A.D. 60.  In selection and arrangement of spells, P. Ryerson is most similar to L 3079 (de Rouge, 1861-76, pls. V-XX), both having unusual additions.  They share strange writings and even errors, e.g. in BD 64 (cf. especially its S 12 f. and 15).  Hence they probably go back to a common ancestral manuscript.  Similarities with T (Lepsius, 1842) are also numerous.  Hieroglyphics occur only in BD 110b, 125d, 148b, 161S, 191-2, and the final offering formulas.  A note in demotic is added below BD 140.  All of the writing is in black.  The vignettes are colored in red, light and dark blue, green, yellow, brown, and white.  R, then, differs from Ptolemaic copies of BD.  The latter, as Daressy has mentioned, are generally written in crowded hieratic, with vignettes merely sketched in black, sometimes set off by a little red.  The scribe wrote with a consistent and steady hand.  He evidently checked his work, for the corrections are largely his.  But another, more angular hand has interlined name, etc. of deceased here and there (especially col. c) and made occasional other additions (cf. col. cxlviii).  The artist who did the vignettes was presumably a different person.  His work shows a good feeling for form, yet sometimes there is squattiness of figure (cf. overlapping scepter-bearers in col. liv) or unevenness of line (cf. kilt of deceased in cols. xxxix and xli).  (Allen p. 19)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="-0525" notAfter="-0031">VIth - Ist century B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Osiris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Unnofer</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Atum</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Re</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Shu</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Min</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Isis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nephthys</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Authority</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Perception</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Seth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thoth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Imset</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hapi</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Duamutef</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Qebehsenuf</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Whom His Father Sees</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Is Under His Moringa Tree</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horus with No Eyes in His Forehead</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anubis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Asdez</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dozer</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Bull Who Gives No Glow from His Hot Breath</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Observant One in His Prime</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Sees by Night Him Whom He Carried Off by Day</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tefnut</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Geb</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Carried Off His Portion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Shezmew</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nefertem</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Bastet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khepri</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Swallower of Millions</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Keen One</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Baba</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Master of His Affairs</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sokar</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ruty</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptah</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Uto</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Amon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Suty</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Upwawet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Baby</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nut</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sekhmet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tatenen</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phoenix</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">the Disk</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menkaure</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hardedef</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Soped</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Selqet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Rerek</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Neit</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hathor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khnum</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apophis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Is Over the Colors</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Sees Millions of Years Twice</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Imperishables</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ihy</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Inundation</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Seshat</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Baby</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sothis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Rekem</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Remrem</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Akhezzef</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tayt</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khonsu</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sobk</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Bibi</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ash</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Akhkhew</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menqet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harakhte</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sesha</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hotep</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpocrates</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Akhem</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Renenutet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Truth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Fate</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Luck</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Spirit of Contentment</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Blessed One</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Magician</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khasety</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Wenty</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sutekh</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Montu</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">the Deep</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Zepa</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horus Khentekhtai</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onuris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aachbyt</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Adjen</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Adj</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ned</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Born of the Two Lips</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sound of Mouth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Opener of the Ways</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Clear</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Asb</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hurler of the Two Knives</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Feller of Fish</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">The Offering Descends</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heh</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ded</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mut</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyh">Hieratic</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyp">Hieroglyphics</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Heracleopolis; Hermopolis; Heliopolis; Maat-lake; Rosetau; Naref; Abydos; Field of Rushes; Mendes; Busiris; Letopolis; Punt; Kheraha; Pe; Dep; Washerman's Shores; Memphis; Aqa-reach; Field of Offerings; Wednet; Turah; Khemmis; Ishru; Xois; Upper Egypt; Lower Egypt; Debew; Athribis; Qenqenet; Hetepet; City of the Great One; the Peaceful; Anet-wadj-wer; the Verdant; Djefat; Hezat; the Powerful; the United; Anpet; Hierakonpolis; Matat; Akhmim; Wenes; Bubastis; Fayyum; City of the Two Truths; Pomegranate; Xoite nome; Weryt; Sais; Wenes; Nedjfet; Atef; Asyut; Antaeopolis; Egypt; Sebeg; Bahbit; Aswan; Ra-antywy; 'Apret; Zekret; the Overflow; Nedit; Pesegro; Atef-wer; Shenew; Hekenew; Shaw; Peqer; Heni; Bedshew; Tayt; Sia; Siatyw; Lake Land; Pelusium; Qawyt;Ass-region; She Keeps Silence; Adew-abode; Elephantine; Heqehqed</term>
               <term>Funerary</term>
               <term>Religion</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. OIM 9787 (3), continued: (lxix) (BD94)Behold me; (14)I am a scribe ?through what has been written for me?.  Bring me the putrid effluent of (16)Osiris, that I may write (there)with.  I do what the god great of beauty has said (18)every day.  My beauty is the beauty that Re-Har(akhte) assigns me.  (20)I do righteousness, that I may go unto Re every day.  (21)(BD 95)Spell for opening beside Thoth.  (22)To be said by Osiris N.: (25) It is I who was terror among the raging, who was guardian of the Coil in the conflict.  (28)I smote the violent one, Ash; I cool(ed) Ash off.  I acted in behalf of the house of the Great One (in the conflict).  (31)I steadied the sharp knife in the hand of Khepri ?among? the raging.  (lxx)(BD96)Spell for opening beside Thoth and putting the blessed (3)into the god's domain.  To be said by Osiris N.: (8)I am the center of his eye; I have come to give truth to Re.  (11)I have appeased the King of Upper Egypt with the spittle (of the Earth-God (and) with) blood from (14)Geb's worthy ones.  (BD 97)To be said (15)in the Night Bark.  (O) scepter (of) Anubis, I have appeased those blessed ones who are in (18)the retinue (of) the lord{s} of (offerings).  {Variant:} I am (lord of) fields; (20)I am (father) of the overflow that drives away (my) thirst and guardian of (the pool).  (23)Just see me, ye Great and powerful gods who preside over the Souls (26)of Heliopolis.  I am high above your head(s); I am the beneficent one who is in (29)your heart(s).  Behold, I reverence (my) Soul, a Great and powerful one; I have not been given over to (32)that harm that came forth from your mouth(s).  (It) is gone; it turned not upon me.  (35)I purified myself in the pool for appeasing the judge with the divine fillet under the sycamores (38)of the god's possessions in the sky, while all the previous triumphant ones were refreshing themselves.  (41)Arrive, come to me, (hasten), truth, (for mine is) the correct and upright one who is in the earth.  I am (the interpreter of his speech), (44)the Might of the sole Lord Re the great, who lives on truth.  (46)(Do) no harm (against) me; unveil the day first of all.  (lxxi) (BD 98)Spell for bringing the ferry.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)Hail to thee, thou district that is in the northern sky in the (6)great lake.  He who sees (thee) dies not.  I stand upon (thee), appearing (8)as a god.  I see (thee, and) I die not as I stand; (10)I live, appearing as a god.  I honk as a semen-goose; (12)I weep as that falcon over the ?fragrant pate of? the Great One.  (15)I cross the earth to the Sky, I stand as Shu.  Akhkhew stands firm, (17)supporting the ladder that lets the Unweariable (Stars) ascend exempt from (20)decapitation.  I have brought these warders-off of evil as I pass by the waret of Ptah.  (24)'' Whence hast thou come (to) Ptah?''  (I have come) from the sea of fire and from the fields of flame.  (27)''What dost thou live on in the sea (of) {my} fire and in the fields of flame?''  I live (30)on that august tree.  ''O planner, bring to him these ships from ?the twin (33)hair-lakes?--to the well and comfortable one.''  I stand up in the bark and rule (35)the water as a god.  I stand, ?trunk{s} and branches?, (when) the traveler embarks.  Opened (38)for me are the gates in Letopolis; set aside for me are fields (41)in Hermopolis.  Given me is shenes-bread in the presence of the Heir.  (lxxii) (BD 99)Spell for bringing the ferryboat in the god's domain.  To be said by Osiris N.: (2)O thou who bringest the ferryboat from the deep over yon bad shoal, bring me the ferryboat, (4)attach for me the towrope, in peace, in peace.  Come, come; hasten, (5)hasten.  I have come to see for myself my Father Osiris.  O lord of red linen, who controllest hearts, O lord of storm, (7)virile one who sails over that shoal of Apophis, O thou who attachest heads and keepest necks firm by escape (8)from wounds, O attendant of the mysterious ferryboat, (thou) who restrainest Apophis, bring me the ferryboat, (9)attach for me the towrope, that I may go forth from it, this difficult terrain where the Topsy-turvy (Stars) fall (on) their face(s) (10)and cannot rise (again).  (O) sprightly one who passes by in the flame of Re, encircler who guides the Two Lands (11)while Geb (remains) (as) their steering oar, Might of the Sky, opener of the Disk, in charge of the red (fishes?), bring me, leave me not boatless.  (12)''(Come,) thou blessed one; then will I proceed to the place whereof thou knowest.''  ''Tell me my name,'' says the mooring pin.  Lady of the Two Lands in the Shrine is (13)thy name.  ''Tell me my Name,'' says the mallet.  Leg of Apis is thy name.  ''Tell me my Name,'' says the bow rope.  Tress (14)That Anubis Presents with Swather's Work is (thy) name.  ''Tell me my name,'' says its ?spindle(s)?.  {They are} A(a)wt's (15)of the God's Domain is thy name.  ''Tell me my name,'' says the ?(mast) socket?.  Darkness is thy name.  ''Tell me my name,'' says the mast{s}.  He Who Fetched the Great One (16)when She Was Far Away is thy name.  ''Tell me my name,'' says the (lower) halyard.  {It is} Abode of Upwawet is thy name.  ''Tell me my name,'' (17)says the masthead.  Windpipe of (Imset) is thy name.  ''Tell me my name,'' says the sails.  Nut is thy name.  ''Tell (me) (18)my name,'' says the halyard-bags.  Ye are made of the hide of the Mnevis-bull.  Seth's ?Dipper? is your name.  ''Tell me (19)my name,'' say the oars.  {They are} Fingers of Horus the Elder is your name.  (''Tell me my name,'') (say) the planks in the hull.  Imset, (20)Hapi, Duamutef, Qebehsenuf, Ruler, Taker by Force, He Who Sees His Father Who Made His Body, and He Who Made His Own Name are (21)your name(s).  ''Tell me my name,'' says the ?joinery?.  Presider over the Garden(s) is thy name.  ''Tell me my name,'' says the iby(st).  ?Singer? is (22)thy name.  ''Tell me my name,'' says the steering oar.  Exact One, Sunbeam in the Hidden Water, ?Bough? is thy name.  ''Tell me my name,'' says the ship.  (23){It is} Leg of Hathor that Re cut off with knife in outstretched hand when he brought (her) to the night bark is thy name.  ''Tell me my name,'' says (24)the boatman.  {It is} Rebuffer is thy name.  ''Tell me my name,'' says the breeze, ''before thou sailest with (me).''  North Wind That Came Forth from Atum (25)to the Nose of the Presider Over the West is thy name.  ''Tell me my name,'' says the river, ''before thou crossest over me.''  Their Beholder is thy name.  ''Tell me (26)my name,'' say the banks.  Annihilator of the Long-armed One in the Tomb is thy name.  ''Tell me my name,'' says the ground, ''before thou treadest (upon) me.''  (27)Nose of the Sky, escaped from (the embalmers) who are in the Field of Rushes, escaped while (his) Father rejoices, is thy name.  To be said facing (28)them: Hail to you, goodly of persons, lord(s) of Truth, who stay alive forever (for) the periods of eternity.  (29)Verily I gain access to you.  Put ye for me the offering list at my mouth, that (I) may speak therewith, (my) cake being baked and my seat (being spacious) (30)before the great god.  I know {of} that great god of yours at whose nose ye place provisions.  (31)His Name is Rekem.  He penetrates the eastern Horizon of the Sky; he enters into the western Horizon.  His name is Rekem.  If he goes, (32)I go.  I will not be ejected from the mesqet-region; transgressors shall not prevail over this my flesh.  My bread is in Pe, (33)my beer is in Dep.  Mine is the offering of this day.  The offering is barley and wheat; the offering is (34)myrrh and clothing.  The offering is life; the offering is (the right) to go forth by day in whatever form I wish.  (35)I go forth from the Fields of Rushes.  As for one who knows this spell, he goes forth from the Field of Rushes.  (36)There are given to him a cake, jars, a loaf, and fields (of) barley and wheat seven cubits (high).  It is the followers of Horus who reap (37)(them) for him.  Then he shall chew on this barley and wheat and shall wipe his body therewith, and his body shall be like (those of) (38)these gods.  He goes forth from the Fields of Rushes in {his} any form in which he may wish to go forth.  (lxxiii) (BD 100)[Spell for] making content the Soul of a blessed one and causing that he ascend to the bark of Re and his retinue.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)I shall ferry the phoenix to Abydos, Osiris to Mendes.  I have opened the cave {as} of the Inundation, (6)I smooth the way of the Disk, I draw Sokar on his sledge, and I make powerful the Great One in her instant.  (9)I have followed and praised Atum.  I have joined the (sun-)praising (baboons); I am one (of them).  I have been (the companion of) Isis; (12)I have made powerful {with} their magic spell(s).  I have attached the towrope.  I have repulsed Apophis, I have restrained his steps.  Re extends (15)his hands to me; his Crew shall not repulse me.  If I am powerful, the Sound Eye is powerful, and vice versa.  (17)As for (anyone) who keeps me away from the bark of Re, (he) shall be kept away (from) the egg and the abdjew-fish.  (19)To be said over a sheet of writing-papyrus with this spell inscribed (upon it), together with the Image of (21)this god that is sketched (therein), with powder of green glaze mixed with myrrh(-water), placed (23)at the feet of this blessed one without letting (it) come near his body.  Initiated is this blessed one (25)and caused to join the gods who are in Re's retinue when he has illumined the Two Lands before them.  (27)He embarks in the bark of Re daily, (28)and {he} Thoth looks after him.  A truly excellent spell (proved) a million times.  (lxxiv) (BD 101)Spell for protecting the bark of Re.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)(O) (traverser) of the water, who came forth from the (primeval) waters and sits on (the stern) of his bark, proceed (5)thou to thy position of yesterday.  Thou sittest on (the stern) of thy Bark, and I have joined (7)thy crew; I am an initiate.  O Re in this thy Name of Re, if (13)(thou) pass(est) by them that are yonder head downward, then (14)thou shalt (make) me stand on (my) feet.  I am an initiate.  If thou stayest sound, I stay sound.  O Re (16)in this thy Name of Re, if thou openest the mystery of the underworld, that (18)the heart of thy Ennead may rejoice, then thou shalt give me my heart.  I am an initiate.  If thou stayest sound, (20)I stay sound.  Thou hast thy body, Re, enduring by means of the spell.  (21)To be said, written with myrrh and retraced with (ink), on a strip of royal linen (23)put at the throat of the blessed one on the day of joining the earth.  (24)If (this) amulet is applied for him at his throat, (25)he shall be with the Ennead, he shall join the follower(s) of Re.  The Starry Host shall be made fast for him (27)in the Sky beside Sothis.  He shall follow Horus (who is) in Sothis, and his shadow shall be (29)a god together with his people.  Bushes (shall be made to grow) for him in his breast by Men(31)qet.  He shall be a god forever.  His body shall (be) preserve(d) in the god's domain by Thoth, who (33)himself did this for the Majesty of Osiris, to cause (34)the Light to shine upon his Corpse.  A truly excellent spell (proved) a million times.  (lxxv) (BD 102)Spell for ascending to the bark of Re.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)O Great One in his Bark, thou hast brought thy Bark, that I may sail upstream to thy ?staircase?.  Thou conductest for me thy journey (6)with these thy attendants who are among the Unweariable (Stars).  My abomination is my abomination.  I will not eat it.  (9)Dung is my abomination; I will not eat it.  My ordure, no harm shall come to me therefrom.  I will not touch it with my hands, (12)I will not step on it with the soles of my feet, because this my bread is of white wheat and my beer of red barley of the inundation.  (15)It is the night bark and the day bark that bring (them) (to) me.  ?Gifts? have been (pro)vided like barley from the altar of the Souls of Heliopolis by (...).  (18)?Praise (be)? to thee, Maker of ?Himself? in the turmoil of the sky, vulture that is on high.  ?(Even with)? these (dogs) united, (21)I ?advance?.  I come in person, (for) this god dwells there.  Those from which he suffers are these sicknesses.  I have come; I have spit on the {my} shank, (24)(I have attached) the {my} upper arm, I have raised the thigh.  I embark to sail the Bark.  (26)(BD 103)Spell for opening beside Hathor.  (27)To be said by Osiris N.: (29)I am a pure departed one, (a aas-?priest?).  (30)O Ihy, I shall be beside Hathor.  (32)(BD 104)Spell for sitting among the great Gods.  (33)To be said by Osiris N.: (35)I sit among the great Gods, having passed by the house of the Night Bark.  It is a servant, (36)the porter of Horus the Son of Osiris, who comes to me on Re's errand, (while) food and nourishment are at their appointed place to sup(37)ply offering-cakes to the great Gods.  It is a fisher and fowler whom he has brought to me.  As for one who knows this spell, (38)he sits among the great Gods.  (lxxvi) (BD 105)Spell for making a man's Spirit content in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)Hail to thee, my spirit, my lifetime.  Behold, I am come (6)unto thee risen, possessed of a soul, powerful, installed.  I (have) brought thee bed-natron (9)and incense, (that I may) purify (thee) therewith, that I may purify thy saliva therewith.  (12)Overlook thou (this) evil utterance which I have said and this evil wrong (15)which I have committed, without giving (me) over to them, for mine is this natural green papyrus-amulet that is at the throat (18)of Re and is given to the Horizon-Dwellers.  If they thrive, I thrive; as they thrive, (21)my Spirit thrives, just as my lifetime thrives, according as they say.  The provisions of my spirit are like theirs.  (24)(O) thou who weighest (in) the balance, may his Truth rise to the nose of Re by day.  (O) my spirit, (27)let not (my) head (be taken away) from (me).  (28)(For) mine is an eye that sees, mine are ears that hear.  I am not a (30)sacrificial bull; none of me shall become a mortuary offering to those who are over Nut.  (lxxvii) (BD 106)Spell for giving offerings in Memphis.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)O Great One, lord of provisions, O Great One presiding over the upper houses, (ye) who give (8)bread to Ptah, give ye me bread, give ye me beer.  My breakfast (consists) (11)of a leg (and) pastry.  O ferryman of Osiris (14)N. in the Field of Rushes, bring (to me) this (19)bread (to) thy (watery) waret as (to) thy Father, the great one who has departed (21)in the god's ship and is gone forth by day after mooring.  (24)(BD 107)Spell for going in and out of the gate of the Westerners (among) the followers of Re and knowing the Souls of the west.  (28)To be said by Osiris N.: I (31)know that gate in the middle of the Sky from which Re comes forth, the gate of the eastern Horizon of the Sky, (33)south of which are the fields of the khar{em}-geese and north of which is the water of the ra-geese, even the place from which Re sails with the stormwind.  I am in charge of announcing (36)in the god's ship.  (lxxviii)(BD 108)Spell for knowing the Souls of the west.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: As for (4)that mountain of the eastern range on which this Sky rests, it exists in (6)the eastern Horizon of the Sky.  It is 370 hundred-cubits long and 240 cubits broad.  (8)Sobk, lord of the Eastern Range, is (9)in the east of that mountain.  His Temple is of carnelian.  (11)On the summit of the mountain is a snake ?30? cubits long and 10 cubits broad, (13)whose first 3 cubits are of flint.  I know the name of this snake (who is) on his mountain; (15)He with Searing Breath is his Name.  After midday he turns (17)his eyes against Re.  Then a stoppage takes place in the bark and great amazement among the sailors.  (19)Then he gulps down 7 cubits of the high water.  Then Suty pits (himself) against (21)him, he puts his spear of metal at his neck and causes (23)him to disgorge all that he (has) swallowed.  To be said over him as a spell: Fall thou back before the (25)sharp metal that is in my hand.  I stand against thee, that (27)the bark's course be true.  (O) farseer, close for him thy eyes and veil thy head, that (29)he may cross.  Fall back before Osiris N., (for) (31)he is a male in his mother's body.  Veil thy head and cool thy upper lip, (for if) I stay sound (33)thou stayest sound.  I am the great of magic, son of Nut; given to me is this powerful spell (35)against thee.  ''What (is it), thou blessed one?''  (O) goer on his belly and his posterior, thou hast no (vertebra).  Behold, (37)Osiris N. is gone, (and) thy strength with him.  He it is who has taken over thy strength.  (40)I have come, I have disposed of the Earth-God (for) Re.  He has set in the evening after traversing this Sky, while thou art in thy bond(s).  This is what has been commanded against thee in the presence of (43)Re.  Then Re sets in the life-region (in) his Horizon.  I know the Souls of the west.  They are Atum, Sobk, lord of the eastern (45)range, and Hathor at evening--said of Isis.  (lxxix) (BD 109)Spell for knowing the eastern Souls.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: I (3)know that eastern gate of the Sky, south of which is the pool of the khar{em}-geese and north (5)of which is the water of the ra-geese, even the place whence Re sails with the stormwind.  I am (7)in charge of announcing in the god's ship; I am a tireless paddler in the bark of Re.  (9)I know that sycamore of turquoise from the midst of which Re comes forth, which grows on the (uplifted) (11)of Shu at every gate through which Re comes forth.  (12)I know that Field of Rushes, whose wall is (14)of metal, the height of (whose) barley is 7 cubits, (15)the ears 2 cubits, its stalks 4 cubits, its wheat 7 cubits, (17)the ears 3 cubits.  It is a blessed one 7 cubits tall, each of them, who reaps (19)them alongside the eastern Souls.  (20)I know the eastern Souls; they are Harakhte, the calf who is in the presence of this god, and the Morning Star.  (22)Osiris N. has built the God's city.  ''Proceed thou with them,'' says the Filler, (25)he (who) is the plumb of the scalepan.  Bull semen is in the midst of thy tongue, (O) ibis who presidest over (living) beings.  (27)Thy counsels in the House of the Snare outweigh ?traps? on papyrus, (O) (29)thou who art cool of mouth while advising.  Love of thee is with everyone, (thou) being the divine falcon on the (31)left hand, black of face, whose shoulder is likewise (black), (32)who hast ascended to the Sky with the Starry Host, bearing that coffin, and sailest on the paths without transgressing (34)the boundaries of the (fields) of the Gods.  (35)''Writings are with thee, as many as (thou) desirest, in the fields of his joy.  (And) to start with grain, wheat is there, (nourished) by the efflux (37)of Sesha.  The height of its barley is 5 cubits, the ears 1 cubit.  Reap for thyself with (39)the blessed alongside the eastern Souls; enter thou freely into the secret portals, (41)(for) thou art pure,'' say they who are in them.  ''Reach thy house by magic, gladdening the heart(s) of (43)thy fledglings.  To die again is thy abomination; eternity is thine as lifetime, as a present given as a reward.''  (45)Magnified is the eminence of Osiris N., possessor of worthiness.  (lxxxi) (BD 110) [This is a series of scenes with captions; see notes.]  (lxxxii) (BD 111)Spell for knowing the Souls of Pe.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)As for that mountain of the Eastern Range on which this Sky rests, (6)Sobk, lord of the eastern range, is in the summit of that mountain of the eastern range yonder.  His Temple is of car(nelian).  Head (9)to Whom the Mountain (Makes Obeisance) is his name.  He is 80 cubits long and 30 cubits broad, while (12)his first 4 cubits are of flint.  After midday he turns his eyes against Re.  That means the time is at hand, (and there is) (15)great amazement within his bark.  Then Seth pits (himself) against him.  He says: ''May the course be true.''  Then he says as (18)a spell: ''(O) farseer, close thou thy eyes and veil thy head.  If thou stayest sound, I stay sound; (21)it is I who have taken over strength.  Given to me is this (powerful spell) against thee.  (23)I have come, I have disposed of the Earth-God on this day at eventide.''  (25)O Osiris N., raise thyself (28)from thy left side, alive, renewed, youthful like (30)Re every day.  Thou shalt never, never die.  (lxxxiii) (BD 112)Another spell (for) knowing the Souls of Pe.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)(O) Swamp-Dweller in (the city of) Anpet in the Mendesian nome, Trappers yonder (5)in Pe, Eldest Ones who cannot come, Baker of pots, and ye who stir up loaves, know ye, (8)why Pe was given to Horus?  I know, but ye know not.  It was Re who gave it to him as recompense for (11)the injury to his eyes, on this (wise): Re said to Horus: ''Let me see this that has happened to thy eye.''  As he was examining it, (14)Re said to Horus: ''Pray look at that black pig.''  (16)After he had been looking at it, then the pains in his eye were very violent.  (18)Horus said to Re: ''Behold, my eye (feels) as (it did at) that blow which Seth struck (20)at (my) Eye.''  Then he lost consciousness.  Re said to these gods: ''Put him on his bed, that he may recover.''  Seth being come, (23)he had assumed his form of black boar.  Then he had struck the blow at the eye of Horus.  (So) Re said to these gods: (26)''Abominate the pig for Horus' sake, so that he may recover.''  (Thus) came about the great pig-abomination which these Gods, (29)his attendants, proclaimed for Horus' sake when Horus was in his childhood (and his) sacrifices consisted of his beef cattle, his small cattle, and his pigs.  As for (32)Imset, Hapi, Duamutef, and Qebehsenuf, Horus is their Father, and Isis is their Mother.  (35)Then Horus said to Re: ''Mayest thou give me my Brother in Pe and in Hieraconpolis of my company (to be) with me, (37)he being with (me by) perpetual assignment, that the earth may grow green and turmoil cease.''  (So) originated (39)his name of Horus on His Papyrus.  I know the Souls of Pe.  They are Horus, (41)Imset, and Hapi.  Lift (42)your face(s), (O) gods who are in the nether world, to Osiris N.  Behold, he (45)is become a great god.  (lxxxiv) (BD 113)Spell for knowing the Souls of Hieraconpolis.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)I know the secrets of Hieraconpolis.  They are Horus and this (5)which his mother did concerning him.  Said she: ''Pray let there be brought to us Sobk, lord of the farthest waters, that (7)he may fish (them) out.''  When he (had) found (them), his mother restored (them) to their proper place.  Then said Sobk, lord of (9)the farthest waters: ''I sought and found (them, but) they kept slipping out from under my fingers (11)at the water's edge.  (So) I netted them (12)with a net by main strength.''  That is how the net originated.  Re said: ''Well, (14)why (does) Sobk (have) fish and find Horus' {my} hands for him in Fish Land?  Say to Sobk: 'Keep secret (17)the secret about this net which brought Horus' (hands) to him.  May it be exposed to view (only) on new-crescent day (19)and midmonth day in Fish Land.' ''  Then said Re: ''I have given Hieraconpolis to Horus to (be) (21)the seat of his hands.  May his (hands) be exposed to view in Hieraconpolis after they have been brought to him, and confine (23)the (genii) that are in them on new-crescent day and midmonth day.''  (24)Horus said: ''Verily Duamutef and (Qebeh)sen(u)f have been given (to) me (to be) with me, (for) they are the ones of my company that I have kept under guard.  As for (the time) while I am there, (27)lo, the god of ?the temple? shall be silent.''  Then said Re: ''Put (them) there, even what thou hast given (29)me.  Let there be done for them what is done for those who are in Hieraconpolis.  So (shall) their corpse(s be) (31)with thee.''  Then Horus said: ''They were with thee, (but) (32)they shall be with me to hear Seth (and) his complaints.''  (Ye) Souls of Hieraconpolis, (34)(blessedness has been) g(iven) to me.  I know the Souls of Hieraconpolis.  They are Horus, Duamutef, and Qebehsenuf.  (lxxxv) (BD 114)Spell for knowing the Souls of Hermopolis.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)(There is) ?a thrust (wound)? in the shoulder.  Neit shines in the stronghold, and the eye ?consumes? him who judges (6)it.  I know and have access to it, I know who brought (8)it from Cusae; (but) I will not tell men nor repeat to gods.  I have come (10)on Re's errand (to) confirm the truth of the shoulder, (while) Neit shines in the stronghold (12)to inspect it.  (I have) come as a mighty one because of knowing the Souls (14)of Hermopolis.  The desire for knowledge is your desire.  I know the truth, counted, (16)complete, and enduring.  Hail to you, (18)Souls of Hermopolis, in accordance with your knowledge.  They are Thoth, Perception, (20)and Atum.  (lxxxvi) (BD 115)Spell for ascending to the Sky and gaining access to the underworld.  Knowing the Souls of Heliopolis.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)I grew large yesterday among the great ones; I came into being among those who had come into being.  Look upon the Eye of the One, (6)?open to (me)? the form of darkness, (for) I am one of you.  I know the Souls (8)of Heliopolis (and) him to whom (even) he whose strength is greatest has no access when passing by (and about) the extending of a hand (10)to us.  ''I give tongue(s) to the gods,'' says he who would destroy the heir of Heliopolis.  (12)I know why a tress is made for a male.  It is (because) Re spoke (to) the King of Upper Egypt in his time.  Then (15)his mouth was mutilated.  That is how the diminution on new-crescent day came about.  Said Re (to) him who was in his time: ''Take the 'thirty'-spear, (O) heir (18)of (men).''  That is how the court of the thirty originated through him who was in his time.  (So) originated the Brother-Sister Pair, (and) so originated the ?6th-day? feast, (and so) originated (21)?he who hears the (spells written on) bright red linen (bandages)? without staying of his hand.  (22)Then he assumed his tressed-woman form.  So originated the tressed one of Heliopolis.  (25)The Mighty had been bared in this temple{s}.  So originated the bared one in  Heliopolis.  When the heir of his heir comes into being, many are (28)the things he shall see; and he shall become the great of strength, the god, even the son who makes (offerings) to his Father.  (30)His portion shall become (that of) the great of strength in Heliopolis.  (31)I know the Souls of Heliopolis.  They are Re and Shu and Tefnut.  (lxxxvii) (BD 116)Spell for knowing the Souls of Heliopolis.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)(Neit) shines in Mata(t), truth has been extracted from the shoulder, and (6)the eye has been eaten by Him Who Counted It.  I have access to it by the setem-priest, (but I) will not tell men nor (9)repeat to gods, and vice versa.  I intrude not into what I know not; I see not the mysteries.  Hail to you, (12)ye gods of Hermopolis.  He who is large on new-crescent day (and) (diminished) on midmonth day--that is Thoth (15)the mysterious.  (The others) are Perception and Atum.  (17)(BD 117)Spell for taking the road in Rosetau.  (19)To be said by Osiris N.: The road of my face is (22)toward Rosetau.  It is I who clothed the great one with Greatness.  I have come, I have come; I have established offerings in Abydos.  (25)Open for me the road in Rosetau, (for) I have healed things in Osiris.  (27)I am one who created water and assigned (his) throne.  Make {my} way for me in the valley (and) in the lake of the Great One.  Make (30)way for me, ?(for) thine and his am I?.  (lxxxviii) (BD 118)Spell for reaching Rosetau.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (5)I am one who was born in Rosetau.  Magic power has been given me (b)y those who are with (8)the mummies (as) a priest of Osiris.  (I) receive (10)old age in Rosetau; I lead (the gods) through ?the (temple) doors? of Osiris.  I am (13)the way, leading to them through the twin abodes of Osiris.  (15)(BD 119)Spell for going forth from Rosetau.  To be said by (17)Osiris N.: I am (20)the Great One who created his light.  I have come unto thee (that I may praise thee) while washing away (23)thy efflux far from thee.  (24)I set up my name in Rosetau, my power in Abydos.  Pray raise (27)thyself, Osiris, that thou mayest circle this sky with Re, that thou mayest see (29)the common folk.  Sole one in the service of Re, lo, he says to thee: (31)''Osiris N. is the mummy of the god.''  (34)What he says comes to pass.  He cannot be kept away from thee, Osiris.  (36)(BD 120)Spell for going in and out.  (37)To be said by Osiris N.: ?Praise (40)to? thee, Re.  Behold, now, (things) more mysterious than the nether world: the scepter and that stake of Geb and that balance (41)of Re wherein he weighs truth every day.  Behold, I hoe the earth.  Mayest thou let me come aged.  (lxxxix) (BD 122)Spell for going in af(ter) going out of the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)Open to me, since thou art become divine through me.  ''(Who) art thou?  Where wast thou born?''  (7)I am one of you.  ''Who is it, then, that is with thee?''  (9)They are the two merty-snakes.  ''Well, whither (art) thou bound?''  Toward him who is intimately associated with the mes(12)qet-region.  He will let me cross ?by? bark to the seat of him who recognizes faces.  (14)Assembler of Souls is the name of the ferryman.  Hair-Comber is the name of (17)its oars; (Wide) Awake is the name of its bow rope.  Evil Are They is the name of (19)its ?dipper?; Dependable (and) Accurate is the name of its steering oar.  (21)Its like is gathered to it for my crossing, when (I am) put into the pool, to give me a jar (24)of milk, a cake, a loaf, a jar (of beer), and a chunk of meat from the temple (27)of Anubis.  {Variant:} All (is mine); the whole of them has been given to Osiris.  He goes in as (30)a falcon, he goes out as a phoenix.  (O) Morning Star, (make) way for him, that he may enter in (33)peace into the goodly west.  (34)He belongs to the pool of Osiris.  Make way for Osiris N., that (38)he may enter and praise Osiris the lord of life.  (xc) (BD 121)Spell for going in after going out.  To be said by (3)Osiris N.: I have gone in as (7)a falcon, I have gone out as a phoenix.  (O) Morning Star, make way for me, (10)that I may praise Re in the goodly west.  Thou who combest the hair of Osiris (13)and carest for the greyhounds of Horus, make way for me, that I may praise Osiris.  (16)To be said over (a pellet) of the ankh-amy-plant put into the (19)right ear of this blessed one and another (pellet) put into a bandage of fine linen (23)with the name of Osiris written on it on the day of burial.  (26)(BD 123)Another spell.  To be said (27)by Osiris N.: I am Thoth; (31)I judged between the Two Comrades.  (33)I did away with their fighting; I put an end to their laments.  (37)I seized the ad(w)-fish when he retreated; I (have) done what thou didst command against him.  (40)I lay down afterward (within) my eye.  I am free from harm; I have come.  (xci) (BD 124)Spell for entering the presence of the Council of Osiris.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)My Soul builds a stronghold in Mendes; my crops are in Pe.  (5)I have plowed (my) fields in (my normal) form.  (My) doum palms are as (those of) Min above th(em).  My abomination is my abomination; (8)I will not eat it.  Dung (is) my abomination; I will not eat it.  Ordure, (10)?no? harm (shall come) therefrom.  I will not touch it with my hands, I will not step on it with (12)the soles of my feet, because my bread is of white wheat and my beer of red barley (14)of the Inundation.  It is the Night Bark and the Day Bark that have brought them to me, (and) I eat (16)beneath the boughs of the tamarisks.  I know ?the bearer of the good?, (18)so that (I) shall recite for myself the hymn to the white crown and I shall wear the uraeus.  O doorkeeper of (20)the Gladdeners of the Two Lands, even these makers of offerings, mayest thou let me bring (as offering) the daughter of truth, and (22)let (the god) Akhem open to me his arm(s).  (23)May the Ennead keep silence (while) the sun-folk speak with Osiris N.  (O thou) who guidest (26)the heart(s) of the gods, (my) power protects (me) in the sky (among) the Divine Images, the Creators.  As for (28)any god or any goddess who may interfere with me, he is assigned to the progenitor(s) of Re, he is assigned to the Progenitors of the light.  (31)The sunshine is clothing the sky among the gods.  My portion is there of the bread of their (mouth(s)), ?(the mouths of) the gods?.  I have come unto the Disk, (34)I have ascended unto the Moon.  He speaks to me, his Followers the gods speak to me, (36)his sun-folk speak to me.  They who are in darkness feel terror before me within the Great Flood beside the dreadful one, (39)(for) lo, I am there with Osiris; his mat is my mat.  I tell him the words of men; I (repeat) to him the words of the gods: ''Come to me, (42)(O) equipped blessed one, (for) thou hast caused truth to ascend to (him who loves her).''  (43)I am a blessed one (better) equipped than any (other) blessed one, (as) perfect as the mummies of Heliopolis, Mendes, Heracleopolis, Abydos, Akhmim, and ?the Sanctuary?.  (46)Osiris N. is triumphant along with every god and every goddess who is hidden in the god's domain.  (xcii) (BD 125)Roll for entering into the broad hall of the Two Truths, praising the cave-gods upon reaching them, entering unto this god in the house of the nether world, and cutting a man off from his sins which he commits, so as to see the faces of the gods.  (4)To be said by N.: Hail to thee, great god, lord of the Two Truths.  I have come unto thee, my Lord, that thou mayest bring me to see thy beauty.  I know (7)thee, I know thy name, I know the name(s) of thy 42 gods that are with thee in the broad hall of the Two Truths, who live on keeper(s) of evil (9)and sip of their blood on that day of taking account of character(s) in the presence of Unnofer justified.  Behold, His Two Daughters, Lord of the Two Truths, is thy name.  Behold, I (11)know you, lords of the Two Truths.  I bring you truth; I do away with (12)sin for you.  (I) have not lied nor sinned against anyone.  I have not oppressed dependents.  I have not done crookedness instead of truth.  (14)I know not sin; I have not done anything evil.  I have not made any man work any day on account of anything he has done.  My name has not reached the bark, (16)guided so that my name would reach (it).  I have not done away with the office{s} of presenter of food(-offerings).  I have not suffered harm, I have not expired, I have not slept (the sleep of death).  I have not done what the gods abominate.  I have not slandered a servant to his superior.  (19)I have not caused (anyone) to go hungry; I have not (caused anyone) to weep.  I have not killed; I have not (commanded) killing unjustly.  I have not done injustice to anyone.  (21)I have not (diminished) the food(-offerings) in the temples; I have not debased the offering-cakes of the gods.  I have not taken the cakes ?set aside for? the blessed.  (23)I have not copulated (illicitly); I have not been unchaste, as priest of the city-god.  I have not increased nor diminished measures.  I have not added to the bal(25)ance weight; I have not (tampered) with the plumb bob of the balance.  I have not taken milk from a child's mouth; I have not driven small cattle (27)from their herbage.  I have not snared birds (for the gods') harpoon tips; I have not caught fish (for) their corpses.  I have not stopped (the flow of) water in its season; (29)I have not damned a canal while it(s water) was flowing.  I have not checked a fire in its hour.  I have not defrauded the Ennead of their haunches of meat.  (31)I have not kept the cattle of the god's property away (from their pastures).  I have not blocked the God's ascent.  (32)I am pure.  (Say) 4 times.  My purity is the purity of that great phoenix that is in Heracleopolis, because I am that nose (34)(of) the lord of the winds who keeps alive all the common folk on that day of seeking the lord of the Sound Eye in Heliopolis on the last day of month 2 of the second season in the presence of the Lord of this land.  (36)I have seen the filling of the Sound Eye in Heliopolis.  Nothing evil can happen to me in this land (in the broad hall) (37)of the Two Truths, because I know of these gods who are with thee in the broad hall (of) the Two Truths.  So (thou) shalt rescue me (39)from them.  O far-strider who came forth from Heliopolis, I have not committed sins.  (40)O open-mouthed one who came forth from Kheraha, I have not robbed.  (41)O nosy one who came forth from Hermopolis, I have not been tricky.  (42)O swallower of shadows who came forth from the twin caverns, I have not stolen.  (43)O fierce of face who came forth from Rosetau, I have not killed people unjustly.  (44)O ye Two Lion-Gods who came forth from the sky, I have not debased measures.  (45)O thou whose eye is fire who came forth from Letopolis, I have not made diminutions.  (46)O face-afire who came forth backward, who came forth from Heliopolis, I have not stolen the god's property.  (47)O bone-breaker who came forth from Heracleopolis, I have not told a lie.  (48)O thou whose breath is fire who came forth from Memphis, I have not taken away food.  (49)O Ombite who came forth from (Wenes), (...)--variant: I have not troubled (others).  (50)O ?thou of the necropolis? of Bubastis who came forth from the crypt, I have not winked--variant: I have not wept.  (51)O backward-facer who came forth from the tomb-cave, I have not done wrong sexually, {variant:} I have not practiced homosexuality.  (xciii) (1)O cavern-dweller who came forth from the west, I have not been ill-tempered--variant: I have not done harm.  (2)O hot-feet who came forth from the twilight, I have not wasted my time.  (3)O white-toothed one who came forth from the Fayyum, I have not transgressed.  (4)O blood-eater who came forth from the slaughtering-block, I have not killed the divine small cattle.  (5)O eater of entrails who came forth from the court of thirty, I have not profiteered on grain loans.  (6)O lord of truth who came forth from the City of the Two Truths, I have not robbed (bread rations).  (7)O strayer who came forth from Bubastis, I have not eavesdropped.  (8)O ?Pale One? who came forth from Heliopolis, I have not been garrulous.  (9)O doubly evil one who came forth from Busiris, I have not quarreled over property.  (10)O wammty-snake who came forth from the place of execution, I have not committed adultery.  (11)O seer of what he brought (who came forth) from the house of Min, I have not been unchaste.  (12)O superior of the Elders who came forth from Pomegranate, who came forth from Mendes, I have not inspired terror.  (13)O lord of Letopolis who came forth from the Xoite nome, I have not been hot-tempered.  (14)O troublemaker who came forth from Weryt, I have not struck a face-blow against words of truth.  (15)O child who came forth from the Heliopolitan nome, I have not transgressed.  (16)O Dark One who came forth from Darkness.  I have not quarreled.  (17)O offering-bringer who came forth from Sais, I have not done violence.  (18)O settler of argument who came forth from Wenes, I have not made trouble.  (19)O lord of men who came forth from Nedj(f)et--variant: (Atef), I have not been quick-tempered.  (20)O Counselor who came forth from Wednet, I have not harmed the divine skin.  (21)O Horned One who came forth from Asyut, I have not been garrulous about matters.  (22)O Nefertem who came forth from Memphis, I have (done) no wrong, {variant:} I have done no ill nor evil.  (23)O letter of none survive who came forth from Mendes, I have not quarreled over the King--variant: I have not reviled my Father.  (24)O Thou Who Acts as He Will who came forth from Antaeopolis, I have not waded in the water.  (25)O Ihy who came forth from the Deep, I have not been loud-voiced.  (26)O prosperer of the common folk who came forth from Sais, I have not reviled the God.  (27)O uniter of benefits who came forth from Heliopolis, I have not debased the offering-cakes of the gods, (28)I have not slandered a servant to his superior.  O Neheb-ka who came forth from (29)his hole, I have not made plots against him--(variant:) I have not exalted anyone more than him, I have not added to the (30)balance.  O Head-up who came forth from his shrine, not large have been (my) plans (31)(ex)cept with my property, (and) I have not taken away the laid-aside raiment of the blessed.  (32)O ?Carrier-off of His Portion? who came forth from the god's domain, I have not insulted the God in my heart--variant: in my face.  (33)Hail to you, ye gods.  I know your name(s).  I shall not fall to (your) sword(s).  (34)(Ye) shall not report my (wickedness) to that god in whose train (ye) are.  No affair of mine shall come before you.  (35)May ye tell the Truth for me before the Lord of the Universe, because I have done what was right in Egypt.  (36)I have not reviled the God.  No affair (of mine) has come before the King (who was) in his day.  To be said by Osiris N.: Hail to you, gods (38)who are in the broad hall of the Two Truths, in whose bellie(s) is no falsehood, who live on (39)truth in Heliopolis and swallow (it) in their heart(s) in the presence of Horus who is in his Disk.  May (40)ye rescue me from Baby, who lives on the entrails of the Elders, on that day of the great accounting.  Behold Osiris N. (42)is come unto you.  He is without sin, he is without (guilt), he is without evil, (43)he is without a witness.  Nothing shall be done against him.  He lives on truth, he sips of truth.  (44)He has been joyous of heart; he (has) done what men request and what the gods (are pleased) with.  He has gladdened the god (45)with his desire.  He has provided bread for the hungry, water for the thirsty, clothing for (46)the naked.  He has given (use of) a ferryboat (to) the boatless.  He has given offerings (47)to the gods and mortuary offerings to the blessed.  May ye indeed rescue him, may (48)ye indeed protect him {because}.  Ye shall not complain against him before the lord of mummies, (49)for his mouth is clean and his hands are clean (and he is one) (to whom is said) ''Welcome, welcome, in peace,'' (50)(b)y those who see him, because Osiris N. hear(d) (51)that important conversation which the ass held with the cat in the house of the Open- (xciv) (1)mouthed One.  ?He testifies (that)? when he looked behind him he uttered a cry.  Osiris (2)N. (saw) the splitting of the ashed-tree{s} beside him in Rosetau.  He is the fodder of the gods, who knows what is in their bellie(s).  (4)He has come hither to cause to ascend and to testify to the truth and (to) equilibrate the balance among (5)the Silent Ones.  O (god) high on his standard, lord of the atef-crown, who has ?set up? his name as lord (6)of the winds, mayest thou rescue Osiris N. from thy Messengers who are over evil and bring about punishment, (8)in whose faces is no pity, because Osiris (N.) has done the truth for the Lord of Truth.  He is (9)pure, his heart is pure.  His front is clean, his rear is undefiled, his middle is (10)the site of truth.  Not one of his members is impure.  Osiris N. purifies himself in that (southern) site, (he) rests (in) the (12)northern ?district?, in the field of grasshoppers wherein Uto purifies herself at that (13)4th hour of the night and (at the) 8th hour of the day and (s)oothes the hearts of the gods when (14)they pass by night and by day.  ''Let him come,'' say they, the gods, (of) Osiris N.  ''Who, pray, (art thou)?'' say they to him.  ''What, pray, is thy Name?'' (16)say they.  I am Osiris N., the (17)lower growth (of) the papyrus plant; He Who Is in His Moringa Tree is the name (of) Osiris N.  ''What (didst) thou pass by?'' say they to him.  (I) pass(ed) by ?shrines? (19)north of a moringa tree.  ''What, pray, didst thou see (there)?''  A leg and ?a thigh?.  ''What, pray, (20)didst thou say to them?''  (I) have seen rejoicing in the lands of the Phoenicians.  (21)''And what, pray, did they give thee?''  A firebrand and a block of green fayence.  ''What, pray, (22)didst thou do with them?''  I buried (them) on that shore of the (m)aa(t)-lake (23)by night.  ''And what, pray, didst thou find on it--that shore of the maa(t)-lake?''  (24)A scepter of flint.  ''(Didst) thou take it?'' is asked.  ''(Did) Osiris N. take it?''  ''What, pray, is (26)this scepter of flint?''  Breath-Giver is its Name.  ''What, pray, didst thou do with {it} the firebrand (27)and the block of green fayence after thou hadst buried (them)?''  Osiris N. (exulted) over them, and he took (them) out.  (29)He quenched the fire and he smashed the green block by throwing (them) (into the lake).  ''Come thou, enter (30)into the broad hall of the City of the Two Truths, (for) thou know(est us).''  ''I will not let thee enter past me,'' (31)says the jamb of this gate, ''unless thou tellest my name.''  Plumb Bob (of) the Place of Truth is thy name.  (32)''I will not let thee enter past me,'' says the right-hand ?beam? of this gate, ''unless thou tellest my name.''  Master of the Counting of Hearts is thy name.  ''I will not let (35)thee pass by me,'' says the floor (of) this gate, ''unless thou tellest my name.''  Pillar of Geb is thy name.  (36)''I will not open for thee,'' says the bolt, ''unless thou tellest my name.''  He Whom His Mother ?Announced? is thy name.  (37)''I will not open for thee,'' says the ?housing? of the bolt, ''I will not let it (the bolt) go forth,'' says the ?channel? of (38)this gate, ''unless thou tellest my name.''  Living Eye of Sobk the Lord of the Eastern Range is thy name.  (39)''Thou shalt not open to me, thou shalt not pass me,'' say the double doors, ''unless thou tellest my name.''  (Breast) of Shu when He Presented (40)Himself as Protection of Osiris is thy name.  ''We will not let thee pass by us,'' say the rails, ''unless thou tellest (41)our name.''  Brats of Renenutet is your name.  ''Thou knowest us; pass on.''  ''Thou shalt not tread upon me,'' (42)says the floor of this broad hall.  But why?  I am pure.  ''Because thou knowest not the name (of) thy feet (43)(with) which thou treadest upon (me).''  I know the name of the feet with which I tread upon thee.  ''Then tell me.''  {The seb(44)seb is mine.}  Sebseb of Ha is the name of (my) right foot; Wenpet of Nephthys is the name of my (45)left foot.  ''Tread thou upon us, for thou knowest us.''  ''(I) will not announce thee,'' says the doorkeeper, ''(un)less thou tellest my name.''  Perceiver (46)of Hearts, Searcher of Bellie(s), is thy name.  ''(To) which god on duty shall I announce thee?''  And who, (47)pray, is the god on duty?  ''The reckoner of the Two Lands will tell thee.''  And who, pray, is that--the reckoner of the Two Lands?  (48)''It is Thoth.''  ''Here I am,'' says Thoth.  ''For what purpose hast thou come?''  Osiris N. comes (49)to report.  ''What, pray?'' says he to thee.  I am pure from (50)all evil deeds.  I am aloof from the quarrels of those who are (on duty) in their day; I am not in on them.  (51)''(To) whom shall (I) announce thee?''  Announce (me) to (him) whose roof is of fire {of fire}, (52)whose wall is of living cobras, and whose floor is (of) water.  ''(Who) is he?''  He is Osiris.  ''Proceed, (53)then.  Behold, thou art announced.  Thy bread is the Sound Eye, thy beer is the Sound Eye; thy mortuary offering is the Sound Eye.''  Triumphant is (54)Osiris N. forever.  To be said by (55)a man who is pure, when he has clothed himself in new raiment, is shod with white sandals, is anointed with the finest oil of myrrh, and has presented bread and beer, oxen and fowl, burnt incense, and all (kinds of) vegetables.  Lo, copy for thyself this (text) in writing on a (56)clean ground with Nubian pigment overlaid with soil on which no small cattle have trodden.  If this roll is used in his behalf, he shall continue to thrive as (shall) his children's children, (for) he is guiltless.  He shall be an intimate of the King (and) his courtiers.  There shall be given (57)him a cake, a loaf, milk, and a chunk of meat from the altar of the great god.  He shall not be kept away from any gate of the west{erners}.  He shall be drawn with the Kings of Upper and Lower Egypt.  He shall be in the retinue (of) Osiris.  A truly excellent spell (proved) a million times.  (xcv) (Over deceased:) (1)To be said by Osiris (N.).  (Over Truth:) (2)Truth, mistress of the west.  May she cause that his (name) be in his temple, (5)associated (with) his eternal tomb.  (Over the balance:) (6)The presider over the god's hall, he says: ''The heart is exactly right (in weight), the balance being full with Osiris (N.), (10)living (forever and) ever.''  (Over Thoth:) (11)To be said by the lord of Hermopolis, the lord of the divine words: ''Put his heart in (13)its place for him, for Osiris (N.).''  (Over smaller figures:) (14)Imset, Hapi, Duamutef, Qebehsenuf, Fate, (18)Luck.  (Over offerings before devouress:) (20)Extermination of enemies (by) the devouress ?of the dead?, (mistress) of the west, in the west.  (Behind the four sons of Horus:) (23)The Birth-Goddess.  (Before Osiris in shrine:) (24)Osiris Unnofer, lord of Abydos, presider over the west, ruler of changelessness, lord of life, great one, lord of changelessness.  (Over shrine:) (28)Osiris Unnofer, lord of life, great God, ruler of changelessness, at the head of the necropolis and the silent land, presider over the west, great God, lord of Abydos, (32)King of Endless Recurrence, ruler of the living, both gods and men, great(est) (in) sky and earth, the sovereign.  (xcvi) (BD 126)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)O ye 4 baboons who sit at the prow of the bark of Re, who cause (6)truth to ascend to the Lord of the Universe, who judge between the needy and the rich, (8)who gladden the gods with the scorching breath of their mouth(s), who give divine offerings (10)to the gods and mortuary offerings to the blessed, who live on truth and sip (12)of truth, who lie not and whose abomination is sin, may (14)ye remove all evil from me, may ye blot out my sins, (for) no foulness (16)attaches to you.  May ye let me penetrate the underworld and enter into Rosetau (18) and pass through the (secret) portals of the west.  Then shall ye give me a cake and (20)a loaf like these blessed ones who go in and out of Rosetau.  (22)Pass; come thou.  I have removed thy evil, I have blotted out (24)thy sins.  What would harm thee is disposed of; I have done away with the evil that attached to thee.  Enter (26)thou into Rosetau.  Thou passest through the secret portals of the west; (28)thou goest out and in (at) will like these blessed ones.  Thou art summoned every day within (30)the horizon.  (xcvii) (BD 127)Roll for praising the cave-gods.  Said by a man on reaching them and entering to see this god in the house of the nether world.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: Hail to you, cave-gods (3)who are in the west.  Hail to you, Doorkeepers of the Gates, (4)who guard this god and report before Osiris.  Ye are clever and esteemed; ye annihilate (6)the enemies of Re.  Ye (il)lumine and dispel your darkness, (while ye see) your holy one and your Elders.  Ye live as he lives; (8)ye call to him who is in his Disk.  May ye lead me to your road, that my Soul may enter into your secrets.  I am one of you; (10)I inspire terror in Apophis, while ye do away with your (foulness) in the west.  Thou art triumphant against thy enemies, great god who is in his Disk.  (12)Thou art triumphant against thy enemies, Osiris presiding over the west, great god, lord of Abydos.  Thou art triumphant against thy enemies in sky and earth, Osiris N., (14)even southerners and northerners, westerners and easterners.  He follows Osiris presiding over the westerners; (16)he is praised before him in the valley.  He triumphs in the great Council, he triumphs in the nether world, like the Starry Host.  The flame (18) of his Soul shall consume the corpses of the dead (who) enter into misfortune and whose wrapping is (that of) the perished.  (20)(Ye) who make righteous the Souls of all the blameless blessed and serve the Sacred Land in the house of life, mistress of Souls, (22)according as Re is praised and according as Osiris is praised, may ye guide Osiris N., (24)may ye open for him the gates of the nether world.  May the earth open its twin caverns, while ye make (26)him triumph against his enemies.  May ye give offerings to Them of the Nether World.  Provide for him the turban rather than (for) its (present) wearer within the secret chamber.  (28)''Lo, thou art a great one, the true seed, the soul of a blameless blessed one; thou art one who has control of his hands,'' say they, the Two Comrades, (30)the great and exalted ones, ''(O) Osiris N.''  They rejoice over him, they praise (32)him as (one who is in) their arms.  They have given him their magical protection for living.  (33)Osiris N. has appeared as the living Soul of Re in the Sky; it has been allotted (35)to him to assume his form.  He has been made to triumph in the Council.  (36)The gate has been opened for him in sky and earth.  (Osiris N., he says: Opened for me is the gate of sky and earth) where the soul of Osiris comes to rest.  I have passed through their gate.  They rejoice (38)when they see me gone in praised and come out loved.  I have (gone on), for no fault of mine has been found and no evil (40)adheres to me.  (xcviii) (BD 128) Praising Osiris.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)Hail to thee, Osiris Unnofer justified, Son of Nut, thou first Son of Geb, Eldest who came forth (5)from Nut, King over the Abydos nome, presider over the west, lord of Abydos, lord of Souls, Great (7)of Dignity, lord of the atef-crown in Heracleopolis, lord of the Scepter in the Abydos nome, lord of the tomb, (9)great of renown in Mendes, possessor of offerings, numerous of festivals in Mendes.  Horus exalts (11)his Father Osiris everywhere, jointly with the divine Isis and her Sister Nephthys.  (13)Thoth has said for him the effective spells that are in his belly and go forth from his mouth.  The heart of Horus has been preserved (better) than (those of) (15)all the (other) gods.  Raise thyself, Horus, Son of Osiris, that thou mayest save thy Father Osiris.  O Osiris, (17)I have come unto thee; I am Horus.  (I) have saved thee alive on this day when mortuary offerings of bread and (19)beer, oxen and fowl, and all good things go forth for Osiris.  (20)Pray raise thyself, Osiris.  I smite for thee thy enemies, (I) save thee from them--I am Horus--(22)on this propitious day at the goodly dawning of thy Soul.  (23)It exalt(s thee) with itself on this day in thy Council.  O Osiris, thy Spirit comes to thee (to be) (25)with thee, that thou mayest be content in this thy Name of Spirit of Contentment.  It bless(es thee) in this thy Name (27)of Blessed One.  It praises thee in that thy Name of Magician.  It opens for thee the goodly ways (29)in this thy Name of Upwawet.  O Osiris, I have come to thee.  I put for thee thy enemies (beneath thee) (31)everywhere.  Thou dost triumph before the Ennead and the Council.  O Osiris, take (33)to thee thy mace, thy standard, and thy stairs beneath thee.  Thou presentest gifts to the Gods; thou presentest (35)offerings to those who are in their tomb(s).  Thou givest thy greatness to the Gods whom thou hast created, (O) great God.  Thou shalt be (37)with (them) as (are) their Mummies; thou shalt embrace all the Gods.  Thou shalt hear the voice of Truth (39)today.  To be said while offering to this God at the wag-feast.  (xcix) (BD 129)Roll for initiating a man and causing that he embark in the bark of Re and his retinue.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (Osiris N. ferries) the Phoenix to Abydos, (4)Osiris to Mendes.  He has opened the cave of the Inundation, he has smoothed the way (6)of the Disk, he has drawn Sokar on his sledge, and he makes powerful the Great One in her instant.  (8)Osiris N. (has) followed and praises the Disk.  He has joined the (sun-)praising (baboons); (11)he is one of them.  He has been the companion of Isis and the associate of Nephthys; he has made powerful their magic spell(s).  He has attached the towrope.  (14)He has repulsed his enemy, he has restrained his steps.  Re extends his hands to him; his Crew shall not repulse him.  (16)If Osiris N. is powerful, the Sound Eye is powerful, and vice versa.  To be said over (19)this Image that is sketched, sketched on a new, clean, unused sheet of papyrus with powder of glaze and (21)myrrh-water, placed at a man's breast without its coming (too) close.  He embarks in the bark of Re (23)daily, and Thoth looks after him at disembarking and embarking.  A truly excellent spell.  Thou shalt sketch it in (25)careful outline, likewise the bark of Re.  As for the powder of glaze, it is mentioned in order to emphasize the green, (27)this with which the document is to be written.  Osiris N. erects the Pillar and sets up (30)the tie-amulet.  He sails wherever he will.  (31)Gracious is the remark that Thoth made to Re, the sanctuary being content with its Lord Re.  Said Thoth: (33)''Look after his Soul at disembarking and embarking in the bark of Re, while the corpse is to remain in its place.''  (c) (BD 130)Roll for initiating the Soul forever and letting it board the bark of Re to pass by the courtiers of the nether world.  (1)To be recited on Osiris' birthday.  To be said by Osiris N.: Open, Sky; open (2)earth.  Open to me, southerners; open, northerners; open, westerners; open, easterners.  Open, double shrine (3)of Upper Egypt; open, double shrine of Lower Egypt.  Open, double doors, open, gate(s), to Re, that he may ascend from the Horizon.  (4)Open to him, double doors of the Night Bark; open to him, gate(s) of the Day Bark.  He inhales Shu; he has created Tefnut.  (5)They who are in his train follow him.  Osiris N. is (6)Re's follower, one who takes on his character, who provides for his sanctuary like Horus when his fate overtakes him, (7)whose seat is hidden in the ?purity? of his shrine, an envoy of the god to her whom he has loved.  Osiris N. has taken (8)(truth); he has offered up her image.  He has taken and bound (9)the shrine.  He abominates storms; there is no Starry Ho(st) beside him.  He has not (been kept away) from Re or Osiris; (10)he has not been warded off by him who accomplishes with his hands.  He has not walked in the valley of darkness; he has not entered the lake of the guilty.  (11)He is not of those that pour out time; he has not fallen as prey in the place among (those) taken before him (12)around Sopd's slaughtering-place.  ?Praise to? you, ?Kneelers?.  The God's knife is in concealment; (13)Geb's arms ?become active at? dawn.  As for him who is indeed refreshed, he shall lead Older than he and younger in his ((good) time).  (14)Now while Thoth is in concealment he (Thoth) has purified (him who takes account of) millions, who opens the sky and dispels cloudiness (15)from about him.  (When Osiris N. has reached him) in his seat, he (N.) grasps his staff, he (takes) his scepter, beside Re, (great) (16)(of beautiful goings).  The Great One (Re) rises after his eye, (his) Ennead (being around) his seat.  They do away with (17)his suffering and his illness when he is sick.  Osiris (N.) has done away with his suffering, he refreshes him (N.); illumined for him is the face of Thoth.  He praises Re, (and) (19)he (Re) hearkens (to him) and has set up obstacles against his enemies.  Osiris N. has not been left boatless, (20)he has not been kept from the Horizon, (for) he is in his knees, for his Name, even Re's name, is in the belly of Osiris (N.) and (22)his dignity is in his mouth.  He tells (it) to him, and he hears his words.  Praise (be) to thee, Re, lord of the Horizon, Osiris, presider over the westerners.  (23)Hail to thee, for whom the sun-folk purify themselves and the Sky brings (offerings) to that great abode past which lead the courses (24)of the rebellious.  Behold, Osiris N. is come; he has proclaimed the truth, since {his} marvels are in the west.  (25)He has broken the fury of Apophis; he is Ruty.  Osiris (N.), he has proclaimed the protection of those who are with him before (26)the great seat.  Mayest thou hearken to (him) when Osiris N. enters (27)into the Council.  He (drives off) Apophis from Re every day, so that he does not attack him when he wakes.  (28)He seizes (the writings); he has received the offerings.  He has equipped Thoth with his Eye.  He has caused that truth circle about (29)at the prow of the great bark that bears him who is true of speech in the Council.  He has established Millions; he has led the courtiers.  (30)Osiris N. gives to them a voyage in joy of face.  Re's Crew circles about, following (31)his beauty; truth rises high, she circles about her Lord.  He (N.) gives praise to the Lord of the Universe.  He has taken the staff; (32)he has ?swept? the Sky therewith.  The sun-folk give him praise as when rises Horus the unwearying.  (33)He exalts Re (by) that which he has done.  He has dispelled cloudiness, he has seen his beauty, he has established (34)his course.  He circles about, he proceeds to the Bark in the Sky; he shows himself as the sunshine.  Osiris N. is the great one in the midst (35)of his eye, sitting (or) kneeling in the great bark of Khepri.  He comes into being, and what he says comes into being; he is this (36)which circles the sky toward the west.  Verily the Starry Ho(st) rise, while Shu is in rejoicing; they take (37)Re's bow rope from his (crew).  As Re circles about, he sees Osiris; entrusted to him is Osiris N. (38)in peace, in peace.  He (N.) has not been kept away, he has not been seized, by the scorching breath that is in thy instant.  No hindrance has gone forth from thy mouth against him; he has not gone ?with? the crocodile.  (39)His abomination is crocodiles; they have not attacked him.  He embarks in thy bark; he takes over thy throne.  He assumes thy dignity; he follows the paths of Re.  (40)His praises shall drive away that noxious one who comes aflame against (thy) Bark (in) this great district.  Osiris N., he knows him; (41)he cannot reach thy bark (while) Osiris N. is (therein).  It is he who makes offerings to the Gods and mortuary offerings (42)to the blessed.  To be said over an image of this initiate put into this bark, after thou hast made the Night Bark at its right side and the Day Bark (43)at its left side.  Offer to them bread and beer, oxen and fowl, burnt incense, and all (other) good things on Osiris' birthday.  If this is done for him, (44)his Soul shall stay alive forever.  It shall not die again.  (This is) a secret of the nether world, a mystery in the god's domain.  Found in the Palace of the Great House (45)under the Majesty of the King of Upper and Lower Egypt, ?Khasety? justified, (as though) found in a mountain cave.  (This) is what Horus used (for) his Father Osiris Unnofer justified.  Since Re looks upon (46)this blessed one as himself, looks upon him as upon his Ennead, great is the fear of him, great is the esteem of him in the heart(s) of men and Gods and the blessed and the dead.  His corpse and (47)his Soul shall live forever; he shall not die again in the god's domain.  He shall not be left over on the judgment day; he shall be justified against his enemies.  His offerings shall be on (48)the altar of Re daily.  (ci) (BD 131)Spell for proceeding to the Sky beside Re.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)Re it is who shines this night.  As for every man who is in his train, he shall stay alive as a follower (6)of Thoth.  He shall give ?the crown? to Horus this night and joy to Osiris, be(8)cause he is one among these while his enemies are well disposed of.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
