<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Coffin texts</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.5528</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)5528</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. OIM 14062</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">See also OIM Photo 27339.  Measurements not given.  Undated.  Allen questioningly dated this papyrus to the 6th dynasty (c.2374-2191 B.C.).  (Allen, p. 31)  Gardiner preferred a First Intermediate Period date (c.2190-2061 B.C.).  (See Willems, p. 246, n. 24.)  Mathieu dates it to the end of dynasty 6 and cites other scholars' datings, as well.  (See BdE 139, p. 254 and n.59-60.)  Dates follow D.B. Redford (ed.), The Oxford Encyclopedia of Ancient Egypt (2001).  The numbers for the entire papyrus are OIM 14059-87.  See Lesko (p. 74) for a list of spell numbers in P. Gardiner III and corresponding line numbers.  P. Gardiner II in the British Museum also contains hieratic coffin texts and may be dated to the same period as this text.  In Spell 943, lines 82(b-c) and 90(e-f) are repeated as refrains after the subsequent lines.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyh">Hieratic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ;</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">On recto: 26 lines in hieratic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto: Coffin texts</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="-2374" notAfter="-2061">XXIVth - XXIst century B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyh">Hieratic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Funerary</term>
               <term>Religion</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. OIM 14062, recto:  (Sp.942) (69)My going forth is the going forth of Him who smote the Great One, the mansion(?)...Seth who turned the land upside down...dances(?)...the horns of Him who smote the Great One are bent in the eastern gate (70)of the sky...her tress of fire is quenched (71)...[he(?)] praises them of Khemennu...they spit out(?) the two powers when I go forth and when this goddess goes forth, having appeared as Re (72)...the Sole Lord, she has taken away the flame of the sunshine, she has shaved the side-whiskers of Anti, who is adorned on (73)...she has nothing which has been done against her in...Seth has been placed beneath her coils for her... (74)...this...is in his hand.  Offering slabs have been made...names of thei(rs)...live... (Sp.943) (75)O you who e[at], speak [to] her who casts the Two Baboons (in gold); (82)(b)I have appeared as the Eye of H[orus], and the Eye of Horus [has appeared] as I; (c)I am it and it is I.  (83)I eat, I speak, I cast the Two Baboons; (90)(e)the Eye of Horus appears as I, and I appear as the Eye of Horus; (f)I [am it and it is] I.  (76)O you who celebrate the...of Re, I have appeared, etc.(b-c)  (84)I celebrate my...for I am...; the Eye of Horus appears, etc.(e-f)  (77)O Mistress of past time(?) who swallowed the Vulture, I have appeared, etc.(b-c) (85)...it is I who bore Sekhmet; the Eye of Horus appears, etc.(e-f) (78)...the Sole Lord.  I have appeared, etc.(b-c)  (86)O you who ran from me, I guide the Sole Lord; the Eye of Horus appears, etc.(e-f)  (79)...my two doubles(?).  O you who make the land bright, I have appeared, etc.(b-c)  (87)Mine is the double(?)...; the Eye of Horus appears, etc.(e-f)  (80)...in front of Her who swallowed her sister; I have appeared, etc.(b-c)  (88)I have swallowed...; the Eye of Horus appears, etc.(e-f)  (81)O you who eat, whose speech is not opposed, I have appeared, etc.(b-c)  (89)I live as Khonsu, I am Nehebkaw; the Eye of Horus appears, etc.(e-f)  (Sp.944) (91)I am Khepri who is over the Lord of...I have opened up the darkness, I have fashioned my father, (92)I have con[ceiv]ed(?) my mother, [I] have taken possession of...whose scalp is shaven in front of the upper sky, I grant powers, (93)[I take away(?)] powers, my face is Horus the Elder, my heart is the Wine-press god who is in...My arm is not opposed, and I appear as the Eye of Horus; I am fire (94)...my arm is not opposed at all [...one who knows] that from this among them, I know...</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
