<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sales agreement</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.14</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)14</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">O. O.I. 12073</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">This ostracon contains regnal dates of two different kings, namely Ramesses III and IV. Dates follow D. B. Redford (ed.), The Oxford Encyclopedia of Ancient Egypt.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: Recto and verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyh">Hieratic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>Ostracon ; 34.1x19.3x4.3 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto: 12 lines in Hieratic; Verso: 2 lines in Hieratic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto: legal transaction; On verso: oath</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The verso contains two lines written beneath the drawing of two fecundity figures.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="-1198" notAfter="-1160">1198-1160 B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Deir el-Medina</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Ramesses III</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ramesses IV</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menna</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pre</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khaay</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyh">Hieratic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Ostracon</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>O. O.I. 12073 recto: (1) The 17th year, first month of Shemu, day [left blank] under the majesty of the King of Upper and Lower Egypt, Lord of the Two Lands, Wser-maat-Ra Mer-Imen, L.P.H., son of Ra, Ra-mes-sw Heqa-Iwnw [Ramesses III]. (2) On this day the giving of the jar of fresh fat which the workman Menna made to the Chief of Police Montu-mes (3) who had said, ''I shall get barley for you with it from this brother of mine who has the responsibility of releasing my obligation. (4) Then shall Pre give you health,'' so he said to me. And I have accused him three times in the Qenbet before the scribe of the necropolis Imen-nakht. And he has not (5) given me anything up to today. I even reported him before him (the scribe) again in year 3, second month of Shemu, day 5 (6) of the majesty of the King of Upper and Lower Egypt, Lord of the Two Lands, Heqa-maat-Ra Setep-en-Imen, son of Ra, Lord of Diadems, Ra-mes-sw Maaty Mer-Amun [Ramesses IV], making a total of 18 years (without relief). (7) He (the Chief of Police, Montu-mes) swore an oath by the Lord saying: ''If I do not repay him his jar (of fat) by year 3, third month of Shemu, last day, (8) I (lit. ''he'') will be liable to 100 blows, and I shall pay double.'' So he said before the three captains of the inside, the controllers of (9) the outside, and the whole crew. Regnal year 4, second month of Peret, day 14. The Chief of Police Montu-mes, brought to Menna a vigorous ox worth 130 deben. (10) What has come to him from the property of Rw-ta, namely a coffin worth 35 deben. What has been given to him by Menna - 40 hin of fresh fat worth 30 deben, total 65 deben. (11) Its balance (due): 65 deben to be given to the Chief of Police Montu-mes by the scribe of the necropolis Imen-nakht, the deputy Imen-Khaa, the guardian Khaay. (12) Pen-pa-mer and the draughtsman Her-shery.  O. O.I. 12073 verso: (1) the Chief of Police made an oath by the Lord saying: ''It is (only) 65 (2) deben of copper which I shall demand from Menna'' [translation by Manning, Grieg, and Uchida].</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
