<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>O. O.I. 25346</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.12</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)12</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">O. O.I. 25346</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Also known as O. Wilson 100.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: Recto and verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyh">Hieratic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>Ostracon ; 21.7x12.3 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Limestone ostracon.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto: 8 lines in Hieratic; Verso: 2 lines in Hieratic at the upper left; 4 in Hieratic at the right; 3 in Hieratic at the bottom, upside down relative to the first two groups.</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto and verso: hymn</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The first two groups of lines on the verso have verse points, but the third does not. There are almost unreadable traces of red following the second of the groups. The hieratic hand is of average quality for a literary text and points to a composition during the Ramesside period. The verse points show that the mode of composition is verse. The lines group clearly into pairs throughout.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="-1315" notAfter="-1080">1315-1080 B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Theban area</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyh">Hieratic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Thebes</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Ostracon</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>O. O.I. 25346, recto: Praised are you, O [divine] one who comes to Thebes in order to ask strength for himself...[from] Her. The districts are rejoicing with cries of satisfaction - our prayers are heard by the One who Illuminates; The House of the Scepter is exalted - She is far-reaching: His son is in celebration; The great memorial stelae reach to the sky because of the epiphanies of him who is divine overlord; Bowed down are the Eight Great Gods, their arms in homage, their mouths directed downward, their strength belonging to the Flourishing One. Enter, in order that you may be renewed within, in order that you may step forth [again] more than perfect. Adoration is recited for you in the Palace; and how beautiful is that which your Name has commanded! The Two Lands entire are bound at your throat, the Nine Bows are under your feet. They are saying, ''O divine ruler (l.p.h.), you who love Truth, you who love [kingship] - There are none who can equal you, none who dare to deceive you! There are none (O. O.I. 25346, verso:) who [brush?] a single consequence aside; There is no [longer] the oppression of falsehood; There is no placing a [rough] hand upon Truth; There is no reciting [a long list of] troubles; There is no striking of anyone [upon any day?].'' O One who causes that the downstream journeys be peaceful fivefold (?) - let good health be to you, Let life [in abundance] be yours, and grant [us also?] renewal each day!</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
