<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Pious notation</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.8242</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)8242</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">OIM 17618 (II)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>As originally presented, the manuscript contained a blank flyleaf of "Alf Lailah" and the first folio, consisting of the title page and the first page of text.  The chonological order of the six entries seems to be: The Alf Lailah or "Thousand Nights" fragment, Scattered phrases on pages 2 and 3, Outline drawing of the figure of a man on page 2, A second group of scattered phrases in different hands on page 2, Rough draft of a letter on page 1, Formulas of legal testimony dated Safar 266 A.H. / October 879 A.D. written on the margins of all 4 pages.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto and verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>paper ; 24.2 cm x 13.0 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Two joined folios of light brown paper of fine texture, partly discolored and considerably damaged with much of the lower half of both folios lost.  There are six distinct entries written in different scripts and with overlapping inks.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">On verso: 3 lines in Arabic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On verso: pious notation</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Three lines written on page 2, upper section are in a fine and careful book hand, but one different from the text of "Thousand Nights" and different from and in a different ink than the two lines on page 3, below initial entry.  Except for the earlier text of the "Nights," both entries have priority to space on their respective pages.  The succeeding entries are fitted into the remaining space.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0800" notAfter="0825">Early IIIrd century A.H. / Early IXth century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Syria</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Religious</term>
               <term>Islam</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">paper</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>OIM 17618, verso (page 2, upper section): (1) In the name of Allah, the Merciful, the Compassionate.  (2) We are your kin and you are our leader.  It is sufficient for us that one like you (3) should guide us through his kindly wisdom.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
