<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Qur'an</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.7825</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)7825</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">O.I. 6960</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Surah 20:61-71 and 20:71-78 (Kufan system)</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">It is impossible to tell whether any ornamentation was used for the surah divisions.  3-6 strokes mark the ends of verses.  A large alif with a bend at right angles to the right marks groups of 5 verses (recto 10 for verse 65, which is verse 66 in the printed text &amp; verso 14 for verse 75, which is verse 76).  A blank circle, also filled in with red, marks off 10-verse groupings (recto 1 for verse 60, which is verse 61 in the printed text).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto and verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>Parchment ; 24.5 x 31.0 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Fine large parchment.  The margins are lost except at the lower left corner (of the recto), where they measure 3.5 cm each.  The upper left corner is missing and the lower half has a large lacuna.  The thick, dark brown ink has eaten into the parchment, damaging much of the text, and has also faded considerably in places.  The verso was originally an unbroken continuation of the recto.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">On recto and verso: 17 lines each in Arabic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto and verso: Qur'an</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The script closely resembles that of Arabic Palaeography (1905) by B. Moritz, pl. 39 (pl. 40 is an enlargement).  In both manuscripts, the script is of medium size, considerably rounded, and well executed.  Spacing is moderate.  Verso 5 shows a small h used to fill in space at the end of a line.  Diacritical strokes are used fully and freely.  The red dot vowel system is used, but the ink of the dots must have lacked sufficient body, for some of them have spread out and others are all but completely faded.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0719" notAfter="0912">IInd-IIIrd century A.H.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Islam</term>
               <term>Qur'an</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Parchment</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
