<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Qur'an</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.7826</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)7826</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">O.I. 6975 a</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Surah 6:158-160 and 7:2-14</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">A narrow band separates the surahs.  More or less heart-shaped elements in gold, alternately erect and inverted, are outlined and filled in with red on a gold background.  The band extends across the page and ends with a circular(?) design on the outer margin.  A single black stroke or dot marks the end of a verse.  What was used for 5 verse groupings is uncertain, since the manuscript is broken where these would occur.  Groups of 10 verses are marked off by a gold square (recto 4).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto and verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>Parchment ; 29.5 x 15.6 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Large fine parchment found in three parts.  The upper and lower portions are lost and the remaining central section is very broken.  The original number of lines must have been 18 per page.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">On recto and verso: 15 lines each in Arabic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto and verso: Qur'an</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The script closely resembles that of Arabic Palaeography (1905) by B. Moritz, pl. 45 b in size, spacing and letter formation.  However, the script of this piece is more square in character, resembling in this respect Ar. Pal. pl. 42 b.  Red vowel dots are used.  A red stroke indicates the waslah (recto 6 &amp; 13; verso 6 &amp; 7).  Medial hamzah of the printed text is expressed by a medial y (recto 10 &amp; verso 6).  The diacritical signs were perhaps originally meant for strokes,  but many of them look very much like heavy dots.  They are fully and freely used.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0816" notAfter="0912">IIIrd century A.H.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Islam</term>
               <term>Qur'an</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Parchment</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
