<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Coffin texts</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.5548</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)5548</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. OIM 14082</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">See also OIM Photo 27359.  Measurements not given.  Undated.  Allen questioningly dated this papyrus to the 6th dynasty (c.2374-2191 B.C.).  (Allen, p. 31)  Gardiner preferred a First Intermediate Period date (c.2190-2061 B.C.).  (See Willems, p. 246, n. 24.)  Mathieu dates it to the end of dynasty 6 and cites other scholars' datings, as well.  (See BdE 139, p. 254 and n.59-60.)  Dates follow D.B. Redford (ed.), The Oxford Encyclopedia of Ancient Egypt (2001).  The numbers for the entire papyrus are OIM 14059-87.  See Lesko (p. 74) for a list of spell numbers in P. Gardiner III and corresponding line numbers.  P. Gardiner II in the British Museum also contains hieratic coffin texts and may be dated to the same period as this text.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyh">Hieratic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ;</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">On recto: 20 lines in hieratic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto: Coffin texts</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="-2374" notAfter="-2061">XXIVth - XXIst century B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyh">Hieratic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Funerary</term>
               <term>Religion</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. OIM 14082, recto:  (472)...you have [no] fire.  O hunter(?), I will not fall because of you.  O shambles of the god, I will not enter into you.  My seat is in the sun-disk.  (473)...my seat in the sun-disk.  I am...I am he who is in charge of the seats of the gods, a st[ar]... (474)...if I live, [Re(?)] will live.  (Sp.994) (475)SPELL FOR THE GOVERNANCE...Hail to you Thoth, in your [p]ow[er]...Find Wadjet in it, (476)and she will make you flourish; find the Eye of Horus in it, and you will be strong by means of it.  I have come that I may see you, that I may recognize your beauty, that I may send your foreleg-offering.  (477)...that I may [s]end your word.  (478)...for Wadjet, make...for me so that I may have light and be high(?)... (479)mother...in her name.  (480)I copulate with you for Horus who protects his father, so that he may do for me what you have done for him.  I will live on heads, for I am Khonsu.  (481)...my pond is excavated, I [have given birth to(?)] my heir, namely he who issued from me.  It is Horus who is on... (482)...Might is created for me...in the riverbank of the ibis; I have power over them (483)...and they [will not have power] over me; I have equipped(?)... (Sp.995) (484)...Re-Atum, I have seen the Tw[ins]...he speaks and guides them both to the middle of the East.  (485)...SAYS RE-ATUM TO THESE ENDURING THINGS.  I am an enduring thing; let the two knots of the ibis be given to me.  I will bring to you (486)...in due course(?).  'A[RE] Y[OU] AN EQUIPPED SPIRIT?' SAYS RE-ATUM.  'BE PLEASED' -- repeat four times -- SAYS SI[A] (487)ALL [MAG]IC...DAUGHTER.  HE HAS OCCUPIED HIS THRONE, HE HAS COME... (488)...TO OSIRIS, FOR HE KNOWS THE NA[ME]... (489)...IBIS SO THAT HE MAY BRING TO ME THE DAUGHTER(?)... (490)...his knife in his hand and he severs the spine of Re whom he sees...in his hand...whom he sees.  Great is Aw who falls for me, mighty is Aw who looks on me...</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
