<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Provisional sale document</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.7</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)7</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. O.I. 25263 (P. Chic. Haw. 9)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">P.Chic.Haw. 4 (P. O.I. 25262) was found rolled inside of this one.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto and verso</note>
                     <note type="related">P. O.I. 25262 (P. Chic. Haw. 4)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyd" otherLangs="grc">Demotic; Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>papyrus ; 107.0 x 33.5 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto: 9 lines in Demotic, 4 lines in the Greek docket; Verso: 16 lines in Demotic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto: Provisional sale document; On verso: witness list</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="-0239">March 9, 239 B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Hawara, in the Fayum district, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Onomastos, son of Pyron</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Archestrate, daughter of Ktesikles</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ankhmerwer, son of Patinaneterw and Tarenenet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herankh, daughter of Maara and Nebettahy(?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sobekhetep, son of Pasy</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sobekhetep, son of Ankhmerwer</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maara, son of Pasherentaihet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maara, son of Pehy</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tayirw, daughter of Patiwsir and Naneferrenpet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pana(?), son of Patihorpasher(en)iset</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Epiphanes, the agent of Rhodokles</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dionysios, the agent of Boethos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">witness list with 16 names</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyd">Demotic</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Crocodilopolis; Arsinoite nome</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. O.I. 25263 (P. Chic. Haw. 9)  recto: (1) [Year 8, first month of the season peret, of Pharaoh] Ptolemy, who lives forever, son of Ptolemy and Arsinoe Philadelphos, the gods Adelphoi, the priest of Alexander and the gods Adelphoi and the gods Euergetai being Onomastos, son of Pyron, while Arche(s)trate, the daughter of Ktesikles, is the Kanephoros before Arsinoe Philadelphos (2) [The god's sealer and embalmer An]khmer[wer], son of Patinaneterw, whose mother is Tarenenet, [has declared] to the woman Herankh, daughter of the god's sealer and embalmer Maara, whose mother is Nebettahy(?): ''You have caused my heart to agree to the money for my one-third share of this house which is built, it being provided with beam and door, which measures 19 god's cubits from south to north and 18 god's cubits from west to east (3) [and my one-third share] of my cell, above and below, which is on the north of my new home, which measures 20 god's cubits from south to north and which measures 5 god's cubits from west to east.  The neighbors of the aforesaid house are: south, the house of the god's sealer and embalmer Sobekhetep, son of Pasy, the street being between them; north, the house of the god's sealer and embalmer (4) [Sobekhetep, son of Ankhmerwer] adjoins them; west, the houses of the god's sealer and embalmer, Maara, son of Pasherentaihet, which are in the possession of his children, the street being between them; east, my house adjoins them.  The neighbors of the cell are: south, my house adjoins it; north, the house of the god's sealer and embalmer Maara, son of Pehy, adjoins them; west, your building plots adjoins them; (5) [east, the wall(?)] of the temple of Hawara, the big path being between them.  Yours is one-third of this house on its southern part, below and above, together with the cell, the measurements and neighbors of which are written above, from today onward.  I do not have anything of any kind in the world due from you for them from today onward.  No one in the world, myself included, shall be able to exercise control over them from today onward.  (6) [As for him who might come against] you regarding them, I will [make] him withdraw from you.  If I do not make him withdraw from you, I will make him withdraw from you and I will clear them for you of every title deed or anything in the world.  To you belong every document that was (ever) drawn up regarding them, and every document that was (ever) drawn up for my father or my mother regarding them, and every document that was (ever) drawn up for me regarding them, and every document by which I am entitled to them.  They belong to you together with the legal rights conferred by them.  To you belongs that by which I am entitled to them.  The oath or the court proof (7) [that might be] required of you in order to cause that I execute it concerning them, I shall perform it.  You may go up (to) and down (from) the roof on the stairway of this aforesaid house and you may go in and out of the forehall, the main doorway and the (other) exits of this aforesaid house.  And you shall make any alterations on it in proportion to your one-third share from today onward forever.''  Whereas the woman Tayirw, daughter of the god's sealer and embalmer Patiwsir, whose mother is (8) [Nanefer]renpet says: ''Write! Do everything [aforesaid].  I am agreed thereto.'' She says also: ''It is because I have claim on the god's sealer and embalmer Ankhmerwer, son of Patinaneterw, whose mother is Tarenenet, above, through the legal right conferred by every document that he has drawn up for me that I give the above consent, and he shall carry out the obligations conferred by them, and I shall carry out the obligations of the above consent.  I relinquish to the woman Horankh, daughter of the god's sealer and embalmer Maara, whose mother is Nebettahy(?), the one-third of this house (9) [and one-third of this] cell, the measurements and neighbors of both of which are written above, from today onward.  I have nothing at all in the world against you in respect to them from today onward.''  Written by Pana(?), son of Patihorpasher(en)iset.  [Greek Dockets:] Year 8, Tybi 19, it (sc. The agreement) has been deposited in the (official) chest at Crocodilopolis of the Arsinoite (Nome) by Epiphanes, the agent of Rhodokles.  (Year) 8, Tybi 19, it has been deposited in the (official) chest, in the presence of Dionysios, the agent of Boethos.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
