<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Qur'an</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.7830</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)7830</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">O.I. 12067</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Qur'an, lacking 3 folios (p. 347-352 = Surah 18:52-99) (Meccan system)</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">The date of the manuscript (812 A.H.) is given on p. 395.  Later additions are dated 1262 A.H. (1846 A.D.) on p. 695.  At juz' divisions, the term waqf, the words waqf min kalam, or the phrase waqf min kalam Allah appears.  There seems to be a fuller waqf notation at the end of juz' 21 on p. 487.  The measurements of the script sections vary from 19-22.5 x 25.5-26.5 cm.  The margins are outlined in red.  The verses are marked off by a small 6 petaled rosette in green and gold.  Groups of 5 and 10 verses are not noted.  Each surah starts a new line without any title or comment and usually without any extra spacing.  In 2 instances, the surah begins with a large thuluth line.  On the outer margin of each page is a large circular ornament of red and gold, framed in a scroll pattern of green.  All juz' divisions start on right-hand pages, leaving the preceding page blank if necessary.  These pages are ornamented with panels of red, gold, and green stretching across the top and bottom of the page.  Each panel is divided into 2 squares and a central rectangle, this last containing the juz' number written in black ink in thuluth script.  The juz' number is in most cases followed by a phrase designating the Qur'an.  From juz' 24 on, the space in the panels is occupied by the number alone.  The manuscript is bound between two wooden boards covered with heavy dark red-brown leather.  The flap and the section joining it to the back cover are made of several layers of paper so compact that they feel like wood.  They are encased in leather.  The back is reinforced on the top and bottom with a heavy headband of cream and tan silk cord.  A large centered arabesque and a small one above and below it are blind-tooled on each of the covers.  A one is blind-tooled on the flap.  The inside of the binding is faced with marble paper; the flyleaves are of this same paper, which carries the same watermark as pgs. 293-296.  Over the upper part of the inside of the back cover and flap, a piece of green cotton cloth has been clumsily pasted as reinforcement.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto and verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>paper ; 25.5 x 31.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The copy, including the covers, is 10.5 cm thick.  Several of the folios have been replaced, many have been mended, and others are torn.  Many of the margins have been patched, usually with a thinner and lighter paper.  The outer lower corners have suffered the most, mainly through much thumbing and turning.  Whole sections of the upper parts of pages are disfigured with what looks like mildew stains.  Many of the marginal ornaments have been lost or removed and their places filled by patches.  Originally a complete copy, the codex now lacks 3 folios (p. 347-352), which have been torn out.  The decorations on some juz' pages are lost and replaced by blank paper.  Whatever the substance of the decorative matter used, it did not stand the test of time.  It has dried up, cracked, and peeled off, leaving damaged pages and margins.  4 folios at the beginning (p.1-8) and 10 at the end (p. 677-696)  are later additions.  This paper is thin, very light in color, and well glossed.  It is of European manufacture with watermarks.  Pages 1 and 695 show the capital letters GFA; pages 7 and 679 show a swan with outstretched wings.  Pages 293-296 are also later additions, but are undated.  The paper is of Italian make and has as watermark the name "Andrea Galvani Pordenone," plus a well-drawn crescent with a face in profile.  The manuscript is bound.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">348 folios with 11-17 lines per page in Arabic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto and verso: Qur'an</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The front flyleaf has several Turkish notations written in a mediocre Turkish hand.  The main manuscript has no reading symbols or notations.  The text has several major and minor scribal errors, some of which seem to have been corrected by the original scribe (p. 146).  Other corrections have been made in at least 6 different hands.  The first, middle, and last line of each page are written in thuluth covering the whole width of the writing space and dividing the page into 2 sections, each of which contains usually 6 shorter centered lines in naskhi.  There are several instances of a naskhi line ending the page and 1 instance of 2 naskhi lines ending the page.  The execution of the thuluth lines is fairly good on the whole, though there are several cases of poor writing and overcrowding.  Frequently, these lines are extended well into the margins.  There is a tendency to slant the lower thuluth line upward.  The naskhi script is fair.  The ink is heavy and very black, and the writing is smudged in several instances.  The text is fully pointed and voweled in the same black ink.  With the pages that were added later, both the thuluth and nasikh scripts are well-executed and the writing is not as heavy or as crowded as the original manuscript.  The text is fully pointed and voweled.  The scribe has usually written the maddah twice, first in black and then in red on a larger scale.  The scribe used the full punctuation system in red ink.  Pages 293-296 are in a different hand and on different paper, both more like the original manuscript than are the 1846 additions.  The watermark is writen in a large Spencerian hand.  The scripts of the text are well-executed and the text is fully pointed and voweled.  A late hand has inserted floral transfers to p. 2, 166, and 695.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="1409" notAfter="1410">1409-1410 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Bukhara (according to Moritz's notation; see Abbott p. 73)</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Siraj Amin Effendi</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sergeant Hajji &amp;apos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Uthman</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Isma&amp;apos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">il Effendi</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">&amp;apos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ali</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ahmad Salih</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">&amp;apos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Uthman Muhammad</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hajji Hafiz Khairi Effendi</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Karahisar</term>
               <term>Islam</term>
               <term>Qur'an</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">paper</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>The Turkish notations on the front flyleaf state that horse artillery gunman Siraj Amin Effendi and Sergeant Hajji 'Uthman read the manuscript on the 25th of Nisan, A.H. (1)309.  Another tells us that a soldier of the third company of the third squadron prayed in the noble mosque of...on the 28th of Haziran, A.H. (1)304.  A third tells us that the head chef, Isma'il Effendi, has this day read a fourth of a juz'.  Finally, the signatures of 'Ali, the villager Ahmad Salih, 'Uthman Muhammad of Karahisar, and Hajji Hafiz Khairi Effendi imply that their owners have at some time read portions of the manuscript.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
