<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A volume that contained selected tales from "The Book of the Tales of a Thousand Nights"</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.8241</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)8241</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">OIM 17618 (I)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>As originally presented, the manuscript contained a blank flyleaf of "Alf Lailah" and the first folio, consisting of the title page and the first page of text.  The chonological order of the six entries seems to be: The Alf Lailah or "Thousand Nights" fragment, Scattered phrases on pages 2 and 3, Outline drawing of the figure of a man on page 2, A second group of scattered phrases in different hands on page 2, Rough draft of a letter on page 1, Formulas of legal testimony dated Safar 266 A.H. / October 879 A.D. written on the margins of all 4 pages.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto and verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>paper ; 24.2 cm x 13.0 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Two joined folios of light brown paper of fine texture, partly discolored and considerably damaged with much of the lower half of both folios lost.  There are six distinct entries written in different scripts and with overlapping inks.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">On recto: 5 lines in Arabic; on verso: 6 lines in Arabic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto and verso: tales</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The script is a light, but well-schooled book hand used at the time for smaller Qur'ans and occasionally for other valued works of a religious and linguistic character.  On the surface, it bears a resemblance to the so-called kufic-naskhi of the third century A.H. in the angularity of letters associated with the kufic script and the cursiveness of letters credited to the naskhi script.  On the other hand, the script bears a marked resemblance to the Christian Arabic writing of the same century evolving in the Asiatic provinces and influenced by the Syriac script, especially in the tendency to give vertical strokes a bit of the wave that is found in the Syriac script.  Upon closer analysis of the letters' forms, this script finds no close parallel in either the Islamic or Christian book hand now extant.  This is not surprising given the very old date of this manuscript.  Diacritical points are used sparingly except in the first few lines.  When a letter calls for two or three points, these are neither consistently grouped together, nor are they accurately placed above or below the letter.  The vertical stroke of the alef and the l are written downward, regardless of the letters' position in the word.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0800" notAfter="0825">Early IIIrd century A.H. / Early IXth century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Syria</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Dinazad</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Shirazad</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Literature</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">paper</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>OIM 17618, recto (page 3): (1) A book (2) of tales from a (3) Thousand Nights.  There is neither strength (4) nor power except in God the (5) Highest, the Mightiest.  OIM 17618, verso (page 4): (1) In the name of Allah the Merciful, the Compassionate.  (2) NIGHT (3) And when it was the following night (4) said Dinazad, "O my Delectable One, if you are (5) not asleep, relate to me the tale (6) which you promised me and quote striking examples of the (7) excellencies and shortcomings, the cunning and stupidity (8) the generosity and avarice, and the courage and cowardice (9) that are in man, instinctive or acquired (10) or pertain to his distinctive characteristics or to courtly manners, Syrian (11) or Bedouin.  (12) [And Shirazad related to her a ta]le of elegant beauty (13) [of So-and-So the ? and] his [f]ame (or [c]raft) (14) [   sh]e becomes more worthy than they who are (or do) not (15) [   or] else more crafty (or malicious) than they.  (16) [   (traces only at the end of the line)]</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
