<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of property</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.7798</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)7798</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. O.I. 6966</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Markurah, son of Kail, sells the remainder of his property to Qalhash, son of Boktor.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>Parchment ; 21.0 x 33.0 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Fine light parchment.  The upper right margin is broken and the lower right part is shrunken, and so the parchment is of an irregular shape, though this must have taken place before the present document was drawn up.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">On recto: 21 lines in Arabic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto: Sale of property</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The parchment is a palimpsest, but very few and light traces only are to be seen of the underscript.  The script is a small cursive hand with some angularity, but on the whole, closer to the regular naskhi hand.  The text is freely though not completely pointed and is not voweled except for one instance in line 9.  The words are closely written, but not crowded in line spacing.  Most of the signatures are in a crude and unpracticed hand.  The same ink--a medium brown--is used for the main document and by the witnesses.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0947">August 22-September 20, 947 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Faiyum</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Qalhash, son of Boqtor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marqurah, son of Kail</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aqtahun, daughter of Ibn Abi Tidur</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Matus, son of Dahlan</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Bani Qasa</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Faqri, son of Shinudah</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tusanah, daughter of Bisanti</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ali, son of Ibrahim</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Fasau(?), son of Ahmad</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ali, son of Ibrahim</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ahmad, son of Muhammad</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ali, son of Husain</persName>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Abu al-Jusuq; Bursh; Fayyum</term>
               <term>Sale</term>
               <term>Property</term>
               <term>Fayyum</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Parchment</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. O.I. A6966, recto: (1) In the name of God, the merciful, the compassionate.  (2) This is what Qalhash, son of Boqtor, bought from Marqurah, son of Kail, of the inhabitants of Abu al-Jusuq, known as Bursh.  (3) He bought from him and from his mother, Aqtahun, (daughter) of Ibn Abi Tidur, their house in Abu al-Jusuq Bursh of the district of the (4) Fayyum for eight dinars, of which one dinar is debased and seven dinars unadulterated, sound (5) full weight by the new mithqals.  And it is the house whose southern boundary extends to the house of Matus, son of Dahlan, and its (6) northern boundary (is) the house of the heirs of Bani Qasa, and its eastern boundary the house of Faqri, son of Shinudah, and its western boundary the house of (7) Tusanah, daughter of Bisanti.  Qalhash, son of Boqtor, bought from Marqurah, son of Kail, and from his mother, Aqtahun, (daughter) of Ibn Abi Tidur, their right (8) in the house delimited and described by the four boundaries that surround it to the limit of all its boundaries, and every (9) right pertaining to it, entering in it, and issuing from it, for these eight dinars specified in this deed.  (10) And Qalhash, son of Boqtor, delivered it to Marqurah, son of Kail, this entire sum in full payment, and he receipted him with a receipt for full payment received.  (11) And they were satisfied and parted on terms of mutual satisfaction on their part.  And they consulted (with each other) in accordance with the Muslim law of sale and its stipulations without option for either of them and without annulment.  (12) These are the terms on which they concluded the sale.  And whatsoever should ensue to Qalhash, son of Boqtor, by way of damages or claims or attachments from anyone whatsoever (13) for any reason whatsoever or in any manner whatsoever--the responsibility for that and security for it rests on Marqurah, son of Kail.  And that (14) in Safar of the year six and thirty and three hundred.  'Ali, son of Ibrahim, al-Aswani, gave witness to that, to all that is in this deed (15) in Safar of the year six and thirty and three hundred.  Muhammad, son of al-Qasr, gave witness to that, to all that is in this deed, and 'Ali, son of Ibrahim, wrote (signed) for him (16) by his order and in his presence.  (17) Muhammad, son of al-Husain, gave witness to all that is in this deed and wrote with his own hand.  (18) Ahmad, son of al-Khashram, testified to all that is in this deed and wrote with his own hand.  (19) Fasau(?), son of Ahmad, gave witness to all that is in this deed, and 'Ali, son of Ibrahim, wrote for him by his order and in his presence.  (20) Ahmad, son of Muhammad, gave witness to all that is in this deed.  (21) 'Ali, son of Husain, gave witness to all that is in this deed and wrote his testimony with his own hand.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
