<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Qur'an</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.7816</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)7816</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">O.I. 6978</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Surah 50:3-27 and 50:34-51:12 (Kufan system)</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">The surahs are separated by a double line drawn in the same ink, using no more than the space of one line.  Above this double line, written in light red ink without any strokes or dots and in a smaller and apparently later hand, are the title and verse count of the surah following.  Four short strokes that might easily be mistaken for dots mark the end of each verse.  A circle enclosing 2-4 dots and itself encircled by a number of dots marks off 10-verse groups in recto 8 and 15.  In verso 10, there are strokes instead of dots within the circle, with strokes and dots surrounding it.  These 3 10-verse divisions mark off verses 10, 20, and 40 of Surah 50 in the manuscript; these are, however, verses 10, 19, and 42 in the printed text.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto and verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>Parchment ; 19.5 x 24.0 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Fine parchment originally containing 24 lines per page.  The 4 missing lines are broken off at the top, and the rest of the piece is badly broken on both sides.  Lines 1-3 on the recto are very fragmentary, but the remainder is more easily read.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">On recto and verso: 20 lines each in Arabic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto and verso: Qur'an</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The recto and verso show different Meccan scripts.  That of the recto is heavier and more angular; that of the verso is not only lighter but also less crowded and more graceful, resembling in many respects that of O.I. A6959 and O.I. A6990.  Vowel points are missing.  Diacritical dots are used on the recto and are placed the same as strokes would have been (as in O.I. A6975a).  To all appearances, the same pen that was used here for the text was used for the dots also.  The diacritical marks are used more freely on the recto than the verso.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0719" notAfter="0912">IInd-IIIrd century A.H.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Islam</term>
               <term>Qur'an</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Parchment</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
