<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Grain receipt</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.5509</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)5509</idno>
            <idno type="TM">42941</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">42941</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.kar.goodsp;;79</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Kar.Goodsp. 79 (MS 1057)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Receipt given to the sitologoi (village grain collectors) by a farmer for an advance of seed-corn issued to enable him to sow the lands assigned him.  The distribution was made in the late autumn, and probably at the rate of one artaba of grain for each aroura of land.  These advances of grain were repaid by farmers after the harvest, usually in the month of Pauni (May 26 - June 24), although sometimes in the preceding (Pachon) or following (Epeiph) months, together with about 23% of the original advance as interest and to cover expenses of collection.  (Goodspeed 1902, 9)</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Bar code: 68652980.  This papyrus is one of 91 belonging to the group MS No. 1057.  Goodspeed divides the papyri into 3 groups, those having a long introductory formula, one with a more exact formula, and those with the formula reduced to its simplest form.  This document falls into the first group.  It is further identified as containing the word cheirogr(a)th(on).  For other documents which contain this word, see papyri numbers 1,2,5,6,8,9,10,13,14,15,16,17,18,21,25,26,27,28,29,30,33,34,35,36,39,41,44,47,52,53,54,55,56,58,63,64,68,71,72,74,79,82,83,85,86,88,89.  (Goodspeed 1902, 7)  Of Goodspeed's 91 papyri containing grain receipts from Karanis, 88 are dated to Antoninus' 22nd year and one to his 15th year.  Because farmers would apply for their seed at about the same time (autumn), nearly all of the collection are from a single season in one year, the 26th of Athur in the 20th year of Antoninus ( = November 22, 156 A.D.). (Goodspeed 1902, 2)  The usual letters represent the numbers, while a horizontal line generally stands above the cleruchy number.  The fractions are arranged with numerators of 1, as usual, but 1/2 and 1/4 are often combined.  (Goodspeed 1902, 6)</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Regenstein</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 7.5 x 6.2 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">For the most part, the receipts were rolled together in packets.  In one case, the pieces had been held together by a string running through the center of each one, as though for filing, and the bit of brown thread still held 12 of them insecurely together.  From the top of the pile to the bottom, this included numbers 72,25,40,47,10,53,82,70,77,45,18,39.  (Goodspeed 1902, 3)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">On recto: 6 lines in Greek</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto: grain receipt</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>In general, the receipts are complete and plainly legible.  There is a great amount of abbreviation in the receipts in the hands of almost all the writers.  Most were written hastily and are much abbreviated.  As with 54 others of the 91 papyri, this document begins in an official hand, which ends with the word kurion.  Of these, all except 1 are written across the fibers.  (Another 12 of the 91 papyri are also written in this manner.)  The determining element with this scribe was probably not so much the fiber relation, however, as the shape of the papyrus, for he prefers to make his line parallel with the longer side of his papyrus.  (Goodspeed 1902, 2-5)  The second hand in this text is identical with the second hand in nos. 14, 75 and 80 and the third hand of no. 36.  (Goodspeed 1902, 53)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0158" notAfter="0159">(Mid) IInd century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Arsinoite nome</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Antoninus Caesar</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Serenos son of Horos</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Karanis; Patsontis; Ptolemais</term>
               <term>Agriculture</term>
               <term>81st cleruchy</term>
               <term>Receipt</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations"/>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
