<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Annuity contract</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.10</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)10</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. O.I. 25256 (P. Chic. Haw. 8)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">The same scribe wrote P.Chic.Haw. 7A  and 7B [P. O.I. 25255]</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; verso is blank</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyd">Demotic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>papyrus ; 177.0 x 38.0 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto: 6 lines in Demotic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto: Annuity contract</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="-0243">July 20-August 18, 243 B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Hawara, in the Fayum district, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Aristoboulos, son of Antinodos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Iamneia, daughter of Hyperbassass</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sematawy, son of Pashemetre and Ankhes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Shety, daughter of Pashwt and Horankh</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Setawtawty, son of Patiwsir</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">no witness list</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyd">Demotic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. O.I. 25256 (P. Chic. Haw. 8)  recto: (1) Year 4, second month of the season shemu, of Pharaoh Ptolemy, who lives forever, son of Ptolemy and Arsinoe, the gods Adelphoi, the priest of Alexander and of the gods Adelphoi being Aristoboulos, son of Antinodos, while Iamneia, daughter of Hyperbassass, is the Kanephoros (2) before Arsinoe Philadelphos. The fisherman of the lake, servant (of) Sobek, Sematawy, son of Pashemetre, whose mother is Ankhes, has declared to the woman Shety, daughter of Pashwt, whose mother is Horankh: ''You have caused my heart to agree to the 21 silver (deben) (weighed) by the pieces in the Treasury of Ptah, (of) refined (silver), being 20 silver (deben) and 9, 5/6, 1/10, 1/30, 1/60, and 1/60 kite, being 21 silver (deben) (weighed) by the pieces in the (3) Treasury of Ptah, (of) refined (silver) again, as your annuity. There belong to the children whom you will bear to me the half of everything of any property that I possess and the half of everything of any property that I shall acquire: the half of house, field, courtyard, building plot, male servant, female servant, cow, ass, every animal, every office, every document, every title deed, every matter of a freeman in the world whatsoever of mine.  (4) Your eldest son is my eldest son among the children whom you will bear to me. He is the owner of half of everything of all property that I possess and half of everything of all property that I shall acquire. And I shall give you 36 (sacks) emmer (by the measure of) 40-hin, being 24 (sacks) barley (by the measure of) 40-hin, being 36 (sacks) emmer (by the measure of) 40-hin again and 1 silver (deben) and 8 kite (weighed) by the pieces in the Treasury of Ptah, (of) refined (silver), being 1 silver (deben) and 7, 5/6, 1/10, 1/30, 1/60, and 1/60 kite, being 1 silver (deben) and 8 kite (weighed) by the pieces in the (5) Treasury of Ptah, (of) refined (silver), again, for your subsistence each year at whatever house you desire. You are the one authorized with regard to the arrears of your subsistence which shall be to my debit, and I am to give it to you. Half of everything of all property that I possess and half of everything of all property that I shall acquire is the pledge for your aforesaid annuity. I shall not be able to say to you: (6) 'Take your aforesaid annuity,' but on whatever day you desire it, I will give it to you. If an oath is required of you to be taken for me, it is at the house in which the judges are that you shall take it.'' Written by the astronomer of Sobek, Setawtawty, son of Patiwsir.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
