<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Qur'an</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.7835</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)7835</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">O.I. 12029 d</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Surah 2:93-140; 4:24-32, 78-84, 150-159; 4:164-5:15; 5:20-26; 7:3-22, 89-106, 115-155; 7:189-8:36; 9:80-92; 9:94-10:10; 11:14-17, 66-83; 15:28-16:49; 16:116-25; 20:53-90; 21:11-18; 23:3-24:19; 29:47-61; 30:56-31:21; 36:31-47, 53-60; 37:150-39:26; 39:67-40:13; 46:11-15; 51:36-54:51; 62:3-5 (Verse counts are Meccan, except that Surah 39 (folio 184b) has 77 verses.)</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">This manuscript is an undated private copy, but is stamped with a circular seal in 9 different places.  The seal is identical with that in Arabic Palaeography by B. Moritz (1905), pls. 42a, 121, 132, 136, 139, etc.  The couplet in the margin alludes to Surah 94.  The 'Abd al-Baki mentioned on the seal was apparently a book collector of some note who lived in the 9th c. A.H.  The text area measures 15.5 x 22.5 cm.  The 5 lines of script are enclosed in a narrow gold band outlined in black with an outer frame of blue.  The verses are separated by small 6 petaled gold rosettes with blue and red points.  10 verse divisions are indicated by circular marginal ornaments in gold, red, and blue, with the word 'ashr written first in blue, then painted over in white.  In many cases, the white has rubbed off, leaving but slight traces.  The total and internal verse divisions do not correspond to any of the systems listed by Spitaler.  At the head of each surah stands a broad panel in gold, blue, red, white, and in some cases black.  Geometric designs, different in each panel, are interspersed with arabesques.  In the center are written the title and number of verses of the surah in gold overlaid with white.  In the margin, centered on the panel, is a circular ornament.  Wide space is allowed on either side of the panel.  The bismillah is written in gold outlined in black and the loop of each h is filled in with blue.  Instead of the usual jiz' division into 30 parts, we have the hizb division into 60 parts.  1/4 and 1/2, but not 3/4, of each hizb are marked by marginal ornaments usually similar to those used for the 10 verse divisions.  In one instance, 2 arcs enclose the motif.  In 3 others, an almond is used, while the words rub' hizb  without any ornament occur once.  An elaborate sajdah ornament in dumbbell form appears twice.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto and verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>paper ; 27.0 x 37.0 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The paper used for this manuscript consists of 4 different qualities and shades of color, the best being creamy white, heavy, and glossy.  Both a light brown and a reddish brown variety are used for large sections.  Both are light in weight, but glossy.  The 4th variety is dull reddish-brown, so light in weight that the writing shows through.  The better quality paper folios are in good condition; the rest are discolored.  Some have damaged edges and some are worm-eaten.  The red used in ornamental work has for the most part retained its color and metallic brilliance.  The blue has not fared so well.  Several shades of it are to be seen; that on the heavy white paper is of a grayish-blue.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">220 folios with 5 lines per page in Arabic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto and verso: Qur'an</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Large thuluth script, fully pointed and voweled in the same black ink.  The muharraf form of alif is used rather generally and the mudghamah and muqawwarah forms of other letters are used.  These give the script a comparatively crowded appearance.  Curiously, j, h, and kh all have a small h below them.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="1398" notAfter="1494">IXth century A.H.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">&amp;apos</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Islam</term>
               <term>Qur'an</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">paper</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>O.I. 12029 d - On the margin is this couplet: When sore affliction troubles you, Then call to mind, "Did we not ope?"  Between two eases stands one grief; If you remember that, then hope.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
