<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Annuity contract</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.9</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)9</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. O.I. 25388  (P. Chic. Haw. 6)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto and verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyd" otherLangs="grc">Demotic; Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>papyrus ; 161.0 x 45.0 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The roll is light brown in color. The inscribed portions are excellently preserved, but both ends have suffered damage</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto:  4 lines in Demotic, 4 lines in the Greek docket</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto: Annuity contract and signature in Demotic, plus Greek docket; On verso: Witness list and signature</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Composed of ten individual sheets of papyrus, averaging 16.5 cm in width. The Greek docket is written by two different hands</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="-0259">August 23-September 10, 259 B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Hawara, in the Fayum district, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Medeios, son of Lampon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Matela, daughter of Androkades</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Patiwsir, son of Ankhmerwer and Naneferibptah</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herankh, daughter of Maara and Nebettahy(?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Djkhonswiwfankh, son of Perel</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Andragathos, the agent of Philinos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sosipatros, the agent of Polemon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Patiwsir, son of Imhetep</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">witness list with 16 names, three of which are not convincingly read</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyd">Demotic</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. O.I. 25388 (P. Chic. Haw. 6)  recto:  Year 26, third month of the season shemu, of Pharaoh Ptolemy, son of Ptolemy and his son, Ptolemy, the priest of Alexander and of the gods Adelphoi Adelphoi (sic) being Medeios, son of Lampon, while Matela, daughter of Androkades, is Kanephoros before Arsinoe Philadelphos. the god's sealer and embalmer Patiwsir, son of Ankhmerwer, whose mother is Naneferibptah, has declared (2) to the woman Herankh, the daughter of the god's sealer and embalmer Maara, whose mother is Nebettahy(?): ''You have caused my heart to agree to the 10 silver (deben) (weighed) by the pieces which are in the Treasury of Ptah, of refined (silver), being 9 silver (deben) and 9, 5/6, 1/10. 1/30. 1/60, and 1/60 kite, being 10 silver (deben) (weighed) by the pieces which are in the Treasury of Ptah, of refined (silver), again, as your annuity.  There belong to the children whom you will bear to me all of everything which I possess and that which I shall acquire in(?) house, field, courtyard, building plot, male servant, female servant, cow, ass, every animal, every office, every document, every title deed, and (3) every matter of a freeman in the world belonging to me, and I shall give to you 36 (sacks) emmer (by the measure of) 40-hin, being 24 (sacks) barley (by the measure of) 40-hin, being 36 (sacks) emmer (by the measure of) 40-hin again and 1 silver (deben), 2 kite (weighed) by the pieces which are in the Treasury of Ptah, of refined (silver), being 1 silver (deben), 1 and 5/6, 1/10, 1/30, 1/60, and 1/60 kite, being 1 silver (deben) and 2 kite (weighed) by the pieces which are in the Treasury of Ptah, of refined (silver), again, for your subsistence each year at whatever house you desire.  You are the one authorized with regard to the arrears of your subsistence which shall be to my debit, and I am to give it to you.  All of everything that I possess and that which I shall acquire is the pledge of your annuity (4) aforesaid.  I shall not be able to say to you: 'Take the aforesaid annuity,' but on whatever day you desire it, I will give it to you.  If an oath is required of you to be taken for me, it is in the house in which the judges are that you are to take it for me.''  Written by Djkhonswiwfankh, son of Perel.  [Greek Docket:] First Hand:  (Year) 27, Epeiph 19, it (sc. the agreement) has been deposited in the (official) chest at Crocodilopolis of the Lake District by Andragathos, the agent of Philinos.  Second Hand: (Year) 27, Epeip (sic) 19, and by Kuprides, the tax-farmer(?), and by Sosipatros, the agent of Polemon.  [Below Greek Docket:] Written by Patiwsir, son of Imhetep.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
