<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Annuity contract</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.5</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)5</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. O.I.  25259  (P. Chic. Haw. 3)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyd">Demotic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>papyrus ; 142.0 x 35.0 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto: 4 lines in Demotic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto: Contract with four witness copies</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The roll is made up of 10 individual papyrus sheets, each ca. 14 cm in width. A 4 cm strip of papyrus is on the right end and a 5 cm papyrus strip is on left end</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="-0311" notAfter="-0310">December 9, 311-January 7, 310 B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Hawara, in the Fayum district, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Ankhmerwer, son of Patinaneterw and Ankhet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nanefermenibptah, daughter of Payarimen and Shety</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sysobek, son of Imhetep</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sobekhetep, son of Herwdja</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ankhsematawy, son of Imenemhat</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Patiherpasheriset, son of Paranetreq</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Djehutyiw, son of Patinaneterw</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyd">Demotic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. O.I. 25259 (P. Chic. Haw. 3)  recto: (1) Year 7, second month of the season akhet, of Pharaoh Alexander (IV), son of Alexander (the Great). The god's sealer and embalmer, Ankhmerwer, son of Patinaneterw, whose mother is Ankhet, has declared to the woman Nanefermenibptah, daughter of the god's sealer and embalmer Payarimen, whose mother is Shety: ''You have caused (my) heart to agree to the silver (deben) (weighed) by the pieces of the Treasury of Ptah, (of) refined (silver), (2) being 9 silver (deben) 9, 5/6, 1/10, 1/30, 1/60 kite, being 10 silver (deben) (weighed) by the pieces in the Treasury of Ptah, (of) refined (silver), again, as your annuity. There belong to you and the children whom you will bear to me everything which I possess and that which I shall acquire (in) house, field, courtyard, building plot, male servant, female servant, cow, ass, every animal, every office, every document, every matter of a freeman in the world belonging to me. To you do they belong. I am to give to you 36 (sacks) emmer (by the measure of) 40-hin, (3) being 24 (sacks) barley (by the measure of) 40-hin, being 36 (sacks) emmer (by the measure of) 40-hin again, and 1 silver (deben) and 2 kite (weighed) by the pieces in the Treasury of Ptah, (of) refined (silver), being 1 silver (deben) and 1, 5/6, 1/10, 1/30, 1/60, 1/60, kite, being 1 silver (deben) and 2 kite (weighed) by the pieces in the Treasury of Ptah, (of) refined (silver), again, for your subsistence each year at whatever house you desire. You are the one authorized with regard to the arrears of your subsistence which shall be to my debit, and I am to give it to you. Everything which I possess and that which I shall acquire are the pledge of your aforesaid annuity. I shall not (4) be able to say to you, 'Take your annuity,' but on whatever day you desire it, I will give it to you. If an oath is required of you to be taken for me, it is in the house in which the judges are that you are to take it for me.'' Written by Sysobek, son of Imhetep.  [Beginning of Witness Copy:] 1 ''Servant of Neith, Sobekhetep, son of Herwdja, being a witness in year 7 etc. to the statement made...'' [Beginning of Witness Copy 2:] ''Ankhsematawy, son of Imenemhat, being a witness in year 7 etc. to the statement made...'' [Beginning of Witness Copy 3:] ''Patiherpasheriset, son of Paranetreq, being a witness in year 7 etc. to the statement made...'' [Beginning of Witness Copy 4:] ''Djehutyiw, son of Patinaneterw, being a witness in year 7 etc. to the statement made...'&amp;apos</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
