<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Qur'an; a waqf (?) given by Sultan Faraj</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.7829</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)7829</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">O.I. 12066</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Surah 41:47-45:32 (most of juz' 25) (Kufan system)</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">The text page is 6.5 x 11 cm.  Folio 2a is the title page for juz' 25.  The original writing on this page refers to something fully detailed in juz' 1 so that although juz' 25 is now separate, it must have originally belonged to a complete copy of the Qur'an donated by Sultan Faraj.  The original waqf notation at the beginning of juz' 1 became a title page and it became necessary to cross-reference that waqf sheet.  The copyist stopped at the end of Surah 45:32, so the juz' is short 5 verses.  The color scheme in this manuscript is gold, red, white, and blue.  The title page bears a rectangular panel at the top with a gold and gray-blue background on which the juz' number is written in white.  The panel is framed with a double gold border outlined in black.  Below this panel and separated from it by a broad gold strip is a square enclosing an 8-lobed medallion, which contains a conventional leaf motif of gold with a few red touches on a background of blue.  The medallion is surrounded by a gold band.  The rest of the space within the square is filled with a design in gold on a background of red.  The square and the juz' panel are together enclosed in a gold frame outlined in double lines of black.  A heavy gray-blue line with small curved ornaments and short "finials" completes the frame.  In the outer margin in line with the juz' panel is a circular medallion of gold over red with a gray-blue frame.  Folios 45b and 46a are ornamental pages of careful execution.  In a gray-blue and gold border is an area 5.8 x 7 cm.  The interlinear space is filled with a tendril and trefoil design, also outlined in black and touched at points with red or blue on a background hatched in red.  The surah titles each occupy the space of a regular line and are written in gold outlined in black.  Small 6-petaled gold rosettes with blue and red dots mark the ends of verses.  A small gold almond outlined in blue and containing a central red trefoil marks off 5 verse groups, while a circular ornament of concentric blue and gold bands with red dots and black "finials" is placed in the outer margin to mark off 10 verse groups.  In the central blue area, written in gold, is the word 'ashr.  The cover design is likewise elaborate.  Interlacing bands form 5 and 6 pointed stars and other polygons, regular and irregular, on a background partly gold-punched.  4 octagons are outlined in gold and the panel is enclosed in a narrow, gold-tooled band.  A narrow double twist filled in with gold punches completes the design of the front cover, which is repeated on the back cover.  The end flap has a gold-tooled medallion formed by interlacing bands that produce 7 pointed stars and other polygons within a circle.  A key pattern fills the rest of the panel, which is enclosed by blind- and gold-toothed bands.  The leather lining of the cover shows a blind-tooled design of tendrils and conventionalized leaves and flowers.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto and verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>paper ; 12.5 x 18.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The folios are well-preserved on the whole.  A few near the beginning are discolored.  Some others are worm-eaten along the inner margins.  The lower margins as well as the lower part of the binding have been damaged by water, so that the leather of the binding has darkened and the paper has lost its gloss and become rough.  The binding has suffered much damage.  The original back strip and also the hinge of the flap seem to have been thoroughly worm-eaten, for the present pieces are later additions and are clumsy attempts at repairing.  But even these are damaged, much of the back strip in particular having been eaten away.  The flyleaves at beginning and end are also later additions.  They are lighter in weight and less glossy, and the leaf at the end bears a watermark that is evidently meant for a sun disk, a symbol used frequently by Italian and French papermakers.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">47 folios with 5 lines each in Arabic.  Folios 45b and 46a have 3 lines each in Arabic.</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto and verso: Qur'an</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The title page, folio 2a, is a palimpsest, done over 6-8 lines of fine script in several hands.  The script is only partly visible, but enough can be read to show that the notations are similarto those that appear on many books of juz' title pages of Qur'ans donated to mosques.  These, in addition to stating the waqf, usually include the incipit and the name of the copyist and sometimes the date of the work, the signatures of 1 or 2 witnesses, and some pious phrases.  The outer margin has a notation in general manuscript hand.  The manuscript is written in a fully pointed and fully voweled naskhi, all in the same black ink.  The title page and the surah titles are in thuluth khafif, the former in white, the latter in gold.  The manuscript is, on the whole, carefully executed, though mistakes are not wanting.  Where these occur a correction has frequently been attempted in a different hand by erasing and rewriting, with the result that the line or page is disfigured.  Reading symbols and notations are lacking.  Folios 45b and 46a contain a naskhi script, each irregularly outlined in black.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="1399" notAfter="1412">1399-1412 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Islam</term>
               <term>Qur'an</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">paper</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
