<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Book of the Dead</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.254</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)254</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. OIM 10486 (2)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Undated.  Presented by Mrs. Elizabeth Milbank Anderson.  Spiegelberg first noted that P. Milbank (M) was a Ptolemaic text in a letter dated 27 June 1922 to James H. Breasted.  Spiegelberg's dating was based on P. Milbank's resemblance to T, the Turin BD published by Lepsius in 1842.  On plate LX of the latter is a demotic marginal note, clearly Ptolemaic (see Spiegelberg in ZAS LVIII [1932] 152 ff).  Georg Moeller, cited by Spiegelberg, would date T more exactly to the 2nd-1st century BC.  Naville, too, at least as early as 1904, had believed T to be ''of the Ptolemaic epoch'' (see his introduction to P. le Page Renouf, The Book of the Dead: Translation and Commentary, Paris and Leipzig, 1907, p. clii).  The name of M's beneficiary is not a certain clue, for it is of a type that begins by the 26th dynasty.  The fine lines of the writing, however, are more definite.  (Allen p. 40);There are vignettes associated with BD 1, 17, 16, 18, 21, 23-8, 30, 64, 31-3, 36, 38-41, 74-5, 77-88, 72, 54, 56, 59, 52, 44, 63, 45, 50, 47, 93, 43, 89, 91-2, 98, 100-2, 94, 104, 68, 71, 105-6, 108, 110, 113, 111, 114-5, 124, 119, 125, 112-3, 125-6, 129, 140, 63, 138-9, 133-4, 102, 143-50, 92, 154, 151-2, 155-62.;BD 16 consists of a vignette only between lines 133 and 134.  For discussions of similar scenes, see K. Sethe, ''Altaegyptische Vorstellungen vom Lauf der Sonne,'' in Preussische Akademie der Wissenschaften, Philos.-hist. Klasse, Sitzungsberichte, 1928, p. 259-84 and H. Schaefer, ZAS 71 (1935), 15-38.  BD 110c is a vignette only, arranged in four registers, each under its own sky.  At the top, Khepri squats enshrined on a bark behind which squat Isis and Nephthys.  In the next panel, the deceased stands praying while Harpocrates presents offerings to the enthroned Osiris flanked by standing Isis.  In each of the bottom two registers, the deceased kneels while presenting offerings to two squatting gods.  BD 110b (lines 597-600) also consists of four registers.  (597) The contents are in disorder and some of its legends are unreadable.  Deceased, kneeling with a tree behind him, presents a bundle of flax (see Gardiner's Grammar M 37 f) to the Sun-god in his bark.  A second, smaller bark bears a deity with ;an inverted basket; for a head.  (cf. a similar scene in vignette BD 17 of BM 10470 (Ani, pl. 10), where the gods are Khepri and Atum respectively.)  The hieroglyphs at left include a horizon sign, three city signs, and possibly the words ''his phoenixes.''  (598) Deceased plows, reaps, and ;binds sheaves; before three squatting sungods.  The hieroglyphs at left repeat in part signs used in top register.  (599) Deceased threshes.  A tree precedes the bark of Osiris, above which is written ''His name is the Good God.''  Two unnamed gods squat at left.  (600-603) The bottom register consists of two islands at right, which display respectively the words ''He whose name is (destined) to (be) Lord of the Gods'' (Or emend initial ''nty'' to ''aa'' and translate ''&lt;Greater is&gt; his name than (that of) the lord of the gods''?) and the figures of three squatting deities.  Toward these deceased is poling a papyrus skiff.  The inscription at left, resembling that at right, says perhaps ''He whose Name is (destined) to (be) Lord{s} of the Gods, the Pig, and the 3000 Snakes.''  (Or emend as before and translate ''&lt;Greater is&gt; his Name than (those of) the lords of the gods, the pig (Seth?), and the 3000 snakes''?)  For lines 660-701, P. Milbank has the same sequence as T, but in reverse order, except that P. Milbank omits 25 and repeats 29 at the end (which should have been thebeginning).  For this reason, 660-701 are translated here in reverse order, since they were evidently reversed in writing.  BD 143 is a vignette only located between BD 130 and 144.  In P. Milbank, the top and bottom registers of the five registers found in P. Ryerson (OIM 9787) are omitted.  BD 150 consists of vignettes further illustrating BD 149.  M's legend ''Abode of water,'' seems to fit abode 13; the rest are not standard.  M's forms represent abodes 1, 4, 10, perhaps 11 (or is this legend meant for ''aat (djew qa) aa'', ''Abode of the two great (high mountains),'' appropriate to abode 4 above it?), 12 (three times), and 15, besides uncertain ones.  In the 2 columns after BD 154, vignettes of BD 151-2 and 155-60 appear, all without text.;Square brackets [ ] denote lost text and lines ; ; indicate uncertain text.  Braces { } denote superfluous words and parentheses ( ) indicate elements supplied, comments or emended text.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyp">Hieroglyphics</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>15 papyri ; 1029.0 cm x 30.6 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">When acquired, this papyrus had never been completely unrolled.  Upon being unrolled for mounting, some of the flyleaf that preceded the writing crumbled.  That end was then trimmed.  The top and bottom edges are slightly frayed and a few minor breaks occur, but even there the signs are damaged rather than completely lost.  (Allen p. 39)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">On recto: 1115 lines in hieroglyphics</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto: Book of the Dead</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The vignettes and the body of the text are in black.  Red is used for text rubrics of various kinds: whole spell, titles, introductory words, designations of hostile beings, sections of a tabulation, and terminal additions.  The vignettes of BD 16 and 144 have some details in red and 125d and 162 use some yellow.  Written in fine lines traced by a split-reed pen.  (Allen p. 45)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="-0199" notAfter="-0001">IInd - Ist century B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Irtywrw</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dyast</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thoth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Osiris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nut</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Re</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Unnofer</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Atum</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ruty</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptah</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apophis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Suty</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khepri</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sokar</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tatenen</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Shu</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Min</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Isis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nephthys</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Truth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Seth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Imset</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hapi</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Duamutef</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Qebehsenuf</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sobk</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Asdez</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Whom His Father Sees</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Is Under His Moringa Tree</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horus with No Eyes in His Forehead</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anubis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nedjhedj</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dozer</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Bull Who Gives No Heat</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Observant One in His Prime</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Sees by Night Him Whom He Carried Off by Day</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">the Great One</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tefnut</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Geb</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Robber</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Shezmew</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nefertem</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Bastet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Swallower of Millions</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Keen One</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Beb</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Master of His Affairs</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">She Who Licks him</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Arsaphes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Uto</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Upwawet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khnum</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menkaure</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hardedef</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Rerek</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hathor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Selqet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Montu</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Neit</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ihy</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tekem</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sopd</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Arptahha</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyp">Hieroglyphics</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Naref; Punt; Khemmis; Abydos; Mendes; Memphis; Pe; Hierakonpolis; Hermopolis; Heliopolis; Rosetau; Dep; Washerman's Shores; Sais; Kheraha; Letopolis; Upper Egypt; Lower Egypt; Heracleopolis; Field of Rushes; Bubastis; Fayyum; Busiris ;Pomegranate; Weryt; Wenes; Nedjfet; Wednet; Asyut; Antaeopolis; Edfu; Kharet; Zekret; Pelusium; Aswan; City of the Two Ears; Antaeopolis</term>
               <term>Funerary</term>
               <term>Religion</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. OIM 10486 (2), recto continued: (508) (BD 99) SPELL FOR BRINGING {WATER} THE FERRYBOAT.  (509) Bring me the ferryboat, bring me the ferryboat of the Deep, attach (for) me the towrope, (that I may) go forth (510) thereby, (that I may) detour around yonder shoal, and vice versa.  (When) I come, may there shine for me that egg of mystery, (that I may)  ascend (to) you.  Bring me (511) the ferryboat, attach for me (the towrope), at Re's ascent, to (cause) that (I) go.  May ye say: ''Bring (him) the ferryboat on the way, (512) attach for him the towrope, (at Re's ascent,) that he may become powerful thereby, that he may circle to (this) his path.  His Soul ascends to know his (Father) Re (at) his setting, (it being) in his train.  (513) He exists in the west, (while) all the gods serve (him).''  The egg that is in secret shines for me.  There has been brought to me the ferryboat of the Deep, and the towrope has been attached for (me), (that I may) go forth (514) thereby (515) every day.  (516) ''TELL ME MY NAME,'' SAYS THE MOORING PIN.  TO BE SAID BY OSIRIS IRTYWRW JUSTIFIED: LADY OF THE TWO LANDS (AND OF) WORK IS THY NAME.  (517) ''TELL ME MY NAME,'' SAYS THE MAL(LET).  TO BE SAID BY OSIRIS IRTYWRW JUSTIFIED: UPLIFTED ?BY? (THESE) GODS IS YOUR NAME.  (518) ''TELL ME MY NAME,'' SAYS ?THE (UPPER) heb?.  TO BE SAID BY OSIRIS IRTYWRW JUSTIFIED: THE HAND OF UPWAWET IS THY NAME.  (519) ''TELL ME MY NAME,'' SA(YS) (...).  TO BE SAID BY OSIRIS IRTYWRW JUSTIFIED: WINDPIPE OF IMSET IS THY NAME.  (520) ''TELL ME MY NAME,'' SAYS THE (azet).  TO BE SAID BY OSIRIS IRTYWRW JUSTIFIED: NUT IS THY NAME.  (521) ''TELL ME MY NAME,'' SAYS THE BOW (ROPE).  TO BE SAID BY OSIRIS IRTYWRW JUSTIFIED: ANUBIS WITH {WITH} (...) WORK IS THY NAME.  (522) ''TELL ME MY NAME,'' (SAYS) ?THE LOWER heb?.  TO BE SAID BY OSIRIS IRTYWRW JUSTIFIED: DUAMUTEF IN THE GOD'S DOMAIN IS THY NAME.  (523) ''TELL ME MY NAME,'' (SAY) WATER (AND) WOOD.  TO BE SAID BY OSIRIS IRTYWRW JUSTIFIED: JUDGE IS YOUR NAME.  (524) Hail to you, lords of truth, void of falsehood, who stay alive forever (for) the periods to eternity.  Separate ye me (from the earth), for I am blessed (with) (525) your form and in control of your  magic and esteemed as ye are esteemed.  (R)escue ye me from (the crocodile) who is in (this land of) the Two Truths.  Give ye (526) to me my (mouth), that (I) may speak therewith.  Oblations are given me in your presence, because I know you (every) day and know the name of that great god (527) at (whose) nose ye place provisions.  His name is (T)ekem.  He has access to the western horizon of the sky; he has access to the {his} eastern horizon of the sky.  If he goes, I go, and vice versa; (if he stays sound,) (528) I stay sound, and vice versa.  Ye shall not eject me from the mesqet-region, and transgressors shall not prevail over (me).  (529) (BD 100) SPELL FOR EMBARKING IN THE BARK OF RE.  (530) I FERRY the phoenix to Abydos, Osiris (531) to Mendes.  I have opened the cave of the Inundation, I have (532) smoothed the way of the Disk, (I...) his (...), (533) and I have (made) powerful Sokar on the sledge.  (534) (BD 102) SPELL FOR PROTECTING THE BARK OF RE.  (535) O Great One in his bark, I have brought thee thy bark (536) which is in charge of thy efflux.  My (...) is in (my) body; ?water is (in) (537) him who goes to his father?.  I am one who has ascended as (538) your doorkeeper ?to barley and to wheat?.  He has ascended, ?my spell being? upon him.  (539) (BD 101) SPELL FOR ASCENDING TO THE BARK OF RE.  (540) O Re in this thy name of Re, if (541) thou passest by thy flood (in) thy bark, (I) go forth (542) with thee.  Behold, I am gone forth (behind thee), (543) Re.  See, I am going forth to thee to thy Bark.  (544) (BD 94) SPELL FOR (OBTAINING THE PALETTE).  (545) O GREAT ONE WHO SEES his Father, O ?Eldest? who art in charge of (546) the book of Thoth, behold, I am blessed, (powerful), possessed of a soul.  (548) (When) I go forth with (thee), it goes to know thee.  (549) (BD 104) SPELL FOR SITTING WITH THE GODS.  (550) SPELL (FOR) OPENING BE(SIDE) Hathor, mistress of the sky.  I am one who sits (am(551)ong) the great gods, having passed along the road of Hathor, mistress (552) (of the sky).  I ascend with thee.  I have gone.  I am one who sees (553) his Father.  Your name goes (and comes every day).  (554) (BD 68) SPELL FOR GOING FORTH BY DAY.  (555) IT HAS BEEN GRANTED (TO) HIM that he control his  mouth and that he go forth (by) day.  It has been granted to him (556) that he control water; it has been granted that he control the flood.  (557) It has been granted to him that he control his legs; it has been granted that he control (558) mortuary offerings; it has been granted that he control his feet in going forth.  (559) (BD 71) SPELL FOR (GOING FORTH BY) DAY AND REPULSING ?THE SWALLOWER?.  (560) O falcon who risest (from) the deep, (lord) (561) of the Great Flood, mayest thou keep me sound just as (562) thou keepest thy(self) sound.  Mayest thou (loose me), (mayest thou free me.  Put me d)own.  ''Grant (563) his desire,'' (says) he who came forth from thee.  (O) falcon, (564) when thou risest, mayest thou keep me sound just as thou keepest thyself sound.  (May I) ascend with thee.  (565) (BD 105) SPELL FOR MAKING SPIRITS CONTENT.  (566) HAIL TO THEE, my spirit within me, as thou standest (there).  I have circled (567) with thee.  Behold, I am blessed, (powerful), (568) possessed of a soul.  I have ascended with thee.  (569) Your (name), ?which I? recognize, goes (and comes).  I (am) ascended in (570) its sight, when (it) circles to see its Father.  I have gone; (I know) that I have gone forth (against) (...).  (571) SPELL FOR MAKING A MAN'S SPIRIT CONTENT.  (572) IT ASCENDS with thee, (O) falcon who risest from the deep.  (573) (The souls), they ascend with thee.  Water comes; (574) it has circled for thee (in) the sight of the gods.  (I am) ascended to see it.  (575) I know that it has gone forth against him who would restrain it.  Hail to (576) thee, my spirit that has gone forth from (me).  I have circled (...).  (577) (BD 106) SPELL FOR GIVING AN OFFERING IN MEMPHIS.  (578) O (thou) Great of provisions, O Great One pre(579)siding over the upper houses, (ye) who give bread {bread} and beer to the gods in his presence, (590) he has commanded that ye give him bread and beer day and night (on) going forth (591) from Memphis.  He has gone to the house of Re.  (592) He shall not be kept away from (any) gate that he may wish to approach (on) going forth against you.  (593) (BD 108) SPELL FOR KNOWING THE SOULS OF THE WEST.  (584) As for that mountain of the eastern range from whose horizon the doorkeepers go forth, (it exists) in the east of the sky.  There are 7 cubits in his length.  He has gone forth in (585) sight of it until Re goes over the top of his mountain.  The 7-cubit doorkeepers go forth when he (Re) shines upon the west.  The gods serve him (when) (586) Re goes forth and has entered (therein).  Sobk, (lord) of the eastern range, shall see Hathor, lady of the eastern range.  (I) shall not be seized (when) (587) Atum goes forth, (for) I know the name(s) (and) I know the (588) name(s) of your 7-cubit Souls who are ascended to him in his broad hall.  Re shines upon him when he is in the west of the sky.  (589) Sobk, lord of the eastern range, shall rejoice over him on (t)his road of them that are in the west as (surely as) he knows his name when Re goes forth.  (590) Seven cubits (...) the broad hall of him who has ascended to me.  He knows your road.  I am the one who has come forth from you; I have gone (...).  His name, which is ascended to him from ?(me)?, it shall not be known (591) by (living) beings.  Sobk, lord of the eastern range, (shall be...).  As for one who knows the name(s of) the gods who exist in the west, (he) shall go forth with them: Atum, Sobk, and Hathor, lady of the eastern range.  (592) (BD 109) KNOWING THE SOULS OF THE EAST.  (593) (I) KNOW the name(s) of the gods ?whom ye (know)?, (for) I am one who has come forth from them.  I know that sycamore of (turquoise) from under (which) Re comes forth, (for) I have come forth (from under th)at sycamore of tur(594)quoise.  (I) know the name (of...) of (...) which Re comes forth.  He knows (...) because of what he has spoken.  The (god of) Light rises for him, having come subject to him.  Come thou, Re (...).  He sees his Father's face (595) and goes, ascending (when) Re rises (for) him.  He rests upon the bark of Re when he is ascended.  (I) know the name(s of) the gods (...).  They circle above the gods of (his) broad hall because of your guidance.  (I) know (596) the name (of the sycamore) that is in them of tur(quoise).  (I) know that Field of Rushes, who(se) wall is (of met)al.  Re ascends, and the double doors serve him (at his ascent).  He shall not take (me) to the east of the sky any day.  (597-603) (BD 110) [This is a series of scenes with captions; see notes.]    (604) (BD 111) KNOWING THE SOULS OF PE.  (605) AS FOR THAT MOUNTAIN OF the eastern range (606) on which the doorkeepers go forth in the west of the sky, (607) this (...) its (...); it goes forth while it exists in (...).  (608) He knows the Gods who are in Pe.  (609) (BD 112) KNOWING THE SOULS OF PE.  (610) (I) know the great gate which is in (611) Pe.  I am Re when he goes forth from (612) his shrine.  He grew large yesterday; (613) he ascends daily.  (614) (BD 113) KNOWING THE SOULS OF HIERACONPOLIS.  (615) (I) know the secrets of (Hieraconpolis).  (616) I am one who came forth from Atum, one whom he knew (617) (of old).  He is one whom (618) the Ennead illumines as he rejoices.  I am one who is seen with you.  (619) (BD 114) KNOWING THE SOULS OF HERMOPOLIS.  (620) ?A THRUST.?  (621) Verily the Deep ASCENDS; god goes (621) with god.  Re ascends to his horizon; (622) he knows him who is in his gate, (for) he has seen his corpse.  (623) The dweller in Hermopolis rises (for) him and sets for him.  They ascend through his (gate) to the day.  (624) (BD 115) SPELL FOR KNOWING THE SOULS OF HELIOPOLIS.  (625) I am one who grew large yesterday.  (I) know (626) him whose hands serve me (when) he has ascended.  I am (627) Re (when) he ascends from his horizon.  (I) know (628) against whom the gods go forth (in) going forth from the sky.  (629) SPELL FOR GOING FORTH TO THE SKY (AND TO) THE GODS OF THE NETHER SKY.  (630) I am one in whose behalf Re GOES FORTH at (whatever) gate he will (when) he sets.  (631) (O) ye gods with whom he has gone, I am one who has ascended to the (632) sky with Re.  Serve me, all gods, (for I am) on (633) his throne (and) Re encircles (my) (image).  (634) (BD 116) Knowing the Souls of Heliopolis.  (635) (I) KNOW you (and) him who has ascended with you.  (636) Ye see me ?(ascended)? to the place which he desires (and) on (637) (his) seat.  The god ?comes?; he knows what is (in) their bodies.  (638) He has gained access to the way to the west.  (When) he ascends, I (a)m ascended ?(with him)?.  (639) (BD 124) SPELL FOR GOING DOWN TO THE COUNCIL of Osiris.  (640) (My) Soul BUILDS its throne in Mendes ?(be)fore? (641) the Elders (when) I ascend (to) the place (whither) one has ascended.  (O thou) who circlest (642) for him and shinest for him, come to me, (for) I am (643) one who has ascended (and) I know my ?destiny?.  (644) (BD 117) SPELL FOR TAKING THE ROAD.  (645) SPELL (FOR) TAKING THE ROAD in Rosetau.  I am the great one who made (646) his light.  (I have) come unto thee, Osiris, that (I) may praise thee and wash away thy efflux which went forth (647) from Rosetau.  The road of my face is (that of) Rosetau.  I go in and out of Rosetau.  (648) (BD 119) SPELL FOR GOING FORTH FROM ROSETAU.  (649) THE ROAD OF MY FACE is toward Rosetau.  I am one who has gone forth from Rosetau.  I have brought offerings (650) to Abydos.  Open for me the road in Rosetau, (for) I have (healed) things in (Os)iris.  (651) My name is in Rosetau.  (I) go in and out of Rosetau (daily).  (652) (BD 125) HAIL TO YOU, ye gods, in the broad hall of the Two Truths, who live on truth and sip of truth in the presence of Him Who Is in His Disk, who live on (keeper(s)) (653) of evil and Who Sip of (their) blood.  (Behold,) I am come unto you.  I have brought you truth; I have done away with {truth (for) you; I have (...)ed} sin (for) you.  I, I have ascended unto you; (654) I am one of you.  (BD 72) Hail to you, lords of truth, void of falsehood, who stay alive forever (for) the periods to eternity.  Separate ye me from the earth, (for) I am blessed with (655) your forms and in control (of) your magic and esteemed as ye are esteemed.  Rescue ye me from the crocodile who is in this land of the Two Truths.  Give (656) ye to me my (mouth), {my (mouth),} that (I) may speak therewith.  Oblations are given me in your presence, because I know y(ou).  (...)  He penetrates the western horizon of the sky; (657) he penetrates the eastern horizon of the sky.  If he goes, I go, and vice versa; if he stays sound, I stay sound, and vice versa.  Ye shall not eject me from the mesqet-region, and transgressors shall not prevail (658) over him.  Ye shall not keep me from (your) gate(s); ye shall not shut your doors on him.  My bread is in Pe, {his} my beer is in Dep.  I have clasped (659) my hands in the temple.  My father Atum gives to me, he (e)rects for me, (a house) as (for) one who is on earth, with in(numer)able barley (and) wheat therein.  A feast has been celebrated for me therein by (my) son of (my) body.  (He) has ascended unto us.  (701) (BD 125) O offering-bringer who came forth (from) (Sais), I have NOT done violence.  (700) O far-strider who came forth from Heliopolis, I have NOT committed sins.  (699) O open-mouthed one who came forth (from) Kheraha--variant: fire(-embracer), I have NOT (robbed).  (698) O nosy one who came forth from Hermopolis, I have NOT been tricky.  (697) O swallower (of shadows) who came forth from the Twin Caverns, I have NOT stolen.  (696) O (fie)rce of face who came forth from the necropolis, I have NOT (killed) settl(ers).  (695) O ye Two Lion-Gods who came forth from the sky, I have NOT debased measures.  (694) O thou whose eyes (are) fire who came forth from Letopolis, I have NOT made diminutions.  (693) O face-afire who came forth afterward from Heliopolis, I have NOT stolen thy property which came forth ?from...?.  (692) O (bone-breaker) who came forth from Heracleopolis, I have NOT told a lie.  (691) O thou whose breath is fire who came forth from the House of Ptah--variant: quickener of the flame, (I) have NOT (ta)ken away food--variant: I have not troubled (others).  (690) O ?thou of the necropolis? of Bubastis who came forth from the crypt, I have NOT wept--variant: I have not wept.  (689) O backward-facer who came forth from the tomb-(c)ave, I have NOT (done wrong sexually), I have not practiced homosexuality.  (688) O cavern-dweller who came forth from the west, I have NOT (been ill-tempered)--variant: done harm.  (687) O hot-feet who came forth from the twilight, I have NOT wasted my time.  (686) O (white)-toothed one who came forth from the Fayyum, I have NOT transgressed.  (685) O blood-eater who came forth from (the slaughtering-block), I have NOT killed the divine bull.  (684) O eater of entrails who came forth from the court of the thirty, I have NOT profiteered on grain loans.  (683) O lord of (truth) who came forth from the Two Truths, (I) have NOT robbed the Surveyors.  (682) O (strayer) who came forth from Bubastis, (I) have NOT eavesdropped {with my mouth}.  (681) O (?pale one?) who came forth from Heliopolis, I have NOT been (garrulous).  (680) O doubly evil one who came forth from Busiris, I have NOT quarreled over property.  (679) O wammty-snake who came forth from the place of execution, I have NOT committed adultery.  (678) O seer of what he brings who came forth from the house of Min, I have NOT been unchaste.  (677) O superior of the elders who came forth from Pomegranate, who came forth from Busiris, I have NOT inspired terror.  (676) O troublemaker who came forth from Weryt, I have NOT been hot-tempered.  (675) O ch(ild) who came forth from the Heliopolitan nome, I have NOT been (deaf) to (words) of truth.  (674) O dark one who came forth from darkness, I have NOT quarreled.  {I have not been (deaf) to (words) of truth.}  (673) O offering-bringer who came forth from Sais, I have NOT done violence.  (672) O settler of argument who came forth from Wenes, (I) have NOT made trouble.  (671) O lord of men who came forth from (N)edj(f)et, (I) have NOT been quick-tempered.  (670) O counselor{s} who came forth from (W)ednet, (I) have NOT harmed the aspect of the divine...  (669) O horned one who came forth from Asyut, (I) have NOT been garrulous (about) matters.  (668) O Nefertem (of) Pe who came forth from Busiris, I have (done) NO wrong, (I) have done no ill nor evil.  (667) O (letter of) none (survive) who came forth from the House of Ptah, I have NOT quarreled (over) the king, (I have) not (revi)led my father.  (666) O thou who acts as he will who came forth from Antaeopolis, I have NOT waded in the water.  (665) O Ihy who came forth from the deep, {he} I have NOT been loud-voiced.  (664) O prosperer (of the common folk) who came forth from Sais, I have NOT reviled the God.  (663) O uniter of benefits who came forth from Heliopolis, (I) have NOT debased the offering-cakes of the gods, (I) have not slandered a servant to his superior.  (662) O Neheb-ka who came forth from his hole, (I) have NOT made plots against him--(variant: I) have not exalted anyone more than him, (I) have not (added) to the {your} balance.  (661) O Head-up who came forth from his shrine, NOT large have been (my) plans except with (my) property, (and I) have not taken away (the laid-aside raiment) (of) Thoth.  (660) O ?carrier-off of his portion? who came forth from the god's (domain), there is NO blasphemy in my heart.  (702) HAIL TO THEE, great god, lord of the City of the Two Truths.  I have come unto thee, (my Lord), (that thou mayest bring) me to see thy beauty.  I have come to thee, Horus.  Hail to you, (703) ye great gods who are in the great broad hall of the City of the Two Truths.  (Behold,) I am come unto you; I am one of you.  Ye who live on truth and sip (704) of truth and chew in the presence of Horus who (is) in his Disk, rescue me.  (I have brought) you truth; I have done away with sin (for) you in (705) the place of truth.  May ye rescue me from (your) Messengers.  I have not sinned (against) you.  I am one who came forth from your place; I go on your road.  There is no evil in (706) me.  May my name be said (to) the gods, (for I have done what men request and) what the heart(s) of the gods are pleased with.  Hail to thee, Osiris presiding over the west, Unnofer justified.  I have not lied.  (May) my name (be said to) the gods.  I have not (been unchaste).  (707) May ye say to the ass and the cat within (that) it was Sobk who cleansed me with the efflux of ?(his)? children.  I have not copulated (illicitly); I have not copulated (illicitly).  I have not done evil against my {his} superior.  (708) I have not taken milk from a child's mouth.  I have not taken food or herbage from the mouth(s of) his cattle.  I have not dammed water while (it was) issuing forth.  I have not been (709) a coward; I have not made trouble.  I have entered your broad hall because I (saw) the splitting of the (ashed)-tree{s} beside (me) in Rosetau.  (I) have not (commanded) {my} killing; (710) I have not inspired terror.  I have ascended.  I know you, and ye see me.  I go on my ascent while ye rejoice in your broad hall.  (I am) (without) sin.  (711) I am one who has ascended in your train.  May ye say (...) me, because of what he has spoken to the king of Upper and Lower Egypt, Unnofer, justified.  ''(Thou shalt not...) unless thou tellest the name (of) thy {my} feet.''  Eldest Who Sees His Father { (712) Hail to you, ye gods who are in the great broad hall of the City of the Two Truths.  I have brought you truth; I (have) done away with (sin) (for you).}  is the name of (my) right foot.  (713) (I) walk upon thee by my magic.  (''I will not announce thee,'' says the doorkeeper,) ''unless thou tellest (my) name.''  (Perceiver) of Heart(s) (...is thy name).  I ascend to see thy (...), who (...when) he has ascended before him.  Conduct ?(me)? to thy hall, (for I) bear his (magic) words.  (714) (He is) Re; he has ascended (in) his bark to which the god goes.  AS FOR ONE WHO KNOWS THIS ROLL ON EARTH OR {HE} RECORDS IT IN WRITING ON (HIS) C(OFFIN), HE GOES FORTH BY DAY (IN) WHATEVER (FORM) (715) HE WISHES WITH EVERY BLESSED ONE OF HIS HOUSE.  THERE ARE GIVEN HIM BREAD AND BEER, A CAKE, LOAVES, AND (A CHUNK OF) MEAT FROM THE ALTAR {FROM} (OF) RE.  HE TARRIES IN THE FIELD OF RUSHES, AND BARLEY AND WHEAT (ARE GIVEN) TO HIM (THERE).  A TRULY EXCELLENT SPELL (PROVED) A MILLION TIMES.  (716) To be said b(y) Osiris Irtywrw justified, born of Dyast justified.  (717) Osiris Irtywrw justified.  (718) The Edfuan, great god, lord of the sky.  (719) To be said by Osiris the presider over the west, (720) lord of Rosetau, lord of Abydos, (721) lord of endless recurrence, ruler of changelessness, lord of the atef-(722)crowns in Heracleopolis, (723) dwelling in Kharet justified.  (724) (BD 126) TO BE SAID BY Osiris Irtywrw justified, born of Dyast justified: O ye 4 baboons who sit (725) at the prow of the bark of Re, who cause truth to ascend to the Lord of the Universe, he has caused that offerings be given (726) to the gods and mortuary offerings to the blessed, who sip (...).  (BD 127) (...) before Him Who Is in His Disk.  (Ye) who live as doorkeeper(s...) (727) evil when ye see me.  I am one of you; I go to your broad hall every day.  (728) (BD 129) I FERRY {TO Abydos} the Phoenix to Abydos, Osiris to Mendes.  (729) I have opened the cave of the Inundation.  He has smoothed the way of his Disk, he has praised So(ka)r (730) on his (sledge), and (he has made) powerful the royal uraeus in her instant.  I have removed (evil) from him; (731) I have ascended with him.  He has (driven away the Mourner), he (has) restrained his steps.  Re extends (his hands) to him; (732) I have ascended with him.  I praise Osiris; (I) continually screech to him.  He has gone to your road; (733) ?Horus? sees him when he has gone forth from you.  This spell which is in writing (is to be said), that a man (may be purified) (734) thereby.  He is permitted to go forth wherever he will, this (man).  (735) (BD 140) TO BE SAID BY Osiris Irtywrw justified, born of Dyast justified:  When the Mighty One dawns in the sky, (736) Re shines for him in his horizon; when Atum dawns, he pours out his fragrance.  Let the greatness of his priest be told to his Ennead.  (737) The water of the gods (comes) from the Sound Eye given to its Lord; it (the Eye) has given its bowl to the Ennead.  A truly excellent spell (proved) a million times.  (738) The sound of jubilation is (in) they sky, while great joy circulates at the dictum of Atum. (...) Given (him) are these: (739) Re, Atum, the Sound Eye, (742) Osiris, Geb, Shu, Tefnut, (746) the Ram of the Mendesian nome, Montu, the Inundation, (749) the Two Comrades, Hathor, Isis, Nephthys, (753) Nut, the Birth-Goddess, Earth, Eternity, (757) Horus, Neit, Uto, (760) Truth, Re, (762) and the {his} Children of Eternity.  (763) AN ALTAR (to) Re, AN ALTAR (to) Atum, AN ALTAR to the Sound Eye.  (766) THESE (ARE) ?ON BEHALF OF THY FATHER...?: (767) white bread in ?flat? loaves, 1; (768) bread and beer, 6 (HELPINGS); (769) white bread in ?flat? loaves, 6; (770) meat, 1; roast, 1; (772) incense in ?flat? loaves, 1.  (773) (BD 127) ROLL FOR PRAISING THE CAVE-GODS.  HAIL TO YOU, Cave-Gods who are in the west.  Hail to you, doorkeepers of the gates; hail to (774) you, doorkeepers of this god.  (Behold,) I am come unto you; I am one of you.  I have done away with and removed his (evil) from the west.  I know all that he discusses with you.  (775) I have come unto (you); it is I who have gone forth as your doorkeeper.  I saw ?Horus? after he had gone forth to the west and had fallen ?(in)? with him who judges his dead, the terror of whose name (hangs) over the west.  I see (my) Father Osiris every day.  (776) (BD 137) Spell for causing (the flame) to ascend.  (777) O Great One, make sound for me the eye of Horus to provide his protection.  He has circled about before him; (778) he (has) come (to) drive away the storm.  ?Horus? ascends when it has gone.  If he prospers, I prosper, (779) and vice versa.  The eye of Horus prospers; his hands have not been repulsed; he has circled about.  A truly excellent spell {justified} (proved) a million times.  (780) (BD 138) O gods who are in the east, the total live Council (as) they ascend, (I) (781) know their name(s).  (I) am esteemed, for I have ascended past all the gods as they come.  (The gates) (782) are opened for me by these gods, (for) I know (them), on the west of (the sky...)  He has ascended on his way.  (783) (BD 139) Praising Atum.  (784) HAIL TO THEE, Atum.  I am Thoth; I judged between the Two Comrades.  I did away with (785) their fighting.  I am Thoth; I have ascended on the beautiful ways of (the west.  I am) one who has judged, because I am (786) one who has ascended with thee, one whose throne has been assigned to him in Heliopolis, one who has heard his cases every day.  (787) (BD 128) Praising Osiris.  (788) HAIL TO THEE, Osiris Unnofer justified, son of Nut, son of the Great One, first (son) of Geb, who came forth from Nut, lord of Souls, Great of Dignity, lord of (the atef-crown) (789) in Heracleopolis, beloved in ?Mendes?, (numerous of festivals) in ?Busiris?, possessor of love in the Abydos nome.  I have come to Thee; (I am) Horus.  O Osiris, pray raise thyself, (790) that thou mayest circle the sky with Re, that thou mayest see the common folk, (for) the only one who sees (them) is Re.  (...) on (this) day of mortuary offerings (of...and) all good (things).  Thoth gives to him the {his} spells of the Great One that are in (791) his belly and go forth from his mouth.  It blesses thee in that thy name of Blessed One.  {It praises thee in that thy name of Blessed One.}  It praises thee in this thy name (of) (792) Magic.  (It) opens for thee {the Ways} the ways, ?that thou mayest come? in this thy name of Upwawet.  O Osiris, pray come.  Horus puts for thee {HIS} THY ENEMIES BENEATH THEE.  A TRULY EXCELLENT SPELL (PROVED) A MILLION TIMES.  (793) (BD 142) Making offering of incense (to) Osiris in his every name: (794) Osiris presiding over the west, Osiris of ankh, Osiris of ankhy, (797) Osiris Sopd, Osiris Orion, Osiris Unnofer, (800) Osiris the lord of ?Mendes?, Osiris the lord of Abydos, (802) Osiris the lord of Rosetau, Osiris the lord of the shetchyt-sanctuary, Osiris the lord of the Seat of Truth, (805) Osiris the lord of the Nether Sky, Osiris the lord of the Abydos nome, Osiris the lord of the Busirite nome, (808) Osiris the lord of the waste land, Osiris the lord of the castle, Osiris the lord of Heliopolis, (811) Osiris the lord of the abode, Osiris the lord of Kheraha, (813) Osiris the lord of endless recurrence, Osiris the lord of changelessness, Osiris the lord of the sky, (816) Osiris as the righteous one, Osiris in his every name, Osiris in his every seat, (819) Osiris in Memphis, Osiris in the House of Horus, Osiris in Zekret, (822) Osiris in Pe, Osiris in Dep, (824) Osiris in the southern and northern sanctuaries (of Sais), (826) Osiris in upper Sais, Osiris in lower Sais, (828) Osiris in the House of Min, Osiris in the house of Letopolis, (830) Osiris in the benben-House, Osiris as the ruler of changelessness, (832) Osiris in the sky, Osiris in the earth, (834) Osiris in the west, Osiris in the east, Osiris in the south, Osiris in the north, (838) Osiris (presiding over) the west, Osiris as Lord of the Universe, Osiris as Khepri, (841) Osiris as Sokar, Osiris in the Land of Sokar, {Osiris in Zekret,} (844) Osiris in the Embalming-House, Osiris in the Hall, Osiris in the House of Being, (847) Osiris in Pelusium, Osiris in Aswan, (849) Osiris in the Place of Execution, Osiris in ?the temple of million(s of years)?, Osiris in the City of the Two Ears, (852) Osiris among the Righteous (Gods), Osiris in the Upper Egyptian shrine, Osiris in the Silent Land, (855) Osiris in the Seat of the Throne, Osiris in Antaeo(polis), (857) Osiris in his every city, Osiris in every temple, Osiris in the Abydos nome; (860) Re-Horus and Atum; (862) Shu and Tefnut, Geb and Nut, Osiris and Horus, Isis and Nephthys; (870) the Night Bark, the Day Bark, the bark of Re; (873) the Deep and Truth; Anubis, Upwawet, and Truth; (878) Him with No (Eye)s in His Forehead, Him Who Sees His Father, Him Who (Sits) Under His Moringa Tree, and (881) Him Who Name(d) Himself.  (882) (BD 133) Spell for protecting the bark of Re.  (883) TO BE SAID BY Osiris Irtywrw justified, born of Dyast justified, engendered of Arptahha.  (884) Thou risest in thy horizon; thou shinest in the evening.  If thou passest (by) the Sound Eye (of) (885) 8 cubits, (then) ascend, (O) Re (886) who is in his shrine, because thy enemies have been brought for thee beneath thy sandals.  (There come to thee) (the two sanctuaries).  (887) (BD 134) Ascending to the bark of Re on the day of the new moon.  (888) HAIL TO THEE, Re in the midst of his shrine, rising in his horizon as he shines every day.  (889) (BD 133) Thou risest in thy horizon; thou shinest in the evening.  If thou passest (by) the Sound Eye (of) (890) 7 cubits, (then) ascend, (O) Re who circles about in this his delightful shining.  Pray lift thyself, for thou hast ascended, (O) Re (891) who is in his shrine, because THY ENEMIES have been brought for thee BENEATH THY SANDALS.  THERE COME TO THEE (THE TWO SANCTUARIES); (892) THEY GIVE THEE praise every day.  If thou passest (by) the Sound Eye (of) 7 cubits, thou ascendest to (thy) horizon every day forever.  (893) (BD 102) Spell for protecting the bark of Re.  O Great One in his bark, I have brought thee thy (bark which is in charge of) thy efflux.  I ascend (895) with thee to the sky when thou ascendest that thou mayest see the Ennead {who} who are in thy Retinue.  (BD 101) O Re in {in} (896) that thy name of Re, if thou goest to his eastern horizon of the sky, (he praises thee).  (897) The water swirls at (his) going forth.  O Re in this thy name of Re, (if) thou risest in thy horizon, (898) he praises the gods.  May (thy) beautiful face be gracious to him.  I have gone forth to see thee every day.  A truly excellent spell (proved) a million times.  (899) (BD 130) Roll for making a Blessed One live forever and letting him board the bark of Re and his follower(s).  Open to him in the sky; open to him, double doors.  Open to him, sky; open to him, earth.  Open to (900) him, West; open to him, East; open to him, South; open to him, North.  Open to him, double doors, in his horizon.  Open to him, gates of the night bark; open to him, double doors of the (901) day bark.  Open to him, bolts of Geb the hereditary prince of the gods.  He has created Shu; he has (inhale)d Tefnut.  Open to him, Upper Egyptian shrine; open, (902) Lower Egyptian shrine.  It has been granted him to enter into the bark of Re and his follower(s).  A truly excellent spell (proved) a million times.  (BD 143) (903) (BD 144) The doorkeeper of the first gate--the name of (its) doorkeeper (is...).  (904) The doorkeeper of the second gate--the name of (its) doorkeeper (is...).  (905) The doorkeeper of the third gate--the name of (its) doorkeeper (is...).  (906) The doorkeeper of the fourth gate--the name of (its) doorkeeper (is...).  (907) The doorkeeper of the fifth gate--the name of (its) doorkeeper (is...).  (908) The doorkeeper of the sixth gate--the name of (its) doorkeeper (is...).  (909) The doorkeeper of the seventh gate--the name of (its) doorkeeper (is...).  (910) (BD 145) (Beginning) of the portal(s) of the Field of Rush(es).  (911) ''HAIL TO THEE,'' SAYS Horus, ''first portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know (913) (thee), I know the name of the God the door(keeper) who is in her.''  (914) ''HAIL TO THEE,'' SAYS Horus, ''second portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know (thee), (916) I know (thy) name, I know the name of the God the door(keeper) in her.''  (917) ''HAIL TO THEE,'' SAYS Horus, ''third portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know (thee), (919) I know the name of the God the door(keeper) who is in her.''  (920) ''HAIL TO THEE,'' SAYS Horus, ''fourth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know (thee), (922) I know (thy) name, I know the name of the God the door(keeper).''  (923) ''HAIL TO THEE,'' SAYS Horus, ''fifth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know (thee), (925) I know the name of the God the door(keeper) in her.''  (926) ''HAIL TO THEE,'' SAYS Horus, ''sixth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know thee, (928) I know (thy) name, I know the name of the God who guards thee.''  ''Proceed.''  (929) ''HAIL TO THEE,'' SAYS Horus, ''seventh portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know (931) (thee), I know the name of the God (thy) door(keeper) who is in her.''  (932) ''HAIL TO THEE,'' SAYS Horus, ''eighth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I {your name} know (thee), (934) I know (thy) name, I know the name of the God (thy) door(keeper).''  (935) ''HAIL TO THEE,'' SAYS Horus, ''ninth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know (thy name), (937) I know the name of the God (thy) door(keeper).''  (938) ''HAIL TO THEE,'' SAYS Horus, ''tenth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know (thee), (940) I know (thy name), I know the name of the God thy door(keeper).''  (941) ''HAIL TO THEE,'' SAYS Horus, ''eleventh portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way (for me).  I know (thee), (943) I know the name of the God thy door(keeper) in her.''  (944) ''HAIL TO THEE,'' SAYS Horus, ''twelfth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know (thee), I (kn)ow (946) (thy) name, I know the name of the God (thy) door(keeper).''  (947) ''HAIL TO THEE,'' SAYS Horus, ''thirteenth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know (949) (thee), I know the name of the God (thy) door(keeper) in her.''  (950) ''HAIL TO THEE,'' SAYS Horus, ''fourteenth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know (thee), (952) (I) know (thy) name, I know the name of (thy) God.''  (953) ''HAIL TO THEE,'' SAYS Horus, ''fifteenth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make (way) for me.  I know the name of the God the door(keeper) who is in her  (955) {the name of the door(keeper); it is ye who are in her}.''  (956) ''HAIL TO THEE,'' SAYS Horus, ''(six)teenth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make (way) for me.  (I) know {know} (958) (thee), I know (thy name), {I know (thee),} (I) know (...).''  (959) ''HAIL TO THEE,'' SAYS Horus, ''seventeenth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know (thee), (961) I know (thy) name, I know the name of the God who is there.''  (962) ''HAIL TO THEE,'' SAYS Horus, ''eighteenth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know (thee), (964) I know (thy) name, I know the name of the God who is in (her).''  (965) ''HAIL TO THEE,'' SAYS Horus, ''(nine)teenth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know (thee), (967) I know the name of the God (thy) door(keeper).''  (968) ''HAIL TO THEE,'' SAYS Horus, ''twentieth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know (thee), (970) I know (thy) name, I know the name of the God (thy) door(keeper).''  (971) ''HAIL TO THEE,'' SAYS Horus, ''twenty-first portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know (thee), {I know (thee),} (972) I know (thy) name, I know the name of the God (thy) door(keeper).''  ''Lady of Fear, greatly esteemed, (is her name;...) is the name of (her) doorkeeper.  (...) is the name (of) the announcer in (973) her.''  ''Proceed, for thou art {thou art} pure with these waters wherewith the purification of Re has been performed (after he has been) b(ared...) with these waters.  They ascend against him every day.''  (974) (BD 146) (Beginning) of the portals of the Field of (Rushes).  (975) FIRST PORTAL.  The name of her doorkeeper is Lord of {Thy} Faces.  (976) SECOND PORTAL.  The name of the announcer in her is Lord of Storm.  (977) THIRD PORTAL.  The name of her doorkeeper is Lord of Heliopolis.  (978) FOURTH PORTAL.  The name of the announcer in her is Lord of This Sky.  (979) FIFTH PORTAL.  The name of her doorkeeper is Lord of Names.  (980) SIXTH PORTAL.  The name of the announcer in her is Lord of Battle.  (981) SEVENTH PORTAL.  The name of her doorkeeper is Lord of Flame.  (982) EIGHTH PORTAL.  The name of the announcer therein is Lord of ?Fire?.  (983) NINTH PORTAL.  The name of her doorkeeper is Lord of Terror.  (984) TENTH PORTAL.  The name of the announcer therein is Lord of the Altar.  (985) ELEVENTH PORTAL.  The name of the announcer therein is Lord of Two Eyes.  (986) TWELFTH PORTAL.  The name of her doorkeeper is Lord of Tumult.  (987) THIRTEENTH PORTAL.  The name of the announcer therein is Lord of ?Arrow(s)?.  (988) FOURTEENTH PORTAL.  The name of her doorkeeper is Rejoicer of the Two Lands.  (989) FIFTEENTH PORTAL.  The name of the announcer therein is Lord of the Sky.  (990) (BD 147) FIRST GATE.  (991) FIRST GATE.  The name of its doorkeeper is Lord of Fear.  The name of the announcer in it (is...).  To be said on (arriving) at this gate.  I have come (992) unto Thee, Osiris, that (I) may praise thee by washing away thy efflux.  O Osiris, come thou, that thou mayest circle the sky with Re, that thou mayest see the common folk.  (993) SECOND GATE.  (994) SECOND GATE.  The name of its doorkeeper is Numerous of Forms.  The name of (the guardian) in it is (995) Announcer; Repeller of (the Crocodile) is the name of the announcer in it.  To be said on (arriving at) this gate.  I have ascended through it every day.  (996) THIRD GATE.  (997) THIRD GATE.  The name of its doorkeeper is Repulsive of Face, Garrulous.  The name of its doorkeeper (is...); the name of the announcer (998) in it is Lord of Tumult.  To be said on (arriving) at this gate.  (O) raise thou thyself, Osiris.  (999) FOURTH GATE.  (1000) FOURTH GATE.  The name of its doorkeeper is Repulsive of Face, Garrulous.  The name of its doorkeeper (is...); the name of the announcer (1001) in it is Lord of Tumult.  To be said on (arriving) at this gate.  (O) raise thou (th)yself, Osiris.  (1002) FIFTH GATE.  (1003) FIFTH GATE.  The name of its doorkeeper (is...).  The name (of) its doorkeeper (is...); the name of the announcer in it (1004) is Violent of Voice.  To be said on (arriving) at (this) gate.  I have (come) from Rosetau.  (1005) SIXTH GATE.  (1006) SIXTH GATE.  The name of its doorkeeper is Lord of the{ir} Altar.  The name of (its door)(keeper) (is...; the name of) the announcer in it is (1007) Repeller of Storms.  To be said on (arriving) at this gate.  (I have come) (today), I have (reached) ?(my) father?.  His face is toward the breeze every day.  (1008) SEVENTH GATE.  (1009) SEVENTH GATE.  Its doorkeeper is Lord of Tumult.  The name of its doorkeeper (is...); the name of the announcer (1010) in it is Repeller of ?Joy?.  {The name of its doorkeeper (is...).}  To be said on (arriving) at this gate.  I am (1011) one who came forth from Rosetau.  I open for myself the road in Rosetau; I have presented offerings in Abydos every day.  (1012) (BD 148) ROLL FOR INITIATING the Blessed One into the mind of Re, putting his might before Atum, (1013) putting his magnification before Osiris, putting (awe) of him before {him} the presider over the west, putting his power before (1014) the Ennead, (putting) awe of him and love (of him) before Sokar-Osiris, letting him leave or enter (1015) the great broad hall of Osiris, that he may see ?Horus? (and) go with Re.  (1016) I have gone forth ?wearing? (...).  I have come into the presence of the great God, the lord of the west.  As for one who knows (1017) (this roll), he shall not be kept from any (gate) of the nether world.  He has conjured him be(1018)fore whom he has appeared, ?(and) none shall trample (him)? when he comes to the desert of Abydos.  (With the cows and bull:) (1019) The Hidden One Presiding Over Her Place; the Red-haired One; She Whose Name Is Powerful Over Her Shadow; the Possessor of Life; (1020) the Bright Red One; She Whose (Love) Is Great; (She of) the Spirit-House, Lady of the Universe; and the bull, the lord of the cows.  (With the steering oars:) (1021a) O circler, Leader of the Two Lands, (1022a) good steering oar of the western sky; (1021b) O good Power, opener of the Disk, (1022b) good steering oar of the eastern sky; (1021c) O sunshine dwelling in the house of the red one, (1022c) good steering oar of the southern sky; (1021d) O (ye) gods (and thou) leader of the Nether World, (1022d) good steering oar of the northern sky.  (1023) May ye rescue me from everything evil; (may ye rescue) me from all evil harm and from your snare; (1024) may ye rescue me from all evil fears; may ye (re)scue me from all evil terror.  A truly excellent spell (proved) a million (ti)mes.  (1025) (BD 149) First abode.  (1026) O THOU FIRST ABODE OF the west, (1027) among who(se people) one lives--(variants:) through whom one (lives), (1028) through whose name one (lives), with who(se people) one sees--(variant:) through whom one (sees).  (1029) Second abode.  (1030) O THOU SECOND ABODE OF the god's domain, (1031) (whose) name is not known, (to) whom the gods have granted, at the command of (1032) her Father Re, that she rise and set.  (1033) Third abode.  (1034) O THOU THIRD ABODE OF the blessed, (1035) to which the gods ascend unseen.  I am subject to (1036) myself (alone), since I know her name.  (1037) Fourth abode.  (1038) O THOU FOURTH ABODE OF the (1039) blameless blessed, to which the gods ascend unseen.  I am (1040) subject to myself (alone, since I kn)ow her name.  (1041) Fifth abode.  (1042) O THOU FIFTH ABODE (OF) the Inundation (1043) that fills (her) mouth with love assigned to her mouth (1044) before his Father daily.  (1045) Sixth abode.  (1046) O THOU SIXTH ABODE OF water, (1047) the one that lives on worm(s), the one that has ascended with you, (1048) the one that ?partakes of? her portion that ascends on her day.  (1049) Seventh abode.  (1050) O THOU SEVENTH ABODE OF water, (1051) (to whom one) ascends at Re's ascent, (whom one serves) and to whom the gods (are assigned).  (1052) (She) is not recognized at her ascent as the inundation.  (1053) Eighth abode.  (1054) O THOU EIGHTH ABODE OF the Inundation, (1055) one whose Father is visible in her sight art thou, (1056) one who proceeds on her ascent as Arsaphes.  (1057) Ninth abode.  (1058) O THOU NINTH ABODE OF the west, (1059) (from whom) Re ascends (to) Kheraha, great being Re's going, (1060) (thou) (whom one serves) and to whom the gods are assigned.  (She) is not recognized at her ascent as the inundation.  (1061) Tenth abode.  (1062) O THOU TENTH ABODE OF the blessed, for whom (1063) Re (...s) (when) he ascends from this his horizon of (flame).  (1064) She has ?indeed? ascended with (him) every day.  (1065) Eleventh abode.  (1066) O THOU ELEVENTH ABODE OF the west, (1067) (from whom) Re ascends (to) (Kheraha), (known) because of that water (1068) of the west, (on whom) the blessed go forth (...).  (1069) Twelfth abode.  (1070) O THOU TWELFTH ABODE OF the burial (of Osiris), (1071) wherein (one) lives and circles about as (does) Re, unto whom the (1072) blameless blessed enter and to whom the gods ascend unseen.  (1073) Thirteenth abode.  (1074) O THOU THIRTEENTH ABODE OF him who is in Rosetau.  (1075) May she go with you, (for) I know (1076) that the God ascends (with) her.  Re ascends to do (1077) her bidding over the water, (yet) she cannot be seen on any day.  (1078) Fourteenth abode.  (1079) O THOU FOURTEENTH ABODE OF the west, (1080) on whom the blessed go forth at her command (when) Re goes forth (1081) from the beautiful west.  (I kn)ow (her) souls, (even though) (1082) her face cannot be seen, (the souls) that serve her.  (1083) (BD 150) Abode of the deep, Pool in front of the sky, Abode of running water, (1084) Abode of ?the viper?, Abode of ?the doubly great?, Abode of ?enjoying food?, (1085) Abode of ?plant life?, Abode of circling, Abode of running water, Abode of water, (1086) Abode of the twin pools, Abode...  (1087) (BD 152) Geb REJOICES when his Son opens for him.  He has gone forth (from) his house in this land (1088) to build his house in the earth, with its foundation in Heliopolis, its circumference in (1089) Kheraha.  He sees his house at the head of the west, and his Son serves him daily.  (1090) I AM ONE WHO HAS ESCAPED FROM THE NET.  I SEE (THIS) HOUSE OF THEM (WHO SHALL) GO FORTH TO the west.  (I am) void of evil.  (I) will not be kept away from (1091) your (net), and ye (shall) not tread the west, for I am one who has escaped from (the net).  I see my Father Osiris, (for) (he has reached) the sky by command of Re; (I) see (1092) those who are in Rosetau.  I have ?journeyed? to the temple of Anubis on his mountain; I am one who has ascended into the presence of Osiris the lord of the west.  (1093) (BD 154) Spell for not letting one's corpse pass away.  (1094) TO BE SAID BY Osiris Irtywrw justified, born of Dyast: HAIL TO THEE, Father Osiris.  I have come (1095) unto (thee that I may praise thee) in ?(thy purity)?.  The heart (of) a man rejoices in thy love.  Come to him, (triumphant one).  (1096) Thou shalt not let that corpse of his pass away, ?thou (to whom)? I have brought myself to behold his beauty, for (1097) I am one who has come forth from Rosetau.  That is, there shall be no passing away of his corpse.  (Lo,) he has come forth by command of (his father) (1098) (this) day.  A truly excellent spell (proved a million) times.  (1099) (BD 161) Re lives, the turtle dies.  (1100) One (opening is for) the east wind.  (1101) One (opening is for) the west wind.  (1102) Re lives, ?the strangled one? dies.  (1103) One (opening is) for the north wind.  (1104) One (opening is) for the south wind.  (1105) SPELL FOR PROVIDING HEAT UNDER THE HEAD OF THE BLESSED ONE.  TO BE SAID BY (N.): HAIL TO (1106) THEE, lord of (mi)ght, lofty of plumes, lord of the double crown, equipped with (the flagellum).  (1107) Thou art (lord of) the phal(lus), numerous of forms; thy na(me) flourishes in the midst of the great Ennead.  (1108) (Thou art he who roars loudly) in the midst of the Ennead, who conceals himself in the Sound Eye (1109) (from) his children, (while) his heart (ceases) not to rise and set.  Come at (1110) my call this day, (for) I am the hiw-snake.  Thy name is in my mouth, and I will tell (it).  (1111) Be (not) one who knows (him) not.  Tail of the Lion-Ram is thy name.  He is the Soul (1112) of the great corpse (th)at rests in Heliopolis.  ?The Essence of the Great One Shines? is his (na)me.  Be not (1113) one who knows him not.  Come thou to him.  Mayest thou conceal him (in) Heliopolis.  TO BE SAID OVER A FIG(1114)URE OF THE HEAVENLY COW MADE OF FINE GOLD AND PLACED AT THE THR(OAT) OF THE BLESSED ONE.  A TRULY (EXCELLENT SPELL, PROVED) A MILLION TIMES.  (1115) Finis.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
