<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Book of the Dead</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.5428</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)5428</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. OIM 9787 (4)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Undated.  Presented by Martin A. Ryerson.  Dates follow D.B. Redford (ed.), The Oxford Encyclopedia of Ancient Egypt (2001).;Square brackets [ ] denote lost text and lines ; ; indicate uncertain text.  Braces { } denote superfluous words and parentheses ( ) indicate elements supplied, comments or emended text.;There are vignettes associated with BD 16-7, 21, 23-8, 30, 64, 31-3, 35-41, 43, 45, 47, 46, 44, 48, 53, 50, 54-5, 52, 57, 59, 56, 63, 65-6, 68, 71-87, 89, 90, 88, 91-4, 98-9, 95, 100-7, 109-10, 112-5, 119, 116-7, 124-36, 138, 137, 140, 143-62, 191.  Most, if not all, of the vignettes were evidently sketched in ahead of the text, and the latter did not always fit as the artist had planned.  (Allen p. 19);Regarding the note ''Finis!'' in BD 140, column cviii, line 37: is this the scribe's way of saying that his source was incomplete?  (Allen, p. 225, ftnt o)  In the blank space below BD 140, column cviii, a demotic note is inserted.  Dr. R.A. Parker read it as ''ben wesh n ;zesh her; f'' meaning ''There is no lack of ;writing on; it,'' i.e., nothing has been omitted here.  (Allen, p. 225, ftnt s) At the end of BD 141 (column cix), the rest of line 37 is blank; what looks like more signs after ''f'' in the photo is a small hole.  (Allen, p. 226, ftnt n)  BD 143 in column cxii consists of 5 registers which duplicate those of T,  the Turin BD published by Lepsius in 1842.  At the bottom, the deceased is praying.  The two unequal disks before the deceased in the middle bark may (as Budge says) represent sun and moon.  (Allen 230)  BD 148b (column cxl) shows deceased praying to Osiris-Sokar, who is supported by the West-Goddess and attended by the seven celestial cows and their bull, the steering oars of the four cardinal points, four sound eyes, and the four sons of Horus.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyh" otherLangs="egy-Egyp">Hieratic; Hieroglyphics</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>10 papyri ; 924.0 cm x 39.0 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The manuscript now starts a little after the beginning of vignette BD 16.  Aside from the initial loss, other damage is slight.  A pointed object had been thrust into the papyrus while it was rolled.  Some seventy holes near the lower edge, gradually decreasing in size toward the end until they cease in BD 148 b, probably represent two thrusts at opposite sides of the roll.  If only one thrust were involved, the roll as we have it would have been just over 3 cm in diameter; but its 924 cm length could scarcely have been rolled into such small compass.  (P. OIM 10486 is only 1/9 as long, but formed a roll about 6.4 cm in diameter when purchased.)  But P. Ryerson could not be checked directly, for it was already mounted in ten frames.  At both beginning and end, it had also been broken across in four places each, and there are minor breaks elsewhere.  (Allen p. 16)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">On recto: 157 columns in hieratic, 3 columns in hieroglyphics</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto: Book of the Dead</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The hieratic signs, when checked against G. Moeller, Hieratische Palaeographie III (1912), show forms varying from the 20th dynasty to about A.D. 60.  In selection and arrangement of spells, P. Ryerson is most similar to L 3079 (de Rouge, 1861-76, pls. V-XX), both having unusual additions.  They share strange writings and even errors, e.g. in BD 64 (cf. especially its S 12 f. and 15).  Hence they probably go back to a common ancestral manuscript.  Similarities with T (Lepsius, 1842) are also numerous.  Hieroglyphics occur only in BD 110b, 125d, 148b, 161S, 191-2, and the final offering formulas.  A note in demotic is added below BD 140.  All of the writing is in black.  The vignettes are colored in red, light and dark blue, green, yellow, brown, and white.  R, then, differs from Ptolemaic copies of BD.  The latter, as Daressy has mentioned, are generally written in crowded hieratic, with vignettes merely sketched in black, sometimes set off by a little red.  The scribe wrote with a consistent and steady hand.  He evidently checked his work, for the corrections are largely his.  But another, more angular hand has interlined name, etc. of deceased here and there (especially col. c) and made occasional other additions (cf. col. cxlviii).  The artist who did the vignettes was presumably a different person.  His work shows a good feeling for form, yet sometimes there is squattiness of figure (cf. overlapping scepter-bearers in col. liv) or unevenness of line (cf. kilt of deceased in cols. xxxix and xli).  (Allen p. 19)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="-0525" notAfter="-0031">VIth - Ist century B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Osiris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Unnofer</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Atum</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Re</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Shu</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Min</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Isis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nephthys</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Authority</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Perception</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Seth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thoth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Imset</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hapi</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Duamutef</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Qebehsenuf</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Whom His Father Sees</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Is Under His Moringa Tree</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horus with No Eyes in His Forehead</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anubis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Asdez</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dozer</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Bull Who Gives No Glow from His Hot Breath</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Observant One in His Prime</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Sees by Night Him Whom He Carried Off by Day</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tefnut</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Geb</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Carried Off His Portion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Shezmew</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nefertem</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Bastet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khepri</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Swallower of Millions</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Keen One</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Baba</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Master of His Affairs</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sokar</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ruty</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptah</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Uto</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Amon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Suty</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Upwawet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Baby</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nut</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sekhmet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tatenen</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phoenix</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">the Disk</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menkaure</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hardedef</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Soped</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Selqet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Rerek</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Neit</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hathor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khnum</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apophis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Is Over the Colors</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">He Who Sees Millions of Years Twice</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Imperishables</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ihy</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Inundation</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Seshat</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Baby</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sothis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Rekem</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Remrem</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Akhezzef</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tayt</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khonsu</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sobk</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Bibi</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ash</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Akhkhew</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menqet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harakhte</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sesha</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hotep</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpocrates</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Akhem</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Renenutet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Truth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Fate</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Luck</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Spirit of Contentment</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Blessed One</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Magician</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Khasety</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Wenty</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sutekh</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Montu</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">the Deep</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Zepa</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horus Khentekhtai</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onuris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aachbyt</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Adjen</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Adj</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ned</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Born of the Two Lips</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sound of Mouth</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Opener of the Ways</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Clear</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Asb</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hurler of the Two Knives</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Feller of Fish</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">The Offering Descends</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heh</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ded</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mut</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyh">Hieratic</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyp">Hieroglyphics</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Heracleopolis; Hermopolis; Heliopolis; Maat-lake; Rosetau; Naref; Abydos; Field of Rushes; Mendes; Busiris; Letopolis; Punt; Kheraha; Pe; Dep; Washerman's Shores; Memphis; Aqa-reach; Field of Offerings; Wednet; Turah; Khemmis; Ishru; Xois; Upper Egypt; Lower Egypt; Debew; Athribis; Qenqenet; Hetepet; City of the Great One; the Peaceful; Anet-wadj-wer; the Verdant; Djefat; Hezat; the Powerful; the United; Anpet; Hierakonpolis; Matat; Akhmim; Wenes; Bubastis; Fayyum; City of the Two Truths; Pomegranate; Xoite nome; Weryt; Sais; Wenes; Nedjfet; Atef; Asyut; Antaeopolis; Egypt; Sebeg; Bahbit; Aswan; Ra-antywy; 'Apret; Zekret; the Overflow; Nedit; Pesegro; Atef-wer; Shenew; Hekenew; Shaw; Peqer; Heni; Bedshew; Tayt; Sia; Siatyw; Lake Land; Pelusium; Qawyt;Ass-region; She Keeps Silence; Adew-abode; Elephantine; Heqehqed</term>
               <term>Funerary</term>
               <term>Religion</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. OIM 9787 (4), continued: (10)Osiris N. is Re's follower, one who takes on his character.  He has come unto thee, his Father Re; (14)he traverses Shu.  He has summoned the Coil (of the Crown of the North); he has taken the place of this Authority.  He has settled accounts with (16)this noxious one who is in Re's way.  He has become a blessed one; he has reached this Eldest One at the limits (18)of the Horizon.  (If) the Coil repulses him, (he) bears thy Soul behind thee; thy Soul becomes mighty (20)through dread of thee and respect for thee.  Osiris N. is one who issues commands to Re in the Sky.  Hail to thee, (22)great god in the east of the Sky.  Thou embarkest in the bark of Re as (does) the (24)divine falcon after he has issued commands and has smitten with (his) Staff, with his scepter.  Osiris (26)N. embarks in thy Bark; he sails in peace to the beautiful west.  Atum speaks to him: (30)''Would anyone enter?  The Sun-snake is Millions (of cubits in size), extending Two Million (32)(from) Starboard to Port, so that the lake of Millions is held back.  The whole Ennead is these on every side of him, (35)divided into the section(s) I mention.  (Each) route (lies) (between) each Million{s} and its mate.  It is a route (37)of fire; they (circle) in flame around him, around him.''  (cii) (BD 132)Spell for letting a man turn around to see his house in the god's domain.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (5)I am the Lion who has gone forth with (6)the bow.  (He) has shot, he has netted; he is the eye (9)of Horus.  (The eye of Horus has come through) this period; Osiris N. (has) reached the shore.  (14)''Come in peace!''  (ciii) (BD 133)Roll for initiating the blessed one into the mind of Re.  To be used on the day of the new-moon feast.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: When (3)Re dawns in his Horizon with his Ennead in his train as the god ascends from the hidden seat, (trembling) befalls (5)the eastern Horizon of the Sky at the voice of Isis.  (6)She has prepared the way for Re before the Great One (when he circles).  Pray lift thyself, (O) Re who is in his Shrine, that (8)thou mayest gulp the breeze and swallow the north wind, that thou mayest swallow the entrails and snare the day, that thou mayest breathe (10)truth and divide the Followers.  The Bark sails (to) the Nether Sky, and the Elders have been seized at thy voice.  (12)Thy countest thy bones; thou assemblest thy members.  Thou turnest thy face toward the beautiful west, thou (comest) thither new (14)every day, for thou art that image of gold ?which bears the companions? of the Disk.  The Sky is (atremble) (16)as thou circlest new every day.  The Horizon rejoices; there is joy in thy towropes.  The gods (18)who are in the Sky, when they see Osiris N. they give him praise like Re.  (He is) the Great One (20)who seeks the coil of Re and counts its needs.  This Osiris alone is sound of character in that first body of those who are in the presence of Re (every day).  (22)Osiris N. is sound on earth and in the god's domain, sound like Re every day.  (Even) if Osiris (N.) hastens, (24)he shall not weary in this land forever.  How good it is to see with the eyes, to hear with the ears, truth twice over.  Osiris N. (26)?(receives offerings) increase(d)? twice over in Heliopolis.  He is Re whose courses are concealed in the train of the deep.  He tells not what he (has) seen, he repeats not what (28)he has heard, in the house of Him Whose Face Is Hidden.  Exultation and rejoicing (are made for) Osiris N., the divine body of Re, in the bark (30)while (crossing) the deep (among) (those) who gratify the spirit of the God with his desire.  Osiris N. is a falcon large of form.  To be said over a bark 4 cubits long (32)made of papyrus ?material? and having the Council on board, with a Starry Sky made under it, purified and cleansed with natron and incense, after thou hast made an image of Re (34)on a new bowl inscribed with Nubian pigment and put into this Bark and after thou hast made an image of this blessed one whom thou lovest in this Bark.  He (shall) sail in the bark of Re, and (36)Re himself shall see him therein.  Do not use it for anyone except thine own self--even thy father, thy mother, or thy son.  Be very careful.  (38)Initiating the blessed one into the mind of Re and putting his might before the Ennead.  Then the gods shall see him as one of themselves, the dead shall see him (and fall) on their face(s), (and) (40)he shall be seen in the god's domain like the couriers of Re.  (civ) (BD 134)Praising Re on the day of the new moon, causing that (he) sail in the Bark.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: Hail (3)to thee, Re in the midst of his Bark, rising as the Rising One, shining as the Shining One, imprisoning (5)Millions at his will, turning his face to the sun-folk.  (6)Khepri in the midst of his Bark, he has overthrown Apophis every day.  It is ye children of Geb (8)who overthrow the enemies of Osiris, the attackers, when they deal evilly with the bark of Re.  (10)Horus cuts off their heads toward the sky as birds, their buttock(s) toward the earth as goats and toward the water as fish.  (12)(As for every) male and every female adversary, if they attack Osiris N., whether they descend from the sky or ascend (15)from the earth, whether they come by water or journey with the stars, (17)Thoth, (son of) the stone, (who came forth) from (the twin eggshells), decapitates (them).  Be dumb and deaf before Osiris N. as before Re, this god great of terror, great of esteem.  (21)He purifies himself with your blood, he drinks of your red blood, (O) attackers who (may) attack Osiris N. (25)in the bark of his Father Re.  Osiris N. is Horus, his Mother is (28)Isis, she who nursed him is Nephthys.  (They do for him) as they d(id) for Horus to ward off the companions of Seth.  When they see his crown abiding (31)on his brow, they fall upon their face(s).  Osiris Unnofer justified triumphs against his enemies in the Sky, in the earth, and in the Council of every god and (34)every goddess.  To be said over a falcon with the white crown on his head, image(s) of Atum, Shu, Tefnut, Geb, Nut, Osiris, Isis, Horus, and (37)Nephthys having been sketched with Nubian pigment on a new bowl put into this Bark together with an image of this blessed one, its body of pine, anointed (40)with ointment (such as is used) for a god's limbs, consisting of heknew-oil, put behind these deities, to whom are to be offered burnt incense and roast fowl.  (43)This is praise of Re truly.  A truly excellent spell (proved) a million times.  (cv) (BD 135)Another spell, to be said when the Moon is waxing on the day of the new moon.  (1)To be said: Open thou to Osiris (2)N., open thou to me, storm cloudiness (that) clothes and preserves (6)the beautiful Horus every day.  (O) great of forms, weighty of might, who dispels (8)the cloudiness (from be)fore Osiris N., (behold), he comes unto thee, Re, sail(ing).  (N. is one) of (12)those 4 gods who are at the side(s) of the Sky.  Osiris N. arrives on duty, ?having escaped from his (16)present bond?.  As for one who knows this spell, he shall be an initiate in the god's domain, (18)he shall not die again, he shall eat beside Osiris.  As for one who knows it (20)on earth, he shall be like the God, he shall be praised by the living.  He shall not succumb to the might of the King nor to the heat of (23)Bastet.  He shall attain to a good old age.  (cvi) (BD 136)Another, to be used on the day of the 6th-day feast, the day of sailing in the bark of Re.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: Behold (3)indeed the Starry Host in Heliopolis, the sun-folk in Kheraha, the offspring of 1000 gods.  (5)(O god) who has bound on (his) band and grasped his steering oar, Osiris N. (has been assigned) (8)with them to the (?rigging lofts?) and shipyards of the gods.  Osiris (N.) takes (10)therefrom the bark recurved (at its ends), that (he) may ascend therewith to the Sky.  When they sail therein with (12)Re, he (N.) sails as the (monkey) who wards off the surf that (covers) that district of Nut (14)to that stairway of Sebeg.  The heart(s) of Geb and Nut are (16)glad, (for) the Name of the new and youthful one has been repeated.  The beauty of Re exists by his magic power; (Wenty) (18)is what he is called.  Thou art the inundation, (O) Eldest One, Father of the gods, who ?tastes better than date(s)? (20)in the heart of him who cannot be attacked, (21)lord of roaring, rouser, courier of the Ennead, esteemed, become a soul, prepared (23)against the gods.  (Mayest thou) rescue Osiris N. (25)from him who does him harm, that one who has interfered with him; may his heart be valiant.  Mayest thou make Osiris N. prevail against all the gods, (27)the blessed, and the dead.  He is mighty if the lord of might is mighty.  He is the lord of Truth, (28)one who issues command(s).  His (protection) is the protection of Re in the Sky.  Mayest thou let him pass by thy bark, (29)(O) Re, in peace.  Make way for him, that thy bark may sail, (for) his protection is (30)thy protection.  It is he who keeps the crocodile away from Re every day.  He has come like Horus who keeps (31)the Horizon clear; he has announced Re at the gates of the Horizon.  The gods rejoice over him at his approach, (32)(for) (the odor of) a god (adheres to) Osiris (N.).  The noxious one shall not attack him; those who are at (33)their gates shall not assault him.  He is the Hidden of Face within the Temple, in charge of (the sanctuary).  (34)(N.) is one who brings (the god's) words to Re.  He has come; he has reported the message to its Lord.  He is (35)this stout-hearted one, weighty of might among (those who make) offerings.  To be said {by (36)a man} over an image of (this) blessed one put into this Bark, while (thou) art pure and clean (37)while censing before Re, with bread and beer, flesh and fowl.  (It is) (a means of) sailing (38)in the bark of Re.  As for a blessed one for whom this is done while he is among the living, (39)his name shall not perish forever, and he shall be a holy god.  No evil things shall befall him, and (40)he shall be a blameless, blessed one in the west.  He shall not die again.  (41)He shall eat and drink with Osiris every day; he shall be drawn with the Kings of Upper (42)and Lower Egypt.  He shall drink (water) from the ?overflow? of the Nile; he shall take (43)sexual pleasure; he shall go forth by day like Horus.  He shall live; he shall be like a god; (44)he shall be praised by the living like Re.  Watch out for thyself very, very carefully.  Do not (45)use it for anybody except thine own self.  (cvii) (BD 138)Spell for entering Abydos.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (4)O ye gods who are in Abydos, the total Council, (7)the whole of it, come rejoicing at my approach.  I have seen (9)assigned to me my Father Osiris from whom I came forth.  I {I} am (12)that (Horus), lord of Athribis, heir of the red (lands), who has seized all (15)and is unconquerable, whose hand--variant: whose eye--prevails (17)against his enemies, who saved his Father {from being} snatched away by the flood (and saved) his Mother, who smote his enemies and drove away the plunderer (thence, who silenced the might of) the noxious one.  (I am) Ruler (24)of the multitude, Sovereign of the Two Lands, who has taken his Father's estate in his hands, (even) (27)Osiris N.  (30)(BD 137)Spell for causing the flame to ascend.  (31)To be said by Osiris N.: (34)I have come unto thee, Re; (I) have come, Re.  (I am) the eye of Horus, Osiris {N.}; lo, (I am) (39)on thy pate.  Thy protections, they protect thee, Osiris, Ruler of changelessness, who illuminest the night (42)after the day.  O Osiris N., thy hand is the hand of Osiris presiding over the westerners while the eye of Horus is upon (44)them.  Osiris N., all thy enemies have been overthrown.  Osiris presiding over the westerners is Osiris N.  (cviii) (BD 140)Roll to be used when the Sound Eye becomes full on the last day of month 2 of the second season.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: When the Mighty One dawns (3)shining in the Horizon, when Atum dawns at the odor of his fragrance, while the blessed one shines in the Sky, the Benben-House is in (5)rejoicing, all those who are with them likewise.  (6)The sound of jubilation is (heard) within the Shrine, while joy circulates in (7)the Nether World, and there is earth-kissing at the dictum of Atum-Harakhte.  (8)His Majesty commands the Ennead, the followers of His Majesty; His Majesty flourishes (9)because of pondering on the Sound Eye.  Behold ye my members which he has given; (10)watched over are all my limbs, which they (the Ennead) have caused to flourish.  He has ascended, his  mouth (11)being the mouth of His Majesty.  His diadem rests in its place (12)on His Majesty (in) this 4th hour of the night, the land being beautiful on the last day of month 2 of the second season.  The Majesty of (14)the Sound Eye is before the Ennead, shining for His Majesty ?as (for) (15)his ancestor?, the Sound Eye being in his head.  ?(His are)? Re-Atum, the Sound Eye, (16)Shu, Geb, Osiris, Sutekh, Horus, Montu, the inundation, Re forever, the Traverser of Eternity, Nut, (18)Isis, Nephthys, Hathor, the Victorious Uraeus, ?he who loves? his Father, Truth, Anubis, earth, the children of Eternity, and the Soul of the Mendesian nome.  (20)(When) the Sound Eye has been checked in the presence of the lord of this land, then it is full and content.  Thereupon these Gods are in rejoicing on this day, (22)their hand(s) supporting it.  Then festivals are celebrated for every God.  They say: ''Hail to thee (the Eye), (and) praise (be) to Re; the Crew sails (24)the bark, (and) Apophis has been overthrown.  Hail to thee, (and) praise (be) to Re; the forms of Khepri have been brought into being.  (26)Hail to thee, (and) praise (be) to Re; joy is in him, (for) his enemies have been driven away.  Hail to thee, (and) praise (be) to Re; (28)the heads of the children of the feeble ones have been struck off.  Praise (be) to thee, Mistress of Osiris N.''  (30)To be said over a Sound Eye of real lapis lazuli or of hemaget-stone set in gold.  Offer (32)to it everything and pure before it in the presence of Re when he shows himself on the last day of month 2 of the second season.  Also (make) another Divine Eye, of red jasper, (34)which a man may place on any limb he prefers.  One who recites this spell shall be  in the bark of Re; he shall be towed with these gods.  (36)He shall be like one of them; he shall be set upright in the god's domain.  As for one who recites this spell (...).  Finis!  Likewise (38)the offering to be made when the Sound Eye is full: (39a)4 altars to Re-Atum, (40a)4 altars to the Sound Eye, (41a)4 altars (to) these gods.  (39-41 vert.)What is (to be) on each one of them: (39b)good bread, white bread, 5 (loaves); (40b)incense (in the form of) white bread, 5 (loaves); (41b)?flat? cakes, 5; (42)natron, 1 basket; fruit, 1 basket; (44)roast meat, 1.  (cix) (BD 141)Roll for initiating the blessed one and knowing the names of the Gods of the southern Sky, the Gods of the northern Sky, the Gods who are in the god's domain, and (3)the Gods who guide the nether world.  To be used for a man or for his Father or mother at the festivals of the west.  It is (the means of) his initiation into the mind of Re and into (5)the mind(s) of the Gods with whom he is to be.  To be said on the day of the new-moon festival by Osiris N., (7)when he has offered bread and beer, oxen, roast fowl, and burnt incense, (8)they being offered to Osiris in his every name as what Osiris N. has given.  (10)To Osiris presiding over the west, great god, lord of Abydos, 4 times; to Re-Harakhte, the Deep the father of the Gods, Truth the daughter of Re, (12)the bark of Re, Atum, and Khepri; the great Ennead and the lesser Ennead; Horus the lord of the Coil; Shu and Tefnut, Geb and Nut, Osiris, (14)Isis, and Nephthys; (Her of) the Spirit-House, Lady of the Universe; Storm Cloud of the Sky, Holding Aloft (the God); Her of Khemmis, Who Wrapped the God; the Hidden One Presiding Over Her Place; (16)Her Whose Love Is Great, Red-haired One; the Possessor of Life, Bright-red-haired One; Her Whose Name Prevails through Her Art; and the bull, male of the cow(s); (18)the good Power, opener of the Disk, good steering oar of the northern Sky; the circler, leader of the Two Lands, good steering oar of the western Sky; (20)the Sunshine dwelling in the house of the Divine Images, good steering oar of the eastern sky; the foremost one (dwelling in) the house of the red ones, good steering oar of the southern sky; (22)Imset, Hapi, Duamutef, and Qebehsenuf; the twin sanctuaries of Upper Egypt and the twin sanctuaries of Lower Egypt; the Night Bark and the Day Bark; (24)Hathor; Thoth the bull of Truth, Thoth the judge of the Ennead, Thoth who leads the Gods; the southern Gods, the northern Gods, the western Gods, (26)the eastern Gods; the ?Kneeler? Gods and the Gods ?who bring offerings?; the Gods of the Upper Egyptian shrine and the Gods of the Lower Egyptian shrine; the regional Gods, (28)the Horizon Gods, the Cave Gods, the field Gods, the ?Throne? Gods; the southern ways, the northern ways, the western ways, (30)the eastern ways; (them) who guide the gates of the nether world, the Doorkeepers of the Nether World; the portals of the Nether World, the secret doors of (32){of} the Nether World; the Doorkeepers of the gates of the Nether World, the hidden (of face) who guard the ways; the Doorkeepers of ?the desert?, who utter crie(s), (34)the Doorkeepers of the cemeteries, who ?present (their)? beautiful face(s); {(them) who put flame on the braziers,} the blazing one(s) who put flame in the brazier, the openers who quench fire and (36)flame in the west; (and) him who gives triumph to the initiate in west and east together with his Spirit.  (38)(BD 142)Another roll (for) initiating the blessed one and making him (able to) walk as a wide-stepper going forth by day in any form he will.  Knowing the Name(s) (40)of Osiris in his every seat in which he may desire to be.  To be said by Osiris N. (42)of the house of Atum the lord of Heliopolis.  (43)To Osiris Unnofer justified, to the Living Osiris, to Osiris the Lord of Life, Osiris the Lord of the Universe, (45)Osiris who decided the battle of the Two Lands, Osiris presiding over the wenet-sanctuary, (46)Osiris presiding over grain, Osiris Orion, Osiris Zepa, Most August of the Souls of Heliopolis, (48)Osiris presiding over the tchennet-sanctuary, Osiris presiding over the southern and northern sanctuaries (of Sais), Osiris the lord of Millions, Osiris the Soul of the Two Ladies (Isis and Nephthys), (50)Osiris Ptah the Lord of Life, Osiris presiding over Rosetau, Osiris the Ruler of the shores, dwelling in Mendes, (52)Osiris dwelling in the waste lands, Osiris the August Soul who is in Mendes, Osiris in Busiris, Osiris in the Hermopolis cemetery, Osiris the lord of the land of life, (54)Osiris in Sais, Osiris in Naref, Osiris in the south, Osiris in Pe, Osiris in Dep, Osiris in Bahbit, (56)Osiris in ?Asyut?, Osiris in lower Sais, Osiris in upper Sais, Osiris as the Two Falcons, (58)Osiris in Aswan, Osiris in Ra-antywy, Osiris in 'Apret, Osiris ?as an ape-god?, (cx) to [Os]iris in Zekret, to Osiris in the Overflow, Osiris in his house in Rosetau, Osiris in the Abydos nome, (5)Osiris in Nedit, Osiris within his city, Osiris the sovereign, Osiris (in) Pesegro, (9)Osiris in his house in Upper Egypt, Osiris in his house in Lower Egypt, Osiris in the sky, Osiris in the earth, Osiris as the enthroned one, (13)Osiris in Atef-wer, Osiris Sokar in the shetchyt-sanctuary, Osiris the Ruler of changelessness in Heliopolis, Osiris the begetter, Osiris in the Night Bark, (17)Osiris encompassing the year, Osiris the lord of changelessness, Osiris the lord of endless recurrence, Osiris in the red land, Osiris in the marsh, (20)Osiris in the southern oasis, Osiris in the northern oasis, Osiris in the Great Abode, Osiris in 'Apret, (24)Osiris in Shenew, Osiris in Heknew, Osiris in the land of Sokar, Osiris in Shaw, (28)Osiris as ?uplifter of? Horus, Osiris in the district of Peqer, Osiris in (the city of) the Two Truths, Osiris in Heni, (32)Osiris as Soul of his Father, Osiris the lord of the shores, King of the Gods, Osiris in Bedshew, Osiris in Tayt, (36)Osiris on his sand heap, Osiris presiding over the pavilion of his cows, Osiris in the tchennet-sanctuary, Osiris in (Sia), (40)Osiris in Siatyw, Osiris in Ishru, Osiris in all lands, Osiris presiding over the lake of Pharaoh the live, sound, and healthy, (44)Osiris in the Benben-House, Osiris in Heliopolis, Osiris the Greatest of the great in Heliopolis, Osiris in the hidden house, (48)Osiris in the ?Embalmer's Shop?, Osiris in the palanquin-house in Heliopolis, Osiris (with) the mekes-scepter, Osiris in Pe and the Deep, (52)Osiris in the Castle, Osiris the lord of life in Abydos, Osiris the lord of Mendes, Osiris presiding over (Them) Whose Seat Is Narrow, (56)Osiris the Sovereign dwelling in Abydos, Osiris the Sovereign dwelling in Lake Land, Osiris living in Memphis, Osiris the lord of might who tramples the wicked, (60)Osiris the black bull dwelling in Athribis, Osiris the possessor of a throat, Osiris Sesha; (cxi) to Re-Harakhte, to Atum the bull of the company of the great Ennead; (3)Upwawet of Upper Egypt, Might of the Two Lands, Upwawet of Upper Egypt, Might of the Sky; Ptah the August pillar in the house of Re, sole Wise One in the Benben-House; (7)Geb the hereditary prince of the Gods; Horus the Elder, Horus with No Eyes in His Forehead, Horus the son of Isis; (10)Min the King of Upper Egypt, Victorious Horus, pillar of his Mother, cleanser of the Upper Egyptian sanctuary; Khnum, Horus the Gracious; (13)Her Who Cares for Horus; Horus Khentekhtai; Thoth; Onuris; (16)Anubis presiding over the hall of the god; Nut; Isis the Divine in her every Name: Her Who Cares for Horus, (19)the Widow, the Ruler, the great neshmet-bark, Neit, Selqet, Truth, the Heavenly Cow; (23)the 4 resting-places in Abydos: the great resting-place, the Happy resting-place, the excellent resting-place, the Beautiful resting-place; (27)Imset, Hapi, Duamutef, and Qebehsenuf; the uraeus dwelling in the Palace; (30)the Gods who lead the nether world, the Cave Gods, the Gods and Goddesses who are in Abydos; (33)the twin sanctuaries of Upper Egypt and the twin sanctuaries of Lower Egypt; the worthy ones of Osiris; (36)Osiris presiding over the westerners, lord of Abydos, Osiris in his every seat: Osiris in his seat in the land of Upper Egypt, (39)Osiris in his seat in the land of Lower Egypt; Osiris in every place where his Spirit may desire to be, Osiris in all his halls; (42)Osiris in all his forms, Osiris in his every Name; Osiris in all his equipment, (45)Osiris in all his crowns, Osiris in all his adornments, Osiris in all his cenotaphs; (48)Horus who saved his Father in his every Name; Anubis presiding over the hall of the god in his every Name, Anubis the Embalmer in his every Name; (51)the Gods and Goddess(es) who are in the sky in their every Name; (53)as what Osiris N. has given.  (cxii) (BD 143) (cxiii) (BD 144)Knowing the names of (those) who are at the 7 gates and their guardian(s) and the announcer(s) in them.  (1)He who is at the first gate is Face-downward, numerous of forms.  The name of (3)its guardian is Eavesdropper; the name of the announcer in it is ?Sad? of Voice.  (6)He who is at the second gate is ?Spy?.  The name of its guardian is ?Watchful? of Face; the name of the announcer in it is Aseb.  (10)He who is at the third gate is Eater of the Excrement of His Posterior.  The name of its guardian is Alert of Face; the name of the announcer in it is Reviler.  (14)He who is at the fourth gate is Repulsive of Face{s}, Garrulous.  The name of its guardian is Alert of Mind; the name of the announcer in it is Big of Face, Repeller of the Crocodile.  (cxiv) He who is at the fifth gate is He Who Lives on Rotten Meat.  The name of (3)its guardian is Ashebw; the name of the announcer in it is Face-afire, Violent of Strength.  (6)He who is at the sixth gate is Clawer of Bread, Violent of Voice.  The name of (8)its guardian is Face-?Remover?; the name of the announcer in it is Keen of Face, who is at the Sky.  (11)He who is at the seventh gate is the Keenest of Them.  The name of its guardian is Big of Voice; the name of the announcer in it is Repeller of Attackers.  (cxv) To be used at dawn of the Thoth-festival.  To be said by Osiris N.: O ye who are at the 7 gates, (3)who man the gate(s) in behalf of Osiris, (O) guardian(s) of the gates, O announcer(s) of dutie(s) (4)at the double doors of Osiris daily, Osiris N. knows you and knows your name(s).  He is one who was born in Rosetau, one who leads the Gods.  (6)Blessings have been given to the lord of the Horizon and the mummy of Osiris N. in Pe as (to) the two horns of Osiris.  He receives the Obeisant--variant: lamenters--in Rosetau (when) leading (8)the Gods through the Horizon, even the courtiers around Osiris.  Isis is one thereof in their company.  Osiris N. is (10)a blessed one, lord of blessedness.  The blessed one whom I beget, he it is who shall celebrate new-crescent day (11)and shall report on the midmonth feast.  Osiris N. circles the eye of Horus which Horus has given and Thoth has set in the night.  (13)He crosses the sky in triumph.  He has been allowed to pass in peace and sail in the Bark.  (14)Behold, Osiris N. is what the great one (fem.) has given, (15)what the great one (masc.) has begotten in behalf of truth.  His abomination is hacking to pieces.  Behold Osiris N.; behold Horus the First-born of Re, whom his heart begot.  (17)He is not seized (nor) repelled from the gate; (Osiris N. is) one whom Ruty equips.  Osiris N. is a follower of the Presider over the Westerners daily.  (19)(His) lands are in the Field{s} of Offering(s) among the learned, (among) those who prepare food for (Osiris).  (N. is) the scribe beside Thoth (among) those who make offerings.  (21)Anubis has commanded them that are among the offerings of Osiris N. (to be) with him.  ''There is none who can take (them) from him,'' say they who are among the booty.  He stays sound (23)like those who keep clear the Horizon of the Sky; he announces Re at the gate of the Horizon.  Verily the Gods rejoice at his approach, (for) the odor of a God (adheres) to him.  The noxious one shall not attack him; (25)those who are at the gates shall not assault him.  He is the Hidden of Face within the Temple, dwelling in (...)--variant: the sanctuary--of the God (who is) lord of the gate at these gates, he being in the train of Hathor.  (Osiris N. is) one who made (27)a way that he might cause truth to ascend to Re, who warded off the strength of Apophis.  Osiris N. is one who opened the sky, who drove away storms, who kept alive (29)the Crew of Re.  He causes offerings to ascend to the place where he is.  Osiris--variant: Isis--has caused that (30)the bark (make) (its) goodly journeys.  Make a goodly way for Osiris N., (that he may) indeed (go forth).  His face is of the (same) size as the coil.  He is the Lord of Might, (32)knowing ?joy?--variant: ?Her Who Has Entered?--in the Horizon as one who is great over you.  Fall ye, wake; make way for your Lord Osiris N.  (34)To be said over this Image which is sketched, painted with Nubian pigment, (and) over the Council of the bark of Re.  Offer to them bread and beer, great offerings, and burnt incense before them.  This is (a means of) keeping the blessed one alive and making (36)him mighty in the presence of these Gods without his being warded off or kept away from the gates--variant: tombs--of the nether world.  Thou shalt make an image of (37)this blessed one set before them, and thou shalt make it arrive at every (gate) with these gods.  To be said at the entrance of every gate (38)as he offers to each one of them (part) of the 2 thighs of a red ox.  Turn over to them 6 bowls; (turn over) to them (39)blood, lung, and heart, 16 loaves of white bread, 8 (pezen)-loaves, 8 shenes-loaves, 8 khenef-loaves, 8 hebennet-loaves, (40)8 jugs of beer, 8 (measures of) wheat (flour)--variant: (8) cuts of beef, a clay basin filled with the milk of a white cow, (41)fresh herbs, fresh ben oil, black face-paint, and burnt incense.  To be said.  (Then) erase every single (figure) (42)after doing what is to be done, namely making this image, when 4 hours of the day are gone.  Beware especially of noon in the sky.  (43)Thou shalt use this roll without letting anybody (else) see it.  It is (a means of) broadening the range of the blessed one in sky and earth and in the god's domain, since (44)(it) is (more) profitable to the blessed one (than anything else) that may be done (for) him, while supplies are ?(available) to? him right down to date.  A truly excellent spell (proved) a million times.  (cxvi) (BD 145)Beginning of the portal of the Field{s} of Rushes in the house of Osiris.  (1)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)''Hail to thee,'' says Horus, ''first portal of the Weary-Hearted One.  Make way for me.  (6)I know thee, I know thy name, I know the name of the God thy guardian.  Lady of Trembling, (8)lofty of upper battlement, lady of breaking and entering, uttering proclamations--variant: (10)smashing staves, warding off storms, rescuing the plundered whether present or (12)far away, is thy name.  Watchman is the name of the God thy guardian.  I am pure (14)with these waters wherewith Re purifies himself (after) he has been bared (of clouds)--variant: for him--in the (16)east side of the Sky.  I am anointed with the best pine oil and adorned (18)with raiment; my club in my hand is of hety-wood.''  ''Proceed, for thou art pure.''  (21)To be said by Osiris N.: ''Hail to thee,'' says Horus, (24)''second portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know thee, I know thy name, I know the name of the God thy guardian.  (27)Lady of the Sky, Mistress of the Two Lands, terrorizing the earth in the place where thou art, is thy name.  Child of Ptah is the name of the God thy guardian.  I am pure (30)with these waters wherewith Osiris purifies himself (after) the Night Bark and the Day Bark have been given to him when he goes forth to the west and (33)descends through the portals.  I am anointed with festival perfume and clothed with a bandage; (36)(my) club in my hand is a beam.''  ''Proceed, for thou art pure.''  (cxvii) To be said by Osiris N.: (3)''Hail to thee,'' says Horus, ''third portal of the Weary-hearted One.  May way for me.  (6)I know thee, I know thy name, I know the name of the God your guardian.  Lady of the Portal, great of (offerings), giving to (9)those who are yonder, presenting offerings, she whom the Gods beside her refreshed on that day when the neshmet-bark sailed upstream (12)to Abydos, is thy name.  Clear is the name of the God thy guardian.  I am pure with these waters (15)wherewith Ptah purifies himself when he sails upstream (after) the henew-bark has been carried (in procession) on the day of revealing (the) face.  I am anointed (18)with the best (he)kenew-oil and with Libyan (oil) and am clothed in linen; my club in my hand is of ahmen-wood.''  (21)''Proceed, for thou art pure.''  (22)To be said by Osiris N.: ''Hail to thee,'' (25)says Horus, ''fourth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know thee, I know thy name, (28)I know the name of the God thy guardian.  Mighty of Knives, Mistress of the Two Lands, damaging the enemies of the Weary-(31)hearted One, doing injury, void of evil, is thy name.  Smiter of the Longhorn is the name of the God (34)thy guardian.  I am pure with these waters wherewith Unnofer justified purifies himself at his going to law with Seth, (37)when justification has been given to Unnofer justified.  I am anointed with wine of Pelusium--variant: inn--and am (40)clothed in the linen ?that wrapped thy son?--variant: ?(linen of) Pe?--and my club in my hand is of tatet-wood.''  ''Proceed, (43)for thou art pure.''  (cxviii)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)''Hail to thee,'' says Horus, ''fifth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  (6)I know thee, I know thy name, I know the name of the God thy guardian.  Lady of the Protecting Flame, Lady of Praise, (9)Lady of the Universe, she to whom prayer is made without him whose head is bald coming near her, is thy name.  He Who Makes the Foe Retreat is (12)the name of the God thy guardian.  I am pure with these waters wherewith Horus purifies himself when he serves as lector-priest and (15)son-who-loves for his Father Osiris.  I am anointed with aber-ointment of the god's possessions; the claw upon me is (18)a leopard's; my club in my hand is the smiter of the evil-intentioned.''  ''Proceed, for thou art pure.''  (21)To be said by Osiris N.: ''Hail to thee,'' says (24)Horus, ''sixth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know thee, I know thy name, I know (27)the name of the God thy guardian.  Lady of Obeisance, loud-roaring {is thy name}, whose height by whose breadth is not known, (30)whose creator has not been discovered since the beginning of time, (on whom are snakes) innumerable who (crawl) upon their bellie(s), image (33)of ?the sound eye? of the night as (one who) has been caused to give birth in front of the Weary-hearted One, is thy Name.  ?Enthroned One? is the name of the God thy guardian.  (36)I am pure with these waters wherewith Thoth purifies himself when he serves as vizier of Horus.  I am anointed (39)with aga-ointment (and clothed in a tchesten-garment); [my] club in my hand is of seped-wood.''  ''Proceed, for thou art pure.''  (cxix)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)''Hail to thee,'' says Horus, ''seventh portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make (6)way for me.  I know thee, I know thy name, I know the name of the God thy guardian.  Storm Cloud Veiling (9)Her Weary One, mourner whose desire it is to conceal the body, is thy name.  ?Rib? of Neit is the name of the God (12)thy guardian.  I am pure with these waters wherewith Isis and Nephthys purify themselves when they conduct (15)the crocodile (Seth) and his (companion) crocodile(s) alongside the pure place.  I am anointed with hekenew-(18)oil and clothed in a garment; my club in my hand is an oar.''  ''Proceed, for thou art pure.''  (22)To be said by Osiris N.: ''Hail to thee,'' (25)says Horus, ''eighth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know thee, I know thy name, I know (28)the name of the God thy guardian.  Kindler of {His} Flame (Whose) Embers Cannot Be Quenched, honored one--variant: (31)upon her; thou art--skilled in (use of) fire, quick in slaying without premeditation, whom none passes through (for fear) of (34)her pain, is thy name.  One whom the great one fears when he roars, He Who Guards His Body is the name of the God thy guardian.  I am pure with (37)these waters wherewith the Soul the lord of Mendes purifies himself when he is vexed at all his members.  I am anointed with myrrh (40)of the God's Limbs (from) an ankh-vase and clothed in a weave of beautiful white; my club in my hand is a beam.''  ''Proceed, (43)for thou art pure.''  (cxx) To be said by Osiris N.: (3)''Hail to thee,'' says Horus, ''ninth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know (6)thee, I know thy name, I know the name of the God thy guardian.  Lady of the Sun's Eye, tranquil Mighty One, lady, offspring (9)of her Lord, a secret--variant: eyes--being half (of) her girth, Millions of Millions of cubit(s) being her depth and (being) the height (12)of her head, is thy name.  Nedjess is the name of the God thy guardian.  I am pure with these waters wherewith Anubis purifies himself when (15)he serves as embalmer--variant: lector-priest--of Osiris.  I am anointed with sefetch-oil and clothed in a garment of red linen; (18)my club in my hand is ?a rush?--variant: is cat?tails?.''  ''Proceed, for thou art pure.''  Variant: it being 300 hundred-cubits around (21)her and Millions of Millions on (her) every road, none knowing them that are in (her), none betraying (the secret) (23)of the veiler of the weary, she who extends her arms.  (24)To be said by Osiris N.: ''Hail to thee,'' says (27)Horus, ''tenth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know thee, I know thy name, I know the name of the God (30)thy guardian.  Lofty of Double Doors, Awaker of Outcrie(s), swollen of {thy} face, to whom entreaty is made--variant: Thy name is She Who Cries Out at (33)the Top of Her Voice, terror of the enemy, without seizing--variant: she (who) seizes (not)--him who is within her, is thy name.  Great Embracer is the name of (36)the God thy guardian.  I am pure with these waters wherewith Asdez purifies himself when he enters to question Seth (39)there within the secret chamber.  I am anointed with red ointment; my club in my hand is the (42)red ?shank? (of) a first(-rate) greyhound.''  ''Proceed, for thou art [pure].''  (Variant:) none knowing them that are in her, none (betraying) (45)the secret of the Veiler of the Weary, great one who lifts her arms to slay her adversaries, is thy name.  (cxxi)To be said by Osiris N.: (3)''Hail to thee,'' says Horus, ''eleventh portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make (6)way for me.  I know thee, I know thy name, I know the name of him who is within (thee).  She Who Cuts Repeatedly, Who Burns (9)Transgressors, most terrifying of all the portals, to whom jubilation is made on the day of hearing wrong(s), (12)is thy name.  Thou art under the inspection of the Veiler of the Weary.''  (14)''Proceed, for thou art pure.''  (15)To be said by Osiris N.: ''Hail to thee,'' (18)says Horus, ''twelfth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know thee, I know (21)thy name, I know the name of him who is within thee.  (Summoner) of the Two Lands, Who Hacks to Pieces Those Who Come at Dawn, (24)?(bright one)?, blessed lady who hearkens to the voice of her Lord every day, is thy name.  I am--variant: Thou art--under the inspection of the veiler (27)of the weary.''  ''Proceed, for thou art pure.''  (cxxii) To be said by Osiris N.: (4)''Hail to thee,'' says Horus, ''thirteenth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  (8)I know thee, I know thy name, I know the name of him who is within (thee).  She (11)to Whose Face the Ennead Extend Their Arms in Praise ?as? one whom the Inundation instructs in (his secrets) is thy name.  Thou art--variant: I am--under the inspection of the veiler of the weary.''  (17)''Proceed, for thou art pure.''  (19)To be said by Osiris N.: (22)''Hail to thee,'' says Horus, ''fourteenth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make (26)way for me.  I know thee, I know thy name, I know the name of him who is within (thee).  (29)Lady of Wrath, Dancing on Red Blood, for whom the haker-feast is celebrated with heat (32)on the day of hearing wrongs, is thy name.  Thou art--variant: I am--under the inspection of the veiler of the weary.''  (36)''Proceed, for thou art pure.''  (cxxiii) To be said by Osiris N.: (3)''Hail to thee,'' says Horus, ''fifteenth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make (6)way for me.  I know thee, I know thy name, I know the name of him who is within thee.  Great of Renown, (9)red of eyelashes, Aachbyt who goes forth by night, who drives away the aggressor{s} with his creator, (12){who} who extends her arms to the Weary-hearted One at his instant of coming and going, is thy name.  Thou art--variant: I am--(15)under the inspection of the veiler of the weary.''  ''Proceed, for thou art pure.''  (18)To be said by Osiris N.: ''Hail to thee,'' says (21)Horus, ''sixteenth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  (23)I know thee, I know thy name, I know the name of him who is within thee.  (25)Lady of Terror, very swift (of arm)--variant: who lays hand--on transgressors whom she burns with flame when she goes forth, creator of the mystery of earth, is thy name.  Thou art--(29)variant: I am--under the inspection of the veiler of the weary.''  ''Proceed, for thou art pure.''  (cxxiv) To be said by Osiris N.: (4)''Hail to thee,'' says Horus, ''seventeenth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make (7)way for me.  I know thee, I know thy name, I know the name of (9)him who is within thee.  Great in the Horizon, Lady of Red Blood, Dancing (11)on Blood, ..., {there is no} mighty one, lady of parching (heat), is thy name.  Thou art--(variant:) (14)I am--under the inspection of the veiler of the weary.''  ''Proceed, for thou art pure.''  (17)To be said by Osiris N.: (20)''Hail to thee,'' says Horus, ''eighteenth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  (23)Make way for me.  I know thee, I know thy name, I know the name of him who is within (26)thee.  She Who Loves Heat, Pure One Whom the Leopard Obeys, who loves (29)to cut off the head(s) of the worthy, lady of the Palace, {variant:} who slays by decapitating (32)transgressors at eventide, is thy name.  Thou art--(variant:) I am--under the inspection of (35)the veiler of the weary.''  ''Proceed, for thou art pure.''  (cxxv) To be said by Osiris N.: (4)''Hail to thee,'' says Horus, ''nineteenth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know thee, (8)I know thy name, I know the name of him who is within thee.  (10)She Who Proclaims Protection--variant: the Dawn--(in) (Her) Time, (great) of heat, lady of the symbols of might, (13)the writings of Thoth himself, is thy name.  Thou art--(variant:) I am--under the inspection of the veiler of the weary.''  (16)''Proceed, for thou art pure.''  (18)To be said by Osiris N.: (21)''Hail to thee,'' says Horus, ''twentieth portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I (24)know thee, I know thy name, I know the name of him who is within (thee.  She Who Is Within) (26)(the Cavern) of Her Lord, Respected One who(se name) is veiled, whose (form) is hidden, who seizes (29)hearts and opens of herself, is thy name.  Thou art--(variant:) I am--under the inspection of the veiler of the weary.''  (32)''Proceed, for thou art pure.''  (cxxvi) To be said by Osiris N.: (2)''Hail to thee,'' says Horus, ''twenty-first portal of the Weary-hearted One.  Make way for me.  I know (3)thee, I know thy name, I know the name of the God thy guardian.  She Who Sharpens the Flint Knife Against Them That Speak Against Her--variant: (4)to Her, Evil of Face, who cannot be overturned, who goes down to her flame, is thy name.  (Thou) (possessest) the se(5)crets of the savior, the God (thy) guardian.  His name is ?Giraffe?.  He (came) into being before pines grew, before (6)trees--variant: acacias--were born, before copper ore was formed in the desert.  The Council of (7)this portal consists of 7 Gods.  Adjen--variant: Adj; variant: Ned--is the name of one thereof.  Ra--variant: Hetep--(8)-mes is the name of another thereof.  Born of Two Lips is the name of another thereof.  Sound of Mouth is the name of another thereof.  (9)Opener of the Ways is the name of another thereof.  Clear is the name of another thereof.  Anubis is the name of another (thereof).  Make way for me.  (10)I am Min-Horus, savior of his Father, heir of his Father Unnofer justified.  (11)I have come that (I) may give life to my Father Osiris, (now that) I have overthrown all his enemies.  I have come today as one justified, (12)possessor of worthiness, from the house of my Father Atum the lord of Heliopolis.  Osiris N. is in the southern Sky.  I have done right by him who did the same; I have celebrated (14)the haker-festival for its Lord.  I have conducted the festival of him who is in the scaffolding; I have given bread to the altar-lords.  (15)I conduct the offering list of bread, beer, oxen, and fowl to my Father Osiris-Unnofer justified.  I am beside the Soul; I cause that the Phoenix go forth to speak.  I have come (17)today from the Temple, offering incense.  I have conducted the kilted one, having crossed to the pool of the neshmet-bark, (18)(for) Osiris presiding over the westerners has been justified against all his enemies.  I ferry all his enemies over to the place of execution of (19)the easterners; they shall not escape from the custody of Geb there.  I set upright for him (the Unveiled Ones) (20)on the day of his justification.  I have come as a spitting scribe, that I may put the power of the God into his legs.  (21)I have come from the house of him who is on his mountain; I have seen him who presides over the hall of the god.  I am entered into Ro(22)setau; I have secreted him whom I found cut to pieces.  I am sent--variant: am sent--to (23)Naref; I have clothed him who was naked.  I am gone upriver to Abydos; (24)I praise Authority and Perception.  I am entered into the house of Asdez; I have extolled the Gods of Combat and Sekhmet within the house of the Elders.  I am entered into Rosetau; (26)I have secreted him whom I found (cut to pieces).  I am gone down--variant: am sent--to Naref; I (have) clothed him who was there naked.  I am gone upriver to Abydos; (28)I have praised Authority and Perception.  I receive my coronation--(variant:) the crown; I occupy (29)my throne in place of my Father the first Primeval One.  The necropolis of the Sacred Land gives praise to me.  (30)My mouth (vomits) up truth; I have drowned the griffins.  I have come from a palace (31)that causes limbs to thrive.  Mayest thou let me sail in the bark of the shining one and offer cows' flesh (32)with hair of--variant: (while) circling--man.  I am entered into the house of Asdez; (33)I have extolled the Gods of Combat and Sekhmet within the house of the Eldest--variant: the Prince.''  ''Thou art come (34)approved from Mendes, Osiris N.''  (cxxvii) (BD 146)Beginning of the portals of the house of Osiris in the Field{s} of Rushes.  To be said by N.: (1)First portal: Lady of Fear, Lofty of Upper Wall, lady of breaking and entering, uttering proclamations--(5)variant: smashing staves, warding off storms, rescuing the plundered, is her name of long standing.  The name of her Doorkeeper is (9)Watchman--variant: Exalted Above Everybody (Else).  (11)Second portal: Lady of the Sky, Mistress of the Two Lands, burning one, lady of all mankind, (15)creator of everyone, is her name.  The name of her Doorkeeper is Child of Ptah.  (18)Third portal: Lady of the Altar, great of offerings, she (who) refreshed every God in her on the day of sailing upstream (22)to Abydos, is her name.  The name of her Doorkeeper is Clear.  (25)Fourth portal: Mighty of Knife, Mistress of the Two Lands, damaging the enemies of the Weary-hearted One, fulfilling (29)Wishes, void of wrongdoing, is her name.  The name of her Doorkeeper is Smiter of the Longhorn.  (cxxviii) Fifth portal: Fire, lady of breath at the nose, she (to) whom prayer is made without coming near (4)her while one exists on earth, is her name.  The name of her Doorkeeper is Slayer of the Foe.  (7)Sixth portal: Lady of Obeisance--variant: Lady of Darkness, loud-roaring, whose length by whose breadth is not known, whose character was not discovered at (12)her beginning, on whom are snake(s) innumerable, (she) (who) was born in front of the Weary-hearted One, is her na(me).  The name of her Doorkeeper{s} is ?Enthroned One?.  (17)Seventh portal: ?Moist? Storm Cloud Veiling the Weary One{s}, (20)mourner whose desire it is to conceal (the body), is her name.  The name of her Doorkeeper is ?Rib? of Neit.  (23)Eighth portal: Kindler of Flame (Whose) Embers Cannot Be Quenched, skilled in (use of) fire, (quick) of hand, slaying (27)(without) premeditation, whom none passes through for fear of her roaring.  The name of her Doorkeeper is He Who Guards His Body.  (cxxix) Ninth portal: Ancestress, tranquil lady of might, offspring of her Lord, it being (2)320 hundred-cubits (5)around her--variant: 300 being her girth, sower with the green stone of Upper Egypt, raising up ?the Newcomer? for the veiler of (9)the weary, (making gifts to) her Lord every day, is her name.  (The name of) her Doorkeeper is Eternity.  (12)Tenth portal: Loud-voiced, Awaker of Outcrie(s), who cries out, (15)great of {thy} terror, esteemed lady, (she who) seizes not him who is within her, is her name.  (The name of) her Doorkeeper is Great Embracer.  (19)Eleventh portal: Violent One Who Burns Transgressors, most terrifying of (22)all the portals, (to whom) jubilation is made on the day (of) hearing wrongs.  Thou art under the inspection of the veiler of the weary.  (26)Twelfth portal: Summoner of Her Two Lands, who annihilates him who comes at dawn, ?(bright one)?, lady of the blessed, (30)who hearkens to (her) Lord every day.  She is under the inspection of the veiler of the weary.  (cxxx) Thirteenth portal: She Over Whom Isis ?Has? Extended Her Arms, she whom the Inundation (?instructs?) (4)in his secret.  She is under the inspection of the veiler of the weary.  (7)Fourteenth portal: Lady of Wrath, Dancing on Red Blood, {variant:} (for) whom the haker-feast is celebrated, who hears trembling--variant: (11)who makes ?rejoicing? over thee--on the day (of) hearing wrongs.  She is under the inspection of the veiler of the weary.  (14)Fifteen(th) portal: ?Soulful One?, red of eyelashes, ?squinter? who goes forth by night, who seizes--variant: who drives away--(18)the aggressor{s} (and) his creator from Re, who extends her arms to the Weary-hearted One at his (appointed) instant, who comes (back if) she goes.  She is under (22)the inspection of the veiler of the weary.  (cxxxi) Osiris N. says: I am one who clothed his perch, who came forth from the Coil.  (I have) come, I have established (3)offerings in Abydos.  Open for me the road in Rosetau, (for) I have healed the sickness (4)of Osiris.  I have come today through the gate of the underworld.  O Hidden One, make (5)way for me.  I am Horus who saved his Father, Son of Isis, heir of Osiris.  (6)I have come, I have spread (my) wings over Osiris.  I have come today (7)through the festival gate (that leads down toward--variant:) that leads down to--the Lady of the Eyelashes.  Make (8)way for me.  I am Horus who saved his Father.  I have come, I have rescued the sufferer (9)from him who caused it.  I have come today through the gate of the Great Embracer.  Ye who are on (10)your bellies, make way for me.  I am Horus the triumphant.  I have come, (11)I have saved my Father Osiris Unnofer justified the Son of Geb, whom Nut bore.  I cause (12)that the Gods shall associate with him who sees him.  The Gods in the Palace, they give him praise.  (13)I have come today through the gate of the west--variant: the gate of the lords of the nether world.  Make (14)way for me.  I am Horus who saved his Father.  I have come, I have driven away evil from (15)my Father Osiris.  I slew his enemies on that sandbar of Nedit on that (day) (16)of the great division.  I have come today through the mesmes-gate.  (O) Possessors (17)of Altars, make way for me.  I am Horus the Son of Osiris.  (My) Mother Isis (18)protects me.  I have come, I have brought life and well-being to My Father Osiris.  I have come today (19)through the gate of the cavern, for I know the secrets that are therein.  I have come today (20)through the high gate.  (O) lords of eternity, make way for me.  I am Horus the Son of Osiris, (21)the heir of Unnofer justified.  I have come today bearing light, (22)I have opened the darkness.  I have come today through the fayence gate.  (23)(O) thou who art in the tchennet-sanctuary, make way for me.  I am the spitter at the prow of the bark.  (24)I have come {today} to provide protection for Osiris.  I have come today through the gate (25)of rejoicing.  (O) lords of rejoicing, make way for me.  I am Horus, a son-who-loves.  (26)I have come today hither from the great city.  I am Re at dawn.  I give the breath of life (27)(to) Osiris.  I have come today through the gate of Qawyt--variant: Selqet, (28)for I know the time of day.  I have come today through the gate of the lords of Kher(29)aha and the princes of the Lord of the Universe.  Make way for me.  I have come today (30)through the gate of fire--variant: flame.  (O) daughter of the Inundation, child of darkness, make (31)way for me.  I have come today through the gate of the Magician.  (O ?ye) thousand violent ones (32)who are? beside him, make way for me.  I have come today through the gate (of) her who loves (33)her ?settlement?, the bird of passage--variant: (the Blameless One).  (34)Protective image, I come to thee seeking the eye of Horus.  Ye who are over the city, make (35)way for me.  Verily I shall be led.  Pure, pure is Osiris N.  (Repeat) 4 times.  He washes his face from the vase (37)of Re on that day of the opening of the year.  He has become an initiate (38)before Osiris at his beautiful festival of putting on the white crown.  (cxxxii) (BD 147)Spells for the gate(s) of the house of Osiris the presider over the west.  (1)Spells for knowing the gate(s) of the house of Osiris the presider over the west and the Gods who are in their twin caverns, (the gods) to whom offerings are made on (4)earth.  First gate.  The name of its Doorkeeper is Face{s}-downward, numerous of forms.  (6)The name of its guardian is (Eavesdropper); the name of the announcer in it is Roaring-voiced.  (8)To be said by Osiris N. on arriving at this gate.  (11)Mine is the name of the sole one--variant: the great one--who created his light.  I have come unto thee, Osiris, that I may praise thee and wash away thy efflux which flowed (14){variant:} (from) thee and remove trouble from thee.  I base the name of Rosetau on it.  (16)Hail to thee, Osiris, in thy might and in thy power in Rosetau.  Raise thyself, Osiris, (18)in thy power and in that might of thine in Abydos, that thou mayest ascend to the Sky--variant: that (20)thou mayest circle the Sky, that thou mayest paddle facing Re, that thou mayest see the common folk.  Sole one, thou circlest Re.  Behold, I have said to thee, Osiris: ''I am the mummy of the God.''  (23){Variant:} What I have said is come to pass.  (I) cannot be kept away from the ?pierced? walls.  Open (25)for me the road in Rosetau, (for) I have healed the sickness of Osiris.  (I) have brought along him who has passed (by) (27)the perch.  Make for me a shining way--for Osiris N.  (cxxxiii) Second gate.  The name of its Doorkeeper is ?Spy?.  The name of its guardian is ?Watchful?; the name of the announcer (4)in it is Asb.  To be said by Osiris N. (7)on arriving at this gate.  I have sat acting as head (while) (10)my mind planned, judging as companion of Thoth.  The protection of Osiris N. is (14)the protection of Thoth (with) (you).  (15)Grow faint, (ye) ?Kneelers?, hidden (of face), who live on their truths and whose years are the years (18)of Osiris.  N. is the powerful one, (21)weighty of might, who made his way through the flame--for there was flame therein.  (24)Osiris N. has mummified ?Horus?.  Make way for me; let me pass.  Preserve (28)him who sees the Sole One when Re circles in company with the Makers of Offerings.  (cxxxiv) Third gate.  The name of its Doorkeeper is Eater of the Excrement at His Posterior.  The name of (4)its guardian is Alert of Face; the name of the announcer in it is the Great One.  (6)To be said by Osiris N. on arriving at (10)this gate.  I am the secret of the flood, who parted the Two Comrades.  I have come; I have driven (13)evil away from Osiris--variant: the Weary-hearted One.  I am one who clothed his perch, who came forth from (16)the Coil.  I have established offerings in Abydos.  Open for me the road in Rosetau, (for) (19)I have healed the sickness of Osiris.  (I am) one who has settled on his perch.  Make (21)way for me in the great valley.  Make a shining way for Osiris N., that he may pass.  (He) drives away (26)the pain, he heals the sickness, of Osiris.  (cxxxv) Fourth gate.  The name of its Doorkeeper is Repulsive of Face{s}, Garrulous.  The name of its guardian is (4)Face-Lifter; the name of the announcer in it is Repeller of the Crocodile.  To be said (7)by Osiris N. on arriving at (11)this gate.  I am the great bull, Son of his hawk--variant: (the hawk) (of) Osiris.  Behold, (14)his Father, lord of ?the inward (parts)?, testifies for him: ''I have cut off the flood from him.  I have brought life, (17)that he may live forever.''  Make way for me, (for) I am Re--variant: Osiris--and (I) want him to live forever.  (20)Osiris N. is Osiris presiding over the west.  (cxxxvi) Fifth gate.  The name of its Doorkeeper is He Who Lives on Rotten Meat.  (3)The name of its guardian is Shawbew; the name of the announcer in it is (6)Face-afire, Violent of Strength.  (8)To be said by Osiris N. on arriving at this gate.  (13)I have brought the jaws from Rosetau; I have brought the backbone from Heliopolis.  (16)I have united the many (parts) of him; I have repulsed Apophis; I have spat upon the wound(s).  (20)Make way for me, (that I may pass) (among) (you).  I have brought (...); I am the greatest of the Gods, (even I,) Osiris N.  (26)Make way for me, (that) I (may) pass.  (cxxxvii) Sixth gate.  The name of its Doorkeeper is (Clawer of) Bread, (Violent of) Voice.  The name of (4)its guardian is Face-?Remover?; the name of the announcer in it is Keen of Face.  To be said by (7)Osiris N. on his arrival at this gate.  I have come (11)today, I have come today.  Make way for me, (that I may proceed), (O thou) whom {I} Anubis created.  I am lord (13)of the Coil, one who has planned magic, saved truth, and saved his eye.  (16)I have brought Osiris' eye to him.  Make way for me, that I may pass.  (cxxxviii) Seventh gate.  The name of its Doorkeeper is the Keenest of Them.  (3)The name of its guardian is One-voiced; the name of the announcer in it is Repeller of Attackers.  To be said by (6)Osiris N. on his arrival at this gate.  I have come unto thee, Osiris, (10)that (I) may wash away thy efflux and praise (thee) and bear (away) thy efflux (12)that thou mayest circle and see the Sky in the presence of Re, that thou mayest see the common folk.  Sole one, thou [ca]llest (14)Re in the Night Bark of the Sky, as he circles the Horizon.  I have said: ''He wants (to become) (16)a mummy whose name is {not} powerful.''  What I say (is come to pass) like what he says.  (I) can(not) be kept away (18)from thee, (Osiris).  Make way for Osiris N., (21)that he may pass, (that he may purify) Osiris yonder.  He has saved Osiris as a justified one.  He has united (23)his bones and assembled his members.  Given are bread and beer, food-offerings, (25)and everything good to Osiris N.  (cxxxix) (BD 148)Roll for initiating the blessed one into the mind of Re, putting his might before Atum, (2)magnifying him before Osiris, (putting) his power before the Presider Over the West, putting awe of him before the Ennead.  (3)It is to be used on the day(s) of the new-moon feast, the sixth-day feast, the fifteenth-day feast, the wag-feast, the feast (4)of Thoth, the birth of Osiris, and the feast of Min and on the night of the haker-feast.  (It is) a secret (5)of the nether world, a mystery in the god's domain: (how) to cleave the mountains and open (6)a valley.  (It is) a secret wholly unknown: (how) to preserve (7)the heart of the blessed one, wid(en) his step(s), make him (able to) walk, remove--variant: provide--the (8)stone from him, and restore his sight and (that of) the God.  (Thou shalt use it) without letting (9)anyone see it except the King of Upper Egypt and the lector-priest, without the face of a man who has come (10)from abroad seeing (it).  As for every blessed one, if this roll is used for him, his Soul (11)shall go forth by day with the living and shall be mighty among the Gods, becoming one who is not (12)repelled, (since this) is a truly excellent spell (proved) a million times.  These Gods shall surround him (13)and recognize him.  Then he shall be like one of them, so that he can tell (thee) what (14)fate has befallen him.  This roll is a real, real secret.  No (15)one else is to know (it) forever; it is not to be told to anybody.  No eye is to see (it); no ear is to hear (it).  None (16)is to be permitted to see it except one's self and one's teacher; and be not garrulous.  (17)Variant: to be permitted except thine own self and thy bosom friend.  Thou shouldst use (it) inside a tent of cloth (18)sown all over with yellow Stars.  This is a real secret.  (19)Of (all) people the rabble is not to know it.  Provisioning the blessed one{s} in the god's domain, (20)giving provisions to his son on earth, keeping him alive forever, without (21)anything prevailing against him.  To be said: Hail to thee, Re who shines in his Disk, (22)living one who has come forth from the Horizon.  Osiris N. (23)knows thy Name; he knows these thy seven cows and (24)their bull.  (O ye) who give bread and beer to the living and provision the Westerners, (25)may ye give bread and beer to Osiris {to Osiris} N. (26)and provision him; may ye give him (27)magic power, that he may lead you.  Osiris (N.), whom ye are to follow, is under your buttock(s).  May (28)ye give him bread and beer and magic power, (for) he is a blessed one in the god's domain, (O Thou of) the Spirit-House, (29)Lady of the Universe; (Storm Cloud of) the Sky, Holding Aloft the God; Blameless One Presiding Over Her Place; (Thou of) Khemmis, (30)Who Didst Wrap the God; Thou Whose Love Is Great, Red-haired One; Thou (31)Whose Name Prevails Over Throat and Mouth; Possessor of Life, Bright Red One; and (thou) bull, male of the cows.  (32)O Power of the Sky, opener of the Disk, good steering oar of the northern sky; O Re, (33)leader of the Two Lands, good steering oar of the western sky; O blessed one dwelling in (34)the house of the divine images, good steering oar of the eastern Sky; O foremost one dwelling in the (35)house of the red one, good steering oar of the southern Sky; may ye give bread and beer, provisions, (36)and magic power to Osiris N. (37)as one who is become a blessed one, even Osiris.  O Father of the Gods, (38)O Mother of the Gods, in the god's domain, may ye rescue Osiris N. (39)from everything evil, from all evil harm, (40)from all evil suffering, from that cruel snare and knives, (from everything evil) (41)that men, Gods, the blessed, (or) the dead may say this day, this night, (42)this half-month, this year and its ?subdivisions?.  To be said by a man before Re when he takes (43)his place over these Gods (and) to be written in green on a tablet.  Offerings are to be given (44)in their presence of bread and beer, meat and incense, and mortuary offerings are to be made.  (45)It is effective with Re.  (It is a means of) provisioning the blessed one in the god's domain.  (46)It is (a means of) rescuing a man from everything evil.  Do not use (it) in behalf of anyone except (47)thine own self--(this) roll of Unnofer justified.  If this is used for him, Re shall be (48)his steering oar and his protection, none of his enemies shall attack him (nor) shall he suffer lack--(49)variant: (nor shall there be lack) to him--in the god's domain, in the Sky, on earth, (or) anywhere he may go.  (50)(It is a means of) provisioning the blessed in the god's domain, being a truly excellent spell (proved) a million times.  (cxl) [This is a series of scenes with captions; see notes.]  (Over deceased:) Praise to thee, bull of the west, great one, lord of changelessness, great god, ruler of the silent land.  Thou receivest Osiris N. in health to the west in peace.  The necropolis (extends) her arms to receive thee and the lady of thy house, and thy body stays sound therein forever and ever.  (Over the god:) Osiris, lord of endless recurrence, great one, lord of changelessness, great God, ruler of the silent land.  (Over the goddess:) The beautiful West, who has extended her arm(s) to receive thee.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
