<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Provisional sale (7A) and mortgage agreement (7B)</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.3</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)3</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. O.I. 25255 (P. Chic. Haw. 7A + 7B)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Text 7A is a provisional sale of one-third share of a house; text 7B is a mortgage agreement for this same one-third of a house</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">P.Chic.Haw. 7C (P. O.I. 25260) was found rolled up in P.Chic.Haw. 7 (P. O.I. 25255). ;Same scribe also wrote P.Chic.Haw. 8 (P. O.I. 25256)</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: Recto</note>
                     <note type="related">P. O.I. 25260 (P. Chic. Haw. 7C)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyd">Demotic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>papyrus ; 136.0 x 35.0 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">10 lines in Demotic (P. Chic. Haw. 7A); 28 lines in Demotic (P. Chic. Haw. 7B)</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto: Provisional sale (7A) and mortgage agreement (7B)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The roll is made up of seven sheets of papyrus, averaging 20 cm in width</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="-0245">July 21, 245 B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Hawara, in the Fayum district, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Archelaos, son of Damas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Arsinoe, daughter of Polemokrates</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pater, son of Ankhmerwer and Ankhet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sobekhetep, son of Pawa and Herankh</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sobekhetep, son of Pasy</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tahena, daughter of Ankhmerwer</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maara, son of Pasherentaihet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tarenenet, daughter of Sobekiw and Nanefersobek</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Setawtawy, son of Patiwsir</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyd">Demotic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Sobek town of Hawara; Canal of Moeris; Nome of Arsinoe</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. O.I. 25255 (P. Chic. Haw. 7A) recto: (1) Year 2, second month of the season shemu, [day] 2 of Pharaoh Ptolemy, who lives forever, son of Ptolemy and Arsinoe, the gods Adelphoi, which is year three of the Greeks, the priest of Alexander and the gods Adelphoi being Archelaos, son of Damas, while Arsinoe, daughter of Polemokrates, is the Kanephoros (2) before Arsinoe Philadelphos. The god's sealer and embalmer Pater, son of Ankhmerwer, whose mother is Ankhet, has declared to the god's sealer and embalmer Sobekhetep, son of Pawa, whose mother is Herankh: ''You have caused my heart to agree to the money for my one-third share of this house which is built, it being provided with beam and door, which measures 18 god's cubits from south to north and measures (3) 19 god's cubits from west to east, upon its southern part, below and above, which is in the Sobek town of Hawara, which is on the northern shore of the Canal of Moeris, in the Nome of Arsinoe. The neighbors of this house, of which I have sold to you its aforesaid one-third, are: south, the house of the god's sealer and embalmer Sobekhetep, son of Pasy, the street being (4) between them; north, the house of the woman Tahena, daughter of the god's sealer and embalmer Ankhmerwer, adjoins it; west, the courtyard of the god's sealer and embalmer Maara, son of Pasherentaihet, which is in the possession of his children, adjoins it; east, my house adjoins it. Yours is the one-third of this aforesaid house upon its southern part, below and above, together with the aforesaid one-third of my bench, (5) which is on its western (side), the measurements and neighbors of which are written above, from today onward. No one in the world, myself included, shall be able to exercise control over them except you from today onward. As for him who might come against you regarding them, I will make him withdraw from you. If I do not make him withdraw from you, I will make him withdraw from you, and I will clear them for you (6) of any title deed or anything in the world. To you belongs every document that was (ever) drawn up regarding them, and every document that was (ever) drawn up for my father and my mother concerning them, and every document that was (ever) drawn up for me regarding them and every document by which I am entitled to them. They are yours together with the legal rights conferred by them. To you belongs that by which I am entitled through them. Any oath or court proof that might be required of you in order to cause that I execute it concerning them I (7) shall perform it. You may go up (to) and down (from) the roof on the stairway of this aforesaid house and you may go in and out of the forehall and the main doorway, and of the exits of this house and this aforesaid courtyard. You may make any alterations on them with your (work-)men and your materials in proportion to your aforesaid one-third share from today onward also.''  (8) [Wh]ereas the woman Tarenenet, daughter of the god's sealer and embalmer Sobekiw, whose mother is Nanefersobek, says: ''Write! Do everything above. I am agreed thereto. It is because I have claim on the aforesaid god's sealer and embalmer Pater, son of Ankhmerwer, whose mother is Ankhet, for the legal rights conferred by the document of annuity which he made for me that I give this consent above, and he shall execute for me (9) the legal obligations conferred by it, but I cede claim on the aforesaid god's sealer and embalmer Sobekhetep, son of Pawa, for the aforesaid one-third of this house and the one-third of the bench upon their southern part, below and above, the measurements and neighbors of which are written above. I do not have anything in the world against you in regard to them from today onward also.'' Written by the astronomer of Sobek, (10) Setawtawty, son of Patiwsir.  P. OI. 25255 (P. Chic. Haw. 7B), recto: (1) In (?) year 2, which is year 3, [second month] of the season shemu, day 2, of Pharaoh Ptolemy, (2) who lives forever, son of [P]tolemy and Arsinoe, (3) the gods Adelphoi. The [agreement]s which the god's sealer and embalmer Pater, son of (4) Ankhmerwer, made with [the like-titled(?)] Sobekhetep, son of Pawa, Pater, son of (5) Ankhmerwer, aforesaid, saying to Sobekhetep, son of Pawa, aforesaid: ''There are (6) a document of payment and a document of cession for the one-third of a house and a (7) bench in Hawara, so as to make two documents. I have put them in your hand (8) upon agreement because you have given to me 1 silver (deben) and 6 kite, in staters, 8 staters, (9) being 1 silver (deben) and 6 kite again. They increase my debit at the rate of 3/4 obols for (10) each stater per month, which makes 6 obols per month, beginning with year 2, which is year 3, (11) the second month of the season shemu, until the completion of two years, being 24 and 1/3 months, being (12) two years again. There increase amounts in the aforesaid period  (13) to 1 silver (deben) and 2 kite, in copper at the rate of 24 obols to 1 stater, making in all, (14) the principal and interest, 2 silver (deben) and 8 kite. The details thereof: (15) the principal in real silver, 1 silver (deben) and 6 kite; the interest, 1 silver (deben) and 2 kite, making in all (16) 2 silver (deben) and 8 kite. [I]f it happens that I have not given to you these 2 silver (deben) and 8 kite (17) aforesaid by the end of the two years aforesaid, I have no (18) claim in the world against you with respect to the aforesaid documents and the (19) legal rights which they convey. If, however, it happens that I have given to you these 2 silver (deben) and 8 kite aforesaid (20) by the end of the period aforesaid, you shall give back to me the aforesaid documents and the (21) legal rights which they convey.'' Whereas they say, the two parties: ''Write! Do everything above.  (22) We are agreed thereto. There is no subterfuge in any agreement of ours.'' Whereas Pater, aforesaid, says: (23) ''Give the aforesaid documents to the woman Tarenenet, my wife, (24) on the day on which I shall give the money to you.'' Whereas he says also: (25) ''The money which I shall give back to you with its interest out of the money (26) aforesaid before this aforesaid date, it will be accepted from me (27) and one will cause that [it be] deducted from the aforesaid (total sum of) money also.'' Written by (28) Setawtawty, son of Patiwsir.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
