<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>History</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.36</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)36</idno>
            <idno type="dclp">129997</idno>
            <idno type="TM">129997</idno>
            <idno type="dclp-hybrid">tm;;129997</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. O.I. 17640</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto and verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar-Arab">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>papyrus ; 19.0 x18.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Fine medium brown papyrus, broken at right and bottom. Narrow margin at the top is intact, but the outer margin is broken, with some of it cut away. The papyrus, particularly the verso, is much damaged by peeling and by numerous breaks, large and small.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto: 16 lines in Arabic; Verso: 17 lines in Arabic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto and verso: account of a battle</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Medium-sized carefully written book hand. Diacritical marks are remarkably rare for a 10th century document. The poetry of the piece is entirely without some needed dots and vowels. The small circle with the dot inside is used for interverse and verse punctuation.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0900" notAfter="0999">10th century A.D.</origDate>
                     <persName type="asn">Yalbuq</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Yahya</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tuwaiq</persName>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar-Arab">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>History</term>
               <term>Islam</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. O.I. 17640, recto: (1-5) Hilal ibn al-'Ajuz and a second man (name lost) in the rebel camp taunt Yalbuq (commander of the caliph's forces) with verses expressing their eagerness to meet and fell him with their piercing arrows and extol their own heroic qualities as cavalry lancers.  (5-9) On hearing this, Yalbuq is greatly disturbed but responds in turn with several verses.  The first couplet (in qasidah style) recalls the house of the beloved, while the remaining verses impute cowardly flight to the enemy, defy him in action, and confidently predict and anticipate victory in battle with the help of God.  (9) He (Yalbuq) said to his companions, ''Leave me alone so that I can give thought (10) [to the matter.''  Later he said to his] companions, ''You are in no (immediate) danger (of battle).''  Then he turned to one of them and said, ''You shall return to him (the enemy) (11) [and turn him away from giving battle.'']  So he (the courier) followed close on his (the rebel's) heels and proceeded to dis[suade him, saying,] ''Stand firm and do not commit the immoral act of (12) [fighting against the Muslims, and] your present disobe[dience will be for]given you.''  [But he (the rebel) said--a]nd he was a fool-- (13) [''Your master fears] the war!  (As for me) I follow my father in his rebellion.''  And he summoned the master (14) [of the horse...And] the courier [returned from the en]emy (camp).  The commander of the cavalry on (15) [the right wing was So-and-So, and he of the cavalry of the left wing was So-and-So.  And] the cavalry [was... (16) ...] all of them.  (17) ...  P. O.I. 17640, verso: (1) And he (Yalbuq or one of his men) said to them, ''It would indeed be a disgrace for us should Yahya fall.'' He then held back the hurler of satire at them (the enemy).  (2) Then each (of the caliphal army commanders) equipped his men with drums, flags, and banners, and they marched to the place of (3) their encampment, (each unit) 10,060 strong.  They encamped outside the city.  Then [he, (Yalbuq) called the (chief) army scout and] (4) asked him about his situation.  And he (the scout) gave (first) his report (of their own army) and then he gave him news of the rebels, describ[ing their a]rm[y and] (5) its condition.  When news of the enemy's approach and of their numbers reached the rebels, they ha[stened] toward [them].  (6) Then the chargers (of the caliphal army) rushed against the advancing enemy, and the two (forces) clashed in a charge of the [lance]rs.  (7) There were (of the enemy) 100,000 fighters and of the Muslims 75(000).  And [the rebels fl]ed (8) [and] their allies fled (too).  Then Tuwaiq, the commander of the rebel inciters (to battle) said to his men, ''Go (your way; as for me,) (9) I hope to make my way to the city under cover of night.  And he [...(was either captured or gave himself up)].  (10) And he was a poet, eloquent and sincere.  And he used to be friendly with [...(Mu'nis or/and Yalbuq?)].  (11) And he (Mu'nis or Yalbuq?) was under oath to return a favor he owed him (Tuwaiq).  Then he (Tuwaiq) was brought before Yalbuq, and he greeted him.  Now Hilal (a fellow officer of Yalbuq's) repelled him, saying, (12) ''Had it not been out of (our) consideration for the troops you (too) would certainly have suffered as calamitous an experience as he (the rebel of recto 11-13 or his father) did in th[e battle... (You will certainly be imprisoned or put to death)] (13) if you do not give us a written agreement (of cooperation).  But if you do give us a written agreement [you will] go [free.  But Tuwaiq refused] (14) and remained firm (in his refusal).  Then H[ilal] said, ''If you will not give me the information (sought) I will demolish it (the enemy's fort or arsenal?) anyway, as I have demolished oth[ers.''  Then Tuwaiq said,] (15) ''Excuse me (for the present.  However,) should you, after a day, give me a written guarantee of that (promised freedom), then I sh[all inform you of the source of supply] (16) of the swords from the people [of...(and of the source of supply of such-and-such arms from)] (17) the (other) groups of peo[ple...].</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
