<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Qur'an; a waqf given by Sultan Faraj</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.7828</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)7828</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">O.I. 12029 a</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Surah 25:21 (beginning of juz' 29) and 56:77-78</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">This is a waqf given by Sultan Faraj.  The text area is 19 x 26 cm.  Folio 2b contains two panels, each 6.5 cm broad, placed once above and one below the script section.  In the central cartouches of these panels, written in white on a background of gold and blue with a few dots in red, is the phrase from Surah 56:77-78.  Circles and other curved motifs are combined with conventionalized leaves and tendrils in the panel designs and the marginal ornaments.  The central cartouches of the panels have on either side a small circle in gold and black and then a larger semicircle of gold arabesques on a background of blue with a few touches of red.  These elements are boldly outlined with white paint.  The line is continuous and intertwined and gives the impression of motion.  The remaining space in the panels shows floral motifs outlined in black on a background of gold touched with red and blue.  The 3 lines of main text are enclosed in a gold border with geometric designs outlined in black and with colored squares of red, white, and blue placed at intervals of 2.5 cm.  An irregular double line of gold and black outlines cloudlike spaces in which the text is written.  The area outside of and between the written lines is crosshatched in red.  The marginal ornaments are gilded, with inner elements of design in black with touches of red.  The outermost frame and the "finials" are drawn in blue.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto and verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>paper ; 31.0 x 42.3 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Two folios of fine, light-colored, lightweight, thin paper, highly glossed and sparsely mottled with small reddish-brown fibers.  The margins are unusually soiled, torn, and roughened, and parts have lost the original gloss of the paper.  Although the two sheets are still partially glued together, they are worm-eaten along the inner margin.  Some of the gold leaf has peeled off, as have some of the colors, the white having suffered the most in this respect.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">2 folios.  On recto 2: 3 lines in Arabic; on verso 2: 5 lines in Arabic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto and verso: Qur'an</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The waqf notation and the following words "the nineteenth" are written in the same ink, but the latter is in a different and larger hand.  The script is thuluth, fully pointed and voweled.  The decorative writing in the title panels represents markedly the mudghamah or assimilated type, in which certain connected letters are run together so as to render the point of ligature indistinct.  The final strokes of some of these letters are are frequently extended and/or curved so as to touch or overlap the following letter or letters.  The round or muqawwarah type, which requires both a curve and an incline in certain thuluth letters, is also much used.  The script of the text proper uses mostly the open or mabsutah stroke, that is, an almost rectilinear one extended out to a point in such letters as m, r, and w.  Thus, though the scripts of both the panels and the text are in thuluth, they present a different general appearance.  Every detail in the script as well as in the design shows very careful and exact workmanship.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="1399" notAfter="1412">1399-1412 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Islam</term>
               <term>Qur'an</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">paper</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Folio 1 is blank.  Folio 2a contains a waqf notation and the words "the nineteenth."  Folio 2b contains three lines of text from the beginning of juz' 19 (Surah 25:21).  In the central cartouches of the panels on this page is the phrase from Surah 56:77-78, "Verily it is an honorable Qur'an (written) in a preserved book."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
