<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Annuity Contract</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.4</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)4</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. O.I.  25257  (P. Chic. Haw. 2)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">P.Chic.Haw. 10 (P. O.I. 25261) was placed within this one. ;Dated to Year 1 of Alexander</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: Recto and Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">P. O.I. 25261 (P. Chic. Haw. 10)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyd">Demotic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>papyrus ; 116.5 x 35.0 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The rightmost portion is much damaged and was restored by Hughes</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto: 4 lines in Demotic; Verso: 24 lines in Demotic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto: Annuity Contract; On verso: Witness List</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The papyrus roll is composed of eight separate sheets, each ca. 15.0 cm in width.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="-0331">October 10-November 8, 331 B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Hawara, in the Fayum district, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Patiwsir, son of Ankhhep and Isetweret</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ankhet, daughter of Ankhmerwer and Peset</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maara, son of Djkhonswiwfankh</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">witness list with 24 names, two of which illegible</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyd">Demotic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. O.I. 25257 (P. Chic. Haw. 2) recto: (1) Year 1, fourth month of the season shemu of Ph[ar]aoh l.[p.]h. Alexander. The god's sealer and embalmer Patiwsir, son of Ankhhep, whose mother is Isetwer(et), has declared to the woman Ankhet, daughter of the god's sealer and embalmer  Ankhmerwer, whose mother is Peset: ''You have caused my heart to agree to the 10 silver (deben) (weighed) by the pieces which are in the Treasury of Ptah, of refined (silver), being 9 silver (deben) and kite 9, 5/6, 1/10, 1/30, 1/60, 1/60 being 10 silver (deben) (weighed by) the pieces which are in the Treasury of Ptah, or refined (silver) again, (2) as your annuity. There belong to the children whom [you will be]ar to me everything of all property which I possess and that which I shall acquire in house, field, courtyard, building plot, male servant, female servant, cow, ass, every animal, every office, every title deed, and every matter of a freeman whatsoever of mine. And I shall give to you 36 (sacks) emmer (by the measure of) 40-hin, being 24 (sacks) barley (by the measure of) 40-hin, being 36 (sacks) emmer (by the measure of) 40-hin again and 1 silver (deben) and 2 kite (weighed) by the pieces which are in the Treasure of Ptah, of refined (silver), being 1 silver (deben) and 1, 5/6, 1/10, 1/30, 1/60, 1/60 kite (3) being 1 silver (deben) and 2 kite (weighed) by the pieces which are in the Tre[asury of Ptah of refine]d (silver), again for your subsistence each year at whatever house you desire. You are the one authorized with regard to the arrears of your subsistence which will be to my debit, and I am to give it to you.  As for everything of all property that I possess and that which I shall acquire in house, field, courtyard, building plot, male servant, female servant, cow, ass, every animal, every office, every title deed, and every matter of a freeman whatsoever of mine, (4) they become a pledge [for your annuity] aforesaid. I shall not be able to say to you ''Take your aforesaid annuity,'' but on [what]ever day you desire it, I will give it [to you]. I shall not be able to require an oath from you [nor from the witne]ss to the aforesaid document except in the house in which the judges are.'' Written by Maara, son of Djkhonswiwfankh.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
