<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Qur'an; given as waqf (see folio 10)</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.7837</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)7837</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">O.I. 12032 a</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Surah 7:52-54, 89-132, 143-161</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Text area measures 13 x 20 cm.  The ornamentation is comparatively simple.  It consists of filling the loops of the letters with gold and the loop of initial 'ayn with a gold dot in the center.  8 petaled whirling gold rosettes with blue and red dots mark the ends of verses.  It is impossible to determine the verse count system since this manuscript contains surahs and verses that are counted alike in all the different systems.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto and verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>paper ; 17.5 x 25.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The folios show evidence of having been trimmed down to their present size by uneven cutting.  Originally these folios must have been of the same size as those of O.I. 12032 b.  The paper is slightly worm-eaten, discolored, with a few pages patched to reinforce the lower outer corners.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">17 folios with 5 lines per page in Arabic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto and verso: Qur'an</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Neat, large, open thuluth, fully pointed and voweled, all in black ink.  Hamzah and sukun are sometimes accompanied by a red dot of later insertion.  For punctuation signs only the letters t (for waqf tamm), k (for waqf kafi), and h (for waqf hasan) are used.  They are in blue.  The following letters, written in red ink above the letters or words concerned, are used to ensure the correct pronunciation: gh (for idgham or assimilation), z (for izhar or vigorous and clear utterance), kh (for ikhfa' or partial assimilation), and bgh (for idgham Basri to indicate assmiliation by the Basran school).  Variant readings are give in the margins with the variations in red and the ramz, or letter symbol for each reader, in black.  All of these signs are later additions to the text.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="1398" notAfter="1494">IXth century A.H.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Islam</term>
               <term>Qur'an</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">paper</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
