<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Annuity Contract</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.1</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. O.I. 17481 (P. Chic. Haw. 1)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written in Year 17 of Nectanebo I</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: Recto and Verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyd">Demotic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>papyrus ; 230.0 x 37.0 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto: 4 lines in Demotic; Verso: 36 lines in Demotic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto: Contract; On verso:  Witness List</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The roll is made up of twelve sheets of papyrus, averaging ca. 20 cm in width. The leftmost sheet is left blank.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="-0365" notAfter="-0364">365/364 B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Hawara, in the Fayum district, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Nectanebo (I)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ankhmerwer, son of Ankhhep (called Patiwsir) and Taimen</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Peset, daughter of Ankhhep (called Patiwsir) and Ankhet</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maara, son of Ptahnefer</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">witness list containing 36 names</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyd">Demotic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. O.I. 17481 ( P. Chic. Haw. 1) recto: (1) Year 17. second month of the season akhet, of Pharaoh l.p.h. Nectanebo (I). The god's sealer and embalmer Ankhmerwer, son of Ankhhep, called Patiwsir, whose mother is Taimen, has declared to the woman Peset, daughter of the god's sealer and embalmer Ankhhep, called Patiwsir, whose mother is Ankhet: ''You have caused my heart to agree to the 30 silver (deben) (weighed) by the pieces which are in the Treasury of Ptah, of refined (silver) being 29 silver (deben) and 9, 2/3, 1/6, 1/10, 1/30, 1/60, 1/60 kite of silver, being again 30 silver (deben) (weighed) by the pieces which are in the Treasury of Ptah, of refined (silver), as your annuity. There belong to the children whom you will bear to me everything which I possess and that which I shall acquire, (2) house, field, courtyard, building plot, male servant, female servant, every animal, every title deed and every free thing in the world which I possess. I am to give to you 36 (sacks) emmer (by the measure of) 40-hin, being 24 (sacks) barley (by the measure of) 40-hin, being again 36 (sacks) emmer (by the measure of) 40-hin and 1 silver (deben) (and) 2 kite of silver (weighed) by the pieces which are in the Treasury of Ptah, of refined (silver) being 1 silver (deben) and 1 kite 2/3, 1/6, 1/10, 1/30, 1/60, 1/60 kite of silver, being again 1 silver (deben) 9 (and) 2 kite of silver (weighed) by the pieces which are in the Treasury of Ptah, of refined (silver), for your subsistence each year at whatever house you desire. You are the one authorized with regard to the arrears of your subsistence which shall be to my debit, and I am to give it to you. Everything which I possess and (3) that which I shall acquire is the pledge of your aforesaid annuity. I shall not be able to say to you, 'Take your aforesaid annuity,' (but on) whatever day you desire it, I will give it to you. I shall not be able to require an oath from you nor (from) the witness to the document except in the house in which the judges are.'' Whereas the god's sealer and embalmer Ankhhep, who is called Patiwsir, son of Pasherentaihet, whose mother is Peset, his father, says: ''Receive the aforesaid god's sealer and embalmer Ankhmerwer, my eldest son, whose mother is Taimen,(4) that he may execute the aforesaid document of annuity for you and that he may fulfill its obligations for you.'' He says also: ''Do everything aforesaid; my heart is satisfied therewith.'' The astronomer of Sobek Maara, son of Ptahnefer, has written.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
