<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P. O.I. 14046</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">chicago.apis.32</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(ICU)32</idno>
            <idno type="dclp">129988</idno>
            <idno type="TM">129988</idno>
            <idno type="dclp-hybrid">tm;;129988</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. O.I. 14046</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Beginning of creation, the number of sacred books and the time of their revelation, the number of the prophets, the angels aiding the Moslems at the Battle of Badr, and the visits and description of the angel Gabriel.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Oriental Institute</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Published: recto and verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar-Arab">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>papyrus ; 20.5 x 10.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Fine quality papyrus; the original format may have been square, as half of the width of the text is missing.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto:19 lines in Arabic; Verso: 20 lines in Arabic</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: On recto and verso: literary fragment</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The script is the fairly careful book hand or ''naskhi '' of the early Islamic centuries employed largely by copyists, a more or less cursive type with the letters generally well formed. Diacritical marks not fully used throughout the text, though used on many words. ''Fa'' and ''qaf'' receive a dot below and above, respectively, as was the practice with some of the earliest papyrus documents. The punctuation device for a full stop - a circle surrounded by a number of dots - is also true to early practice.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0800" notAfter="0840">ca. 800-840 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Upper Egypt</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar-Arab">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>History</term>
               <term>Islam</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P. O.I. 14046, recto: (1) [....] Sinan on te authority of my grandfather on the authority of Wahb ibn Munabbih the Yamanite. (2) [....] the beginning of creation when Allah caused it to rise .... (3) [....] and the earth until the Pentateuch was sent down to Moses (4) [.... Wahb sai]d that he had read seventy-two books of the books of (5) [the prophets. And the books that were sent down from heaven to] all the prophets were a hundred and four books. (6) [Of these to Seth the son of Adam a book of fifty] leaves and to Idris a book of thirty (7) [leaves and to Abraham a book of twenty leaves and] to Moses the Pentateuch and to David the (8) [Psalms and to Jesus the Gospel and to Muhammed - may Allah bless him] and give him peace - the Furqan. (9) [.. (the leaves of Abraham) .. were sent] down on the first night of the month of Ramadan. (10) [.. (the Pentateuch) ..] of the month of Ramadan after the leaves of Abraham by nine hundred years. (11) [.. (the Psalms) ..] of the month of Ramadan after the Pentateuch by five hundred [years.] (12) [.. (the Gospel) ..] of the month of Ramadan after the Pentateuch by a thousand and [? years.] (13) [And the Furqan (was sent down) to Mohammed - may Allah bless him and grant] him peace - on the twenty-fourth of [the month of] (14) [Ramadan after the ........] and five and twenty years. And ........ (15) [........] in the Night of Power. What ........ (16) [........ Mohammed - may Al]lah bless him and grant him peace. (17) [........] so that every Night of Power of ........ (18) [........] and the Quran was sent down to him during twen[ty (years)] (19) [.... Mohammed - may Allah bless him and grant him pe]ace.  P. O.I. 14046, verso: (1) [Wahb mentioned on the authority of I]bn Abbas ..... [Mohammed] (2) may Allah bless him and grant him peace. And the prophets were [a hundred and twenty four thousand. The Apostles] (3) among them were three hundred and fifteen. Of these [five were Hebrew - Adam, Seth, Idris, Noah,] (4) and Abraham; and five were Arabs - Hud, Sal[ih, Ishmael, Shuaib, and Mohammed - may Allah's blessings be upon them.] (5) The first prophet of the Children of Israel was Moses and the last of them [Jesus, the Apostle of Allah - may Allah bless him] (6) and grant him peace - said to his Companions on the Day of Badr, ''You are the same number as that [of the company of Talut and as that of the Apostles. Among the prophets] (7) is he who hears the voice and heads it, he to whom re[velation is made (in a dream or trance), and he who is (directly) spoken to .... (8) comes to me as a man comes to his friends in gar[ments white.... (9) His head like a mass of curls and his hair as [coral.... (10) on it, and two headbands of beautiful pearls [.... (11) green. And the form on which he was formed [.... (12) And the Prophet - peace be upon him - said to him, ''I desire to see you in your own form [...''  (13) and he filled the space between the two horizons. And [.... (14) of the children of Israel except fifteen prophets. Among these [were .... (15) [and Ab]raham and Ishmael, and Isaac and Jaco[b.... (16) [Mohammed] may Allah bless him and grant him peace [.... (17) [....] Allah on the prophets of Allah and on the[m..... (18) Wahb mentioned on the authority of Ibn Abbas that the first thing that Allah created was the [pen.... (19) his pen is lightning and his book is light. Allah most high looks [into it every day three hundred times [.... (20) and causes to die and to live, humbles and exalts, and lifts up people [....</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>No citations.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
