<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title type="main"> HGVTITLE (DDBTITLE) </title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">hgv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="TM">gv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">hgv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;8;215</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2021-02-26T05:22:58-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="r,ctr" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> Apollonous to Thermouthas her mother, many greetings. Before all things we pray that you are in good health, along with Apollonarion. I want you to know that I heard from those who have come to me that you have been ill; but I was glad to hear that you have gotten better. I ask you earnestly and beg you, take care of yourself and also of the little girl, so that you may get through the winter, so that we may find you in good health. We are also all well. And concerning the Syrian woman, up to now nothing bad. I ask you if you hear about Thermouthas, send me word. I ask you—it isn't a big deal—if you find anyone coming down, send me word concerning your health and the little girl's. I ask you and beg, if it is possible, for you to see the little girl three times a day. Think that I am near you. I will send you the earring now, for mine hasn't been made yet. If Esas the son of Thermouthas finds you a (good) price, sell (it). Also pay us a visit. Receive from . . .ktor a salotion, 
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="r,md" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="30" unit="line"/> in which there are twelve dried fish and twenty-two sesame cakes for the little girl, and give them to her one by one. Gaius send you his best regards, and Thermouthas, and Isidoros, and Diogenas, and we greet Apollonarion. We send regards to Ammia and her child. All send regards to you. Farewell. I send regards to Hera and her children. Tybi 3. 
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="35" unit="line"/> (ADDRESS): Deliver to Philadelphia to Thermouthas. 
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
