<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>letter</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1850</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1850</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.16.12694</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;16;12694</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;16;12694</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">30654</idno>
            <idno type="TM">30654</idno>
            <idno type="filename">30654-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 3164</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.395565-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>". . . I come to you. I received from Satrios 24 drachmas, with you (?) writing to me about the mattress and towel and linen cloth. I have given an order for these to be made, and they are not yet finished. If they are finished soon, if I find someone trustworthy, I shall send them with Joulas' people. I also bought 2 artabas of lentils, and Satrios is not willing to take them. The mattress is 5 by 3 (cubits), 36 drachmas; the towel is 10 (?) drachmas; the linen cloth 6 drachmas. I write these things to you so that our relatives may not know and give me trouble. I have safely received the 24 drachmas which you sent by Satrios. I for my part will supply the balance. If it is possible, send Apollos or someone trustworthy before Epeiph 25 so that if I receive my wages I can send you the 240 drachmas for the unsettled business of (the past) two years. All that is fitting for my mother I shall send her, if she wants anything. Have a cloak made for me by her so that I do not buy one again and get smeared too; everyone will be paid. Concerning Neilos, let me know what he wants. I greet Joulia my sister and Hephesta. Pauni 25."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>McNamee K, ZPE 46, 128-33, 1982, Pl IV 2 -- SB XVI 12694 (and XVIII, p. 484) -- BL IX, 289 (l. 13)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
