<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>a sale of land</title>
            <author>Aurelius Aion and Aurelius Pharitas</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1547</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1547</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.14.11703</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;14;11703</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;14;11703</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">30889</idno>
            <idno type="TM">30889</idno>
            <idno type="filename">30889-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1930</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.247902-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>" . . . (free from . . . ) and any other cessions or other transactions and from any plaintiff or claimant from this day forward. They have given their full guarantee that if they violate these terms, they will be liable to the penalty stipulated for breach of contract, and the terms of the acknowledgement will nonetheless be valid. This instrument has been drawn up at their risk, and the right to first payment belongs to the fiscus without prejudice to public or private interests. They have been questioned about the legality and fairness of these terms and have given their assent. This sale is valid.;(2nd hd.)We, Aurelius Aion and Aurelius Pharitas, both sons of achois, our mother being Tanetbeus, have sold the aforementioned two and a half arouras, and we have received the price of 370 drachmas in full and will give our full guarantee; the public payments in grain and money and all other payments are our responsibility as the party of Aion. We have been questioned and have given our assent. I, Aurelius Amois, also called Sarapion, wrote for them since they are illiterate."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Gignac FT, BASP 13, 45-7, 1976, Plate -- SB XIV 11703 -- BL IX, 276 (provenance)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
