<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.16/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
     n="0008;;233"
     xml:id="chr.wilck.233"
     xml:lang="en">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>chr.wilck.233</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">chr.wilck.233</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0008;;233</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">chr.wilck;;233</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">3666</idno>
            <idno type="TM">3666</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Duke Databank of Documentary Papyri. This work is licensed under a <ref type="license" target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p/>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <handNotes>
            <handNote xml:id="m2"/>
            <handNote xml:id="m1"/>
         </handNotes>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
          <change when="2020-10-08T14:57:38-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/james.cowey">Finalized - Ready. I have attempted to summarise the editorial history of the voting in a commentary on line 31.</change>
          <change when="2020-10-08T05:32:42-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/simoeis">Vote - AcceptText - I agree with D. Kaltsas and would treat the two lines of text on the left as separate from the name Μεγχεῖ. I also am not convinced of ἐπέδωκα. Perhaps record traces and note in the commentary that it could be an impression from the cartonnage, as suggested by Kaltsas?</change>
          <change when="2020-10-08T05:24:10-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/james.cowey">General - In an email from Demokritos Kaltsas I received the following comments "My impression of WChr. 233: I would be more or less happy with κωμογρ(αμματεῖ) | Κ̣ε̣ρ̣κεοσί̣(ρεως); the iota is indeed a bit strange, but this could be owing to the interference of the long tail of the rho above. The two words obviously belong together and should stand apart from Μεγχεῖ in the transcription, too. (so, three lines instead of two?)&#xD;
As to ἐπέδωκα, I could see it with a lot of good will, but I think it is a mere impression from the cartonnage. If you use ‘flip horizontal’ in Preview the kappa becomes a ny. In any case, it is so off-centre that it can hardly belong to the two words preceding."</change>
          <change when="2020-07-23T11:50:48-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/james.cowey">General - The reading in lin30 κωμογρ Μεγχεῖ is clear. I would prefer to interpret this as κωμογρ(αμματεῖ) Μεγχεῖ. The reading in lin31 (Κερκεοσ̣ί̣(ρεως)) is less clear. Only the sigma is really clear. That the following iota is slightly crooked and so long is not that usual, but perhaps its length signifies abbreviation. All other letters have various grades of damage. The reading is certainly justifiable. I would tend to underdot the first six letters. The reading ἐπέδωκα is attractive. The delta is very small, the kappa large and somewhat stretched in its width. Is there ink after what would be a rather round alpha? If the reading is correct I would prefer to understand it as an individual indication of a bureaucratic act. What exactly would it mean in the context. That I find unclear.</change>
          <change when="2020-07-22T02:38:29-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/ThomasBackhuys">Vote - AcceptText - Very well observed and clearly an improvement. I wonder if one cannot read more: κωμογρ and ΜΕΓΧΕΙ (in caps) are on the same line, with Κερκεσιρ (no dots needed) below. Indented in a third line (the one below) I see something in a cursive script that appears to be ἐπέδωκα. This reminds me of P.Petaus 121, the writing exercise in which Petaus practices Πεταῦς κωμογραμματεὺς ἐπιδέδωκα ("I, Petaus, komogrammateus, have handed over") with varying degrees of success. Accordingly, the address ΜΕΓΧΕΙ could be written by a first hand (that of recto), whereas the mostly abbreviated part could be interpreted as [Μεγχῆς] / κωμογρ(αμματεὺς) / Κερκεοσίρ(εως) / ἐπέδωκα, which would point to a second hand, maybe that of Menches or one of his subordinates.</change>
          <change when="2020-07-21T12:47:16-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/giuditta%20mirizio">Submit - No mention of ll. 30-31 on the verso in the ed. pr. No mention in Chrest. Wilck. No mention in Verhoogt (Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXIX) nor in BL. Mention of the address in APIS. Therefore I inserted the reading based on the photo available online.</change>
          <change when="2017-11-25T15:36:41-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/james.cowey">Finalized - Ready.</change>
          <change when="2017-11-25T15:21:34-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/james.cowey">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Well spotted. Fine</change>
          <change when="2017-11-24T12:39:02-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/giuditta%20mirizio">Submit - Removed the duplication of the expression (ἐλ(άβομεν)) ((ἔτους)) &lt;#β=2#&gt; Τῦβι &lt;#κθ=29#&gt; in l. 1, which is absent from the papyrus, according to the edition and the image</change>
          <change when="2011-12-14" who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/gabrielbodard">rationalized languages in langUsage</change>
          <change when="2011-12-14" who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/gabrielbodard">changed editor names to URIs</change>
          <change when="2011-10-04" who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/Faith">Automatically updated revision description</change>
          <change when="2011-09-20" who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/Faith">Automated transfer of accents across reg-orig pairs</change>
          <change when="2011-03-02" who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/gabrielbodard">batch converted all tei:sic to tei:orig and tei:corr to tei:reg</change>
          <change when="2010-05-05" who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/gabrielbodard">changed schema; added xml:space=preserve; indented; moved title/@n to idno</change>
          <change when="2009-11-12" who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/gabrielbodard">Added language la-Grek</change>
          <change when="2009-06-27" who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/gabrielbodard">Converted from TEI P4 (EpiDoc DTD v. 6) to P5 (EpiDoc RNG schema)</change>
          <change when="2008-12-23" who="http://papyri.info/about">Automated split from transcoder files</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <head n="3666" xml:lang="en">
            <date>115 BC</date>
            <placeName>Tebtynis</placeName>
            <ref n="p.tebt;1;30" type="reprint-from">P.Tebt. 1 30</ref>
         </head>
         <div xml:lang="grc" type="edition" xml:space="preserve"><div n="r" type="textpart"> <ab> 
    <lb n="1"/><handShift new="m2"/> Ὀννῶφρις <expan><ex>ἄρουραι</ex></expan> <num value="24">κδ</num>, <expan><ex>γίνονται</ex></expan> <num value="24">κδ</num>. <expan><ex>ἔτους</ex></expan> <num value="2">β</num> <expan>Τῦ<ex>βι</ex></expan> <num value="29"><hi rend="supraline">κθ</hi></num>.  <expan>ἐλ<ex>άβομεν</ex></expan> <expan><ex>ἔτους</ex></expan> <num value="2">β</num> Τῦβι <num value="29"><hi rend="supraline">κθ</hi></num>.  

    <lb n="2"/><handShift new="m1"/> Ὀννῶφρις Μεγχεῖ χαίρειν.  τῆς παρʼ Ἀπολλωνίου τοῦ Ποσειδωνίου τοῦ βασιλικοῦ γραμματέως ἐπιστολῆς 

    <lb n="3"/>περὶ ὧν σημαίνουσι παρακεχωρῆσθαι Διδυμάρχωι Ἀπολλωνίου ὑπὸ Πέτρωνος τοῦ Θέωνος περὶ Κερκεοσῖριν <expan><ex>ἀρουρῶν</ex></expan> <num value="24">κδ</num> 

    <lb n="4"/>τὸ ἀντίγραφον ὑπόκειται, ὅπως εἰδὼς κατακολουθῇς τοῖς ἐπεσταλμένοις. 

    <lb n="5"/>ἔρρωσο.  <expan><ex>ἔτους</ex></expan> <num value="2">β</num> Τῦβι <num value="28"><hi rend="supraline">κη</hi></num>. 

    <lb n="6"/><supplied reason="lost">Ἀπ</supplied>ολλώνιος Ποσειδωνίου Πολέμωνι χαίρειν.  τῆς παρὰ Πτολεμαίου καὶ Ἑστιείου τῶν γενομένων πρὸς τῆι 

    <lb n="7"/>συντάξει τῶν κατοίκων ἐπιστολῆς περὶ ὧν σημαίνουσι παρακεχωρῆσθαι Διδυμάρχωι ὑπὸ Πέτρωνος τοῦ 

    <lb n="8"/>Θέωνος περὶ Κερκεοσῖριν <expan><ex>ἀρουρῶν</ex></expan> <num value="24">κδ</num> καὶ ὧν οἱ γραμματεῖς ἀνενην<supplied reason="lost">όχ</supplied>ασιν ἀντίγραφα ὑπόκειται. 
<milestone rend="paragraphos" unit="undefined"/>
    <lb n="9"/><expan><ex>ἔτους</ex></expan> <num value="2">β</num> Τῦβι <num value="27"><hi rend="supraline">κζ</hi></num>. 

    <lb n="10"/>Πτολεμαῖος καὶ Ἑστιεῖος Ἀπολλωνίωι χαίρειν.  τοῦ δεδομένου ἡμῖν <supplied reason="lost">ὑ</supplied>πομνήματος παρὰ Διδυμάρχου τοῦ Ἀπολλωνίου 

    <lb n="11"/>Μακεδόνος τῆς <num value="5"><hi rend="supraline">ε</hi></num> <expan>ἱπ<ex>παρχίας</ex></expan> τῶν <expan><ex>ἑκατονταρούρων</ex></expan> τὸ ἀντίγραφον ὑποτετάχαμεν.  ἐπεὶ οὖν καὶ οἱ παρʼ ἡμῶν γραμματεῖς 

    <lb n="12"/>ἀνενηνόχασιν γεγονέναι αὐτῶι τὴν παραχώρησ<supplied reason="lost">ι</supplied>ν τῶν <num value="24">κ<supplied reason="lost">δ</supplied></num> <expan><ex>ἀρουρῶν</ex></expan> καλῶς ποιήσεις <del rend="erasure"><gap reason="illegible" quantity="2" unit="character"/></del> συντάξας 

    <lb n="13"/>καὶ παρὰ σοὶ ἀναγράφειν εἰς αὐτὸν ἀκολο<supplied reason="lost">ύθω</supplied>ς. 
<milestone rend="paragraphos" unit="undefined"/>
    <lb n="14"/><expan><ex>ἔτους</ex></expan> <num value="54">νδ</num> Φαρμοῦθι <num value="8"><hi rend="supraline">η</hi></num>. 

    <lb n="15"/>Πτολεμαίωι καὶ Ἑστιείωι τοῖς πρώτοις φίλοις καὶ πρὸς τῆι συν<supplied reason="lost">τά</supplied>ξει παρὰ Διδυμάρχου τοῦ Ἀπολλωνίου 

    <lb n="16"/>Μακεδόνος τῆς <num value="5"><hi rend="supraline">ε</hi></num> <expan>ἱπ<ex>παρχίας</ex></expan> τῶν <expan><ex>ἑκατοναρούρων</ex></expan>. παρακεχωρημένου μου ὑπὸ Πέτ<supplied reason="lost">ρ</supplied>ωνος τοῦ Θέωνος Πέρσου τῆς αὐτῆς 

    <lb n="17"/>ἱππαρχίας τὸν ὑπάρχοντʼ αὐτῶι κλῆρον περὶ κερκεοσῖριν τῆς <supplied reason="lost">Πο</supplied>λέμωνος μερίδος <expan><ex>ἀρουρῶν</ex></expan> <num value="24">κδ</num>, τῶν δὲ 

    <lb n="18"/>πρὸς ταῖς γραμματείαις ἀγνοούντων τὴν γεγονυῖαν περὶ ἐ<supplied reason="lost">μο</supplied>ῦ οἰκονομίαν καὶ <del rend="erasure"><gap reason="illegible" quantity="2" unit="character"/></del> ἔτι <choice><reg>ἀναγραφόντων</reg><orig>ἀναγραφουσι</orig></choice> 

    <lb n="19"/>τὸν κλῆρον εἰς τὸν Πέτρωνα, ἀξιῶ συντάξαι γράψαι Ἀπολλ<supplied reason="lost">ω</supplied>νίωι τῶι βασιλικῶι γραμματεῖ ἵνʼ <add place="above">ε</add>ἰδὼς 

    <lb n="20"/>ἀναγράφηι εἴς με τὰς σημαινομένας <expan><ex>ἀρούρας</ex></expan> <num value="24">κδ</num> ἵνʼ ὦ τετευχὼς <supplied reason="lost">φιλ</supplied>ανθρωπίας. 
<milestone rend="paragraphos" unit="undefined"/>
    <lb n="21"/>εὐτύχει. 

    <lb n="22"/>παρὰ τῶν γραμματέων.  τῆι παρὰ Πτολεμαίου καὶ Ἑ<supplied reason="lost">σ</supplied>τιείου τ<supplied reason="lost">ῶν</supplied> γενομένων πρὸς τῆι συντάξει τῶν 

    <lb n="23"/>κατοίκων ἱππέων προκειμένηι ἐπιστολῆι περὶ ὧν γράφο<supplied reason="lost">υσι</supplied> παρακεχωρῆσθαι Διδυμάρχωι Ἀπολλωνίου 

    <lb n="24"/>ὑπὸ Πέτρωνος τοῦ Θέωνος τὸν ὑπάρχοντʼ αὐτῶι περὶ Κερ<supplied reason="lost">κεοσ</supplied>ῖριν τῆς Πολέμωνος μερίδος κλῆρον <expan><ex>ἀρουρῶν</ex></expan> <num value="24">κδ</num> 

    <lb n="25"/>παρεπιγεγραμμένου ἀνενεγκεῖν τὰ πρὸς ταύτας, ἐπισκοποῦντες διὰ τοῦ ἀπολογισμοῦ τοῦ ἐδάφους 

    <lb n="26"/>τοῦ <num value="54">νδ</num> <expan><ex>ἔτους</ex></expan> τῆς Κερκεοσίρεως εὑρίσκομεν ἀναγραφόμενον ἐν κληρουχίαι ἐν τῆι ἐπὶ τοῦ πατρὸς τοῦ βασιλέως 

    <lb n="27"/>καταμεμετρημένηι ἐφόδοις μεταβεβηκότα εἰς τὴν κατοικίαν <expan><ex>ἀρουρῶν</ex></expan> <num value="24">κδ</num>, ἃς καὶ τοὺς περὶ τὸν Ἑστιεῖον 

    <lb n="28"/>γράφειν παρακεχωρῆσθαι τῶι Διδυμάρχωι.  ἀναφέρομεν. 
<milestone rend="paragraphos" unit="undefined"/>
    <lb n="29"/><expan><ex>ἔτους</ex></expan> <num value="2">β</num> Τῦβι <num value="24"><hi rend="supraline">κδ</hi></num>. 
</ab></div>
<div n="v" type="textpart">
<ab> 
    <lb n="30"/><app type="editorial"><lem resp="PN G. Mirizio (from online photo)"><expan>κωμογρ<ex>αμματεῖ</ex></expan> Μεγχεῖ

    <lb n="31" xml:id="div2-lb2"/><expan>Κερκεοσ<unclear>ί</unclear><ex>ρεως</ex></expan>
</lem><rdg/></app>
 </ab>
</div></div>
         <div type="commentary" subtype="linebyline">
            <list>
               <item corresp="#div2-lb2" xml:space="preserve"><ref>31</ref> <p>Under this line and slightly to the right there appear to be traces. T. Backhuys suggests the reading: ἐπιδέδωκα. With varying degrees of willingness, J.M.S. Cowey, D. Kaltsas and R. Ast can accept hesitantly. The observation by D. Kaltsas that the traces may be a "mere impression from the cartonnage" is perhaps the most compelling.</p></item>
            </list>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
