<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Census Return</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">uts.apis.1</idno>
            <idno type="controlno">(NNUT)1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invno">P.UTS inv. no. 255</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItem>
                     <note type="general">On recto, 27 lines with the fibers; verso blank</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItem>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>2 pieces; a) 10.4 x 9.7 cm; b) 11.1 x 18 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0048">28 September - 27 October 48 AD</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Oxyrhynchus</origPlace>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>
                  <rs type="genre_form">Papyri</rs>
               </term>
               <term>
                  <rs type="genre_form">Document</rs>
               </term>
               <term>
                  <rs type="genre_form">Census</rs>
               </term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>To Dorion, Strategos, and to Apollonios, royal secretary, and to Didymos and Apollonios, secretaries of the region and of the village, from Thermoutharion the daughter of Thoonis, with her lord Apollonios the son of Sotades.  There are resident in my house behind the alley .... Thermoutharion, a freedwoman of the aforementioned Sotades, 65 years of age, medium, honey-colored, with a broad face, with a scar on the right knee. 3. I, Thermoutharion, the aforementioned, with my master the same Apollonios, swear by Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator from her health and on her freedom to have given over the list in question of those living with me, and that no-one else lives with me, neither foreigner nor Alexandrian citizen nor freedperson nor Roman citizen nor Egyptian apart from those written above.  If I swear truthfully, may it be well for me; if I perjure, the opposite.  In the ninth year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, Phaophi...</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Oxy. II 255 W.Chr. 201 <note>BL VIII, 234; X, 138</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Oxy.:2:255</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>