<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Private Letter</title>
            <author>Satornilos (Saturninus)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1655</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1655</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">28798</idno>
            <idno type="TM">28798</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;3;209</idno>
            <idno type="filename">28798-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 284</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.82091-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Saturnilus to Sempronius, his brother and lord, very many greetings. Before all things I pray for your health and success; at the same time I also make daily obeisance for you before our ancestral gods. I wonder, brother - this is the second letter which I have sent to you since I came home, and you have written me no reply.  I therefore ask you, brother, to write me at once about your well-being, that I too may be less troubled. For you know, brother, that I regard you not only as a brother but as a father and lord and god. For when I reached my house I at once wrote you perforce the first letter, having reached my house safely on the twenty-first, and I found all things well and our lady in good health. Our lady sends you salutations, as do also Maximus and his wife and children, and Gemellus, and Iulius and his wife, and Helene and all the children, by name. Give many salutations to Valerius and Celer and all his household, and Iulius Serenus and Serenus Sabinus and Sarapion and all who love you, by name. I pray for your welfare, most lordly brother.;;(Verso) . . . to Sempronius Maximus . . . from Satornilos his brother.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Winter JG, PMich III, 209, 1936 -- BL III, 111 (bibliography); BL XI, 131 (bibliography) Bell HI, Aus Antike und Orient. Festschrift Wilhelm Schubart zum 75. Geburtstag, 43-45, 1950 -- BL X, 123 (bibliography). - Verso, l. 1, at the end: read apo instead of para. (PH)</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
