<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Contract of Division of Property</title>
            <author>Soeris daughter of Elekis the elder; Tapetsiris daughter of Orsenouphis; and Stotoetis daughter of Isidoros</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2589</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2589</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.9.559</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;9;559</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;9;559</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">28808</idno>
            <idno type="TM">28808</idno>
            <idno type="filename">28808-2</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 5907</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.819375-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(9 lines too fragmentary to be translated);;(3rd hand) I, Tapetsiris, daughter of Orsenouphis, with my husband . . . as my guardian, have joined in making the division forever and have been allotted as my share two hundred cubits from the east side on the south as aforesaid. Herakleides, son of Herakleides, wrote for them.;(4th hand) I, Stotoetis daughter of Isidoros, with as guardian my husband, Petheus son of Charidemos, have joined in making the division forever and have been allotted as my share two hundred cubits from the east side on the north as aforesaid. I, Harpochration, son of Ammonios, wrote for them since they are illiterate.;(5th hand) . . . am my wife's appointed guardian.;(6th hand) I, Petheus, son of Charidemos, am my wife's appointed guardian, Stotoetis.;(7th hand) We, Stotoetis, daughter of Isidoros, and Tapetsiris, daughter of Orsenouphis, amd Soeris, daughter of Elekis the elder, with as guardians of Stotoetis and Tapetsiris their husbands and of Soeris her maternal uncle, Petheus, son of Thrasyllos, have joined in making the division forever and have received each her allotted share as aforesaid.;(8th hand) Has written for (them?) Harpalos, Mecheir the thirtieth. Registered through the grapheion of Karanis.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich IX, 559, 1971, Pl. IX -- BL VII, 113 (on lines 13,17,17-8); one small fragment added to lines 4-6, confirming the editor's restitutions (PH)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
