<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Private Letter</title>
            <author>Sempronius</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1544</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1544</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">28820</idno>
            <idno type="TM">28820</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;15;751</idno>
            <idno type="filename">28820-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 192</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.925163-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Sempronius to his mother and lady Satornila, very many greetings. Before everything I pray for your health, and at the same time I make daily supplication for you [before] the lord Sarapis. I wonder why you did not write to me neither through Celer nor through Sempronius. For when I came from my journey, I found them and asked them, why they did not bring a letter for me. They said: "Because of your journey". After I had heard about your welfare, I felt less anxiety. Therefore, my lady,  do please [without delay] write to me about your welfare. I have received [a letter] through Sokrates and another small one through Antonianus, and I have received a letter from Hexas(?) and I have received another from Lobotes(?). You [wrote] to me also about [- - - (10 lines too damaged to be translated) - - -] I now write to you [so that] you may remember him, for now his letters fell on deaf ears and you wrote your second letter to us about these matters. I write about these matters; for I would have done everything to come to you, in the first place to make obeisance to your good and child-loving character and in the second place also because of these matters. Now I did not find an opportunity; but I rather wrote to you about these matters because I am travelling. Greetings to Maximus and his wife and Sempronius Kyrillos and Saturnilus and Gemellus and Iulius and his family and Helene and her family and Skythikos and Kopres, Chairemon, Thermouthis and her children. Farewell, my lady, always.;(Post-script note in left margin: too damaged to be translated);;(Verso);;Deliver to Maximus(?) from his brother Sempronius.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep_Editor - Horsley GHR;  Rep_Ser -  New Docs. 2 (1977);   Rep_Year - 1982;   Rep_Pg_No - 21, text 5 Sijpesteijn PJ, ZPE 21, 172-175, 1976, Pl. II Sijpesteijn PJ, PMich XV, 751, 1982 -- BL VIII, 220 (bibliography); BL XI, 134 (bibliography); BL XI, 134 (l. 3)</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
