<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>List of property</title>
            <author>Theonas, son of Isidoros and Soeris</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">perkins.apis.3986</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(TxDaM-P)3986</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.oxy.10.1269</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0181;10;1269</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;10;1269</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">28984</idno>
            <idno type="TM">28984</idno>
            <idno type="filename">28984-2</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Oxy.  X 1269</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:24.230694-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>To Ptolemaios, priest and exegetes in office, from Theonas, son of Isidoros and Soeris of the city of Oxyrhynchos. Appended is a copy of the list which I presented to Sarapion, your predecessor as exegetes, of the articles left to my nephew and niece, being minors, Sarapas and Sarapous, by their deceased father, who was my full brother, Isas.;To Sarapion, priest and exegetes in office, from Theonas, son of Isidoros and Soerous of the city of Oxyrhynchos. Being asked by you for a list of th furniture and other articles left to my nephew  and niece, being minors, Sarapas and Sarapous, by their deceased father, who was my full brother, Isas, I declare that they are as follows: a coffersupllied with a false key, another out of use, a box of bronze, a plate or dish pledged by Isas during his lifetime to Panares for twenty drachmae of silver, another box likewise pledged for ten drachmae to the same Panares, a flask of tin pledged to the same person for four drachmae, a ... coloured ... pledged to me for a further sum of twelve drachmae, a tunic pledged to Tnephersois for eight drachmae, and a half share in three weavers's looms which belonged to his father, a pig sold by me, Theon, after the death of my brother Isas for forty drachmae, a large chest of bronze, one cup of tin and one of silver, a pillow ...</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Grenfell BP - Hunt AS, POxy X, 1269, 1914 -- BL XI, 148 (Ptolemaios, exegetes, identical with Ptolemaios in P.Mert. I 12, 1?)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
