<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Loan of Money</title>
            <author>Dioskous, son of Pausiris, and his wife Thermouthion, daughter of Achilleus</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3115</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3115</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21338</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21338</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;3;191/192dupl</idno>
            <idno type="filename">21338-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 76</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.261515-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Year 6 of Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, Pharmouthi (2nd hand) 23, (1st hand) in the city of Oxyrhynchus of the Thebaid.;Dioskous, son of Pausiris, and his wife Thermouthion, daughter of Achilleus, acting with her guardian Diogenes, son of Pasion and husband of her mother Ploutarche, all residents of the city of Oxyrhynchus, make acknowledgment in the street; Thermouthion, that she has not given to her aforesaid husband Dioskous more than the sum of 200 drachmai of imperial and Ptolemaic silver coinage out of the price for which she, acting with her guardian, the same Dioskous, sold to Didymos, son of Didymos, her portion of a house inherited from her father in the Hippodrome Quarter, because she has paid the remainder of the price to her mother Ploutarche, daughter of Harpaesis, toward the amount owed to her by Achilleus, son of Pastous, the designated father of Thermouthion and the former, and now deceased, husband of Ploutarche, according to a receipt that she (Ploutarche) has given to her; and Dioskous, that he has now received from Thermouthion the aforesaid 200 drachmai of silver and that he must repay it to her without interest within sixty days from the day that it is demanded of him or she has the right of execution regarding this amount both upon him and upon all his property as if in accordance with a court decision. This agreement is binding.;(3rd hand) Year 6 of Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, Pharmouthi 23. Registered through Andromachos, associate of Chairemon and Sotades, agoranomoi.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Schuman VB, PMich III, 192, 1936 -- BL III, 110 (l. 32; see also BL VIII, 212)</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
