<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Private Letter</title>
            <author>Paniskos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1408</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1408</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.3.218</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;3;218</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;3;218</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21348</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21348</idno>
            <idno type="filename">21348-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1366</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.954495-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Paniskos to his wife, many greetings. I send many salutations to Heliodora, my daughter. And do you attend to her. I want you to know: if you have need of anything, I wrote to Aion (to supply your wants), and if you happen to go off to Heliopolis send (word to him) for the things you need. And I sent fleeces for yourself in order that if you want anything you may (sell them and) spend the money for yourself. And attend to your cattle, and as for the three holokottina, make anklets of them for my daughter, and make ready the materials of your chiton and your himation. And if the god wills and I come I will send Achaos there (to inform you). And make ready my leather cloak, and if they (Aion and Achaos) want anything do you follow their orders. Know, then, that I write to you as a brother, not as . . . of you &lt;a stranger?&gt;. I pray for your health.;(Continued in the left margin:) I send many salutations to your mother and to Nonnos and his children and to Sarapion.;;(Verso);;Deliver to my wife, from Paniskos in the house(?) of Mopsarion.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Naldini M;    Rep Ser. - Cristianesimo in Egitto;   1998(2);   Pg_No 15 (with add., p. 430-431) -- L. 7: read aneloses (so Winter), not analoses (Naldini). (PH) Winter JG, JEA 13, 68-70, 1927, Pl. XXV -- SB III 7250 Winter JG, PMich III, 218, 1936 -- BL III, 111 (l.3-4, 16-17); BL VI, 81 (l. 7); BL XI, 131 (l. 17)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
