<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lease of Land</title>
            <author>Aurelius Elias, son of Kollouthos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2207</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2207</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.11.611</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;11;611</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;11;611</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21363</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21363</idno>
            <idno type="filename">21363-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 441</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.085486-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Year after the 9th consulship of our lord Honorius and the 4th of our lord Theodosius, the eternal Augusti. Thoth 30.;To the heirs of Phoibammon of glorious memory, formerly duke, landholders in the city of Oxyrhynchus, from Aurelius Elias, son of Kollouthos, from Fuller's Farmstead in the same nome.;I willingly undertake to lease from the present 89th = 58th year for the cropof the twelfth indiction, of the property belonging to you in the arable area of the village Plelo, in the field called Paeianos, a . . . water wheel outfitted and serving thirty and three-quarters arourai. Fifteen arourai are to be sown in wheat at the fixed rent of one hundred twenty artabai of wheat; five arourai in barley, at the fixed rent of one hundred twenty artabai of wheat; five arourai in barley, at a rent for these of forty artabai of barley; two arourai in vegetables, at a rent for these off six and a half artabai four choinikes of vegetables; and of the remaining eight arourai and three-quarters in grass, you are to have four and three-eighths(?) arourai in grass. The rent is free of all risk, and the public dues are to be paid by you, the landlords. And I will necessarily deliver the rent by the paralemptic measure at the fitting time without delay; and I will maintain the dikes. The lease is valid, and when asked the formal question I so declared.;(2nd hand) I, Aurelius Elias, son of Kollouthos, have leased the land and will deliver the rent as stated. I, Aurelius . . ., wrote for him, as he is illiterate.;(1st? hand, in Latin). (Drawn up) by me, . . .;;(Verso);;Lease of a water wheel serving Phaeianos' field to Elias, son of Kollouthos, from Fullers';;. . .</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Shelton JC, PMich XI, 611, 1971 -- BL VII, 115 (l. 7); BL X, 125 (l. 14-15; 20)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
