<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Hire of a Secretary</title>
            <author>Aurelius Sarapammon alias Dionysios and Aurelius Cornelius, anadothentes eis sitologian</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1606</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1606</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.11.604</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;11;604</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;11;604</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21360</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21360</idno>
            <idno type="filename">21360-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 259</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:26.71829-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Aurelius Sarapammon also called Dionysios, son of Theon also called Demetrios, and Aurelius [Aphynchis] alias Cornelius, son of Aphynchis, grandson of Aphynchis, both from the city of Oxyrhynchus, appointed in the present year by the amphodogrammateus of the 5th tribe, 3rd cycle, to the office of sitologoi for the village of Phthochis in the Eastern Toparchy, acting through their surety Aurelius Saturnilus also called Theon, son of Theon, from the same city;;and Aurelius Valerius, son of Sarapammon and Marcia Eudaimonia, from the same city, make the following agreement with one another:;The party of Sarapammon also called Dionysios, acting through their above stated surety Saturninus also called Theon, agree that they have appointed Valerius to the post of secretary of the afore-mentioned sitology on condition that the same Valerius shall receive all of the government wheat measured in to the same sitology, issuing receipts attesting to grain transfers and to grain deposited in private accounts; and that he shall obey the strategos of the nome in respect to each monthly report, presenting summaries of the wheat received by him; that he shall further deliver to the shipowners who are sent all of the wheat designated by him (the strategos), receiving the customary receipts.;And Valerius, who is satisfied with respect to salary and all expenses, agrees that he does approve upon these terms, and that he will perform each duty as above stated. It shall not be permitted for either of the parties to this agreement to violate the afore-stated terms; and as for this being done properly and well, they have asked each other the formal question and have so declared.;Year 2 of the Emperor Caesar Marcus Aurelius Severus Alexander Pius Felix Augustus, Pauni 6.;(2nd hand) We, Sarapammon also called Dionysios, son of Theon, and Cornelius also called Aphynchis, son of Aeis, acting through me, Aurelius Saturnilus, have appointed Aurelius Valerius upon all the afore-stated conditions, with his approval.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Shelton JC, PMich XI, 604, 1971 -- BL VII, 115 (l. 4); BL IX, 162 (bibliography). - L. 2-3: restitute (from l. 31) Demetrio[u kai Aphynchis ho] ; kai Kornelios. (PH)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
