<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Contract for Purchase and Delivery of Radish Oil (Paid Requisition)</title>
            <author>Flavius Kyrillos, princeps of the officium of the praeses of Arcadia</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1552</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1552</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.11.613</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;11;613</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;11;613</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21365</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21365</idno>
            <idno type="filename">21365-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1939</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.35055-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>[The year after] the consulship of the most illustrious Constantius and the most illustrious Constans, Mesore 26. In Herakleopolis in the province of Arcadia.;[Flavius Kyrillos, princeps] of the officium of the praeses of Arcadia, to Flavius Areios, councillor of the great city of Alexandria, and Flavius Theopemptos, councillor of the same city.;[In accordance with the orders] of my lord Flavius Lausus Horigenes, the most illustrious praeses of the province of Arcadia, I have received from you out of the [account] for the provisioning of [the great city] of Alexandria for the purchase of radish oil, on behalf of the citizens of Arsinoe, gold solidi of full weight, one hundred fifty in number, [and I am prepared to] deliver to you for each solidus sixty sextarii of oil, grand total 9000 sextarii. These I shall deliver [in the harbor of the] Arsinoite nome by the measure sent out by you from the great city of Alexandria whenever you desire, [without delay or] argument; and I swear by Almighty God and the holy reverence and victory of our lords [Honorius and Theodosius] the eternal Augusti that I will make delivery of the oil and have engaged in no deceit. The contract is valid and when asked the formal question [I so declared].;(2nd hand) I, Flavius Kyrillos, princeps, have received from you on behalf of the citizens of Arsinoe for the purchase of [radish oil] one hundred fifty gold solidi for nine thousand sextarii; and these [I will deliver when] you desire in the harbor of the Arsinoite nome as stated, and when asked the formal question I so declared and had this document prepared.;(1st hand) Drawn up by me, Heraiskos.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Shelton JC, PMich XI, 613, 1971, pl. III -- BL VII, 115 (l. 3)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
