<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Declaration under Oath</title>
            <author>Aurelius Paesis, son of Horos, kybernetes; Aurelius Diogenes, son of Diogenes</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2162</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2162</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21390</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21390</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;20;815</idno>
            <idno type="filename">21390-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 422</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.770891-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>[- - -] . . . [- - -], son of Eusebios, and Sarapion, [son of Ploutarchos - - -] from Aurelius Paesis, son of Horos, from [- - - pilot of a boat - - -] ex-curator, with [Aurelius Diogenes], son of Diogenes, of the aforesaid [- - -] as surety for the delivery of the cargo [- - -. We acknowledge, swearing] the august and divine oath by our lords - - -], I, the pilot, that I have received from [- - - and have put on board the aforesaid boat], of the harvest of the fortunate new 9th indiction[ six hundred eighteen artabai of pure wheat, free of barley and] unadulterated, measured with the large public measure, [total 618 art. which I shall transport] to the most illustrious Alexandria and deliver [safe and undamaged to whomever I am ordered to deliver it, and] I shall produce certificates  of delivery for these; [I, Aurelius Diogenes, - - -], that I serve as surety for the same pilot that he will deliver [the artabai of wheat to whomever he will be ordered by] you, the epimeletai, to deliver it, or I, the surety, [am necessarily responsible for everything that may be] made the subject of inquiry [against him] concerning this cargo so as to [incur blame] in [no respect, otherwise may I be liable to the divine oath]. (2nd hand) I, Aurelius Diogenes, son of Diogenes, [am surety for Aurelius Paesis, son of Horos, pilot], that he will deliver the cargo of wheat, and [I have sworn the divine oath, as stated above, and in answer to the formal question, I have given my consent]. (3rd hand) I, Aurelius Paesis, son of Horos, have received and put on board [the six hundred] eighteen [artabai of wheat], total 618 art., and I shall deliver, as stated above. I, Aurelius [- - -, have written on his behalf as he is illiterate].</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn PJ, BASP 13, 71-74, 1976 Sijpesteijn PJ, PMich XV, 724, 1982, Pl. XX -- BL VIII, 219 (l. 12); BL X, 127 (bibliography). - The date suggested for this papyrus in CE 69 (1994) p. 134, n. 6, should be corrected from "373?" to "365/366". (PH)</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
