<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>List</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">oslo.apis.20</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NoOU)20</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.oslo.3.122</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0177;3;122</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oslo;3;122</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21553</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21553</idno>
            <idno type="filename">21553-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Oslo inv. 656</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:31.239394-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Aurelius Cronion, Roman citizen, (belonging to the) turma of Nicolaus, (enrolled) in the consulship of Iulianus II; Aurelius Hermaiscus, Roman citizen, (belonging to the) turma of Quintianus, (enrolled) in the consulship of Valerius Comazon; Iulius Horigenes, Roman citizen, (belonging to the) turma of Titus, (enrolled) in the consulship of Modestus; Aurelius H(...), Roman citizen, (belonging to the) turma of Flaminius, (enrolled) in the consulship of Agricola; Aurelius (A)rtem(idorus), Roman citizen, (belonging to the) turma of ..., (enrolled) in the consulship of Agricola.;Ten sesquiplicarii:;Aelius Sarapion, (belonging to the) turma of Ammonianus Cosanus, (enrolled) in the consulship of Praesens; Aurelius Ammonianus, (belonging to the) turma of Flaminius, (enrolled) in the consulship of Iulianus II; Iulius Sarapion, (belonging to the) turma of Sarapion, (enrolled) in the consulship of Gratus; Aurelius Heras, (belonging to the) turma of Titus, (enrolled) in the consulship of the Divus Alexander; Theon, son of Serenus, (belonging to the) turma of Ammonianus, (enrolled) in the consulship of Praesens ...;(the list breaks off)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Eitrem S-Amundsen L, P.Oslo III, 122, 1936, Pl. X</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
