<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Application concerning a loan</title>
            <author>Aurelia Didyme alias Dionysia</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">perkins.apis.3995</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(TxDaM-P)3995</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.oxy.12.1474</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0181;12;1474</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;12;1474</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21875</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21875</idno>
            <idno type="filename">21875-2</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Oxy.  XII 1474</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:24.231925-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>To Aurelios Anoubion, strategos of the Oxyrhynchite nome, from Aurelia Didyme alias Dionysia, and however she is styled, through Aurelios Nilos, scribe. A copy of the communication which I have received from the bureau is as follows.;Aurelius Casius, priest and archidikastes, to the strategos of the Oxyrhynchite nome, greeting. Let a copy of the publication which has been effected be served, as follows. Goodbye. The 24th year of Aurelius Severus Antoninus Caesar the lord, Mecheir 5. I, Marcus Aurelius Harpokration, have signed for 14 drachmae. I, Marcus Aurelius Nemesianus alias Eirenaios, and however I am styled, scribe of the bureau, wrote the document.;To Lucius Septimius Aurelius Casius, priest, archidikastes and superintendent of the chrematistai and other courts, from Arelia Didyme alias Dionysia, and however she is styled. Appended is a copy of the bond issued to me in duplicate and of the signature beneath it. Pekysis son of Peusirion and Thetheus of Oxyrhynchos, to Aurelia Didyme alias Dionysia, and however she is styled, through Souchammon, freedman of your grandfather Aurelios Diogenes, greeting. I acknowledge that I owe you without interest in the month of Epeiph of the present 23rd year in wheat that is new, pure, unadulterated, unmixed with earth or barley, sifted, and measured into the public granary here in the Oxyrhynchite nome by your receiving-measure of the village of Syron, the measurement being performed by your agents, all without a delay, or, if I fail, I will forfeit to you interest for the overtime at the rate of half the capital, you having the right of execution upon my person and all my property of every kind. This bond, written in duplicate, is valid wheresoever it is produced and whosoever produces it on your behalf. The 23rd year of the emperor Caesar Marcus Aurelius Severus Antoninus Parthicus Maximus Bretanicus Maximus Germanicus Maximus Pius Augustus, Choiak 20. I, Pekysis, son of Pausirion, have received the aforesaid 45 artabae and will repay them as aforesaid. The period of the loan having expired and no repayment having been made, I desire that of this duplicate bond [a single copy should be sent to the Library of Hadrian etc.]</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Grenfell BP - Hunt AS, POxy XII, 1474, 1914 -- BL II,2, 100 (lthe proposal on l. 15 "os" instead of "kai" proved on the original)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
