<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Application to join the gerousia</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">wisconsin.apis.5415</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(WU)5415</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.wisc.2.56</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0226;2;56</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.wisc;2;56</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">15897</idno>
            <idno type="TM">15897</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Wisc. inv. 53</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>It is probably an application to join the gerousia, although this is not explicity mentioned. As the top of the document has been lost it is no longer possible to ascertain to whom this application was directed.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Department of Special Collections; Memorial Library; Madison; Wisconsin</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: recto; verso is blank</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 22 x 8.8 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">A medium-brown papyrus, regularly cut off at the bottom and partially so at the left and right-hand sides.  The ink traces yet visible in the free space have been occasioned by folding the text when it was still wet.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">30 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>At the left there is a margin of 1 cm, while at the bottom 6 cm have been left free. The text runs along the fibers. Two vertical and two horizontal folds are still visible.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0209">March 24, 209 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Oxyrhynchos, Oxyrhynchite nome, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Severus and Antoninus and Geta Caesar Augusti, emperors</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thoonis, son of Thoonis, grandson of Harpaesis, mother Taseus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thoonis, son of Harpaesis, grandson of Thoonis</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Oxyrhynchos, Oxyrhynchite nome, Egypt;Thoeris, quarter, Oxyrhynchos, Oxyrhunchite nome, Egypt</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[To NN from Thoonis, son of Thoonis, grandson of Harpaesis, mother Taseus, from the city of Oxyrhynchos, the great and] glorious, registered in the Thoeris quarter - - -. From the first roll. Having become 73 years old I  certify that I am now registered in the Thoeris quarter in accordance with the first roll of the persons scrutinized in the house-to-house census for the 14th year of the deified Marcus at the age of 38, with no distinguishing features. The relevant section of this scrutiny I have extracted and subjoined. Accordingly I present this petition and I request that I may be enrolled in the lists and I swear by the genius of the lords Imperatores Severus and Antoninus and Geta Caesar Augusti that I have not made a false statement. Year 17 of the Imperatores Caesares Lucius Septimius Severus Pius Pertinax Arabicus Adiabenicus Parthicus Maximus and Marcus Aurelius Antoninus Pius Augusti and Publius Septimius Geta Caesar Augustus, the 28th of Phamenoth. Viz.: extract from the public record office from the terrier of scrutiny for the house-to-house census of the 14th year of the deified Marcus, Thoeris quarter, from the first roll, 7th sheet from the strategos department: the part of Thoonis, son of Thoonis, garndson of Harpaesis, his mother being Taseus without a father, with no distinguishing features, aged 38, in the West bordering (the land) of Thoonis, son of Harpaesis, grandson of Thoonis. He passed the scrutiny aged 38, with no distinguishing features.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn PJ , PWisc II, 56, 1977, Plate XVI -- BL VII, 281 (lines 9 and 24); BL VIII, 512 (line 23)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Wisc.:2:56</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5415&amp;viewid=W53R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/5/3/r/w53r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5415&amp;viewid=W53R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5415&amp;viewid=W53R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
