<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Census Return</title>
            <author>Sambathion, daughter of Diodoros, alias Dioskoros son of Petesuchos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">wisconsin.apis.5412</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(WU)5412</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.wisc.1.36</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0226;1;36</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.wisc;1;36</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">13712</idno>
            <idno type="TM">13712</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Wisc. inv. 25</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>This papyrus contains a property return, following the customary lay-out. It is addressed to the full range of officials to whom these returns are usually sent in the villages of the Fayum: the strategus Theon; the basilikos grammateus Artemidoros; the village scribe Heras and the laographoi, two of whom, not occurring elsewhere, are referred to by name. Ptolemaios’ sister states that she owns a house in Theadelphia, acquired by purchase and that it is inhabited by her brother Ptolemaios, also acting as her guardian, together with his wife and son. She also owns property in the village of Apias and has returned this as well.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Department of Special Collections; Memorial Library; Madison; Wisconsin</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso has some traces which don not seem to be part of the text on the Recto side.</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 21.1 x 17.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">A light-brown papyrus, cut off regularly on all sides. At the left-hand side there is a margin of 2 cm., at the top one of 1.5 cm. and at the bottom one of 3.5 cm. the scribe has endeavored to fill up the lines at the right-hand side. Five vertical folds are still visible. The papyrus is worm-beaten. On the verso side, at 8 cm. from the bottom, some traces remain which do not seem to be part of the text on the recto side.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">20 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The text runs parallel to the fibers. The hand is clearly well-trained.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0147">July 9, 147 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Theadelphia, Themistou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Theon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Artemidoros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Diodoros, alias Dioskoros, the son of Petesuchos, her mother being Isidora</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anubiaine, alias Achillis</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Themistes;;Polemon;;Theadelphia;;Apias.</term>
               <term>Census Return</term>
               <term>Officials</term>
               <term>Villages of the Fayum</term>
               <term>Strategus</term>
               <term>Basilikos grammateus</term>
               <term>Scribe</term>
               <term>Laographoi</term>
               <term>Theadelphia</term>
               <term>Sister</term>
               <term>Brother</term>
               <term>Guardian</term>
               <term>House</term>
               <term>Wife</term>
               <term>Son</term>
               <term>Village of Apias.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>To Theon, strategus of the Arsinoites of the division of Themistes and Polemon and to Artemidoros royal scribe of the division of Themistes and to Heras, village scribe of Theadelphia and Heron and Satabus and the fellow-laographoi of the same village from Sambathion, daughter of Diodoros, alias Dioskoros, the son of Petesuchos, her mother being Isidora from the people of the village of Theadelphia, her guardian being Ptolemaios, having also made a property return in the village of Alias. I own in the aforesaid village of Theadelphia a bought house, in which I declare for the property return of the past 9th year of Antoninus Caesar, the lord in the aforesaid village of Theadelphia my above brother from the same father and mother, Ptolemaios, 35th year old and his son, born to him from his present wife, living with him, Anubiaine, alias Achillis, citizeness, Dioskoros, alias Heron, 3 (or 13) years old. That is why I submit the property return. I, Heras, village scribe of Theadelphia, have received a copy through Dios. Year of Antoninus Caesar, the lord, the 15th Epeiph.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn P.J., PWisc  I, 36, 1967, Plate XIV</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Wisc.:1:36</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5412&amp;viewid=1">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
