<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Liturgy list</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">wisconsin.apis.5449</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(WU)5449</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.wisc.2.85</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0226;2;85</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.wisc;2;85</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">15904</idno>
            <idno type="TM">15904</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Wisc. inv. 51</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>If N. Lewis (op. cit., introduction to text no. 2) is correct in his assumption that this papyrus should be dated to the latter part of the IInd century A.D., year 6 mentioned in line 28 could be the sixth year of the reign of Septimius Severus (15.10.197 A.D.). However, the sixth year of the reign of Alexander Severus (15.10.226 A.D.) cannot be excluded. The text is a nomination of every time two men to superintend the irriügation of the fields. First two men of each six toparchies of the Oxyrhynchite nome are nominated (lines 6 - 27); from line 29 onwards at least 15 more men are nominated. These men are living in certain villages of the Oxyrhynchite nome. It is possible that each village contributed two men as well (it is not absolutely certain that line 37 was directly followed by line 38 = the beginning of the second London fragment). Anyhow, one village must have contributed either one or three nominees. The text is in all probability a draft. The addressee is not named; the text is written on the back of another document (our text no. 49), and the entries are all different and far from complete. I have in most instances refrained from resolving the abbreviated proüper names when there was more than one possibility.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Department of Special Collections; Memorial Library; Madison; Wisconsin</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: recto (P.Wisc. II 49) - verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Lond. inv. 2214</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 23 x 11.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">A medium-brown papyrus, regularly cutoff at the top and the right-hand side. Traces of a preceding column are still visible at the left-hand side.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">P.Wisc. inv. 51: 16 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>P.Wisc. inv. 51 + P.Lond. inv. 2214: The text runs along the fibers. There is a margin of 3 cm at the top and the left-hand side.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0150" notAfter="0250">(late) IInd/(early) IIIrd century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kleochares</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hyginos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apion, son of Dion( ) and Isidora, also known as Herais, grandson of Herakleides</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius Cassius Apollinarius, also known as Sarapinus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Panechrotes, son of Harthoonis and Plutarche, grandson of Dion( ) also known as Amois</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Sarap( ) and Bibia, grandson of Did( )</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides, son of Apol( ) and Heraklios, grandson of Herakleides</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Theon, son of Horion and Saraeus, grandson of Pek( )</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Justus, also known  as Herakleides, son of Theoxenos, grandson of Alexander</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapammon, son of Chaere( ), grandson of herodes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Theon, son of Sarap( ) and Eirenos, grandson of Panechotes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">NN, son of Sareious and Tauris, grandson of theo( )</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">N.N., son of Herakleides and N.N., grandson of Ptol( )</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">N.N., son of N.N. and Thermo( )</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">N.N., son of N.N. and Taaph( )</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">N.N., son of Indicus and Taaph( )</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">N.N., son of Harpse( ) also known as Kerdo( )</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">N.N., son of N.N. and N.N., daughter of Theo( ), grandson of N.N.(?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">N.N., son of Auctus also known as Capiton, grandson of Papontos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">N.N., son of N.N. and Thae( ), grandson of Thrac( )</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petsiris, son of Tekous</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">N.N. also known as Pisois, son of Neil( ) and Harseis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hareotes, son of Pausi( ) and Nemesous</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">N.N., son of Totoes and Thatres, grandson of Ammo( )</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Panetbeus, son of Anto( )</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">N.N., son of Theo( )</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">N.N., son of Lysas and Thae( )</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Translation of both P.Lond. inv. 2214 + P.Wisc. inv. 51;From Herakleides, town-clerk of Oxyrhynchos. In response to your reüquest for names (of persons) to supervise the irrigation, I present the following propertied nominees, viz.: Upper Toparchy: Hyginos, freedman of Kleochares, son of Herakleides, aged 59, possessing property worth 1 taülent. Apion, son of Dion( ) and Isidora also known as Herais, grandson of Heracleides, aged 22, possessing property worth 3.000 drachmas. Western Toparchy: Gaius Cas(s)ius Apol(1)inarius also known as Sarapinos, aged 23, possessing property worth 1 talent. Panechotes, son of Harthoonis and Plutarche, grandson of Dion( ) also known as Amois, aged 49, possessing property worth 3.000 drachmas. Eastern Toparchy: Sarapion, son of Hierax, possessing property worth 4.000 drachmas. Dionysius, son of Sarap( ) and Bibia, grandson of Did( ), aged 46, possessing property worth 3.000 drachümas. Middle Toparchy: Herakleides, son of Apol( ) and Heraklous, grandson of Heracleides, possessing property worth 1 talent. Theon, son of Horion and Saraeus, grandson of Pek( ), possessing property worth 1 talent. Thmoisepho Toparchy: Justus also known as Heracleides, son of Theoxenos, grandüson of Alexander, possessing property worth 4.000 drachmas. Sarapam(m)on, son of Chaere( ), grandson of Herodes, possessing property worth 4.000 drachmas. Lower Toparchy: Theon, son of Sarap( ) and Eirenus, grandson of Panechotes, possessing property worth 1 talent. N.N., son of Sareius and Tauris, grandson of Theo( ), possessing property worth 4.500 drachmas. Year 6, Phaophi 18. Phobou: N.N., son of Herakleides and N.N., grandson of Ptol( ), aged 23, possessing property worth 5.000 drachmas. N.N., son of N.N. and Thermo( ) of Oxyrhynchos, [(now) living in] Phobou, nearly 31 years old, possessing property worth 5.100 drachmas. N.N., son of N.N. and Taaph( ), possessing property worth 5.100 drachmas. N.N., son of Indicus and Taaph( ), possessing property worth 5.000 drachmas. N.N., son of Harpse( ) also known as Kerdo( ) and N.N., possessing property worth 5.100 drachmas. N.N., son of N.N. and N.N., daughter of Theo( ), grandson of N.N.(?), aged 29, possessing property worth 5100 drachmas N.N., son of Auctus also known as Capiton, grandson of Papontos, possessing 40 property worth 5.000 drachmas. N.N., son of N.N. and Thae( ), grandson of Thrac( ), aged 57, possessing property worth 5.000 drachmas. Tychis Nekotis: Petsiris, son of Tekous, possessing property worth 5.000 drachmas. N.N. also known as Pisois, son of Neil( ) and Harseis of Oxyrhynchos (now) living in Tychis Nekotis, possessing property worth 5.000 drachmas. ---: Hareotes, son of Pausi( ) and Nemesous, possessing property worth 5.000 drachmas. N.N., son of Totoes and Thatres, grandson of Ammo( ), possessing property worth 5.000 drachmas. ---: Panetbeus, son of Anto( ), possessing property worth 5.000 drachmas. N.N., son of Theo( ) of Oxyrhynchos, possessing property worth 200 drachmas. N.N., son of Lysas and Thae( ), possessing property worth 200 drachmas.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Lewis N , P.Leit., no 2, 1963 -- VIII 10193 Sijpesteijn PJ , P.Wisc. II, 85, 1977, Plate XL</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Wisc.:2:85</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5449&amp;viewid=W51V.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/5/1/v/w51v.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5449&amp;viewid=W51V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5449&amp;viewid=W51V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
