<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Declaration to the property-register office</title>
            <author>Isarous, daughter of Apollonios, granddaugher of Eudaimon, her mother being Akousous alias Tamysthe, daughter of Asklepiades</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">wisconsin.apis.5363</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(WU)5363</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.wisc.2.54</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0226;2;54</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.wisc;2;54</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">13718</idno>
            <idno type="TM">13718</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Wisc. inv. 17</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>The papyrus is a declaration, written on June 3, A.D. 116 and registered on June 27. It is direceted to the keepers of the "bibliotheke egkteseon" (property-register office) of the Arsinoite nome, to the efefct that Isarous has given her slave Sarapias to another woman, whose name has been lost (line 130, as a security for a loan of 456 drachmas which she has received from this woman. The papyrus has been crossed out (invalidated), thus making the document null and void. We may assume that Isarous only bregistered her slave because she had to give her as a security for a loan.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Department of Special Collections; Memorial Library; Madison; Wisconsin</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: recto; verso preserves traces of ink (no letters)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 21.7 x 10.9 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">A light-brown papyrus, regularly cut off at all sides.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">32 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>There is a left margin of c. 1.5 cm, one at the top of c. 1 cm and one at the bottom of c. 2 cm. The text runs along the fibers. Four vertical folds are still visible.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0116">June27, 116 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Arsinoe, capital of the Arsinoite nome, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Isarous, daughter of Apollonios, son of Eudaimon, and of Akousous alias Tamysthe, daughter of Asklepiades</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Signed by me, NN, 19th year of Traianus Optimus Caesar the lord, the 3rd of Epeiph. (2nd hand) ToThrakidas and Herakleides, also called Demetrios, ex-gymnasiarchs, keepers of the property-registers of the Arsinoite nome, from Isarous, daughter of Apollonios, granddaugher of Eudaimon, my mother being Akousous alias Tamysthe, daughter of Asklepiades, registered in teh quarter of the Bithynians and Neighboorhood with as guardian Eudaimon, my brother on both father's and mother's side. I want voluntarily and on my own free will to mortgage my slave Sarapias, wo I Have registered to-day through you, to NN, daughter of Souchion, also called Eumelos, for the capital sum of fourhundred and fifty-six silver drachmas and the interest which I owe her in accordance with a title-deed and I do not want you to cooperate with me in anything whatsoever until I bring forward the receipts of the payment of everything. (3rd hand) I, Isarous, daughter of Apollonios, with as gurdain my brother Eudaimon, son of Apollonios, have presented this voluntary memorandum of mortgage of my slave Sarapias for the capital sum of fourhundred and fifty isx silver drachmas and the interest as stated above. I, Eudaimon, have written the larger part. Year 19 of Imperator Caesar Nerva Traianus Optimus Augustus Germanicus Dacicus Parthicus, the 9th of Payni. (4th hand) I, Isarous, daughter of Apollonios, have presented the mortgage as stated above.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn PJ , PWisc II, 54, 1977, Plate XV</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Wisc.:2:54</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5363&amp;viewid=W17R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/1/7/r/w17r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5363&amp;viewid=W17R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5363&amp;viewid=W17R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/1/7/v/w17v.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5363&amp;viewid=W17V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5363&amp;viewid=W17V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
