<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of a house</title>
            <author>Aurelius Titus Valerius Gaeanus, son of Titus Valerius Satrianus, also called Serenus, and Iulia</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">wisconsin.apis.5418</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(WU)5418</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.wisc.2.59</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">13722</idno>
            <idno type="TM">13722</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.wisc;2;59dupl</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Wisc. inv. 66</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>This and P.Wisc. inv.66a (= P.Wisc. II 58) are copies of a contract of sale of a small building, formelly a mill (the present ppayrus has some divergences from the text of the other copy). Titus Valerius Gaenus sells it to Aurelia Tapaeis and at the same time he cedes his rights to the products Aurelia Tapaeis may get out of the exploitation of the house. P.Mich. inv. 197 (= P.Mich. XII 627) records a later stage in the same transaction. It is reauest by Aurelia Tapaeis to the "bibliotheke egkteseon" of the Arsinoite noem to enter a provisional registartion to ensure the priority of her claims.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Department of Special Collections; Memorial Library; Madison; Wisconsin</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: recto; verso is blank</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 22.2 x 19.6 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">A medium-brown papyrus with dark blots, regularly cut off at the bottom and partly so at the left-hand side. The papyrus is regularly broken off at the right-hand side.  As this papyrus is more damaged than the preceding one, it must have been on top of the other.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">23 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: b; recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>At the left there is a margin of 3 cm,  while at the bottom 2.5 cm. The text runs along the fibers on both sides. Four vertical and eigth horizontal (new-made?) folds are still visible.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0298">April 4, 298 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Ptolemais Euergetis, meris of Herakleides, Arsinoite nome, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Caesar Gaius Aurelius Valerius Diocletianus, emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Caesar Marcus Aurelius Valerius Maximianus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Flavius Valerius Maximianus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ancius Faustus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Virius Gallus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Titus Valerius Gaeanus, son of Titus Valerius Satrianus, also called Serenus and Iulia</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelia Tapaeis, daughter of Papnuthis and Thaeisa</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Heron, son of Aphiconius</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Plution</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Philadelphia, meris of Herakleides, Arsinoite nome, Egypt;;Ptolemais Euergetis, Arsinoite nome, Egypt</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Year 14 of Imperator Caesar Gaius Aurelius Valerius Diocletianus and year 13 of Imperator Caesar Marcus Aurelius Valerius Maximianus Pii Felices Augusti and year 6 of our lords Flavius Valerius Maximianus the most illustrius Caesars in the consulship of Ancius Faustus and Virius Gallus, Pharmouthi 10 in Ptolemais Euergetis of the Arsinoite nome. Aurelius Titus Valerius Gaeanus, son of Titus Valerius Satrianus, also called Serenus, and Iulia, Antinoite and however he is styled about 55 years old, with a scar --- acknowledges having sold to Aurelia Tapaeis, daughter of Papnuthis and Thaeisa, from the village of Philadelphia of the division of Herakleides, acting without a guardian in accordance with the customs of the Romans in virtue of the ius liberorum he, Titus Valerius Gaeanus, the party of the first part, to her in accordance with the agreement and through the property record office from now on for ever a house of one storey formerly a mill in which there is a dilapidated yard that belongs to him located in the same village of Philadelphia the house itself and what is around it with the measurements, cubits, foundations, walls, windows, entrances, exits of the same house and with all the appurtenances and all the rights as they are customary from of old up till now. The neighbours are, as they themselves dicated by mutual agreement, on the south and on the west ---, on the north the house of Arion, son of Sarapion, on the east the public street and he, the party of the first part, Titus Valerius Gaeanus --- has received from Tapaeis the entire price agreed upon, in full, three thousand silver drachmas, total 3.000 dr., forthwith from hand to hand; and both he, the party of the first part, and his representatives will guarantee to Tapaeis and her representatives the house sold to her as stated above with full guarantees and he will deliver the property unencumbered, unpledged, not offered as a collateral security, free from any debts, both public and private, and from any claims continually and he will see to it that no one hinders Tapaeis or her representatives from exercising ownership over the same and he, the party of first part, has not only sold the building but also the right to bring to her own place all that proceeds from it from now on and she has the right to exercise ownership and to manage it however she chooses on condition that neither he, the party of the first part, nor anyone else on his account will in no way whatsoever proceeds against it or claims it at his own costs and he will in addition forfeit the price increased by one half and the costs double and nevertheless the above stated will be valid. In answer to the question concerning this whether it is rightly and fairly done he has given his consent. (2nd hand) I, Titus Valerius Gaeanus acknowledge having sold to Aurelia Tapaeis the house that belongs to me in the village of Philadelphia in which there is a yard --- and I will deliver it free as above stated. (3rd hand) I, Aurelia Tapaeis and however I am styled, have received the deed of sale. I, Aurelius Heron, son of Aphiconius, have written it for her because she is illiterate. (4th hand) I, Aurelius Horion, senator and archivist of the land registry office of the Arsinoite nome through me, Aurelius Plution and however I am styled, have registered it as stated above.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn PJ , PWisc II, 59, 1977, Plate XIX -- BL VII, 281 (line 22); BL VIII, 512 (line 3); BL X, 284 (lines 5, 16); BL XI, 290 (lines 9, 14-15, 17, 20-21); For P.Wisc. II 59 see also BL XI, 290 (lines 10, 15, 18, 20-21) Boswinkel - Sijpesteijn, Greek Papyri, Pl. 32</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Wisc.:2:59</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5418&amp;viewid=W66BR.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/6/b/r/w66br.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5418&amp;viewid=W66BR.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5418&amp;viewid=W66BR.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
