<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Petition to an Assistant of the Imperial Procurator</title>
            <author>Ptolemaios son of Diodoros alias Dioskoros</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">wisconsin.apis.5410</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(WU)5410</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.wisc.1.34</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">13710</idno>
            <idno type="TM">13710</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.wisc;1;34dupl</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Wisc. inv. 37</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Ptolemaios, the leaseholder of the plot of land bearing various kinds of brushwood, had up to 7th Hathyr, not received sufficient water for his drymos. Consequently he wrote a letter on this matter to Aelius Heraclitus (the name Aelius would seem to indicate that he or his father was imperial freedman), the assistant of procurator usiacus, to inform him of the situation and to obtain his co-operation to prevail upon the aigialophlax, who is, among other things, charged with the distribution and supply of water, that he will still receive the usual amount of water and secure compensation in case of damage.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Department of Special Collections; Memorial Library; Madison; Wisconsin</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; traces of washed-off text are visible on the verso side</note>
                     <note type="related">+P.Wisc. inv. 38</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 14.7 x 28 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">A middle-brown papyrus, cut off regularly at the top and right-hand side and partially at the bottom and left-hand side. At the top there is a margin of 2.5 cm., at the left one of 1 cm., and at the bottom one of 2.5 cm. Damage has occurred especially at the folds (1 horizontal and 8 vertical).</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">16 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The text runs parallel to the fibers. Traces of a washed-off text, running against the fibers, are visible on the verso side. The first hand, writing large letters and leaving a wide space between the lines, is well-trained and makes his lines, which slope down towards the right, reach up to the very edge. The second hand, writing small letters close together and bespeaking great skill, does not endeavor to make his lines, which slope upwards towards the right, run up to the edge.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0144">November 3, 144 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Theadelphia, Themistou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Aelius Heraclitus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ailius Aclectus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Diodoros, alias Dioskoros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonius</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Theadelphia</term>
               <term>Petition</term>
               <term>Leaseholder</term>
               <term>Plot of land</term>
               <term>Brushwood</term>
               <term>Water</term>
               <term>Freedman</term>
               <term>Procurator usiacus</term>
               <term>Aigialophlax.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>To Aelius Heraclitus, assistant of Ailius Aclectus, procurator of Caesar the lord, from Ptolemaios, son of Diodoros, alias Dioskoros, leaseholder of the brushwood of the village of Theadelphia. Although the usual amount of water should flow to the above-mentioned brushwood, until it is filled, it has not so far received it, but is in danger of drying out and therefore I request you to send a letter to the shore guard, that if neglect of water-supply occur and it is not filled in the usual manner, the consequence will not only be damage for next year (the brushwood has after all been leased), but it will be without yield for three years. I therefore request you, lord, to make it clear to the shore guard, in order that, if damage arises from neglect. I have remedy against him with the egregious procurator. Year 8, the 7th Hathyr.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn P.J., PWisc  I, 34, 1967, Plate XIII</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Wisc.:1:34</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5410&amp;viewid=W37R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/3/7/r/w37r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5410&amp;viewid=W37R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5410&amp;viewid=W37R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
