<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Customs account</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">wisconsin.apis.5443</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(WU)5443</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.wisc.2.80</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0226;2;80</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.wisc;2;80</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">13727</idno>
            <idno type="TM">13727</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Wisc. inv. 16</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>The Wisconsin part of this papyrus, immediately following P.Merton I 15 was originally published by NY Clauson, A Customs House Registry from Roman Egypt (P.Wisconsin 16), Aegyptus 9 (1928), 240 ff (= SB IV 7365).</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Department of Special Collections; Memorial Library; Madison; Wisconsin</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: recto; on the back there are illegible traces (washed-ot?) of writing in another hand</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Mert. I 15</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 59.9 x 21.8 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">A light-brown papyrus, regularly cut/brokenoff at all sides.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">P.Wisc. inv. 2 + P.Mert. I 15:;col. I: 34 lines; col. II 36 lines; col. III: 34 lines; col. IV: 31 lines; col. V: 32 lines; col. VI: 28 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>P.Wisc. inv. 2: The writing is along the fibers. At the top there is a margin of 1 to 1.5 cm. Below col. I there is a margin of 1 cm; below col. II, III and IV one of 3 cm and below col. V one of 4 cm. There are kollemata at 10.5 and 21 cm from the left-hand side and 4.5, 15.5 and 26 cm from the right-hand side. Several vertical  folds are still visible.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0114">October 1, 114 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Capitolinus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Abous</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Elis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apol( )</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Longinus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chratos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petech( )</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Euang( )</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ninnas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anoub( )</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Zoilas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Syros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Spartas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kainos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Panetbeis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pankrat( )</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psenamounis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Germanus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphro( )</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnos(?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Achillas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mareis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petobastis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Diosc( )</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hermias</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apias</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Konnos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpoch( )</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Epimachos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petechon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Felix</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kephal( )</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Paramon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Lampon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kollouthis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ision</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Flavios Heraklides</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chaireas, son of Chairemon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Caesar Nerva Trajanus Augustus Germanicus Dacicus, emperor</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>P.Wisc. inv. 16:;4th, Phaesis, importing lentils, 1 donkey, 4 art. at 1/2 dr. , tot. 2 ob. Phaesis, for the inspection of wool, 1 fleece, 30 bales, tot. 1/2 ob. Tot. for the day, 2 1/2 od. 5th, Horion, black beans, 2 donkeys, 8 art. at 1 _ ob. per art., tot. 2 dr. and bitter vetch, 1 donkey, 4 art. at 1/2 ob. per art., tot. 2 ob. Capitolinus, vinegar, 3 jars, at 1 dr., 1 1/2 ob. per jar, tot. 2 ob. Abous, juicy dates, 2 donkeys, 8 art. at 1 dr., 1 1/2 ob. per art., tot. 10 dr. and black beans, 1 donkey, 4 art. at 1 1/2 ob. per art., tot. 1 dr. Am(m)onios, oil, 1 donkey, 2 met. and on others 1 1/2 met. at 5 dr. per met., tot. 17 dr., 3 ob. Elis, oil, 1 donkey, 2 met. and on others 1 1/2 met. at 5 dr. per met., tot. 17 dr., 3 ob. Tot. for the day 52 dr., 1/2 ob. 6th, Apol( ), black beans, 3 donkeys, 12 art. and on another 2 art. at 1 1/2 ob. per art., tot. 3 dr., 3 ob. Longinus, on 2 donkeys, 4 chlibia of garlic at 1 dr., 1 1/2 ob per chlibion, tot. 5 dr. Chratus, black beans, 2 donkeys, 8 art. and on others 2 art. at 1 1/2 ob per art., tot. 2 dr., 3 ob. Tot. for the day, 11 dr. 7th, Petech( ), white leaves, 1 donkey, 1 dr., tot 1 dr. Euang( ), juicy dates, on a donkey, 2 art. at 1 dr., 12 ob. per art., tot. 2 dr., 3 ob. Zoil( ), black beans, 1 donkey, 4 art. at 12 ob. per art., tot. 1 dr. Ptol( ), black beans, 1 donkey, 4 art. at 12 ob. per art., tot. 1 dr. Ninnas, black beans, 1 donkey, 4 art. at 12 ob. per art., tot. 1 dr. Anoub( ), for the inspection of wool, 1 fleece, 30 bales, tot. 2 ob. Petobastis, oil, 2 donkeys, 3 met. at 5 dr. per met., tot. 15 dr. Petesis, oil, 2 donkeys, 3 met. at 5 dr. per met., tot. 15 dr. Tot. for the day, 36 dr., 32 ob. 8th, Zoilas, green olives, 2 art. at 1 dr., 12 ob. per art., tot. 2 dr., 3 ob. Chairas, juicy dates, 2 art. at 1 dr., lk ob. per art., tot. 2 dr., 3 ob. Tot. for the day, 5 dr. 9th, Potam( ), oil, 4 containers, 70 2 sacks, 5 met. on 2 donkeys at 5 dr. per met., tot. 25 dr. Elis, black beans, 2 donkeys, 8 art. and on others 2 art. at 12 ob. per art., tot. 2 dr., 3 ob. Tot. for the day, 27 dr., 3 ob. 10th, "workless day". 11th, Ptolem( ), vinegar, 1 jar, 1 dr., 1 1/2 ob. Elis, black beans, 2 donkeys, 8 art. and on another 2 art. at lk ob. per art., tot. 2 dr., 3 ob. Syrus, garlic, 1 donkey, 2 chlibia at 1 dr., 12 ob. per chlibion, tot. 2 dr. 3 ob. Spartas, garlic, 1 donkey, 2 chlibia at 1 dr., 12 ob. per chlibion, tot. 2 dr., 3 ob. Apollonius, black beans, 3 donkeys, 12 art. and on another 2 art. at 12 ob. per art., tot. 3 dr., 3 ob. Tot. for the day, 12 dr., 12 ob. 12th, "workless day". 13th, Phasis, oil, 6 containers, 4 newer (containers), 1 sack, 21 met. on 9 donkeys at 5 dr. per met., tot. 105 dr. Kephalis, oil, 2 containers, 1 half-jar, 3 met. on 1 donkey at 5 dr. per met., tot. 15 dr. Sabinos, oil, 2 sacks, 1 1/2 met. on 1 donkey at 5 dr. per met., tot. 7 dr., 3 ob. Kainos, oil, 3 containers, 6 1/2 met. on 3 donkeys at 5 dr. per met., tot. 32 dr., 3 ob. Tot. for the day, 160 dr. 14th, Panetbeis, for the inspection of wool, 3 fleeces, 10 bales, tot 1 ob. Pankrat( ), oil, 1 half-jar on 1 donkey 2 dr., 3 ob., tot. 2 dr., 3 ob. Horion, for the inspection of wool, 2 fleeces, 15 bales, tot. 1 ob. Horion, barley, 1 art., tot. k ob. Horion, black beans, 1 donkey, 4 art. at 12 ob. per art., tot. 1 dr. and for the inspection of wool, 1 fleece, 30 bales, tot. 2 ob. 100	Psenamounis, black beans, 2 art. on 1 donkey at 12 ob, per art., tot. 3 ob. Tot. for the day, 4 dr., 3 ob. 15th, Horion, vinegar, 2 jars at 1 dr., 12 ob. per jar, tot. 2 dr., 3 ob. Germanus, exporting 2 stallions with black spots branded with anchors at 13 dr., 1 ob. per horse, tot. 26 dr., 2 ob. Chrat( ), oil, 2 chous, 5 ob. Prot( ), vinegar, 2 jars at 1 dr., 12 ob. per jar, tot. 2 dr., 3 ob. Am(m)onius, oil, 2 donkeys, 32 met. at 5 dr. per met., tot. 17 dr., 3 ob. Ells, oil, 2 donkeys, 32 met. at 5 dr. per met., tot. 17 dr., 3 ob. Abous, juicy dates, 1 donkey, 4 art. at 1 dr., 12 ob. per art., tot. 5 dr. and black beans, 2 donkeys, 8 art. at 12 ob. per art., tot. 2 dr. Tot. for the day, 74 dr., 1 ob. 16th, Petesis, oil, 2 donkeys, 3 met. at 5 dr. per met., tot. 15 dr. Aphro( ), for the inspection of wool, 12 fleeces, 2 bale, tot. 5 ob. Aphro( ), green olives, 2 art. at 1 dr., 12 ob. per art., tot. 2 dr., 3 ob. Tot. for the day, 18 dr., 2 ob. 17th, Poplius, oil, 4 newer containers, 1 sack, 42 met. on 2 donkeys at 5 dr. per met., tot. 22 dr., 3 ob. Kephal( ), oil, 2 newer containers, 2 met. on 1 donkey at 5 dr. per met., tot. 10 dr. Elis, oil, 1 donkey, 12 met. at 5 dr. per met., tot. 7 dr., 3 ob. Apollonius, for the inspection of wool, 3 fleeces, 10 bales, tot. 1 ob. Onnos(?), fine salt, 1 art. on a donkey, 3 ob., tot. 3 ob. Tot. for the day, 40 dr., 4 ob. 18th, Achillas, 3 chests upholstered in leather at 2 dr. per chest, tot. 6 dr. Mareis, iron and slag, 24 mnas, tot. 3 dr., 12 ob. and bronze, eight mnas, tot. 3 dr. Amais, 130 oil, 3 donkeys, 6 met. at 5 dr. per met., tot. 30 dr. Tot. for the day, 42 dr., 1, ob. 19th, Apoll( ), vegetable seed, 1 donkey, 4 art. at 1 dr., 12 ob. per art., tot. 5 dr. Apol( ), black beans, 1 donkey, 4 art. and on another 2 art. at 12 ob. per art., tot. 1 dr., 3 ob. Petobastis, oil, 1 donkey, 12 met. at 5 dr. per met., tot. 7 dr., 3 ob. Petobastis, oil, 1 donkey, 12 met. at 5 dr. per met., tot. 7 dr., 3 ob. Maron, oil, 1 donkey, 1 met. at 5 dr. per met., tot. 5 dr. Diosc( ), black beans, 2 art. at 12 ob. per art., tot. 3 ob. Tot. for the day, 27 dr. 20th, Hermias, green dates, 1 art. at 2 ob. per art., tot. 2 ob. 21st, Apias, green dates, 1 art. at 2 ob. per art., tot. 2 ob. Konnos, green olives, 1 art., tot. 1 dr., 12 ob. Paeis, green dates, 1 donkey, 3 art. at 2 ob. per art., tot. 1 dr. Apoll( ), wild chickling, 1 donkey, 4 art. at 2 ob. per art., tot. 2 ob. Tot. for the day, 2 dr., 52 ob. 22nd, Panetbeis, 1 wheat-coloured ox, 2 dr. Petechon, white leaves, 1 donkey, tot. 1 dr. Harpoch( ), vinegar, 4 jars at 1 dr., 12 ob. a piece, tot. 5 dr. Tot. for the day, 8 dr. 23rd, Am(m)onius, importing 5 male donkeys of which 3 mouse-coloured having shed their foal-teeth and another white not having shed his foal-teeth, 1 and another white mouse-coloured, 1 having shed his foal-teeth at 13 dr., 2 ob. a piece, tot. 66 dr., 4 ob. Chairas, fresh fish, 3 donkeys at 2 dr. a donkey, tot. 6 dr. Epimachos, fresh fish, 1 donkey, tot. 2 dr. Tot. for the day, 74 dr., 4 ob. 24th, Diosc( ), importing 1 art. of wheat, tot. 2 ob. Apias, oil, 4 containers and newer (containers) 2, 2 small sacks, 14 met. on 6 donkeys at 5 dr. a piece, tot. 70 dr. Felix, oil, 2 containers, newer (containers) 4, 2 small sacks, 11 met. on 5 donkeys at 5 dr. per met., tot. 55 dr. Apol( ), for the inspection of wool, 1 fleece, 30 bales, 2 ob. Tot. for the day, 125 dr., 1 ob. 25th, Harpaesis, for the inspection of wool,5 fleeces, 6 bales, 2 ob. Apias, green dates, 2 art. on donkeys at 2 ob. per art., tot. 4 ob. Tot. for the day, 1 dr. 26th, "workless day". 27th, Lampon, green dates, 1 donkey, 3 art. at 2 ob. per art., tot. 1 dr. and leaves, 1 donkey, tot. 1 dr. Petechon, white leaves, 1 donkey, tot. 1 dr. 170 Cephal( ), salted fish, one chlibion on 1 donkey, 7 dr., 1 ob. Paramon, green dates, 2 art. at 2 ob. per art., tot. 4 ob. Tot. for the day, 10 dr., 5 ob. 28th, Horion, for the inspection of wool, 1 fleece, 30 bales, 2 ob. Pkemis, oil, 1 donkey, 12 met. at 5 dr. per met., tot. 7 dr., 3 ob. Chenas, oil, 1 donkey, 12 met. at 5 dr. per met., tot. 7 dr., 3 ob. Horion, for the inspection of wool, 3 fleeces, 10 bales, tot. 1 ob. Tot. for the day, 15 dr., 12 ob. 29th, Petesouch( ), for the inspection of wool, 1 fleece, 30 bales, 2 ob. Konnos, wild chickling, 1 donkey, 4 art. and on another 2 art. at 2 ob. per art., tot. 3 ob. Tot. for the day, 32 ob. 30th, Zoilas, firewood, 1 donkey, 1 dr. Zoilas, black beans, 2 art. on a donkey at 12 ob. per art., tot. 3 ob. Tot. for the day, 1 dr., 3 ob. Total for the month 959 dr., 32 ob. Commission for a clerk and exchange fee 8 dr., 3 ob. per mna, tot. 81 dr., 32 ob. Tot. 1041 dr., 1 ob. of which Ision and Ammonius, the Arabian archers, as salary per person 16 dr., (makes) 32 dr. Remain 1009 dr., 1 ob. which I paid to the state bank on the fourth, 4th, of the 190 present month Phaophi for the account of Thoth, audited by Colluthus, agent of Flavius Heraclides, the limenarch. I, Chaeras, son of Chaeremon, grandüson of Apollonius, swear by Imperator Caesar Nerva Trajanus Augustus Germanicus Dacicus that the above written account has correctly and truthfully been submitted and that I have made no false declaration or may I be liable to the penalties of the oath. Year 18 of Trajanus Caesar the lord, Phaophi 4.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Clauson NY , Aegyptus 9, 240-, 1928 -- IV 7365 Sijpesteijn PJ , P.Wisc. II, 80, 1977, Plate XXXV and XXXVI -- BL VII, 282 (line 149); BL Corcondance, 269 (lines 90-91 and 149); BL VIII, 513 (lines 67 and 144); BL IX (lines 12, 30, 31, 84, 154);</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Wisc.:2:80</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5443&amp;viewid=W16RO.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/6/r/o/w16ro.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5443&amp;viewid=W16RO.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5443&amp;viewid=W16RO.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
