<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Petition to dekaprotoi</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">wisconsin.apis.5450</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(WU)5450</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.wisc.2.86</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">13729</idno>
            <idno type="TM">13729</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.wisc;2;86</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Wisc. inv. 56</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Department of Special Collections; Memorial Library; Madison; Wisconsin</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: recto; verso is blank</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 21.1 x 16.7 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">A light-brown papyrus, regularly cutoff at all sides. The papyrus is riddled with holes.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">36 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Top margin is 1 cm; left-hand side margin is 2 cm. Between lines 33 and 34 is a free space of 2 cm.  The text runs along the fibers. Five vertical folds are still visible.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0245" notAfter="0247">May 26 - June 24, 245, 246 or 247 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Philadelphia, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Valerius Diogenes, son of Lucretius</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Valerius Longinus, son of Lucretius</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Valerius Clementinus, son of Lucretius,</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harsous</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Claudius Marcellus, vir perfectissimus, rationalis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marcius Salutarius, vir egregius, procurator Augustorum</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Caesar Marcus Julius Philippus Pius Felix, emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marcus Julius Philippus most noble and renowed, emperor</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Second toparchy, division of Herakleides;Philadelphia, herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, Egypt</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>To the dekaprotoi of the 2nd toparchy of the division of Herakleides from (2nd hand) Valerius Diogenes, Valerius Longinus and Valerius Clementinus, all sons of Lucretius, Antinoites. We own in the vicinity of the village of Philadelphia, in sect. 4 eight and a half arouras of grain-producing land under seed, in sect. 5 four and a half arouras of unwatered land, in sect. 7 seven arouras of unwatered land, and ten orchard arouras partly dead, in sect. 14 likewise seven orchard arouras, three of which have been cut over, in Sect. 20 six and a half orchard arouras and two totally cut over arouras. But the village registrar, possibly through error, assessed us in the posted list of individual taxpayers with the following: in Sect. 4 a total of nine and five-eighths arouras under seed, adding an aroura and an eighth, in Sect. 5 a total of six arouras of unwatered land, adding an aroura and a half, in Sect. 7 a total of 15 1/2 arouras of unwatered land and eleven and a half orüchard arouras, adding eight and a half arouras of unwatered land and one and a half orchard arouras, in Sect. 14 in our names and in that of our maternal grandmother, Harsous, a total of ten and seventeen thirty-seconds orchard arouras, adding three and seventeen thirty-seconds arouras, in Sect. 20 in the same names twenty-three and a half orchard arouras, adding fifteen arouüras, and subtracting three and a half arouras from the seven arouras of unüwatered grain-producing land which we have in the same section. Wherefore, the wrong being not slight, we submit this petition, attesting in accordance with the orders given by Claudius Marcellus, vir perfectissimus, rationalis, and Marcius Salutarius, vir egregius, procurator Augustorum, and we ask that the registrar and boundary-fixer be present with you when you come for a perüsonal inspection, and that they make an accurate measurement so that, when the false registration against us has become evident, there may be no controüversy with you over taxes on what he assessed in excess, our right of posüsession thus preserved. Farewell. (3rd H.) I, Valerius Longinus, have subümitted (this petition). (4th H.) I, Valerius Clementinus, have joined in subümitting (this petition). (5th H.) I, Valerius Diogenes, have joined in subümitting (this petition). (2nd H.) Year [.] of the Emperor Caesar Marcus Julius Philippus Pius Felix and Marcus Julius Philippus most noble and renowed Caesar Augusti, Payni [</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boswinkel - Sijpesteijn, Greek Papyri, pl. 30 Lewis N , P.Leit., no 16, 1963 -- SB VIII 10208 Sijpesteijn PJ , P.Wisc. II, 86, 1977, Plate XLI -- BL IX, 375 (for Marcius Salutarius, lines 24-25); BL X, 284 (dating)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Wisc.:2: 86</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5450&amp;viewid=W56R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/5/6/r/w56r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5450&amp;viewid=W56R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5450&amp;viewid=W56R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
