<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter from the Assistant to an Aigialophlax</title>
            <author>Aelius Heraclitus</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">wisconsin.apis.5464</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(WU)5464</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.wisc.1.34</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Wisc. inv. 37</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Ptolemaios, the leaseholder of the plot of land bearing various kinds of brushwood, had up to 7th Hathyr, not received sufficient water for his drymos. Consequently he wrote a letter on this matter to Aelius Heraclitus (the name Aelius would seem to indicate that he or his father was imperial freedman), the assistant of procurator usiacus, to inform him of the situation and to obtain his co-operation to prevail upon the aigialophlax, who is, among other things, charged with the distribution and supply of water, that he will still receive the usual amount of water and secure compensation in case of damage.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Department of Special Collections; Memorial Library; Madison; Wisconsin</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; traces of washed-off text are visible on the verso side</note>
                     <note type="related">+P.Wisc. inv. 38</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 14.7 x 28 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">A middle-brown papyrus, cut off regularly at the top and right-hand side and partially at the bottom and left-hand side. At the top there is a margin of 2.5 cm., at the left one of 1 cm., and at the bottom one of 2.5 cm. Damage has occurred especially at the folds (1 horizontal and 8 vertical).</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">12 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The text runs parallel to the fibers. Traces of a washed-off text, running against the fibers, are visible on the verso side. The first hand, writing large letters and leaving a wide space between the lines, is well-trained and makes his lines, which slope down towards the right, reach up to the very edge. The second hand, writing small letters close together and bespeaking great skill, does not endeavor to make his lines, which slope upwards towards the right, run up to the edge.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0144">November 3, 144 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Theadelphia, Themistou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Aelius Heraclitus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonius</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Leaseholder</term>
               <term>Plot of land</term>
               <term>Brushwood</term>
               <term>Water for his Drymos</term>
               <term>Letter</term>
               <term>Imperial freedman</term>
               <term>Assistant</term>
               <term>Procurator usiacus</term>
               <term>Aigialophlax</term>
               <term>Secure compensation.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Aelius Heraclitus to Apollonius, shore guard, my most beloved, greetings. I had not expected that a petition would reach me concerning the brushwood for you to supply the adequate amount of water as Ptolemaios, the leaseholder thereof has requested me. It fell to your care, did it not, before he requested, to see to this as well. If up to now anything has acted impedingly or anything else of the things which seemed to you to be more urgent, caused delay in filling the brushwood, then see now to it, brother that the usual amount of water is supplied to it. I pray that you are inn good health, my most beloved. Year 8 of Antoninus, the 7th Hathyr.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn P.J., PWisc  I, 34, 1967, Plate XIII</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Wisc.:1:34</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5464&amp;viewid=1">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
