<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sworn Declaration to Agents from the Centurion Cattius Catullus:  P.Col. inv. 90</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p516</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa3692</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.thomas.5.</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">44491</idno>
            <idno type="TM">44491</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.thomas;;5</idno>
            <idno type="filename">44491-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col. inv. 90</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:24.589918-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(m. 1) Psonsneus, about 38 years, medium height, honey-complexioned, long-faced straight-nosed, with a scar beneath the right knee. (m. 2) Psonsneus, son of Praxias, of those from Philadelphia of the Herakleides division of the Arsinoite nome, to agents from Cattius Catullus, centurion. I swear by Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator that I willingly have become surety for Praxias, son of Diodorus, my father, and Thaesis, daughter of Anoubion, my mother, whom I shall also present to Nemesion, praktor of the same village in the public logisterion of Herakleides (division) in the twenty-five days from the present day.  If I do not present them, I shall pay their debts with interest to the public (bank).  To me swearing honestly, may it be well, but to me forswearing, the opposite.  I, Nikanor, son of Nikanor, wrote for him when asked because he says he does not know letters.  Year 6 of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, Epeiph thirtieth.  (m. 3) Dositheos, I have signed. Year 6 of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, Epeiph thirtieth.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Thomas 5</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
