<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Antichretic loan with right of habitation in lieu of interest</title>
            <author>Unknown (lost)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3899</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3899</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.thomas.4</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0258;;4</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.thomas;;4</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">44492</idno>
            <idno type="TM">44492</idno>
            <idno type="filename">44492-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich. inv. 96</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.83986-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Year ... of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, Germanikeios 28, in Tebtynis of the district Polemon of the Arsinoite nome.;... son of -eris/-ereus, Persian of the epigone, about ... years old, with a mark, a wart, on the right side of his nose, declares to Thases daughter of ..., about forty-eight years old, with a mark ..., with as kyrios her brother on her father's and mother's side Paopis, about thirty-... years old, with a mark on his right shin, to have received from her at once, from hand to hand, on the spot ...-six/sixteen silver drachmas, that instead of the interest on these the declarant has granted Thases and her representatives and whoever she wants the right to inhabit for ... years from the present time the pastophorion which he himself holds by virtue of a contract (?) of lease from Thaubastis daughter of -pis and Marepsemis son of Marepkemis within the inner enclosure wall of the temple of the god Kronos in the above-mentioned village Tebtynis, and that the declared and his representatives will guarantee for Thases and her representatives all which pertains to this contract of lease for the duration agreed upon ...</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>van Minnen P, PThomas, 87-89, no 4, 2001, Plate 6</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
