<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Settling of accounts</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">oxford-ipap.apis.237</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(EG-CaMus)237</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.cair.masp.2.67156</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">JE40900</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Settling of accounts between Aur. Tekrompia,  anthylopratissa, and Aur. Maria her daughter. Since the death of her husband, the first named has worked and managed the fortune alone. The elder of the children, Mary, being at present married, claims her part of her father's legacy. Recapitulating receipts and expenses, the estate finds itself in deficit of 8 nomismata less 48 keratia. Mary claims from her mother the payment of a rent (1 nomisma less 6 keratia), for the part which comes to her - that is to say a quarter - of two houses previously belonging to her father and apparently occupied by the widow. In response, the widow demands of her daughter the payment of a quarter of the common debt of 8 n. less 48 k. Following the agreement they have concluded, Mary will not make this payment until after the death of her mother; she will pay her part of the debt to the estate, and undertakes to claim nothing from the moveable goods or furniture, at the beginning of this inheritance, having already received her part. She renounces even all claims on the goods which her mother might acquire, after the contract. For her, there remains only her right to the fourth part of the aforesaid houses, whose rent, while waiting, shall be paid to her each year by Aur. Tekrompia. Belongs to the archive of Dioscoros.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="local_note">CG67156</note>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 31 x 50.7</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0570">AD 570</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Antinoopolis</origPlace>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Cair.Masp. 2 67156</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Cair.Masp.:2:67156</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://ipap.csad.ox.ac.uk/4DLink4/4DACTION/IPAPwebquery?vPub=P.Cair.Masp.&amp;vVol=2&amp;vNum=67156&amp;vSide=">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
