<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml" ?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hgv1">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>...</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <idno type="filename">0000000000043636.xml</idno>
        <idno type="biblio">0000000000043636</idno>
        <idno type="bp">09/4/212</idno>
        <idno type="isbn">978-0-674-02595-0</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl type="monograph" subtype="ISBN-Solo"/>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <p>This file encoded to comply with EpiDoc Guidelines and Schema version 8
                <ref>http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/gl/5/</ref>
         </p>
    </encodingDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change who="BP" when="2011-06-14">Record created</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="bibliography">
        <bibl>
          <title level="m" type="main">Greetings in the Lord. Early Christians and the Oxyrhynchus Papyri. (Harvard Theological Studies. 60.)</title>
          <author n="1">
            <surname>LUIJENDIJK</surname>
            <forename>AnneMarie</forename>
          </author>
          <publisher>
            <placeName>Cambridge, Mass.</placeName>
            <orgName>Harvard University Press</orgName>
          </publisher>
          <date>2008</date>
          <edition>8°</edition>
          <biblScope type="pageCount">294</biblScope>
          <biblScope type="prefacePageCount">xix</biblScope>
          <biblScope type="illustration">6 pll.</biblScope>
          <note type="annotation">Diss. Harvard Divinity School, 2005. - 1. Destination Oxyrhynchus: Historical detective work in the footsteps of monks and papyrologists. - Part one. Meeting Christians at the marketplace: 2. How do you know a Christian when you see one? God, Christian, and personal names; - 3. What's in a Nomen? Recognizing Christians through nomina sacra. - Part two. Papa Sotas, bishop of Oxyrhynchus: 4. &amp;quot;Beloved Papa Sotas&amp;quot;: Recommendation, networking, and Christian education; - 5. The business of the bishop: Fundraising, travel, and book production. - Part three. Legal matters and government dealings: 6. Searching for Christians in official papers: Certificates of sacrifice, summons, and property confiscations; - 7. Subversion and resistance during the Great Persecution: From countryside church to Alexandrian courtroom; - 8. Early Christians in the Oxyrhynchus papyri: New voices in ancient history. - Bibliography. Indexes.</note>
        </bibl>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
