<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml" ?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="hgv1">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>...</title>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <idno type="filename">0000000000043516.xml</idno>
        <idno type="biblio">0000000000043516</idno>
        <idno type="bp">09/4/092</idno>
        <idno type="isbn">978-0-471-71933-5</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <bibl type="monograph" subtype="ISBN"/>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
      <p>This file encoded to comply with EpiDoc Guidelines and Schema version 8
                <ref>http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/gl/5/</ref>
         </p>
    </encodingDesc>
    <revisionDesc>
      <change who="BP" when="2011-06-07">Record created</change>
    </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div type="bibliography">
        <bibl>
          <title level="a" type="main">Cleopatra's Kidnappers: How Caesar's Sixth Legion Gave Egypt to Rome and Rome to Caesar.</title>
          <author n="1">
            <surname>DANDO-COLLINS</surname>
            <forename>Stephen</forename>
          </author>
          <date>2005</date>
          <edition>8°</edition>
          <biblScope type="pageCount">286</biblScope>
          <biblScope type="prefacePageCount">xviii</biblScope>
          <biblScope type="illustration">3 cartes.</biblScope>
          <note type="annotation">Introduction. - I. Last Stand in Alexandria. - II. Trapped. - III. According to Brutus. - IV. The Deal. - V. Cleopatra's War. - VI. Mark Antony, Ruler of Rome. - VII. Sailing into History. - VIII. Egyptian Resistance. - IX. The Kidnap. - X. Caesar’s Baby. - XI. Defeat and Castration. - XII. Reinforcements. - XIII. Taking the Island. - XIV. Releasing the King. - XV. The Relief Column. - XVI. Battle on the Nile. - XVII. To the Victor, the Spoils. - XVIII. Going after Pharnaces. - XIX. The Chariots of Zela. - XX. The Roman Triumphs of the 6th. - XXI. One Last Battle. - XXII. Porcia's Secret. - XXIII. After the Murder. - XXIV. The Wolf's Twins. - XXV. The Imperial 6ths. - Appendix A: Republican Roman Military Ranks, First Century B.C., and Their Modern-Day Equivalents; - Appendix B: Imperial Postings of the Two 6th Legions; - Appendix C: Sources. - Glossary. Index.</note>
        </bibl>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
