<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>List, Roman CE 222</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">yale.apis.4400124200</idno>
            <idno type="controlno">(CtY)DP 12(B) fol</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invno">P.CtYBR inv.DP 12(B) fol</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Roster of centuries, turmae, dromedarii</summary>
                  <msItem>
                     <textLang mainLang="la">Latin</textLang>
                  </msItem>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>15 frames.Frame 12:1: 2 cols., (in mm) (col. i): 130 x 228, 11 lines, no margins, (col. ii): fragments (a)-(j), (a) 52 x 32, 8 lines, no margins, (b) 32 x 21, blank, (c) 35 x 19, offset, (d) 37 x 24, traces (?), (e) 45 x 27, blank, (f) 55 x 28, 7 lines, (g) 39 x 34, 4 lines (?), no margins, (h) 44 x 46, 5 lines, no margins, (i) 45 x 27, blank, (j) 38 x 7, blankFrame 12:2: fragments of a roll, height 241 mm, 5 cols., top marginFrame 12:3: fragments of roll, height 241 mm, 5 cols., top marginFrame 12:4: fragments of roll, height 236 mm, 4 cols., top marginFrame 12:5: fragments of roll, height 222 mm, 4 cols., upside down (?)Frame 12:6: fragments of roll, height 218 mm, 4 cols., (col. i): 13 lines, left margin, (col. ii) 24 lines, bottom right margins, (col. iii): 29 lines, bottom margin, (col. iv): traces of right columnFrame 12:7: fragments of roll, height 202 mm, 3 cols., (col. i): 24 lines, bottom margin, (col. ii): 24 lines, left bottom margins, (col. iii): 10 lines, left marginFrame 12:8: roll, 2 cols., (col. i): 23 lines (?), bottom left right margins, (col. ii): 26 lines, bottom left right marginsFrame 12:9: roll, height 249 mm, 2 cols., (col. i): 26 lines, bottom left right margins, (col. ii) 29 lines, bottom left right marginsFrame 12:10: roll, height 256 mm, 3 cols., (col. i): 26 lines, bottom left right margins, (col. ii): 26 bottom left right margins, (col. iii): 31 lines, bottom left right marginsFrame 12:11: roll, height 256 mm, 3 cols., (col. i):29 lines, all margins, (col. ii): 30 lines, all margins, (col. iii): 23 lines, all marginsFrame 12:12: roll, height 256 mm, 3 cols., (col. i): all margins, 29 lines, all margins, (col. ii): 24 lines, all margins, (col. iii): 28 lines, left bottom right marginsFrame 12:13: height 255 mm, 3 cols., 31 lines, left right margins, (col. ii): 29 lines, left right bottom margins, (col. iii): 26 lines, left right marginsFrame 12:14: fragments of roll, height 256 mm, 3 cols., (col. i): 25 lines, left right bottom margins, (col. ii): 25 lines, all margins, (col. iii) 12 lines, left right bottom marginsFrame 12:15: fragments (a)-(z) (in mm), (a) 20 x 79, traces, (b) 14 x 38, 2 lines, no margins, (c) 23 x 18, traces, (d) 37 x 21, traces, (e) 9 x 32, traces, (f) 16 x 23, blank, (g) 29 x 19, traces, (h) 44 x 8, 3 lines (?), no margins, (i) 23 x 131, 3 lines, no margins, (j) 41 x 112, 3 lines, no margins, (k) 25 x 39, blank, (l) 48 x 57, 3 lines (?), no margins, (m) 28 x 23, blank, (n) 31 x 22, blank, (o) 26 x 29, traces, (p) 51 x 38, blank, (q) 36 x 32, blank, (r) 45 x 24, blank, (s) 39 x 28, blank, (t) 39 x 79, 4 lines, no margins, (u) 8 x 109, 2 lines, (v) 6 x 160, traces, (w) 21 x 27, blank, (x) 13 x 13, 3 lines, blank, (y) 12 x 6, blank, (z) 18 x 263, 2 lines, no margins</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0222"/>
                     <origPlace>Dura-Europos</origPlace>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>
                  <rs type="genre_form">Papyri</rs>
               </term>
               <term>
                  <rs type="genre_form">List</rs>
               </term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Dura 101Rom.Mil.Rec. 2Ch.L.A. VIII 356 <note>P.Dura, pp. 339-364, pl. xlvDavies 1968: 32Rom.Mil.Rec.: PP. 52-81Ch.L.A. VIII: pp. 50-84, pls. 51, 52, 53, 54, 57, 59, 60, 61, 63, 65, 66, 67, 69, 71, 72, 75, 79, 81, 83</note>
               </bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>[DP 12:1 Folio (B)]</head>
               <figDesc> thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://brbl-svr1.library.yale.edu/papyrimg/T4183646.JPG"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>[DP 12:1 Folio (B)]</head>
               <figDesc> Screen</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://brbl-svr1.library.yale.edu/papyrimg/S4183646.JPG"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>[DP 12:1 Folio (B)]</head>
               <figDesc> Zoom</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://brbl-svr1.library.yale.edu/papyrimg/Z4183646.JPG"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>[DP 12:2 Folio (B)]</head>
               <figDesc> thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://brbl-svr1.library.yale.edu/papyrimg/T4183648.JPG"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>[DP 12:2 Folio (B)]</head>
               <figDesc> Screen</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://brbl-svr1.library.yale.edu/papyrimg/S4183648.JPG"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>[DP 12:2 Folio (B)]</head>
               <figDesc> Zoom</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://brbl-svr1.library.yale.edu/papyrimg/Z4183648.JPG"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>