<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>copy of receipt</title>
            <author>Heraklas alias Herakleon, son of Archelaos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1341</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1341</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.16.13003</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;16;13003</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;16;13003</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">16343</idno>
            <idno type="TM">16343</idno>
            <idno type="filename">16343-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1230</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.21977-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>"Heraclas alias Heracleon, son of Archelaos, from . . . of the city of Oxyrhynchus, to Ammonios, son of Sarap[   ] . . . alias Zeneios, greetings. I have attached this copy of the receipt for the payment of the fine related to the 1/4 of an aroura of the property cultivated with wheat, as stated in the autograph receipts which I have issued, so that you may be informed (on the matter). It runs as follows: In year 22 of Imperator Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrianus Antoninus Augustus Pius, Pharmouthi 26. Heraklas alias Heracleon, son of Archelaos, has paid to Apion, son of Herodes, and his fellow public bankers of Oxyrhynchos, the penalty, which he owed for the admission of the treasury in the 22nd year, on a 1/4 of an aroura, next to the Upper Iseion,;of the property of Sogenes of the private land cultivated with cereal chosen for the construction . . . entered by the royal scribe: 75 drachmas with 6 drachmas, 2 obols and 3 chalkoi for prosdiagraphomena, that was 6 drachmas, 2 obols and 3 chalkoi , in total 81 drachmas, 2 obols and 3 chalkoi.;I, Hierakion, assistant, have signed for 81 drachmas, 2 obols and 3 chalkoi . ;Year 19 of Imperator Caesares Marcus Aurelius Antoninus and Lucius Aurelius Commodus, our lords Augusti, Thoth 5."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Gara A, ZPE 50, 61-6, 1983 -- SB XVI 13003 -- BL XI, 221 (l. 1-2, 12, 14, 14) Gagos T, BASP 34, 44-46, 1997, Pl. 2-3</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
