<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>loan of money</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1603</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1603</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.16.13030</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;16;13030</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;16;13030</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">16347</idno>
            <idno type="TM">16347</idno>
            <idno type="filename">16347-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 256</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.618018-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>"NN . . . from the village of Alabastrine of the Hermopolite nome, priest of the first-rank temples of Apollo and Isis, to NN, eques and signifier of the turma of Heraclides of the Ala Mauretana, greetings.;I acknowledge that I have received from you as a loan in cash the full sum of 116 drachmas in imperial silver coinage, at interest of 1 drachma per mina a month, which I bind myself to repay to you within 4 months from Epeiph of the current thirteenth year without delay. If I do not make repayment, when the time for repayment begins, I agree to be laible to seizure until such time as I repay both the principal with a 50% surcharge and the simple interest, and interest at the same rate for the period beyond the term of the loan. You have the right of execution against both me and all my property, as if there were a judgement. Let this chirograph, written in one copy and subscribed by me, be valid, as if registered in the public archives. The thirteenth year of the Imperatores Caesares Lucius Septimius Severus Pius Pertinax Arabicus Adiabenicus Parthicus Maximus and Marcus Aurelius Antoninus Pius Augusti, Epeiph.;(2nd hd.) I, NN, acknowledge that I have received 116 drachmas in full, as stated above."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Priest NE, ZPE 51, 65-70, 1983, Pl IV -- SB XVI 13030</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
