<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Deed of Surety</title>
            <author>Aurelius Paris, son of Harpokration</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">wisconsin.apis.5388</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(WU)5388</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.wisc.1.12</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0226;1;12</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.wisc;1;12</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">16819</idno>
            <idno type="TM">16819</idno>
            <idno type="filename">16819-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Wisc. inv. 70</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:26.253322-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Recto:;During the consulate of Flavius Amantius Albinus the most radiant to Aurelius Achilleus, son of Asklepiades prytanis, gymnasiarch, councilor of the radiant and most radiant town of Oxyrhynchos, from Aurelius Paris, son of Harpokration from the village of the goddess Amata, contractor of field-irrigation. I declare, having sworn the imperial and divine oath by our lords Augusti, of my own free will and of my own choice to stand surety for Aurelius Aion, son of Aion wine-grower of the same village, that he stays in the same village and that he sees to the cultivation of his own land, fulfilling everything which has been agreed by him or that I, his surety, perform of necessity all that which is required with regard to him, so that in no respect can anything be found fault with or else I may be liable to the consequences of the divine oath. During the aforesaid consulate the 5th Payni. I, Aurelius Paris, son of Harpokration, have sworn the divine oath and stand surety for Aurelius Aion, son of Aion, wine-grower, as is written above and when asked I have consented. [I, N.N.,] son of Apollonios have written it for him, because he said not being able to write. This document has been made by me, Harpalos.;;Verso:;Surety for Aion, son of Aion, from (the village) of the goddess Amata.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn P.J., PWisc  I, 12, 1967, Plate V</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
