<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Loan of Money</title>
            <author>Aurelius Kolluthos, son of Anuthios</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">wisconsin.apis.5386</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(WU)5386</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.wisc.1.10</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0226;1;10</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.wisc;1;10</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">16818</idno>
            <idno type="TM">16818</idno>
            <idno type="filename">16818-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Wisc. inv. 76</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:26.235097-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Recto:;After the consulate of Falvius Pusius and Flavius Johannes the most radiant the 13th Phaophi of the 7th indiction, Aurelius Kolluthos, son of Anuthios vegetable merchant from the town of Oxyrhynchos to Aurelius Papnuthios, son of Mataios, grandson of Monaxon from the village of Kerke in the southern part of the Theodosipolite Nome, abiding in the town of Oxyrhynchos, greetings. I admit having received on loan from you directly in ready cash for my own and necessary use one gold solidus, without additional charge, legally of correct weight, in total 1 gold solidus,  which I shall necessarily repay you free of any risk on the twenty-fifth of the month of Phamenoth of the present year 145/114 of the seventh indiction without delay and without any contradiction and lawsuit and conviction while you are entitled the right of execution against me and all my possessions. The contract, of which there is one copy, is valid and when asked I have consented. I, Aurelius Kolluthos, son of Anuthios, the above mentioned, have received on loan the one gold solidus in total and I shall repay him on the aforesaid date, as is mentioned above and asked I have consented. I, Aurelius Phoibammon, son of Phuraxionios, have written if for him because he cannot write. By me,Boethos;;;Verso:;From Kolluthos, vegetable merchant, from Oxyrhynchos 1 gold solidus.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn P.J., PWisc  I, 10, 1967, Plate IV</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
