<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lease an Exhedra</title>
            <author>Aurelia Philoxena, daughter of Joseph</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">wisconsin.apis.5384</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(WU)5384</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.wisc.1.8</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0226;1;8</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.wisc;1;8</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">16816</idno>
            <idno type="TM">16816</idno>
            <idno type="filename">16816-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Wisc. inv. 79</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:26.245526-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Recto:;In the 20th year after the consulate of Flavius Basilius, the most exalted, the 19th Choiak, the 10th indiction. Aurelia Philoxena, daughter of Joseph, her mother being Irene, from the exalted town of Oxyrhynchos to [N.N.], of most noble birth, daughter of Makarios, son of Papnuthios of the same town, greetings. I undertake of my free will to rent from the first of the present month of Choiak of the present year 237/206 of the present tenth indiction of the parts of a house belonging to you, facing east, of the town of the district of Ano Achillis, the complete hall, facing north, with all the rights and appurtenances of the complete house and I shall annually pay in rent for this ten carats of the current money, in total 10 carats of the current money, which rent I shall pay you over my possession of the hall, as I have received it. The rent, of which there is only copy, is valid and when asked I have consented. The rent, as mentioned above, pleasure me, Aurelia Philoxena, daughter of Joseph. I, Daniel, have written it for her, because she cannot write. By me, Daniel, it was made.;;Verso:;Rent of Philoxena, daughter of Joseph of the town of Oxyrhynchos, at a rental of 10 carts of the current money.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn P.J., PWisc  I, 8, 1967, Plate III</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
