<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Cession of Land</title>
            <author>Sarapion, son of Sarapion, grandson of Sarapion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">wisconsin.apis.5385</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(WU)5385</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.wisc.1.9</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0226;1;9</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.wisc;1;9</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">16817</idno>
            <idno type="TM">16817</idno>
            <idno type="filename">16817-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Wisc. inv. 34</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:26.24468-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Sarapion, son of Sarapion, grandson of Sarapion, his mother being Demetria, from the town of Oxyrhynchos to Zoilos, the elder, son of Zoilos, grandson of Dionysios, his mother being Sarapias, alias Arsinoe from the same town, ex-agoranomos of the same town, archpriest in function of the most sacred Nile, greetings. I admit having ceded to you half of the arurae written down below, that formerly belonged to my mother, of the twelve and one-sixteenth arouras from the property of Spokeus, situated round the village of Kerkeura of the middle-toparchy and of the six and one-fourth and one-twenty-fourth arouras from the property of Xenon and Spledon, situated round Kerkemunis of the south toparchy and of the arouras in collective ownership the parts in which the private dike is situated, of which the neighbours in total are: in the south [the house?], that formerly belonged to Theogenes, the son of Theogenes, with on the east part the state-dike and on the west part the aforesaid private dike; in the east the property that formerly belonged to Dionysios, the son of Erieus; in the west the same private dike. Everything taken together it is eighteen and one-third and one forty-eighth; half of this is nine and one-sixth and one-ninety-sixth arouras. The conveyance money of this amount to four thousand silver drachmas, of which I have personally received from you three thousand six hundred silver drachmas on the condition that I received the remaining four hundred silver drachmas from you before the end of the month of Hadrianus of the present year, wile I perform for you the registration of conveyance of the arouras round Kerkemunis, registered [               ] the arouras round Kerkeura as well. The complete six and one-sixth and one-ninetieth arouras I will hand over to you and your descendants and successors guaranteed against everything, and I have also guaranteed with every guarantee, that they are also exempt from cultivating of crown-land and land that belongs to the patrimonium of the emperor, and from every taxation and from working on and guarding state-dikes and from every other obligation, whatever, and from all taxes that are paid for this and payments up to and including the past twenty-third year inclusive, because the payment of the wheat for the present twenty-fourth year is for the account of you, Zoilos. The cession, of which there are two copies, is valid. The twenty-fourth year of Imperator Caesar Marcus Aurelius Commodus Antoninus Augustus Armeniacus Medicus Parthicus Sarmaticus Germanicus Maximus the 1st of the month of Hadrianus. I, Sarapion, son of Sarapion, grandson of Sarapion, great grandson of Dionysios, have ceded the above nine and one-sixth and one-ninety-sixth arouras to Zoilos at a conveyance sum of four thousand drachmas, of which I have received three thousand six hundred and I shall perform the registration of conveyance of this when I have received the remaining four hundred and I shall ratify it as mentioned above. [I, N.N.,] have written it for him, as he is illiterate.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn P.J., PWisc  I, 9, 1967, Plate III -- Papyri; ZPE 91 (1992) pp. 91-94</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
