<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lease of Land</title>
            <author>Aurelius Theodous, son of Neikammonios, grandson of Neikammonios</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">wisconsin.apis.5383</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(WU)5383</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.wisc.1.7</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0226;1;7</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.wisc;1;7</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">16815</idno>
            <idno type="TM">16815</idno>
            <idno type="filename">16815-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Wisc. inv. 58</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:26.226524-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Aurelius Theodous, son of Neikammonios, grandson of Neikammonios, [             ]; From the town of Oxyrhynchos has leased to Aurelius Philotas, son of Melas, his mother being Phicholia, from Senokomis, for two years fro the present 7th year the two arouras, which belong to his daughter Aurelia Athenodora alias Horigeneia, in the neighborhood of Senokomis, already previously cultivated by the lease-holder, to sow them for the present 7th year with green-stuffs at an agreed rent of a hundred drachmas, to sow them for the coming 8th year with wheat at an agreed rent of twelve artabas of wheat, everything free of any risk, while the taxes for the land are paid by the owner, who remains in possession of the produce, until he has received the annual rent due to him. If, which God forbid, in the following period of time the land is not reached by the flooding of the Nile, the lease-holder must needs irrigate at his own cost and expense two-thirds of the land which he would have had to cultivate in case of inundation by the flooding of the Nile, as well as (pay two-thirds) of the rent (, which he would have had to pay in case of inundation by the flooding of the Nile). When the lease has been ratified, the lease-holder must pay the money due, the rental in the month of Payni, the wheat on the threshing-floor of Senokomis, new pure, unadulterated, not mixed with clods of earth or barley, sieved with the sixth measure of the landowner, while his people perform the measuring. He will have the right execution of the lease-holder and all his possessions. The lease is valid and when asked he has consented. The year 7 of the Imperatores caesares Publius Licinnius Valerianus and publius Licinnius Valerianus Gallienus Germanici Maximi PII Felices and Publius Licinnius Cornelius Valerius the most illustrious Caesar Sebasti. I, Aurelius Philotas, have leased it and shall pay as written above. [I, N.N] have written it for him because he cannot write.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn P.J., PWisc  I, 7, 1967, Plate II</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
