<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll </title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2152</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2152</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12000</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12000</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;225</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12000-2</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.848246-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 102;;On Pauni 4:;Petheus, son of Petesouchos  - (through) Ebasthanmintiles -, for garden land, for year 13: for apomoira, 5 obols; for olive (transportation), 1 obol; for naubion, 1/2 obol; for supplements, 1 1/2 obols; for eparourion, 3 1/2 obols; for supplements, 1/2 obol; for kollybos, 1/2 obol. Total: 2 drachmai 1/2 obol. (In left margin: 20 obols.);Pakysis, son of Kalatytes and Segathis, grandson of Heras: 16 drachmai;    column 39;Artemis, daughter of Mysthes - (through) Phasis, son of Pakysis -, for garden land, for year 13: for apomoira, 6 drachmai 3 obols; for olive (transportation), 5 obols 1/2 2 chalkoi; for naubion, 4 obols; for supplements, 1 drachme 4 obols; for eparourion, 4 drachmai 2 obols; for supplements, 2 obols 2 chalkoi; for kollybos, 1 1/2 obols. Total: 14 drachmai 4 1/2 obols. (In left margin: 20 drachmai 9 obols.) and;Soeris, daughter of Teos, through Phasis, son of Pakysis, for garden land, for year 13: for apomoira, 2 drachmai 2 obols 2 chalkoi; for olive (transportation), 2 obols 2 chalkoi; for naubion, 1 obol 2 chalkoi; for supplements, 3 1/2 obols 2 chalkoi; for eparourion, 1 drachme 3 1/2 obols; for supplements, 1 obol; for kollybos, 1/2 obol 2 chalkoi. Total: 5 drachmai 2 1/2 obols 2 chalkoi.;Nikephoros, slave of Longinus Isidoros, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;    column 57;Iulius Ptolemaios - (through) Maximus the leper -, for garden land, for year 13: for apomoira, 39 drachmai 1 obol; for olive (transportation), 5 drachmai 3 obols; for naubion, 3 drachmai 5 1/2 obols; for supplements, 9 drachmai 4 1/2 obols; for eparourion, 26 drachmai 1 obol; for supplements, 2 drachmai 1 1/2 obols; for kollybos, 1 drachme 2 1/2 obols 2 chalkoi. Total: 88 drachmai 1 obol 2 chalkoi. (In left margin: 88 drachmai 6 obols.);Ptollis, son of Orsenouphis - (through) Heras, worker on irrigation machines -, for garden land: for apomoira, 2 drachmai 5 obols; for olive (transportation), 2 1/2 obols; for naubion, 1 1/2 obols 2 chalkoi; for supplements, 4 obols 2 chalkoi; for eparourion, 1 drachme 5 1/2 obols; for supplements, 1 obol; for kollybos, 1/2 obol 2 chalkoi. Total: 6 drachmai 1/2 obol 2 chalkoi;;for the naubion of the catoeci, for year 14: 4 obols; for supplements: 1/2 obol; for kollybos: 2 chalkoi. Total: 4 1/2 obols 2 chalkoi (In left margin: 8 drachmai.);Mystharion, son of Ischyrion and Tapetheus, grandson of Euemeros: 8 drachmai;    column 56;Pnepheros, son of Petheus and Thaisas, grandson of Petesouchos, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;    column 59;Phaesis, son of Pasoxis and Tapetsiris, grandson of Phaesis: 12 drachmai;    column 58;Gaius Iulius Priscus - (through) Akousarion, daughter of Thankotis -, for garden land, for year 13: for apomoira, 5 drachmai 3 1/2 obols 2 chalkoi; for olive (transportation), 4 1/2 obols 2 chalkoi; for naubion, 3 1/2 obols; for supplements, 1 drachme 2 1/2 obols; for eparourion, 3 drachmai 4 1/2 obols; for supplements, 2 obols; for kollybos, 1 obol 2 chalkoi. Total: 12 drachmai 4 obols 2 chalkoi;;for the naubion of the catoeci, for year 14: 3 drachmai 3 1/2 obols; for supplements: 2 obols 2 chalkoi. Total: 4 drachmai 2 chalkoi.;for the naubion of owners of private land, similarly: 1 drachme; for supplements: 1 obol 2 chalkoi; for kollybos, 2 chalkoi. Total: 1 drachme 1 obol 2 chalkoi. (In left margin: 16 drachmai 23 obols.);Tapetesouchos, daughter of Korakion, through Melanous also called Tasoucharion, daughter of Petesouchos, for garden land, for year 13, for Karanis (and) Psenarpsenesis: for apomoira, 20 drachmai 3 1/2 obols; for olive (transportation), 3 drachmai 1 obol 2 chalkoi; for naubion, 2 drachmai 1/2 obol; for supplements, 5 drachmai 1 obol 2 chalkoi; for eparourion, 17 drachmai 3 1/2 obols; for supplements, 1 drachme 3 obols; for kollybos, 5 obols 2 chalkoi. Total: 51 drachmai 2 chalkoi;;for the naubion of the catoeci, for year 14: 2 drachmai 5 1/2 obols; for supplements: 2 obols; for kollybos: 1/2 obol. Total: 3 drachmai 2 obols;;other (parcels): for garden-land for year 13: for apomoira, 1 drachme 4 obols; for olive (transportation), 1 1/2 obols; for naubion, 1 obol; for supplements, 2 1/2 obols; for eparourion, 1 drachme 1/2 obol 2 chalkoi; for supplements, 1/2 obol 2 chalkoi; for kollybos, 1/2 obol. Total: 3 drachmai 5 obols. (In left margin: 56 drachmai 26 obols.);;(Account in left margin:);Of Chairemon, son of Ouasis: 4 drachmai;of Tkames the physician: 36 drachmai;Of Theagenes: 8 obols;Of me: 4 drachmai 10 obols.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 102 (l. 1736-1775), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
