<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3260</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3260</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.2.358D</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.2;358D</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.2;358D</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12006</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12006</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12006-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Cair. inv. JdE 57187</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.468768-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 1[73?];;(either 4th intercalary day or 4th Thoth, continued);;Kastor also called Sabinus, son of Ptolemaios and Melitous, grandson of Satabous, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Heras, son of Petheus - (through) Beilikas - for the five-drachm tax on donkeys, for year 14,  for the maintenance work of year 12: 5 drachmai, and supplements: 2 obols. Total 5 drachmai 2 obols. (In the left margin: 4 drachmai 14 obols);Tesenouphis, son of Aiaus and Thases, grandson of Orsenouphis: 4 drachmai;Total for the day: 96 drachmai.;;On the 5th(?), similarly:;Horion, son of Heron also called Heras and Segathis, grandson of Sisois, diseased, for the guards: 5 drachmai; (and) for the guard towers: 1 drachme 4 obols. Total 6 drachmai 4 obols.;Aphrodisis, son of Petheus and Taseus, grandson of Pnepheros, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Kanis, son of Anchophis and Taorsoraipis, grandson of Mares, over the age (of liability to the poll-tax), for the guards: 1 drachme; (and) for the guard towers: 3 drachmai. Total: 4 drachmai.;Anchophis, his son, his mother being Thermouthis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;[Heron], son of Pekmeis also called Heuremon and Sambathion, for ch(--): 28 obols;[Maron], son of Petheus the younger and Apollonous, grandson of Anchorimphis, for ch(--): 8 drachmai;[Lucius] Longinus Gemellus, [for the third] (of the revenue) of the bath establishment, for year14: 28 drachmai including extra charges.;[Aphrodisios], son of Petheus and Stiynchis, grandson of Petesouchos, for ch(--): 8 drachmai;[Orsenouphis], son of Petheus and Tapetheus, grandson of Horion, for ch(--): 4 drachmai; (and the) remainder of ch(--);[Kastor], son of Onnophris and Tapetheus, grandson of Petheus: 12 drachmai;[Petheus], son of Kollouthos and Thaesis, grandson of Phaesis, for guards: 1 drachme; (and) for guard towers: 3 drachmai. Total: 4 drachmai.;[Heron], his son, his mother being Taorsenouphis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;[Aunes], son of Aunes and Tapetheus, grandson of Hermas, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;[Petheus], son of Ptollis and Thases, grandson of Herakles, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus and Tanesneus, grandson of Petheus, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;[Phasis, son of Petheus] and Thaesis, grandson of Heras, for guards: 4 drachmai;[Pakysis, son of Phasis] and Tanomgeus, grandson of Esouris, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;[Herakles], son of Apollonios and Tapetheus, grandson of Petoraipis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Total for the day: 116 drachmai 10 obols.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC - Pearl OM, PMich IV/2, 358D ([col. 173, 174, or 175?]), 1939</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
