<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Loan of Money and Sale of Grain</title>
            <author>Horos son of Onnophris</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2621</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2621</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.9.567</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;9;567</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;9;567</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12059</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12059</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12059-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 6004</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.672486-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>The eleventh year of the Emperor Caesar Vespasian Augustus, 29th of the month Sebastos, in Karanis in the Herakleides division of the Arsinoite nome. Horos, son of Onnophris, a Persian of the epigone, about 35 years old, with a scar on his left knee, acknowledges to Diodora, daughter of Heron, about 20 years old, unmarked, with her guardian, her husband Chairemon, son of Chairemon, about 23 years old, with a scar on his right shin, that he has received from her at once from hand to hand out of the house the loan of forty-eight drachmai of silver at interest at the rate of one drachme (per mina per month); and that he has also received the value of two artabai of new, clean and unadultered  wheat measured in the six-choinix measure of the broker of Karanis. The party of the first part, Horos, shall repay (the loan) to Diodora in the month of Pauni of the present year, and if he does not repay in accordance with what is written, he shall pay the money increased by one half, and for each artaba of the wheat he shall pay in addition the market price that shall be the highest current at that time, the right of execution resting with [Diodora] against Horos and [against his] property . . .</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich IX, 567, 1971 -- BL VI, 83 (date); BL VIII, 215 (date); BL X, 125 (l. 8-9)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
