<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Register of Contracts Prepared at the Grapheion</title>
            <author>Kronion, son of Apion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3236</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3236</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.238</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;238</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;238</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12078 78518</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12078 78518</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12078-5</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 968</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.757014-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Phaophi 5, continued).;Agreement to furnish lodging for the sum of 100 silver drachmai, (made) by Serapas and his wife to Onnophris. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Loan of the same capital, (made) by Onnophris to the same (people). (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Agreement to nurse a slave child, (made) by Tamarres and others to Sadalas, (and);loan of 500 silver drachmai, (made) by Sadalas to the same (people). (Fee:) . . drachmai.;Agreement of lease of (. .) arourai, (made) by Marepkemis to Herodion. Gratis, for Heronas.;Agreement to nurse a slave child, (made) by Thermouthis and her husband to Iucundus, (and);on the 6th, loan of 64 silver drachmai, (made) by Iucundus to the same (people). (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;On the 7th. Agreement of lease, by way of payment in advance, of 6 arourai, (made) by Herakleides and his wife to Paches. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Acknowledgment of receipt of a dowry of 200 drachmai, (made) by Tapsosneus to Papnebtynis and another. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Agreement to furnish lodging for the sum of 100 silver drachmai, (made) by Papontos and others to Thenmaron. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Agreement of sale of a donkey, (made) by Potamon to Apynchis. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Agreement of sale of a donkey, (made) by Horsisouchos to Chairemon. (Fee:) 5 obols.;Agreement of sale of a donkey, (made) by Areios to Serapas and another. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Agreement of sale of a donkey, (made) by Herakleides to Hatres. (Fee:) 7 obols.;Agreement of sale of a donkey, (made) by Sekonopis to Pakebkis. (Fee:) 4 obols.;Lease of 6 arourai, (made) by Marsisouchos to Orseus. (Fee:) 5 obols.;Agreement of sale of a donkey, (made) by Patynis to Serapion. (Fee:) 6 obols.;On the 9th. Lease of a vineyard, (made) by Sadalas to Didymos. (Fee:) 9 obols.;Agreement of sale of a donkey, (made) by Patermouthis to Serapion. (Fee:) 5 obols.;Agreement of sale of a donkey, (made) by Euangelos to Serapion. (Fee:) 7 obols.;Agreement (of - - -) of 40 silver drachmai, (made) by Apynchis to Sambous. (Fee:) 8 obols.;Agreement (of - - -) of 100 drachmai, (made) by Marres to Phomsaeis. (Fee:) 18 obols.;On the 10th. Agreement of sale of a donkey, (made) by Akes to Ischyrion. He owes the fee.;Lease of a vineyard, (made) by Herodion to Panechotes. (Fee:) 9 obols.;Loan of 68 silver drachmai, (made) by Marsisouchos to Psenosiris. (Fee:) 11 obols.;On the 12th. Loan of 22 drachmai, (made) by Thermouthis to Pakebkis and his wife. (Fee:) 5 obols.;On the 13th. Acknowledgment of deposit of 100 silver drachmai and 7 artabai of wheat, (made) by Siphon to Kronion. (Fee:) 3 drachmai.;On the 21st. Lease of an orchard and others, (made) by Didymos to Orsenouphis. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;On the 22nd. Agreement to nurse a slave child, (made) by Tapnebtynis and her husband to Apion, (and);on the 25th, loan of 100 silver drachmai, (made) by Apion to the same (people). Gratis, for Apion.;Agreement of sale of a vineyard of 2 arourai 1/4 and a twenty-fourth, (made) by Galates and another to Didyme. She owes the scribe's fee.;On the 26th. Lease of a vineyard, (made) by Lysimachos to Kronion. He owes the scribe's fee.;Agreement of cession of 2 1/8 arourai, (made) by Apollonios to Demetrios. (Fee:) 8 drachmai.;On the 30th. Sale of a house and a storeroom, (made) by Patermouthis to Kronion. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;On month Neos Sebastos 2. Agreement to furnish lodging for (the loan of) a stone used in the manufacture of pottery, (made) by Tephersos to Tephersos. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Agreement (of - - -) of 32 silver drachmai and 13 artabai of barley, (made) by Orsenouphis to Orseus. (Fee:) 11 obols.;Agreement of cession (of a pastophoros's cell), (made) by Paopis and another to Kronion, (and);loan of 100 drachmai with the same pastophoros's cell (as guaranty), (made) by Kronion to the same (people). (Fee): 4 drachmai.;Lease of 1 aroura, (made) by Orsenouphis to Petsiris. He owes the fee.;Agreement (of - - -) of 36 silver drachmai, (made) by Marepsemis and his wife to Herodion. (Fee:) 7 obols.;Alimentary (contract) for a dowry of 320 silver drachmai, (made) by Orseus to Taos. (Fee:) 6 drachmai.;Agreement of cession of 2 arourai, (made) by Diodoros and his wife to Horion. (Fee:) 12 drachmai.;Agreement of division (of property), (made) by Psyphis to his sons. (Fee:) 40 silver drachmai.;On the 5th. Agreement to nurse a slave child, (made) by Thenatymis to Esertaeis, (and);loan of 100 silver drachmai, (made) by Esertaeis to Orseus and his wife. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;On the 6th. Acknowledgment of receipt (of - - -), (made) by Peteesis to Orseus. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Loan of 560(?) silver drachmai, (made) by Marsisouchos to Panesis and his wife. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Loan of 260 silver drachmai, (made) by Lysimachos to Marsisouchos. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Agreement (of - - -) 208 drachmai, (made) by Harmiysis and his wife to Didyme. (Fee:) . . drachmai.;Loan of the same capital, (made) by Didyme to the same (people). (Fee:) 10 drachmai.;Agreement (of - - -) of 100 silver drachmai, (made) by Harpaesis to Nekpheraus. (Fee:) 3 silver drachmai.;Agreement to furnish lodging for the sum of 120 silver drachmai, (made) by Tamarres and others to Marres, (and);on the 7th. Acknowledgment of deposit of 200 silver drachmai and 2 artabai of wheat, (made) by Thaubastis and others to Kronion. (Fee) for both (documents): 4 drachmai.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich V, 238, col. III, 1944 -- BL VII, 111 (bibliography); BL VIII, 213 (bibliography).</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
