<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Petition to a Strategos</title>
            <author>Pakebkis son of Horos; Kollouthos son of P[- - -] (and others?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2786</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2786</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.231</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;231</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;231</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12072</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12072</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12072-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 627</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.583714-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>To Apollonios, strategos of the Arsinoite nome, from Pakebkis, son of Horos, and Kollouthos, son of P[- - -];[- - -] of the same village [- - -] them of false accusations and assaults in regard to which each of those who have suffered wrong has made his complaint. Even then the same accused with his customary daring attacked another of the residents of the same village, Kronion, son of Petesouchos, who is also called Chales, wishing to ruin him by penalties, so that, because of his needy condition, Kronion laid hands on himself and perished. Wherefore, acting not unwisely, Petesis, the brother of Kronion, and Kronion's own wife, Tephereus, daughter of Sigeris, laid the complaint at that time in accordance with what they declared to Tiberius Claudius Chrysermos, the former strategos, about these occurrences in the petition. Since, then, the matter has become evident from the . . . of the accused Orses [- - -] we shall appear as plaintiffs wherever our lord Gnaeus Vergilius Capito shall hold the assizes of the nome to the end that through his judgment he (i.e. the accused) may meet with the punishment he deserves. Farewell.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich V, 231, 1944 -- BL III, 115 (l. 7); BL VI, 82  (l. 15; 16; 20; 21); BL XI, 131 (l. 17); BL XI, 131 (l. 11)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
