<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Register of Contracts Prepared at the Grapheion</title>
            <author>Kronion, son of Apion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3238</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3238</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.238</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;238</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;238</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12078 78518</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12078 78518</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12078-2</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 968</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.012652-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Choiak 9, continued).;Agreement (of deposit?) of 18 silver drachmai and 10 1/2 artabai of wheat, (made) by Tephersos to Phomsaeis. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Alimentary (contract) for a dowry of 200 silver drachmai, (made) by Herakleides to Tamarres. (Fee:) 6 drachmai.;Agreement of lease, by way of payment in advance, of 2 arourai, (made) by Orseus to Paches. Gratis, for Paches.;Agreement (of - - -) of 240 silver drachmai, (made) by Harsiesis and his wife to Bremon. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;On the 11th. Agreement (of deposit?) of 24 silver drachmai and 3 artabai of barley, (made) by Akousilaos to Herodion. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Loan of 156 silver drachmai, (made) by Didymos to Orseus and his wife. (Fee:) 3 drachmai.;On the 13th. Loan of 24 drachmai, (made) by Herodion to Peteesis and his wife. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Agreement (of - - -) of 24 drachmai, (made) by Orseus and his wife to Herakles. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Loan of 140 silver drachmai, (made) by Didymos to Heronas and his wife. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;On the 16th. Alimentary (contract) for a dowry of 500 silver drachmai, (made) by Kronion to Taarmiysis. He(?) owes the fee.;Alimentary (contract) for a dowry of 500 silver drachmai, (made) by Ptolemaios to Tausis. (Fee:) 8 drachmai.;Agreement of lease of 1 aroura of an allotment, (made) by Pasis to Apollonios. (Fee:) 10 obols.;Lease of 2 1/2 arourai of an allotment, (made) by Apollonios to Herakles. (Fee:) 12 obols.;On the 17th. Loan of 120 silver drachmai, (made) by Lysimachos to Onnophris and his wife. (Fee:) 4 silver drachmai.;Loan of 128 silver drachmai, (made) by Lysimachos to Miysis and his wife. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;On the 19th. Acknowledgment of deposit of 300 silver drachmai, (made) by Papnebtynis to Anempeous. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Acknowledgment of deposit of 1,000 silver drachmai, (made) by Papontos to Orsenouphis. (Fee:) 8 drachmai.;Agreement to farm in good faith &lt;or: to give surety to conduct farm operations&gt;, (made) by Petsiris to Phemnasis. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Agreement of division (of property), (made) by Orsenouphis to his sons. (Fee:) 8 drachmai.;On the 22nd. Acknowledgment of receipt, (made) by Ischyrion also called Gaius to Onnophris. Gratis, for Onnophris.;Acknowledgment of receipt, (made) by Timon to Ischyrion. (Fee:) 4 silver drachmai.;Loan of 60 silver drachmai, (made) by Herodion to Tephersos and another. (Fee:) 6 drachmai.;On the 23rd. Acknowledgment of deposit of 24 silver drachmai and 4 artabai of barley, (made) by Pakebkis and his wife to Didymos. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;On the 25th. Acknowledgment of 72 drachmai and 5 1/2 artabai of wheat, (made) by Kronion and his wife to Herodion. (Fee:) 6 drachmai.;On the 27th. Agreement of cession of 16 1/2 arourai, (made) by Herodes to Herakleides. (Fee:) 12 drachmai on account.;Acknowledgment of receipt of a dowry of 60 silver drachmai, (made) by Thatres to Papontos and another.;On the 28th. Agreement (of - - -) of 3 arourai of an allotment, (made) by Komon to Onnophris. Gratis, for Onnophris.;Agreement of division of lands, (made) by Papnebtynis to Maron and another. (Fee:) 3 drachmai.;On the 29th. Acknowledgment of deposit of 60 drachmai and 3 1/2 artabai of wheat, (made) by Cheos to Lysimachos. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;On the 30th. Agreement of division (of property), (made) by Harmiysis to his sons. (Fee:) 8 silver drachmai.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich V, 238, col. V, 1944 -- BL VII, 111 (bibliography); BL VIII, 213 (bibliography).</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
