<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Guild Ordinance</title>
            <author>Heron son of Orseus &amp; other members of his guild</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3089</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3089</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.243</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;243</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;243</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12084</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12084</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12084-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 720</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.455593-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Recto);;[- - - have chosen as president for the . .] year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus Heron, son of Orseus, in whose company they shall hold a banquet each month on the 12th, each one contributing for his monthly dues the twelve silver drachmai assigned equally to each. If anyone fails to meet his obligations in these or the other matters, the president has the right to exact pledges. If anyone misconducts himself, let him be fined whatever the society may decide. If anyone receives notice of a meeting and does not attend, let him be fined one drachme in the village, but in the city four drachmai. If anyone marries let him pay two drachmai, for the birth of a male child two drachmai, for a female one drachma, for the purchase of a property four drachmai, for a flock of sheep four drachmai, for cattle one drachme. If anyone neglects another in trouble and does not give aid to release him from his trouble, let him pay eight drachmai. And each one who in taking seats at the banquets shoves in front of another shall pay an extra three obols for his own place. If anyone prosecutes another or defames him, let him be fined eight drachmai. If anyone intrigues against another or corrupts his home, let him be fined eight drachmai. If anyone is given into custody for a private debt, let them go bail for him up to one hundred silver drachmai for thirty days, within which he will release the men. May health prevail! [But] if one the members dies, let all be shaved and let them hold a feast for one day, each bringing at once one drachme and two loaves, and in the case of other bereavements, let them hold a feast for one day. Let him who is not shaven in case of a death be fined four drachmai. Whoever has taken no part in the funeral and has not placed a wreath on the tomb shall be fined four drachmai. And let the other matters be as the society may decide. Let the law be valid. When subscribed by the majority (and) validated, let it be returned to the president.;Herakleios, son of Aphrodisios, about 42 years old, with a scar between the eyebrows.;Orses, son of Kronides, about 45 years old, with a scar on an eyebrow.;Mieus, son of Harmiysis, about 46 years old, with a scar on his face to the left.;Harmiysis, son of Phasos, about 55 years old, with a scar on the right . . .;(2nd hand) I, Heron, son of Orseus, president, approve (the law) as set forth above.;(3rd hand) I, Soterichos, son of Soterichos, give my approval.;(4th hand) I, Patron, son of Patynis, give my approval.;(5th hand) I, Herodes, son of Soterichos, give my approval.;(6th hand) I, Psenobastis, son of Herodes, give my approval.;(7th hand) I, Herodes, son of Herodes alias(?)  Isidoros, give my approval.;(8th hand) I, Orsenouphis, son of Harmiysis, give my approval.;(9th hand) I, Apollonios, son of Aphrodisios, give my approval.;(10th hand) We, Herakles, son of Aphrodisios, and Harmiysis, son of Phasos, and Orses, son of Kronides, and Mieus, son of Harmiysis, give our approval as set forth above. Nikanor, son of Heliodoros, wrote for them since they are illiterate.;(11th hand) I, Orsenouphis, son of Horos, give my approval.;I, Orsenouphis, son of Aphrodisios, give my approval.;I, Heraklas, son of Ptolemaios, give my approval.;Orsenouphis, son of Horos, . . ., wrote for them since they illiterate.;;(Verso: text too fragmentary to be translated).</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich V, 243, 1944 -- BL IX, 160 (l. 12-13). Arangio-Ruiz, F.I.R.A. III. Negotia, 46bis (l. 1-13 only), 1969(2)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
