<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Cession of Sacred Land</title>
            <author>Akes, son of Pisais</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3079</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3079</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.256</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;256</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;256</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12091</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12091</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12091-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 711</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.964234-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>I, Akes, son of Pisais, acknowledge that I have ceded to Orsenouphis, son of Pr- - -, from the sacred land of the god Souchos that belongs to me near the farmstead of Herakleides in the division of Polemon, five arourai, or as many as there may be, in one parcel, apart from the impost of the village, the neighbors of the whole allotment being on the south the allotment of Ptolemaios, son of . . ., on the north the allotment of Psenobastis, on the west the canal through which the allotment is watered, on the east the canal through which the allotment is drained. And I have received from Orsenouphis the entire sum of money established for the cession and I guarantee the sale with every guarantee from all public debts and all charges and the naubion taxes and the artab taxes and the price of the land except the impost of the village and from all other sums demanded from past times up to the past fifteenth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus and for the fifteenth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus as well, and from private encumbrances and every claim forever as aforesaid. Marsisouchos, son of Marepsemis, wrote for him because he is illiterate.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 256, 1944</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
