<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Cession of Catoecic Land</title>
            <author>Herodes alias Orseus the younger, son of Herodes</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2817</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2817</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.268</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12103</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12103</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;267/268dupl</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12103-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 634</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.479829-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>I, Herodes, also called Orseus the younger, son of Herodes, son of Herodes also called Isidoros, a Macedonian of the katoikoi, acknowledge that I have ceded to Didymos the elder, son of Lysimachos, to him and to his heirs and assigns, for transference, from the present day foreverm the catoecic allotment near Tebtynis, that belongs to me by inheritance from my father, consisting of three arourai, or a many as there may be, in one parcel. The neighbors are on the south the allotment of the purchaser Didymos, on the north that of Kronion, son of Eirenaios, on the west the barren land with the canal by which the allotment is watered between, on the east the allotment of Psabotos, son of Apollonios, and his associates. I shall draw up the customary documents for the transfer and cession of the property to Didymos through the catoecic record office. And I have received from Didymos the sum fixed for the cession in full, and I guarantee it with every guarantee from all public debts and charges and naubion taxes and the artab tax and the arithmetikon and surtaxes and price of the land and the village impost and fines and everything else demanded from the past up to and including the first year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator; and I guarantee it from private encumbrances and every claim forever as aforesaid. Sokrates, son of Sokrates, wrote for him, because he is illiterate.;(2nd hand) Didymos, the elder, son of Lysimachos. The cession was made to me as aforesaid.;;(3rd hand) Herodes, about 37 years old, with a scar on his left calf. Didymos, 48 years old, with a scar on the 1st finger of his left hand. Sokrates, 35 years old, with a mole above his right eyebrow.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 268, 1944 -- L. 15: read in the description of Sokrates: phak(os) hyp(er) ophr(yn) dex(ion), instead of o(ule) . . . . . . . . (PH)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
