<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of a House</title>
            <author>Kronion, son of Labesis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1363</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1363</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.277</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;277</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;277</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12115</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12115</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12115-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1278</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:26.495269-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Top left)  Kronion, son of Labesis, [his mother being] Tapnebtynis, about 27 years old, with a scar on his nose below his brow (sells) [to Apollonios, about] 44 years old, with a scar on the little finger of his left hand and on his left shin a one-story house in Tebtynis; (neighbors:) on the south the house of his brother Labesis, [[on the north]] and in part the yard of the seller; [on the north] the house and yard of the purchaser, [Apollonios], on the west the house of Orsenouphis, son of Challes, and in part the yard of the purchaser, Apollonios, and also in part that of the seller himself, Kronion, on the east the royal road.;;(Top right)  8th year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, Mecheir 8.;;;;(In the space left for the body of the contract)  Became void because of his wife(?).;;;;I, Kronion, son of Labesis, my mother being Tapnebtynis, acknowledge that I have sold to Apollonios, my brother by the same father and mother, in accordance with this sale, from the present time forever, the one-story house that belongs to me, and all the appurtenances, in Tebtynis, of which the neighbors are on the south the house of my brother Labesis and in part the yard belonging to me, Kronion, the seller; on the north the house and yard of Apollonios, the purchaser; on the west the house of Orsenouphis, son of Chales, and in part the yard of the purchaser, Apollonios, and also in part that of the seller, Kronion; on the east the royal road. And I have received from Apollonios the entire price agreed upon, in full, at once, from hand to hand, out of the house, and I guarantee the sale with every guarantee both from public debts of past time up to the eighth year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator and of the eighth year itself, and from private encumbrances and every claim forever. My wife, Tamarres, daughter of Orseus, her mother being Taarmiysis, consents to this sale and agrees that she will not proceed against it forever, or bring any claim, and that no one else shall do so in her behalf as aforesaid. Lysimachos, son of Lysimachos, wrote for them because they are illiterate.;(2nd hand) Apollonios, son of Labesis, his mother being Tapnebtynis. The sale of the house was made to me as aforesaid. Heron, also called Sagatos, son of Haryotes, wrote for him since he is illiterate.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 277, 1944, Pl. IV</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
