<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of a Vineyard</title>
            <author>Heron &amp; Phariene, children of Akousilaos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3108</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3108</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.274</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12110</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12110</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;274/275dupl</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12110-2</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 748</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.41043-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Recto);;I, Heron, son of Akousilaos, and my wife Thaesis, daughter of Herakles, and my sister Phariene, and our mother Thermoutharion, daughter of Pharos, with the guardians of each of the women, of Thaesis, me, her husband, and of Phariene and Thermoutharion,                                       acknowledge that we, Heron and my sister Phariene, have sold to Horion, son of Didymos, the vineyard that belongs to us, inherited from our father, in which the vines are trained on trees, consisting of one half of an aroura in the class paying the tax of one sixth, and all the appurtenances, among which there are a half share of the stone well and the windlass, and a share of the storeroom and of the irrigation canal and the fishing and the dyke, and a half share of the supply of Greek reeds at the storehouse, all near Ibion Eikosipentarouron of the same division. The neighbors are on the south and east the holdings of the Maecenation estate of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, on the north the vineyard of Didymion, and on the west the vineyard of Kronion. And we have received from Horion the entire price agreed upon, in full, at once, from hand to hand, out of the house, and we guarantee the sale on mutual security with every guarantee both from public debts of past time up to the seventh year and of the seventh year also of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator and from private encumbrances and every claim forever as aforesaid. I, Heron, wrote also for my wife since she is illiterate.;;(Verso);;Sale (made) by Heron and others to Horion.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 274, 1944</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
