<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Loan on Security</title>
            <author>Orseus, son of Orseus</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3183</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3183</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.332</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12141</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12141</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;332dupl</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12141-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 952</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.852442-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Col. I);;I, Orseus, son of Orseus, acknowledge that I have sold to Kronion, son of Labesis, in accordance with this agreement from the present day forever the quarter share, common and undivided, of the new three-story house that belongs to me and of all the appurtenances in Tebtynis. The neighbors of the whole house are on the south the house and court of the sons of Panos, and in part the house of Chrates, son of Hippalos, on the north the entrance and exit of the sons of Hatres and of the sons of Herakleides, son of Maron, and of Orseus the elder, son of Paopis, on the west the courtyard of our son Orseus, and of Areios, son of Patynis, and on the east the royal road. And I have received from Kronion the entire price agreed upon, in full, at once, from hand to hand, out of the house, and I guarantee with every guarantee from public debts from past times up to the month Pharmouthi and for the month Pharmouthi also of the coming ninth year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, and from private debts and every claim forever. My wife Taarmiysis, daughter of Patynis, consents [to this agreement] and agrees that she will not proceed against it or bring any claim and [that no one else shall in her behalf as aforesaid. Sarapion, son of] Ptolemaios, [wrote for them] because [they are illiterate].;;(Col. II) We, Orseus, son of Orseus, a Persian of the epigone, and my wife, Taarmiysis, daughter of Patynis, with as guardian, the two of us being sureties for each other for the payment, have received from Kronion, son of Labesis, a loan amounting to one hundred and thirty-two drachmai of minted silver, at the interest of one drachme per mina per month, which money I shall repay in the month Pharmouthi of the coming ninth year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator as aforesaid. Sarapion, son of Ptolemaios, wrote for them because he is illiterate.;;(Verso);;Mortgage, (given) by Orseus to Kronion</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 332, 1944</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
