<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Agreement not to prosecute</title>
            <author>Thenarmaeis, daughter of Petesouchos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2769</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2769</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.345</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;345</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;345</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12154</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12154</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12154-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 623</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.714429-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Recto);;Choiak [13].;;The thirty-seventh year of the rule of Caesar, son of the deified (Julius), the thirteenth of the month Peritios, Choiak thirteen, in Tebtynis of the division of Polemon of the Arsinoite nome.;;;;Year 37 of Caesar, Choiak 13, registered through Apion, nomographos of Tebtynis.;;I, Thenarmaeis, daughter of Petesouchos, acting under the guardianship of my own husband Stothouetis, son of Stothouetis, agree that neither I nor another on my behalf will bring suit now or in the future against my brothers Harmaeis and Petesouchos, whose mother and father are my own, either about our paternal inheritance or about any matter at all, recorded or unrecorded, in the past up to the aforesaid day. And if I shall proceed against the aforesaid Harmaeis and Petesouchos or prosecute them, or anyone else shall do so on my behalf, the prosecution and charge shall be invalid for me and whoever shall proceed against them on my behalf, and I shall also pay a penalty of double damages and costs, and if I shall break the agreement the penalty shall be two hundred drachmai in silver and the cost and nonetheless {apart from} the terms of the agreement shall be valid for all time, as it has been written above. Maron, son of Euemeros, wrote for them upon request because they are illiterate.;;(Verso);[- - -] Harmaeis and Petesouchos.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich V, 345, 1944</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
