<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Release of Property</title>
            <author>Thenmenches and Thaesis, daughters of Akes</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1364</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1364</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.352</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;352</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;352</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12162</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12162</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12162-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1279</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.300206-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>[6th] year of Claudius. Official copy. The 30th of . . .;;;;We, Thenmenches and Thaesis, the two daughters of Akes, with the guardians of each of us, that of Thenmenches being her son Horos, son of Harmiysis, and that of Thaesis being her husband Onnophris, son of Nepheros, acknowledge that we have given a release to Soeris, our aforesaid sister on both our mother's and our father's side, in regard to all the building sites of Soeris in Tebtynis and the household utensils and furnishings and the sums owed her, which were given as dowry by the mother of the three of us, Soeris, daughter of Patynis,when she was still alive, in the alimentary contract which you made with your husband Eutychos, son of Soterichos, in the present sixth year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator on the sixth of the month Neos Sebastos, through this same record office; and we agree that neither we nor our representatives shall proceed against the aforesaid Soeris or her representatives in regard to these mattersor in the matter of any other transaction whatever, written or unwritten, since we have been persuaded by Soeris by a consideration in money; the aforesaid husband of Soeris, who is her appointed guardian, Eutychos, son of Soterichos, suffering no loss in respect to what the aforesaid Horos, together with his wife, owes him on account of the agreement of deposit, as aforesaid. Dionysios, son of Maron, wrote for them because they are illiterate.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 352, 1944</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
