<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Guarantee of Immunity</title>
            <author>Ptolemaios the younger, son of Akousilaos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2897</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2897</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.354</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;354</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;354</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12165</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12165</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12165-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 663</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.968087-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Personal.;;(2nd hand) Ptolemaios the younger, son of Akousilaos, to Kronion, son of Apion, nomographos of Tebtynis, greeting.;Since you prepared the documents for me in my sale to Pausis, son of Peteuris, of a half share and court and entrance and exit in Tebtynis, as I have already declared, formerly the property of the sons of Tisenxis, the son of Petesouchos (son of/alias?) Apoulas, (and) because you, Kronion, have prepared for me the documents for the correction of the public records, in order that no loss may ensue to the treasury I shall pay to the treasury the price which I received from Pausis. And I shall render you, both Kronion and Pausis, free from constraint and execution and annoyance in every way, since the sons of Tisenxis havedisappeared, where I do not know, because they were heavily indebted to the fiscus. And if anyone shall summon you or proceed against you in respect to these things, I myself will oppose his claim at my personal expense and cost. Let this handwriting be valid wherever produced. The thirteenth year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, the twenty-first of the month Sebastos.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich V, 354, 1944 -- BL VI, 82 (l. 23; 26)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
