<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Declaration of Property</title>
            <author>Sarapion son of Esouris</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1722</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1722</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.6.370</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;6;370</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;6;370</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12174</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12174</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12174-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 2977</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.45948-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>To Ammonios, the strategos of the division of Herakleides of the Arsinoite nome, and Harpokration also called Hierax, the royal secretary of the same division, and the secretary of the village of Karanis, and the registration officers of the same village, from Sarapion, son of Esouris, of the village of Karanis. There belong to the persons whose interests I represent, to Tasoucharion, whose father is unknown, her mother being Sarapias, an Antinoite, the  mother of the persons named below, a house and courtyard and a third share of another house in the village, and to Gaia Apolinaria and Gemellus Horion, her children, Antinoites, in common and equally, a house and two courtyards formerly the property of Valeria Diodora and a third share of two houses and two courtyards, and elsewhere a half share of a house and courtyard and of another courtyard, and elsewhere a house and courtyard, and two courtyards formerly the property of Gaius Longinus Apolinarius, veteran, and a house and courtyard formerly the property of Ptolemais, and elsewhere a third share of a house and courtyard, which I declare for the house by house registration of the past 28th year. Wherefore I submit the declaration.;(2nd hand) I, Ptolemaios, have received the copies of this declaration for examination.;(3rd hand) I, Isidoros, have also received the declaration.;(4th hand) I, Souchammon, have also received it.;(5th hand) I, Ptolemaios, have also received it.;(6th hand) The 29th year of Aurelius Commodus Antoninus Caesar the lord, Mesore 16.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Pearl OM-Youtie HC, PMich VI, 370, 1944</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
