<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Receipts for Money Taxes</title>
            <author>Ptole(--); Kastor; Apion; Sokr(--)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2296</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2296</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.6.383</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;6;383</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;6;383</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12186a 12186b 12186c 12186d 12186e 12186f</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12186 12186 12186 12186 12186 12186</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12186e-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4746</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.211265-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Recto);;The tenth year of the Emperor Caesar Nerva Traianus Augustus Germanicus Dacicus, Hathyr 30 . . . 29. Has paid to Ptol(  ), collector, Petheus son of Phaesis and Taseus and grandson of Sarapion, for syntaximon of the tenth year of Karanis, sixteen drachmai 6 chalkoi, 1 drachme 1 obol(?), = 16 drachmai 6 chalkoi, &lt;1 drachme 1 obol&gt;; for guard tax, 1 drachme 2 1/2 obols; Tybi . . . 23, eight drachmai, = 8 drachmai; Pharmouthi 30 . . . 27(?), twelve drachmai, = 12 drachmai; Pauni . . . 23, four drachmai, = 4 drachmai; for one half of the bath tax and others, 7 obols;  (2nd hand) and for syntaximon, four drachmai, = 4 drachmai; (1st hand) and in the eleventh year, month of Sebastos, for epikephalaion and for tax for the prison guards, two drachmai 4 obols, = 2 drachmai 4 obols.;(Marginal note to the left of the preceding lines) The tenth year, Hathyr 30 . . .  29, for epikephalaion of the ninth year, two drachmai 2 obols 2 chalkoi, = 2 drachmai 2 obols 2 chalkoi, and for one half of the bath tax, 7 obols.;;The eleventh year of Emperor Caesar Nerva Traianus Augustus Germanicus Dacicus, Hathyr 30 . . . 27. Has paid to Ptol(  ), collector, Petheus son of Phaesis and Taseus and grandson of Sarapion, for syntaximon of the same eleventh year of Karanis, sixteen drachmai, = 16 drachmai; for guard tax, 1 drachme 2 1/2 obols;  (3rd hand) Choiak &lt;. . .&gt;, eight drachmai 2 chalkoi, = 8 drachmai 2 chalkoi; and through Kastor and Apion, assistants, on Mecheir . . . 26, eight drachmai 1/2 obol, [=] 8 drachmai [1/2 obol];  (4th hand) Pharmouthi . . . 23, eight drachmai, = 8 drachmai, and through Ptole(  ), collector, . . . ., four drachmai, = 4 drachmai;  (5th hand) for guard tax, 2 obols; for one half of the bath tax, 1 drachme 2 chalkoi.;;The eleventh year of Emperor Caesar Nerva Traianus Augustus Germanicus Dacicus, Pharmouthi . . . 29, &lt;has paid&gt; through Kastor and Apion, assistants, Petheus son of Phaesis, for the tax of one-sixth on garden land of the tenth year of Psenarpsenesis, 800 copper drachmai; for transport of olives, 115 copper drachmai; for naubion, 80 copper drachmai; for additional charges, 200 copper drachmai; for acreage tax, 535 copper drachmai; for additional charges, 45 &lt;copper drachmai&gt;; for exchange, 35 &lt;copper drachmai&gt;; for geometria of the eleventh year, six drachmai 5 obols, = 6 drachmai 5 obols, and the additional charges.;;(6th hand) The twelfth year of Emperor Caesar Nerva Traianus Augustus Germanicus Dacicus, Pachon 23 for reckoning of the eleventh [year]. Has paid to Sokr(  ), . . ., Petheus son of Phaesis, for the tax of one-sixth on garden land of the eleventh year of Psenarpsenesis, two drachmai 4 obols; for transport of olives, 2 obols 2 chalkoi; for naubion, 1 obol 6 chalkoi; for additional charges, 4 obols; for acreage tax, 1 drachme 4 obols 6 chalkoi; for additional charges, 1 obol; for exchange, 6 chalkoi; for receipt &lt;. . .&gt;; for geometria, six other drachmai 4 obols, = 6 drachmai 4 obols; for additional charges 2 1/2 obols; for receipt &lt;. . .&gt;.;;(Verso);;(7th hand) The tenth year of Emperor Caesar Nerva Traianus Augustus Germanicus Dacicus, Pharmouthi 18. Has paid Petheus son of Phaesis and grandson of Sarapion for beer tax on individuals of Karanis, for the tenth year, in silver, four drachmai, = 4 drachmai; Epeiph 22, three drachmai 4 obols, = 3 drachmai 4 obols.;;(8th hand) The eleventh year of Emperor Caesar Nerva Traianus Augustus Germanicus Dacicus, Tybi 4. Has paid Petheus son of Phaesis for beer tax on individuals of the present eleventh year of Karanis, four drachmai, = 4 drachmai; Pachon 6, three other drachmai 4 obols, = 3 drachmai 4 obols.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Pearl OM-Youtie HC, PMich VI, 383, 1944, Pl. IIIb (Recto, Col. I)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
