<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Petition concerning Theft and Maltreatment</title>
            <author>Unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1688</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1688</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.6.421</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;6;421</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;6;421</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12260</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12260</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12260-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 2921</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.394832-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>. . . On the night of the . . . of Pharmouthi of the present [. . . year of . . .] Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus the Emperor, certain persons dug their way like thieves into the courtyard where we stable our donkeys and having effected an entrance drove off two full-grown white donkeys of mine valued at 280 drachmai; and concerning this matter I submitted a report to the archephodos of Karanis, Pankrates. With his help I loaded one donkey with water and another with food, and we set out, tracking the culprits from the place where we picked up their trail. We found that it led into the region of Bacchias and back into the desert, but just as we were on the point of taking the culprits in their own abode the archephodos of Bacchias, Pasion, and the (customs) guards stationed at the gate prevented us. They placed both me and the archephodos of Karanis under restraint, and after breaking the water jars and seizing our staves they kept us in confinement for three days, until we should be unable to lay hands on the culprits. Then having carried off our two packsaddles, the bread, a sheepskin, and two fodder bags(?), they also beat me. The village secretary and the elders spoke with them and compelled them to release us. I beg that you come to my assistance.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Pearl OM-Youtie HC, PMich VI, 421, 1944, Pl. VI -- BL VII, 111 (date); VIII, 214 (l. 3 and date); IX, 160 (line 16).</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
