<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lease of a Bakery</title>
            <author>Herakleides, son of [- - -]</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2928</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2928</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.10.586</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;10;586</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;10;586</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12273</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12273</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12273-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 673</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.445862-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>[- - - has leased to - - - and - - -, Persians of the epigone], and mutual sureties for recovery, in the yard belonging to Herakleides in the same village, and therein a Theban millstone with nether millstones and a grinding handle, and one mortar and one oven. The lease is for two years from the above-mentioned date, for the purpose of baking, if the lessees wish, on condition that the lessees pay to Herakleides on account of rent in entirety for the above-mentioned premises annually eighty silver drachmai free from every deduction. It shall not be permissible for the lessees to abandon the lease, but the lessees shall deliver the rental indicated to Herakleides in four equal installments, in Tybi, Pharmouthi, Pauni, and Epeiph, in every case on the twentieth, viz. twenty silver drachmai per installment, the right of execution resting with Herakleides against the lessees and against all their property as if in accordance with a legal judgment, the lease being guaranteed by Herakleides. Signatory for the lessees: Diodoros, son of Ptolemaios, with a scar on the right foot. (2nd hand) We, Petesouchos and Sochotes, both sons of Petesouchos, Persians of the epigone, and mutual sureties for recovery, have leased in accordance with all the aforesaid terms. Diodoros, son of Ptolemaios, wrote for them, as they are illiterate.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Browne GM, PMich X, 586, 1970, Pl. III</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
