<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Antichretic Loan </title>
            <author>Katoites and Petesouchos, sons of Horos, and their mother</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1327</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1327</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.11.605</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;11;605</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;11;605</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12282</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12282</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12282-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 119</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.34396-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>[- - -] with a scar under [- - - acknowledge] to Harmas, son of Ptolemaios, [- - -], that Katoites and Petesouchos have received forthwith from Hermas sixty drachmai in coined silver of the Augusti, from hand to hand, out of the house; and instead of the interest thereon the parties of the first part have agreed with Hermas that he and his ignees and whomever he wishes shall live in the property belonging to the parties of the first part by inheritance from their father, owned in common and undivided with him, Hermas; viz., four twenty-sevenths of the house(?) with all its appurtenances; and the parties of the first part and their assignees shall guarantee to Hermas and his assignees the rights of this habitation with full guarantee; and let them present the property free from all debt public and private, and see to it that nolays claim to the property or to a part thereof, or prevents &lt;Hermas and his assignees from living in the property or letting others live there and collecting the rent and using its appurtenances without hindrance.&gt; And if it be shown that Hermas has undergone expense for repair or construction and the parties of the first part wish to make repayment, let them do so along with the above stated sum of money, the responsability resting on him, Hermas.;Signatory for the parties of the first part, (2nd hand) Heliodoros, son of Heliodoros, age about 44, with a scar on his right cheek.;We, Katoites and Petesouchos, the sons of Horos, and their mother . . ., daughter of Katoites, acting with her guardian, her daughter Soueris's husband Apollonios, son of Apollonios, acknowledge that we have received the sixty silver drachmai from Hermas from hand to hand, and instead of the interest we agree that he shall live in the property that has fallen to our share, four twenty-sevenths of a house(?), and we will guarantee it, and if he be shown to have undergone expense for repair or construction we will make repayment, the responsibility resting on him as stated above. Heliodoros, son of Heliodoros, wrote on their behelf, as they are illiterate.;(3rd hand) Hermas, son of Ptolemaios. I have received the receipt as stated.;(4th hand) Registered in the Bacchias grapheion.;;(Verso);;Agreement of Katoites and others with Hermas, about habitation.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Shelton JC, PMich XI, 605, 1971 -- L. 18: read Souerios inst of Thauerios. (PH)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
