<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Hire of Scribes</title>
            <author>Diogenes, Euporos, Mystes, Marion, Sarapion, Sabinus, Herakleides, Harpokration, and Heliodoros, all scribes</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1422</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1422</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.11.603</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;11;603</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;11;603</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12281</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12281</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12281-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 140</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.496947-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Diogenes, Euporos, Mystes, Marion, Sarapion, Sabinus, Herakleides, Harpokration, and Heliodoros, the 9 scribes, to Marion and Herodes, secretaries of the metropolis, greetings.;Whereas we agreed with you, apart from the house-by-house registration, to draw up single copies of the population lists arranged person-by-person, lists of katoikoi, and lists of minors and of those excluded from the tax estimate; now also we have agreed to draw up single copies of population lists in summary for the same 18th year of Hadrian Caesar the lord, with you supplying whatever records of the 17th year we require for the compilation, on condition that once you receive the copies of the above-stated documents we shall not be detained(?) further for any purpose whatsoever. The transport and cost of the clean papyrus and the official deposition are to be incumbent on you, Marion, and yoru partner. We have received forthwith the salary agreed upon for the summary lists, as above stated, and the contracts we hold from each other are to remain valid. We have prepared this cheirograph in two copies. I, Diogenes, wrote this document.;(2nd hand) I, [Euporos], have agreed as stated.;(3rd hand) I, Sabinus, have agreed as stated.;(4th hand) I, Marion, have agreed as stated.;(5th hand) I, Mysthes, have agreed as stated.;(6th hand) I, Herakleides, have agreed as stated.;(7th hand) I, Sarapion, have agreed as stated.;(8th hand) I, Harpokration, have agreed as stated.;(9th hand) I, Heliodoros, have agreed as stated.;(10th hand) [Year 18] of Hadrianus the lord, Mecheir 10.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Shelton JC, PMich XI, 603, 1971, pl. I -- BL VII, 115 (l. 18); BL VIII, 216 (l. 36); BL XI, 132 (bibliography) Zingale LM, La vita privata e la vita pubblica, 14, 1992</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
