<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Receipt for Taxes on a Contract of Loan with Right of Habitation</title>
            <author>Valerius Apollonios andStatilius Apion, nomarchai</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1326</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1326</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12290</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12290</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;11;625</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12290-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 118</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.509673-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Recto);;Year six of the Emperor Caesar Traianus Hadrianus Augustus, the 22nd(?) of the month of Sebastos. Paid into the bank for the tax on property transfer located in Ptolemais Euergetis in the Arsinoite nome, to the account of the nomarchs Statilius Apion and Valerius Apollonios, by Tapekysis, daughter of Horos, the tax for entering into a habitation agreement and for "renewing" it, in a house(?) in the village of Bacchias belonging to the debtor Hermas, son of Ptolemaios, against the sum of three hundred drachmai, as verified from the list of abstracts of the village, volume 40 column 81(?) of the fourth year.;(2nd hand) Signed by me, Valerius Apollonios acting through my steward Isidoros. Tax paid by Tapechusis for entering into a habitation agreement and for "renewing" it, against the sum of three hundred drachmai.;(3rd hand) Signed by me, Statilius Apion acting through Ailourion also called Ammonios. Tax paid by Tapechusis for entering into a habitation agreement and for "renewing" it, against the sum of three hundred drachmai.;;(Verso, in circular stamp);;Year 5 of the Emperor Caesar Traianus Hadrianus Augustus.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Shelton JC, PMich XI, 625, 1971, Pl. VII -- (see also BL X, 126 about P.Mich. inv. 138); BL XI, 133 (complete edition of P. Mich. inv. 138, cf. BL X, 126)</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
