<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Request for Provisional Registration of a Property</title>
            <author>Aurelia Tapais, daughter of Papnouthis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1560</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1560</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.12.627</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;12;627</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;12;627</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12292</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12292</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12292-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 197</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.417131-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>To Aurelius Horion, senator and archivist of the registry of real property of the Arsinoite nome (2nd hand) from Aurelia Tapais, daughter of Papnouthis and Thaisas, from the [village] of Philadelphia of the division of Herakleides, acting without a guardian in accordance with the customs of the Romans in virtue of the ius liberorum. I purchased (in accordance with a contract) drawn up here in the Arsinoite nome on the present day a building of one story, formerly a mill, in which there is a dilapidated yard, located in the same village of Philadelphia, at a price of three thousand drachmai of silver, equal [three thousand drachmai], from Aurelius Titus Valerius Gaianus, son of Titus Valerius Satrianus also called Serenus and of Iulia, Antinoite and however he is styled, not registered. Accordingly, I submit the application that a provisional entry be made in accordance with the copy of the contract of sale which I have deposited. For when I submit the declaration for this property, I shall show that it belongs to me and is unencumbered and unclaimed by anyone, but if the building should appear to belong to another or to be subject to a previous claim through the record office, there shall be no hindrance from the present entry.;(1st hand) Aurelius Horion, senator and archivist of the registry of real property of the Arsinoite nome . . .</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Browne GM, HSCP 75, 177-180, 1971, Plate Browne GM, PMich XII, 627, 1975 -- BL VIII, 216 (l. 7); BL X, 216 (l. 2). - L. 2: Papnouth[ios] is to be preferred to Patermouthios (suggested in P.Graux II, p. 50); Aurelia Tapais in P.Graux II, 17-19, may then not be identical with the homonymous woman in P.Mich. XII, 627 and P.Wisc. II, 58-59. (PH)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
