<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Copy of a Will</title>
            <author>Tithoues the elder, son of Petaus</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1675</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1675</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12337</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12337</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;18;785A</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12337-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 2899</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.432894-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>[Year eight of . . . Claudius] Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, the 3rd of the month Dystros, Tybi 3, in Ptolemais [Euergetis of the Arsinoite nome]. Tithoues the elder, son of Petaus, about forty-three(?) years old, with a scar on his right shin, [acknowledges to have divided after his death] to his own children, Petaus, Thaesis and Tamystha, all three born to him [of his wife Tapetsiris, daughter of] Pnepheros, [with whom he lives together (according to the laws)], and to Tapetsiris herself: to his male son Petaus, the [paternal] catoecic allotment of one and a half aroura out of three arourai which the acknowledging party owns jointly and undivided [with his brother, Tithoues, in one] parcel without a village impost(?), which belongs [to the acknowledging party, Tithoues, in the village of Karanis(?)]; and to the same son Petaus also [the half share of his paternal] house which belongs to him, [the acknowledging party, jointly and undivided] and the half [share] which belongs  to the same acknowledging party, in Karanis, of maternal building plots, [which the acknowledging party  owns jointly and undivided with] his brother, Tithoes; and to the same son Petaus also of the [animals] that belong [to the acknowledging party, Tithoues, a female donkey] and the accompanying female foal; and to the same son Petaus and to his [daughters (Thaesis and Tamystha) in common and equally, to each a] third part, the [miscellaneous] sheep of the flock [with a total number of - - - and the] accompanying lambs and kids which belong to the acknowledging party; the aforementioned wife of the acknowledging party (Tapetsiris) [will be entitled to have the right of occupation of the aforementioned house and] whatever he will leave in the way of utensils and furniture and sums due to him in any [way whatsoever and the revenues] of the parcels of catoecic land which the acknowledging party cultivates from the present [8th year on. In exchange for the resulting] revenues, his wife Tapetsiris will settle [all kinds of debt which] the acknowedging party has [in whatever way, having(?)] the usufruct of them. The products and the revenues of the goods divided to the [children will go to Tapetsiris after having been collected by(?)] Petaus, which goods Tapetsiris will hand over after a period of five years, free from [all] public charges [and every expense - - -] [[disposing of nothing of the goods divided to the children]] [and I appoint her and Aphrodisios as legal(?)] and independant (guardians), and she shall, however, alienate simply nothing on the basis of a disposal [of the goods divided to the children without(?)] the consent [of the heirs(?)]. Tapetsiris, daughter of Pnepheros, about 41 years old, with a scar on her right forearm, with as guardian her brother [- - - about . . . years old, with a scar on his] right [. . .], and Aphrodisios, about 55(?) years old, with a scar on his right shin.;[Year 8 of . . . Claudius Caesar Augustus] Germanicus Imperator, Tybi 3. Registered through the record-office in Ptolemais Euergetis</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn PJ, PMich XVIII, 785A, 1996, Pl. XXV</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
