<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>list of names</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2991</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2991</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.petaus.93</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0185;;93</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.petaus;;93</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12705 12706</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12705 12706</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12705-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 6884</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.862413-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>" (Col. i):;Ischyrion, son of Sarapion, grandson of Ischyrion, mother Soumenis;;Phaesis, with the nick-name Kerset, his brother;;-----;Aphrodas, son of Touanis, metropolite, mother Soumenis;;Pa . . . , son of Ischyrion, grandson of Stephanos, mother Sarapous;;Paesis, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Artemas, mother Sambathion;;-----;Ischyrion, son of Kephalas, grandson of Meiouris, mother Thermouthis;;Kephalas, his son, mother Sarapous;;-----;Pnepheros, son of Deios, grandson of Isidoros;;-----;Chaireas, from Kaine, linen-weaver;;Bassos, his brother, likewise;;-----;Ischyrion, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Mystharion, mother Thermouthis;;Ischyrion, his son, mother Taptollis, metropolite;;Isidoros, another;;Patas, another;;Heras, another;;-----;Kloris, son of Phasis, grandson of Kastor, mother Heraklous;;Neseus, his son, metropolite;;-----;Kollouthos, son of Didymos, grandson of Didymos;;-----;Akiaris, mender;;-----;Malis, son of Malis, grandson of Heraklas, mother Thermouthis;;-----;Pnepheros, son of . . ., grandson of . . ., mother . . .;;-----;Akiaris, [     ];;. . .;;(col. ii);Ischyrion, son of Sarapion, grandson of Didymos, mother Isis nick-named Tkaria;;Akiaris, son of Maron, gardener;;-----;Apynchis, son of Papontos, grandson of Apynchis, mother Thaubas;;-----;Apynchis, son of Dioskoros, grandson of Komon, mother Demos;;-----;Phaesis, son of Touamis, mother Apollomous;;Kallas, his brother with the same mother, nick-named Phillamon;;Sansneus, another brother nick-named Anabok;;-----;Ischyrion, son of Heras, grandson of Heras, mother Heras;;Apynchis, his brother with the same mother;;Phasis, another brother with the same mother;;Pnepheros, son of Ischyrion, mother Achnes;;Penoupis, his brother with the same mother;;Heras, son of Apynchis, mother Taseaipis;;-----;Penneis, donkey-driver from the Oxyrhynchite nome;;Poualis, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Pholemis, mother Soumeis, nick-named Pouro;;-----;Hatres, son of Heraklas, grandson of Heron, mother Ammonia;;Peteeus, his brother with the same mother;;-----;Syros, son of Sambathion, grandson of Syros, mother Herais, gardener;;Ischyrion, his son, mother Akousarion;;-----;Tourbon, son of Heras, grandson of Heras, mother . .eus;;. . .a, nicknamed Sarapion, his son, mother Sambathion;(2nd hd.) . . ., nick-named Hilario;;-----;(1st hd.) Antonius, son of Maron;;Sansneus, his son, mother Sarapias;;-----;(col. III);Sokras, fatherless, mother Taphaeis;;Heraklas, his brother;;-----;Hatres, son of Sambas, grandson of Ischyrion, mother Sambous, nick-named Nana;;Deios, son of Ploution, mother Didyme;;-----;Ischyrion, son of Atha, grandson of Maron, nick-named Gonkos, mother Thermouthis;;Deios, his brother, nick-named Maxima;;-----;Ischyrion, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Sokrates, nick-named Os;;-----;Ischyrion, son of Hermeias, grandson of Ischyrion, mother Sambous, nick-named Stroma;;-----;Heraklas, son of Rufus, mother Didis, under-age;;Aphrodas from Arsinoe;;Ischyrion, his sin;;Onnophris, another (son);;-----;Ischyrion, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Sambas, mother Ischyriaine, nick-named Asoubos;;Ischyrion, his son;;Ischyrion, son of Neseus, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Demos, nick-named Pkenna;;-----;Hatres, son of Hermeias, nick-named Kalaphelt, linen-weaver;;-----;Heron, son of Deios, grandson of Damas, mother Seeietos, nick-named Ourous;;-----;Neseus, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Maron, mother Diodora, greengrocer, nick-named Thienpee;;-----;Sambathion, son of Dioskoros, grandson of Dioskoros, mother Demos;;-----;Hatres, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Herakles, mother Charis;;-----;Piolis, son of Hatres, mender;;-----;Tou. . ., grandson of Pnepheros, mother ...rios;;(col. iv [38]);(in left margin: actuarius phylakeiou) Kronion, son of Pouaris alias Kynaros, nick-named Samanytis;;Ischyras, son of Ischyras, nick-named Korkodilos;;-----;Samaleis, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Piolis, mother Taphaseis;;-----;Phanias, son of Phimenis, grandson of Phanias, mother Soumeis;;Polemon, son of Pholemeus, mother Thensisois, nick-named Laberis;;-----;Sansneus, son of Ischyrion, mother Ammonia, metropolite;;-----;Heraklas, nick-named Mithini, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Ka..., mother Tap...(), nick-named Pou.();;-----;Peteeus, son of Hatres, grandson of Peteeus, mother Didyme;;-----;Hatres, his son, mother Tabous;;-----;Dionysios, son of Hermeias, grandson of Ischyrion, mother Sambous;;-----;Ischyrion, son of Psamis, grandson of Psamis;;-----;Neseus, son of Krolis;;-----;Deios, son of Papontos, grandson of Apynchis, mother Thaubas;;-----;Apollonios, son of Posis;;-----;Heron, son of Deios, grandson of Mysthes, mother Teenaus;;Helas, his brother, linen-weaver;;-----;Ischyrion, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Ph........s, mother Thenpetion, nick-named . . . ;;-----;Ischyrion, son of Ammonios, mother ...;;-----;Pamounis, fatherless, mother Tan...[]..s;;-----;(in left margin: stath())Serenos, son of Dioskoros, grandson of Komon, mother Demos;;Maron, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Artemas, mother Sambathion;;Pabok, son of Neseus, mother Soumeis;;-----;Paesis, mother Sambathion, nick-named Pares;;and from the horiodeiktes.;(verso, col. 1):;Ischyrion, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Mystharion, mother Thermouthis;;Ischyrion, his son;;Isisdoros, another son;;Patas, another son;;Heras, another son;;Deios, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Mystharion, nick-named Alasas;;Hatres, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Herakles, mother Charis;;(in left margin: guard) Aphrodas, son of Papontos, grandson of Aphrodas, underage;;Syros, son of ...audeios, grandson of Ammonios, mother Tapontos;;Chaireas, linen-weaver, from Kaine;;Bassos, his brother;;. . .;;. . .;;(col. ii);guards:;Neseus, son of Palamounis, grandson of Philammon, mother Tepheros;;Ischyrion, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Philotas, mother Thaesas;;(in left margin: the older) Apynchis, his brother;;Kephalas, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Kephalas, under-age;;(in left margin: not useable) Ischyrion, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Komon, mother Tamounis;;Heron, son of Deios, grandson of Damas, mother Seietos;;Benipis, son of Sansneus, grandson of Ischyrion, mother Artemis;;Hatres, son of Dioskoros, mother Taphaseis;;Kopres, son of Heras, grandson of Syros;;Panoupis, son of Ischyrion, mother Anches;;Pnepheros, son of Deios, grandson of Isidoros, mother Heras;;. . .;;. . .;;. . ., mother Tamysthe;;(in left margin: the older) S....s, Ischyrion, mother Didis, nick-named Penaths;;col. iii:;648;20 23 20 21 21;19 19 22 21 21 20 21;21 20 20 20 23 21 22;20 22 20 23 21 22;23 21 20 21 21;19;   648;(col. iv):;(in left margin: Neseus) Peteeus, son of Ischyrion, mother Thaubastis, nick-named alias Salytouaphios, metropolite;;Ischyrion, son of Neseus, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Demos, nick-named Kenna;;(Pnepheros) Abillas, son of Petenoupis, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Taorsenouphis, nick-named Smel;;Dioskoros, son of Komon, grandson of Dioskoros, mother Tepheros;;Peteeus, son of Hatres, grandson of Peteeus, mother Didyme;;Apynchis, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Philotas, mother Thaesis;;Syrion, son of Apynchis, grandson of Sambathion, mother Sarapous;;Kalos, son of Papontos, grandson of . . . , mother Tapontos;;Damas, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Demetrios, mother Tapes;;Phaesis, son of Pasis, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Demetrous;;Malis, son of Malis, grandson of Heraklas, mother Thermouthis;;(in left margin: brother) [[Ischyrion, son of Pitreus, grandson of Ischyrion, mother Tabous]];;Sansneus, son of Touameus, mother Apollonous;;(in left margin: brother) Touanis, son of Harphaesis, grandson of Ischyrion, mother Tasos;;Hatres, son of Sambas, grandson of Ischyrion, mother Sambous;;Pantonymos, son of Heraklas, mother Thermouthis;;Sansneus, son of Ischyrion, mother Ammonia;;Syros, son of Kronion, grandson of Mysthes, mother ......;;Euporas, son of Pebaus, grandson of Ischyrion, mother ....;;Akaris, mender;;Onnophris, his son;;Peteeus, son of Heraklas;;(col. v);Heron, son of .......;;Neseus, son of Palamoneus. . .;;Theon, . . . . . ;;Naaraus, son of Haratheios, grandson of Haratreios, mother Tasouchas;;Sisois, fatherless, mother Taonnophris."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Hagedorn U - Hagedorn D - Youtie LC - Youtie HC, PPetaus, 93, 1969</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
