<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Pilot's Receipt</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">princeton.apis.p624</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NjP)apis.p0624</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.princ.2.26</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0192;2;26</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.princ;2;26</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12826</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12826</idno>
            <idno type="filename">12826-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">AM 8930</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:26.083052-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>To the sitologoi of Philadelphia, in the Heracleides division of the Arsinoite nome from Achais, son of Phathres, the son of Petephnouthis, from around the village of Athra [l. 5] of the Prosopeite nome, with the guarantee of Didymos, who is also called Hermeios, and with the assistance of the clerk Serenus, son of Didymos, son of Althaieus.  I, a pilot of three ships with the following cargo:   8700 artabas, with one entry for the one percent tax, 87 1/2 artabas and with the one and a half percent tax being 43 1/2, [l. 10] totals 8830 1/2 artabas.  According to which he has willingly unloaded 200 artabas, with the one percent tax being 2 artabas, and the one and a half percent, 1 artaba, which totals 203 artabas of wheat.  What remains for the embole is 8500 artabas, with the one percent tax being 85 artabas, and the one and a half percent 42 1/2, which totals 8627 1/2  [8827 1/2, pap.]. [l. 15] At the command of Domittius Rufus, procurator of Neapolis, I agree to have had measured and loaded (the cargo) by you at the harbor of Kerke, so that it can be conveyed to Alexandria for the administration of Neapolis, [l. 20] at the instruction of Ptolemaios, royal scribe of the Themistes division, who is serving in the place of both the strategos and [l. 25] the royal scribe of the Heracleides division.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Princ. II 26 <note>BL VIII, 283</note>
               </bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
