<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Cession of Catoecic Land</title>
            <author>Apollonios &amp; Didymos, sons of Apollonios</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1372</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1372</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.252</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">15159</idno>
            <idno type="TM">15159</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;252dupl</idno>
            <idno type="filename">15159-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1287</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.387842-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>We, Apollonios and Didymos, both sons of Apollonios, acknowledge that we have ceded to Zenon, son of Ptolemaios, to him and to his heirs and assigns, for transference from the aforesaid day forever, from the four arourai, or as many as there may be, of the catoecic allotment that belongs to us, inherited from our father, near Talei in Polemon, two arourai on the east side, including the barley already sown this year; and we shall transfer it, measured by the ninety-six-cubit schoinion with the correct carpenter's wooden cubit measure on the foundation wall in Phremei. The neighbors of the two arourai that have been ceded are on the south the allotment of Taorseus, daughter of Chairemon, with a drain between; on the north the vineyard of Mystharion, son of Pyrrhos, and the allotment of Alkimos; on the west our remaining two arourai; and on the east the allotment of the purchaser Zenon, on condition that the irrigation and the drainage shall be carried on according to past custom. And we have received a sum of money for the cession and guarantee it with every guarantee from public encumbrances and from surtaxes and the artab tax and the naubion tax and the arithmetica and from all other imposts from the past time up to the twelfth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus and for the present twelfth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, and from every claim forever. The wife of Apollonios, Tapaeis, also called Tapitynis, daughter of Peteeus, and the wife of Didymos, Taorseus, daughter of Mieus, with their husbands as guardians consent to the sale and agree not to proceed against it. Herodes, son of Herodes, wrote for them, because Apollonios is illiterate and Didymos writes rather slowly.;(2nd hand) I, Didymos, ordered him to write on the aforesaid conditions, and have joined in receiving the money and in making the guarantee, as aforesaid.;(3rd hand) Zenon, son of Ptolemaios. The cession of the two catoecic arourai was made to me on all the aforesaid conditions.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 252, 1944 -- BL III, 115 (l. 10); BL IX, 160 (l. 8). - L. 2-3: in an unpublished note, H.C. Youtie understands "syn toi ephe;teoi krithinoi sporoi" as "including the barley already sown this year" (rather than as "with a year's supply of barley seed"), and dates the papyrus of 26-27 A.D. (rather than 25-26 A.D.), between the sowing and the harvest, as did the editor of P.S.I. VIII, 905. (PH)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
