<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Loan on Security</title>
            <author>Orseus, son of Kollouthos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3092</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3092</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.328</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;328</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;328</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">15160</idno>
            <idno type="TM">15160</idno>
            <idno type="filename">15160-2</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 723</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.013654-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Recto, col. I);;I, Orseus, son of Kollouthos, acknowledge that I have sold to Orseus the elder, son of Kollouthos, whose mother is Tereus and who is my brother on both my father's and my mother's side, the three-story house that belongs to me, and the courtyard and all the appurtenances, in Talei, the neighbors of the house and court being on the south the house of Nestnephis, on the north the royal road, on the west the house of the same Nestnephis, and on the east the house of Pelemasis. And I have received from Orseus the entire price agreed upon, in full, from hand to hand, out of the house, and I guarantee the sale with every guarantee. My son Kollouthos consents to this sale and agrees not to proceed against it forever, or to make any claim as aforesaid. Patynion, son of Herakles, wrote for them because they are illiterate.;;(Col. II);I, Orseus, son of Kollouthos, and my son Kollouthos, both Persians of the epigone, sureties for each other for the payment, have received from Orseus the elder, son of Kollouthos, a loan amounting to four hundred and twenty drachmai of minted silver, at the interest of one drachme per mina per month, which money we will repay in the month of Neos Sebastos of the ensuing seventeenth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus as aforesaid. Patynion, son of Herakles, wrote for them because they are illiterate.;;(Verso);16th year. Contract (made) by Kollouthos, of Talei, to the president of Matres(?). Keep it until Mecheir to receive from . . . [- - -]</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 328, 1944, Pl. V (verso only)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
