<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Official Correspondence</title>
            <author>Unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2274</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2274</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">15691</idno>
            <idno type="TM">15691</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.turner;;23</idno>
            <idno type="filename">15691-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4714</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.60123-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>[- - - To Aelius] Sarapion(?), strategos of [the Herakleides division] of the Arsinoite nome, [- - -] . . . alias Proclus [- - -]. Regarding a letter written to Serenus, former strategos, and turned over to you with unfinished business, (a letter) by Herennius Pansa, former epitropos of Caesar(?), concerning mortgages brought in by Valerius Marion on behalf of Zenon, tax-collector at the border post of Syene, was written to the strategoi [as follows(?)]: I have subjoined a copy of a letter written to me by Tyrannus Crispinus Eueides, oikonomos of our lord Caesar in accordance with a statement of Valerius Marion about mortgages on behalf of Zenon, tax-collector at the border post of Syene, on property in your nome. Attend to (the security?) and lest it be encumbered for another person, (appraise it?) and up to the full (valuation?) safeguard the amount of the revenues . . . and maintain a lien on (the property) through the record-offices in your nome, and report both to me and to Eulalos the tabularius, and to the oikonomoi. I pray for your health. Seventh year of the Emperor Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrianus Antoninus Augustus Pius, Mecheir 28.;         Tyrannus Crispinus Eueides, to the epitropos Herennius Pansa, vir egregius, greetings [- - -]</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Pearl OM, P.Turner, 23, 1981, Pl. X</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
