<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter to the Praefectus Annonae Alexandrinae</title>
            <author>Flavius Claudius Patricius</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2136</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2136</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.turner.45</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0214;;45</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.turner;;45</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">15703</idno>
            <idno type="TM">15703</idno>
            <idno type="filename">15703-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4022</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.117284-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Copy. Flavius Claudius Patricius, clarissimus praefectus annonae Alexandriae, to the exactor of the Oxyrhynchite nome, greeting. Know that in accordance with the report which you sent to the office one thousand nine hundred and forty-three artabas of wheat for the 2nd indiction have been brought to the sacrd granaries in the vicinity of Alexandria from the nome under your administation through Horion, son of Ptolemaios and Hesychios, son of Ioulianos and their associate supervisors, through the skippers named below: on the day before the nones of April eight hundred and ninety and a half artabas, and on the fourth day before the ides of the same month one thousand and fifty-two and a half artabas, in the consulship of our lord Gratianus, eternal Augustus, for the third time and of count Fl. Equitios, vir clarissimus; and (know further that) these are being entered into the accounts with a subscription by Agathos Daimon, Megetios, Nemesion, and Asklas, receivers in the civil service (?). My devotion has been informed by a report (made) at their own risk by Arios and Isidoros, tabularii of the office, Epimachos and Proechios, oikonomoi, and Dionysios, auditing (?) assistant, of which a copy is appended, and I have ordered that these facts be written in reply to you in consideration of the payment. Farewell.;To wit: through Paomios, 890 1/2 art.; through Paabeus, 1052 1/2 art.;Fl. Isisdoros, tabularios: the stated quantity of wheat, amounting to one thousand nine hundred and forty-three artabas, is accurate as stated.;I , Fl. Nemesion, receiver, have signed the receipt for the wheat,  amounting to one thousand nine hundred and forty-three artabas exactly.;Fl. Epimachos, oikonomos: the stated quantity of wheat,  amounting to one thousand nine hundred and forty-three artabas, is accurate.;Fl. Ammonios, assistant: it is accurate,  amounting to one thousand nine hundred and forty-three artabas of wheat exactly.;(m. 2) I, Aurelios Serapion, supervisor, have received together with my associates the original receipt of which you presented this copy, as stated.;(back) ( m. 3?) Paymios 890 1/2 art. wheat and Paabeus 1052 1/2 art. wheat, skippers, for the 2nd indiction.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Shelton JC, PTurner, 45, 1981, Pl XX -- BL X 278</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
