<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Application for Admission of a Boy in the Gymnasial Class</title>
            <author>Aurelius Seuthes</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1549</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1549</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.14.676</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;14;676</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;14;676</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">15708</idno>
            <idno type="TM">15708</idno>
            <idno type="filename">15708-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1935</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.539224-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>[- - -] Marcus Aurelius Thonis, his mother being Thermouthion, being 14 years old in the present 3rd year, with no scar, 
               apprentice [- - -]. Therefore, having come for his examination, I declare that the great-grandfather of the grandfather 
               of him who is coming forward, Apollonios, was selected at the selection of those from the Gymnasium, which took place in 
               the 5th year of the deified Vespasian in the Broadstreet quarter in accordance with the proofs produced by him and that 
               the great-grandfather of his father, Dionysios(?), also known as [- - -], coming forward was selected in the 4th year of 
               the deified Trajan in the said quarter and that his great-grandfather Diogenes coming forward was selected in the 11th 
               year of the deified Aelius Antoninus in the said quarter and that his grandfather Amous - - - coming forward was selected 
               in the 21st year of the deified Commodus in the said quarter and his father Kopreus coming forward was selected in 
               the 5th(?) year of the reign after the deified Severus Antoninus upon the aforesaid proofs in the Lycians' Camp quarter 
               and that the great-grandfather of the great-grandfather of the mother of him (Thonis) who is coming forward, Sarapion, 
               the son of Theoninos, belongs in the category of those selected in the 3rd year and in the 4th year of Nero by Curtius 
               Paulinus, tribunus militum, in the Myrobalanus quarter, and that the great-grandfather of her grandfather, Theon, coming 
               forward was selected in the 4th year of Domitian in the said quarter and that the great-grandfather of her father, 
               Sarapion, coming forward was selected in the 15th year of the deified Trajan in the said quarter and that her 
               great-grandfather Euphellis coming forward was selected in the 21st year of the deified Aelius Antoninus in the said 
               quarter and that her grandfather Anti- - - coming forward was selected in the 32nd year of the deified Commodus in the 
               Myrobalanus quarter and that her father, Sarapion, coming forward was selected in the 4th year of the deified Alexander 
               upon the same proofs in the quarter of the North Street(?) I have furnished witnesses of (his) epikrisis and I swear by 
               the fortune of Aurelian Caesar, our lord, Augustus, that the aforesaid is true and that Thonis is by birth the son of 
               Kopreus and Thermouthion and that he is neither adopted nor supposititious and he has not availed himself of credentials 
               belonging to others or identity of names; otherwise may I be liable to the consequences of the oath. The 3rd year of the 
               Emperor Caesar Lucius Domitius Aurelian Gothicus Maximus Pius Felix Augustus, Mesore 11.;(2nd hand) I, Aurelius Seuthes, 
               have submitted this declaration and have sworn the oath as stated. I, Aurelius Didymos, also known as Sarapion, write for 
               him since he is illiterate. (3rd hand) I, Aurelius Sarapion, son of Diogenes, mother being Helen, from the city, witness 
               that Thonis is by birth the son of Kopreus and of Thermouthion, as stated. (4th hand) I, Aurelius Amois, son of 
               Aphynchios, mother being Aolis(?) [- - -], jointly witness regarding Thonis, as stated. (5th hand) I, Aurelius Justus, 
               son of Heraklammon, mother being Iseis, jointly witness regarding Thonis, as stated.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>McCarren VP, Diss, 1, 1975 McCarren VP, PMich XIV, 676, 1980, Pl. VI-VIII -- L. 12: read 3 (etei) kai 4 (etei) (as in P.Oxy. XLVI, 3279) rather than 3 (etei) kai 5 (etei). (PH)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
