<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Division of property</title>
            <author>Marcus Aurelius Herodes also called Lourios</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">berkeley.apis.170</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(CU)170</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.tebt.2.319</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0206;2;319</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.tebt;2;319</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">13478</idno>
            <idno type="TM">13478</idno>
            <idno type="filename">13478-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Tebt.0319</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:20.988389-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>To Aurelius Maximus also called Hermaiskos, priest, Archidikastes, and superintendent of the chrematistai and the other courts, from Marcus Aurelius Herodes also called Lourios, of Antinoe, and from Marcus Aurelius Sarapammon and however else he is styled. Whereas Aurelius Sarapammon and Lourios have come by succession of inheritance into possession of grain lands about the village of Kerkeosiris in the division of Polemon in the Arsinoite nome, viz. 7 arouras in two parcels, and near the village of Tebtunis in the same division in the place called Karion 7 arouras likewise, and near the village of Kerkesis 1 aroura, making a total of 15 arouras, which have hitherto been undivided, and they have now decided to divide these on the understanding that each should distinguish his own share, Aurelius Lourios and Aurelius Sarapammon now agree that they have divided the aforesaid arouras, and that of the 7 arouras near the village of Kerkeosiris each of them has received 3 1/2 arouras, of the 7 arouras near the village of Tebtunis each of them has received 3 1/2 arouras, and of the land near the village of Kerkesis each of them has received one half, so that each of them may henceforth possess and own the part that has fallen to him, viz. 7 1/2 arouras, and administer and dispose of them, each in whatever way he chooses; and that Aurelius Sarapammon has entire control of his property near the village of Theogonis, viz. 3 out of 6 arouras, because Lourios has sold his half share; and they have left as common property the 2 arouras belonging to them near the village of Tebtunis in the place called Pagagoros, until some decision shall be reached about them, and further settlement shall be made by them about whatever other property they find to appertain to the estate. And Aurelius Lourios shall not proceed against Aurelius Sarapammon on account of the house in the metropolis, having sold the half share belonging to him: and so on. The 5th year of the Philippi, Mecheir 9.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Tebt., II.319; Hunt, A.S. Sel.pap., v. 1, no. 53; Meyer, P.M. Juristische Papyri, No.53 <note>P. L. Bat. 30, p. 142-154.</note>
               </bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
