<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Achilleus' census declaration</title>
            <author>Achilleus, Son of Apollonios</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">berkeley.apis.273</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(CU)273</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.tebt.2.322</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0206;2;322</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.tebt;2;322</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">13481</idno>
            <idno type="TM">13481</idno>
            <idno type="filename">13481-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Tebt.0322</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:20.563706-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(6th h.) I, Apollonios also called Diogenes, have signed. (1st h.) To Ammonios, strategos of the division of Herakleides of the Arsinoite nome, and Harpokration also called Hierax, Basilikos Grammateus of the same division, and Mysthes and Heron, ex-scribes of the metropolis, from Achilleus son of Apollonios son of Lourios also called Apollonios, enrolled as a Katoikos, and already registered through another memorandum. I own in the Moeris quarter a share of a house and area, court, and hall, in which I further return the following inmates for the house-to-house registration of the past 28th year of Aurelius Commodus Antoninus Caesar the Lord, being inhabitants of the metropolis registered in the Syrian quarter, in which they were also returned in the house-to-house registration of the 14th year. They are Pasigenes son of Theon son of Eutyches, subject to poll-tax, a donkey-driver, aged 61 years, and his son Eutychos by Apollonous daughter of Herodes, aged 30, and the wife of Pasigenes, Herakleia daughter of Kronion, freedwoman of Didymos son of Heron, of the Treasuries' quarter, aged 40, and their daughter Thasis, aged 5, and Herakleia's children, Sabinos son of Sabinos son of Kronion, subject to poll-tax, a wool-carder, aged 18, and Sarapias, aged 22, returned in the former registration in the Treasuries' quarter, and the wife of Eutyches, who is his sister on the father's side, Tapesouris daughter of Isidora, aged 18. I accordingly present this statement. (2nd h.) Tapesouris owns in the Moeris quarter a sixth share, formerly her mother's, of a house. (1st h.) The 29th year of Aurelius Commodus Antoninus Caesar the Lord, Mesore 4th of the intercalary days. (3rd h.) Submitted to the strategos in the 29th year, Mesore 4th of the intercalary days. (4th h.) Submitted to the Basilikos Grammateus on the same day. (5th h.) Submitted to the scribes of the (metro)polis on the same day.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Tebt., II.322 <note>Census publications: R. S. Bagnall &amp; B. W. Frier, The demography of Roman Egypt. (1994)</note>
               </bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
