<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Petition to Prefect </title>
            <author>Ptolemaios son of Diodoros alias Dioskoros</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">wisconsin.apis.5409</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(WU)5409</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">apf.67.374</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0226;1;33</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">apf;67;374</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">13709</idno>
            <idno type="TM">13709</idno>
            <idno type="filename">13709-2</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Wisc. inv. 24</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:26.249546-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>To Marcus Petronius Honoratus Praefect of Egypt from Ptolemaios, son of Diodoros, alias Dioskoros, of veterans of the Arsinoites. I have, lord, attached below a copy of the petition and of the note written on it by you. The Sarapammon, mentioned below, says that he will not come even not to your most sacred court, not yet, in order that you learn what has been said by the strategus. If it seems right to your most benevolent fortune, order that it is written to the strategus of the division of Herakleides, whether Sarapammon is in the nome, or in the Herakleopolites, to take sufficient guarantee from him, that he appears before your most sacred tribunal. I have added a copy. To Marcus Petronius Honoratus praefect of Egypt from Ptolemaios, son of Diodoros, alias Dioskoros, of those of the Arsinoites. Of all the injustices in life the most infamous is that free persons become the victim of overweening pride and therefore, lord, I resort to you , take measures against the insolent way of acting. A certain Sarapammon in fact from the Herakleopolite nome from the village of [          ] held the strategus of the two divison  [             ]in contempt, so that he is in risk of his life. For that reason investigating his character and the time he has lived before this, I have found out that he used to be a village scribe and he has left [              ] I resorted to requesting before the most illustrious Mamertinus [              ] and yet, as such persons have been freed for affairs of state [      ] and [      ] to be strategi, that that is, to rule and to prevent and to crush, and to beat and give a thrashing and to flog the free-born like slaves. That is why I resort to you in order to obtain in your most free [         ] the coming to an end. May it now seem right to you to write the orders to the strategus of the division of Herakleides to take sufficient guarantee until [        ] your presence, in order that I obtain the satisfaction yielding results. Copy of the note. When I take cognizance after the [               ] to the strategus, I have written the 11th year 10th Thoth. Farewell. I, Ptolemaios, son of Diodoros, I submitted it.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn P.J., PWisc  I, 33, 1967, Plate XII</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
