<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<bibl xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
      xml:id="b82121"
      type="article"
      subtype="book"
      xml:lang="en">
  <title level="a" type="main">From Greek Lyric to Rap Song: A New Swiss Sappho? (An Impertinent Comparison). Translation by James Kierstead.</title>
  <author n="1">
      <forename>Claude</forename>
      <surname>Calame</surname>
   </author>
  <note resp="#BP">1. The comparative approach. - 2. From mélos to rap: an improbable comparison. - 3. Comparandum: Steff la Cheffe of Bern and Annabelle. - 4. Comparatum: Sappho of Lesbos and Helen of Troy [Fr. 16 V.]. - 5. From comparison of differences to comparison of similarities.</note>
  <relatedItem type="appearsIn">
      <bibl>
         <ptr target="http://papyri.info/biblio/80204"/>
         <!--ignore - start, i.e. SoSOL users may not edit this-->
         <title level="m" type="main">Donum natalicium digitaliter confectum Gregorio Nagy septuagenario a discipulis collegis familiaribus oblatum. A Virtual Birthday Gift Presented to Gregory Nagy on Turning Seventy by his Students, Colleagues and Friends.</title>
         <editor/>
         <date>2012</date>
         <!--ignore - stop-->
      </bibl>
  </relatedItem>
  <idno type="pi">82121</idno>
  <idno type="bp">2012-0336</idno>
  <idno type="bp_old">12/4/063</idno>
  <seg type="original" subtype="index" resp="#BP">364 Sappho</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="titre" resp="#BP">Calame Claude, From Greek Lyric to Rap Song: A New Swiss Sappho? (An Impertinent Comparison). Translation by James Kierstead.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="publication" resp="#BP">Victor Bers, David Elmer, Douglas Frame and Leonard Muellner (Edd.), Donum natalicium digitaliter confectum Gregorio Nagy septuagenario a discipulis collegis familiaribus oblatum. A Virtual Birthday Gift Presented to Gregory Nagy on Turning Seventy by his Students, Colleagues and Friends (Washington, D.C., 2012) s.p. [Uniquement accessible en ligne, en téléchargement gratuit: &lt; http://chs.harvard.edu/wa/pageR?tn=ArticleWrapper&amp;bdc=12&amp;mn=4606 &gt;.]</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="resume" resp="#BP">1. The comparative approach. - 2. From mélos to rap: an improbable comparison. - 3. Comparandum: Steff la Cheffe of Bern and Annabelle. - 4. Comparatum: Sappho of Lesbos and Helen of Troy [Fr. 16 V.]. - 5. From comparison of differences to comparison of similarities.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="nom" resp="#BP">Calame Kierstead</seg>
</bibl>
