<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<bibl xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
      xml:id="b82181"
      type="article"
      subtype="book"
      xml:lang="en">
  <title level="a" type="main">The Aiakidai, the Herald-less War, and Salamis.</title>
  <author n="1">
      <forename>Thomas</forename>
      <surname>Figueira</surname>
   </author>
  <note resp="#BP">1. The Aiakidai as ritual allies: The beginning of the "herald-less war"; - The nature of the Aiakidai; - The Delphic oracle and the foundation of the temenos of Aiakos at Athens; - The Aiakeion [refers to P. Oxy. XVII, 2087 (= M.-P.3 2120; LDAB 4806)]; - The Aiakidai as ritual allies at Salamis. - 2. To be an Aiakidês: The mythological paradigm; - To be an Aiakidês in Homer; - To be an Aiakidês in Hesiod; - To be an Aiakidês at Athens. - III. Summoning the Aiakidai as a moment in polis history.</note>
  <relatedItem type="appearsIn">
      <bibl>
         <ptr target="http://papyri.info/biblio/80204"/>
         <!--ignore - start, i.e. SoSOL users may not edit this-->
         <title level="m" type="main">Donum natalicium digitaliter confectum Gregorio Nagy septuagenario a discipulis collegis familiaribus oblatum. A Virtual Birthday Gift Presented to Gregory Nagy on Turning Seventy by his Students, Colleagues and Friends.</title>
         <editor/>
         <date>2012</date>
         <!--ignore - stop-->
      </bibl>
  </relatedItem>
  <idno type="pi">82181</idno>
  <idno type="bp">2012-0372</idno>
  <idno type="bp_old">12/4/132</idno>
  <seg type="original" subtype="index" resp="#BP">364 Glossaria</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="titre" resp="#BP">Figueira Thomas, The Aiakidai, the Herald-less War, and Salamis.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="publication" resp="#BP">Victor Bers, David Elmer, Douglas Frame and Leonard Muellner (Edd.), Donum natalicium digitaliter confectum Gregorio Nagy septuagenario a discipulis collegis familiaribus oblatum. A Virtual Birthday Gift Presented to Gregory Nagy on Turning Seventy by his Students, Colleagues and Friends (Washington, D.C., 2012) s.p. [Uniquement accessible en ligne, en téléchargement gratuit: &lt; http://chs.harvard.edu/wa/pageR?tn=ArticleWrapper&amp;bdc=12&amp;mn=4610 &gt;.]</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="resume" resp="#BP">1. The Aiakidai as ritual allies: The beginning of the "herald-less war"; - The nature of the Aiakidai; - The Delphic oracle and the foundation of the temenos of Aiakos at Athens; - The Aiakeion [refers to P. Oxy. XVII, 2087 (= M.-P.3 2120; LDAB 4806)]; - The Aiakidai as ritual allies at Salamis. - 2. To be an Aiakidês: The mythological paradigm; - To be an Aiakidês in Homer; - To be an Aiakidês in Hesiod; - To be an Aiakidês at Athens. - III. Summoning the Aiakidai as a moment in polis history.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="nom" resp="#BP">Figueira</seg>
</bibl>
