<bibl xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="b82669" type="article" subtype="book" xml:lang="it">
  <title level="a" type="main">The Relevance of the Dispute about the Photograph of the Konvolut for the Debate about the Artemidorus Papyrus.</title>
  <series>
    <title level="s" type="main">Colloquium</title>
  </series>
  <author n="1">
    <surname>Hammerstaedt</surname>
    <forename>Jürgen</forename>
  </author>
  <biblScope type="pp" from="221" to="230"/>
  <note resp="#BP">Appendice agli Atti del Convegno internazionale del 27 novembre 2009. - 1. The Artemidorus Papyrus and its alleged forgery. - 2. Dating the Artemidorus Papyrus and its texts and drawings. - 3. Is the Artemidorus Papyrus a fake? Preliminary considerations. - 4. The most important areas of dissent between those who suspect and those who defend the authenticity of the Artemidorus Papyrus. - 5. The debate about the Konvolut photo.</note>
  <relatedItem type="appearsIn">
    <bibl>
      <ptr target="http://papyri.info/biblio/82486"/>
      <!--ignore - start, i.e. SoSOL users may not edit this-->
      <title level="m" type="main">Intorno al Papiro di Artemidoro. II. Geografia e cartografia. Atti del Convegno internazionale del 27 novembre 2009 presso la Società Geografica Italiana, Villa Celimontana, Roma</title>
      <editor>Claudio Gallazzi</editor>
      <date>2012</date>
      <!--ignore - stop-->
    </bibl>
  </relatedItem>
  <idno type="pi">82669</idno>
  <idno type="bp">2012-0588</idno>
  <idno type="bp_old">13/1/103</idno>
  <seg type="original" subtype="index" resp="#BP">364 Artemidorus Geographus</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="titre" resp="#BP">Hammerstaedt Jürgen, The Relevance of the Dispute about the Photograph of the Konvolut for the Debate about the Artemidorus Papyrus.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="publication" resp="#BP">Claudio Gallazzi, Bärbel Kramer e Salvatore Settis (a cura di), Intorno al Papiro di Artemidoro. II. Geografia e cartografia. Atti del Convegno internazionale del 27 novembre 2009 presso la Società Geografica Italiana, Villa Celimontana, Roma = Colloquium (Milano, 2012) pp. 221-230, 1 fig.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="resume" resp="#BP">Appendice agli Atti del Convegno internazionale del 27 novembre 2009. - 1. The Artemidorus Papyrus and its alleged forgery. - 2. Dating the Artemidorus Papyrus and its texts and drawings. - 3. Is the Artemidorus Papyrus a fake? Preliminary considerations. - 4. The most important areas of dissent between those who suspect and those who defend the authenticity of the Artemidorus Papyrus. - 5. The debate about the Konvolut photo.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="nom" resp="#BP">Hammerstaedt</seg>
</bibl>