<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Affidavit of state farmers</title>
            <author>Petechon, son of Horos;Petesouchos, son of Arsenouphis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">oslo.apis.86</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NoOU)86</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.30.17666</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;30;17666</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">397761</idno>
            <idno type="TM">397761</idno>
            <idno type="filename">397761-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Oslo inv. 1468</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:31.203072-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(We swear by the Emperor Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus) to cultivate and to sow from the current 15th year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus the Imperator, the public land near Ptolemais Melissourgon in the meris of Polemon: (I) Petechon, son of Horus, (swear to cultivate) the parcels previously cultivated by Phasiyris, son of Phasipsemis, one and a half aruras on the north side, and likewise: (2) Petesouchos, son of Arsenouphis, one and a half arouras of (the land) about the same village, previously farmed by the same person, making (altogether) the three aruras formerly assigned to Phasiyrei, son of Phasipsemis, (land) for which we will measure out the appropriate annual public rentals, and (pay) the expenses in accordance with the other joint farmers, and we will not allow (the parcels) to be left unsown, whether unflooded or flooded. If we swear truly, may it be well with us, but if we swear falsely, the reverse. The nomographos of the village wrote on their behalf. The 15th year of Emperor Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus. Phaophi 14th.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
