<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<bibl xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
      xml:id="b80795"
      type="article"
      subtype="journal">
  <title level="a" type="main">with contributions by Mohammed Abdel Rahim, Louise Blanke, Darlene Brooks Hedstrom, Wendy Dolling, Father Maximous al-Anthony, Dawn McCormack, Mohammed Khalifa, Saad Mohammed, Peter Sheehan, Anna Stevens, and Nicholas Warner, Shenoute and a Recently Discovered Tomb Chapel at the White Monastery. Avec résumé en anglais.</title>
  <author n="1">
      <forename>Elizabeth S.</forename>
      <surname>Bolman</surname>
   </author>
  <author n="2">
      <forename>Stephen J.</forename>
      <surname>Davis</surname>
   </author>
  <author n="3">
      <forename>Gillian</forename>
      <surname>Pyke</surname>
   </author>
  <biblScope type="pp" from="453" to="473">453-473</biblScope>
  <note resp="#BP">In December 2009, conservation of the paintings in the triconch funerary chapel discovered by the SCA in 2002 at the White Monastery revealed new details that connect this space with Shenoute. It is likely that his monastic community originally designed this tomb and its associated church to function not only as the burial place for the saint, but also as a shrine dedicated to his memory.</note>
  <relatedItem type="appearsIn">
      <bibl>
         <ptr target="http://papyri.info/biblio/262"/>
         <!--ignore - start, i.e. SoSOL users may not edit this-->
         <title level="j" type="short">JECS</title>
         <!--ignore - stop-->
      </bibl>
  </relatedItem>
  <biblScope type="issue">18</biblScope>
  <date>2010</date>
  <idno type="pi">80795</idno>
  <idno type="bp">2010-0775</idno>
  <idno type="bp_old">12/2/031</idno>
  <seg type="original" subtype="index" resp="#BP">714 810</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="titre" resp="#BP">Bolman Elizabeth S., Stephen J. Davis and Gillian Pyke, with contributions by Mohammed Abdel Rahim, Louise Blanke, Darlene Brooks Hedstrom, Wendy Dolling, Father Maximous al-Anthony, Dawn McCormack, Mohammed Khalifa, Saad Mohammed, Peter Sheehan, Anna Stevens, and Nicholas Warner, Shenoute and a Recently Discovered Tomb Chapel at the White Monastery. Avec résumé en anglais.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="publication" resp="#BP">JECS 18 (2010) pp. 453-473, 10 figg. n./bl. et coul.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="resume" resp="#BP">In December 2009, conservation of the paintings in the triconch funerary chapel discovered by the SCA in 2002 at the White Monastery revealed new details that connect this space with Shenoute. It is likely that his monastic community originally designed this tomb and its associated church to function not only as the burial place for the saint, but also as a shrine dedicated to his memory.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="nom" resp="#BP">Bolman Davis Pyke Abdel Rahim Blanke Brooks Hedstrom Dolling al-Anthony McCormack Khalifa Mohammed Sheehan Stevens Warner</seg>
</bibl>
