<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Loan of money involving labour duties</title>
            <author>Aurelius, . . .</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2372</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2372</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.20.15043</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;20;15043</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;20;15043</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">38532</idno>
            <idno type="TM">38532</idno>
            <idno type="filename">38532-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 502</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.261221-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>"[From X to Y] greeting. I acknowledge that I have received [. . .] five gold solidi less six carats on the public standard of the said city, total 5 gold sol., which I will provide to you whenever I give up the irrigation of the said vineyard in stamped money as I received, without any delay or dispute or lawsuit or legal process, all my possession present and future being mortgaged to you as though by decree of court. The document (is) enforcceable and guaranteed and, having been questioned, I have given my consent. I, Aurelius . . ., the aforementioned, have drawn up this contract as writen above. I, Aurelius Iordanes, son of . . ., from Hermopolis, having been requested, have signed on his behalf because he does not know letters. (2nd hd) I, Aurelius Phoibammon, from Hermopolis, witness the document having had it read to me from the person who has drawn it up. (3rd hd) I, Aurelius Georgius, son of Achilleus, from Hermopolis witness the document having it read to me from the person who has drawn it up. (4th hd) Through Victor, by the Grace of God, public notary."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Gagos T, ZPE 79, 276-80, 1989, Pl VIII -- SB XX 15043 -- BL X, 233 (l. 16)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
