<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale on Delivery</title>
            <author>Makarios, son of Makarios, grandson of Herminos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">wisconsin.apis.5387</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(WU)5387</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.wisc.1.11</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0226;1;11</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.wisc;1;11</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">38681</idno>
            <idno type="TM">38681</idno>
            <idno type="filename">38681-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Wisc. inv. 82</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:26.237303-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Recto:;In the name of our lord and master Jesus Christ, our god and savior, the 8th Epeiph of the approved current fourth indiction. I, Makarios, son of Makarios, grandson of Herminos from the estate of Taruthis, the great, from the Oxyrhynchite Nome, signing below with his own hand, to you, Severus, carpenter, son of Severus, from this town of Oxyrhynchos, greetings. I declare having received from you without delay for my necessary need one gold solidus, containing twenty-two and a half carats, in total 1 gold solidus, containing 22 1/2 carts and I declare that I shall supply you for this with twenty-five jars of four sextarii each with wine from the vintage in the month of Mesore of the present fourth indiction from the vintage of the D.V. fifth indiction. We wait up to and including the month of Tybi for the purifying of the wine. I have sworn  to the almighty god and the salvation of those who reign my consent. I, Makarios, son of Makarios, grandson of Herminos, it pleases me, as it is written above. By me, Victor, son of Schedias, it was drawn up.;;Verso: From Makarios, son of Makarios, grandson of Herminos from the estate of Taruthis, the great, from the Oxyrhynchos nome I gold solidus containing 22 1/2 carats.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn P.J., PWisc  I, 11, 1967, Plate IV</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
