<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.16/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
     n="0097;;7"
     xml:id="p.corn.7"
     xml:lang="en">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>p.corn.7</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">p.corn.7</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0097;;7</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.corn;;7</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10608</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10608</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Duke Databank of Documentary Papyri. This work is licensed under a <ref type="license" target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p/>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
          <change when="2013-11-21T12:03:39.733-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Finalized - Ready. In line 1 I kept the addition of the diaeresis but removed the designation as a new reading. The argument for it is in the editorial history. I also chose to leave Claytor's suggestion of Φαήσ̣ε̣ω̣(ς) in line 6. The doubts and discussion of exactly what can be read is likewise in the history of the suggestions made.</change>
          <change when="2013-11-21T12:03:39.724-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/pheilpor">Vote - AcceptText - Accept text. I agree that Φαήσεως, with the suggested prosopographical link, is much better than the unsupported Φαήρμιος, though I still have some doubt about the exact spelling (it might be Φαή&lt;σ&gt;ε̣ω̣(ς) as suggested in Claytor's original comment). Line 13, underdot the omicron of ὑπὸ in the BL reading (BL has ὑπ(ὸ) from Schubart and ὑπὸ̣ from Vitelli; the later is better from the photograph). I'm not sure whether the diaeresis on the iota of Τραιανοῦ (l. 1 and 14) should really be marked as a new reading (other times, other editorial standards; and, as Claytor points out, it overloads the apparatus). While we are at it, a supralinear should be added on the day numbers in l. 2 (κθ/κε) and on the year number in line 14 (ζ) - but not, as far as I can see on the online image, on the day number of line 15. </change>
          <change when="2013-11-21T12:03:39.712-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/simoeis">Vote - AcceptText - This satisfies my concerns, and I agree that κθ is the better reading in ln2.</change>
          <change when="2013-11-21T12:03:39.681-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/simoeis">Vote - ReturnToSender - I am OK with reading Φαήσ̣ε̣ω̣(ς).  As Claytor states, the bowl-shaped traces fit sigma, and I believe that it is followed by the peak of a very cursive epsilon, then omega.  I agree however with Sosin that the change in line 2 needs a sentence of justification.  From a paleographical standpoint, I think I prefer theta over epsilon, but why has Claytor made the change.</change>
          <change when="2013-11-21T12:03:39.652-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/joshuad.sosin">Vote - ReturnToSender - Return for clarification/explanation. Lin2=&gt;? 〚.1〛 ; lin3=&gt; \〚.4〛/ ; lin2 &lt;:&lt;#κθ=29#&gt;=PN W.G. Claytor (autopsy)|ed|&lt;#κε=25#&gt;:&gt; I urge returning to Claytor with invitation to justify the new reading/date a more fully. Is there cause beyond palaeography to prefer 29 over 25? It is not obvious to me from the APIS image that the letter following κ is not an ε as in ἔντο at lin6. Reality may be much clearer on the original. A bit more explanation on this point seems warranted. The rest is all clear. lin10=&gt; ἀποδῦ ;</change>
          <change when="2013-09-16T15:42:23.463-04:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/gclaytor">Resubmission.  I have addressed the editors' comments by adding commentary to ll. 2 and 6 and have corrected Leiden+ errors.  I was unable to add links in the commentary b/c of a bug (?): whenever I selected the volume, then volume number, all the fields would go grey and I couldn't selected an individual text.  I tried this both through the DDB and HGV fields.</change>
          <change when="2013-08-14T16:04:24.08-04:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/gclaytor">added corrections from BL 2.2 with some of my own from autopsy.&#xD;
&#xD;
The name Φαήρμ(ιος), attested only here, has been tentatively read as a form of the common name Φάησις.  The ed.'s rho does not seem likely, since elsewhere the tail of rho comes straight down or has a slight hook (although cf. Τραιανοῦ, l. 14), and the ligature to the next letter seems to come from high on the letter, which is unlikely for rho, but fits sigma (cf. Σαμβαθίῳ l. 4) or epsilon. On the other hand, fitting σεω in after Φαη seems difficult, and it seems somewhat hazardous to suggest Φαή&lt;σ&gt;ε̣ω̣(ς) vel sim. when there's so much abrasion.  &#xD;
&#xD;
The name Phaesis, however read, is perhaps guaranteed by the Tax Rolls, which have a Phaesis s. of Pekmeis (alias Heuremon) and Sambathion (P.Mich. IV.2, p. 244), who's also probably found in BGU 15 2498 (143/4?).  This is likely the son of the Pekmeis in this document, who's acting as kyrios for his wife Sambathion.&#xD;
&#xD;
The other changes are minor; the app. crit. seems a bit overloaded when adding diaereseis, but they weren't in the original edition.&#xD;
&#xD;
If accepted, I'll add some short commentary. </change>
          <change when="2011-12-14" who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/gabrielbodard">rationalized languages in langUsage</change>
          <change when="2011-12-14" who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/gabrielbodard">changed editor names to URIs</change>
          <change when="2011-10-31" who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/gabrielbodard">changed type=inWord to break=no</change>
          <change when="2011-10-04" who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/Faith">Automatically updated revision description</change>
          <change when="2011-09-20" who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/Faith">Automated transfer of accents across reg-orig pairs</change>
          <change when="2011-03-27" who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/gabrielbodard">updated markup for fractions (rend=tick)</change>
          <change when="2011-03-02" who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/gabrielbodard">batch converted all tei:sic to tei:orig and tei:corr to tei:reg</change>
          <change when="2010-05-05" who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/gabrielbodard">changed schema; added xml:space=preserve; indented; moved title/@n to idno</change>
          <change when="2009-11-12" who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/gabrielbodard">Added language la-Grek; tagged num rend=fraction</change>
          <change when="2009-06-27" who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/gabrielbodard">Converted from TEI P4 (EpiDoc DTD v. 6) to P5 (EpiDoc RNG schema)</change>
          <change when="2008-12-23" who="http://papyri.info/about">Automated split from transcoder files</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <head n="10608" xml:lang="en">
            <date>AD 126</date>
            <placeName>Karanis</placeName>
         </head>
         <div xml:lang="grc" type="edition" xml:space="preserve"><ab>
    <lb n="1"/><num value="10">ι</num> <expan><ex>ἔτους</ex></expan> Τρα<hi rend="diaeresis">ι</hi>ανοῦ Ἁδρ<supplied reason="lost">ι</supplied>ανοῦ Κ<supplied reason="lost">αίσαρ</supplied>ος τοῦ <expan>κυρίο<ex>υ</ex></expan> 

    <lb n="2" xml:id="lb2"/><app type="editorial"><lem resp="PN W.G. Claytor (autopsy)"><del rend="erasure"><gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="character"/></del></lem><rdg/></app> μηνὸς Καισαρείου <app type="editorial"><lem resp="PN W.G. Claytor (autopsy)"><num value="29"><hi rend="supraline">κθ</hi></num></lem><rdg><num value="25"><hi rend="supraline">κε</hi></num></rdg></app> ἐν <expan>Καρ<ex>ανίδι</ex></expan>. 

    <lb n="3"/><app type="editorial"><lem resp="PN W.G. Claytor (autopsy)"><add place="above"><del rend="erasure"><gap reason="illegible" quantity="4" unit="character"/></del></add></lem><rdg/></app> <expan>ὁμολ<ex>ογεῖ</ex></expan> Ταπεθεῦς Πασοκνοπαίου 

    <lb n="4"/>τοῦ Διδυμίωνος Σαμβαθίῳ 

    <lb n="5"/>Ἡρᾶτος μετὰ κυρίου τοῦ ἀνδρὸς Πε

    <lb n="6" break="no" xml:id="lb6"/>κμήιτος τοῦ <app type="editorial"><lem resp="PN W.G. Claytor (autopsy)"><expan>Φαή<unclear>σεω</unclear><ex>ς</ex></expan></lem><rdg><expan>Φαήρμ<ex>ιος</ex></expan></rdg></app> χρῆσιν ἔντο

    <lb n="7" break="no"/>κον <expan>ἀργ<ex>υρίου</ex></expan> <expan><ex>δραχμὰς</ex></expan> <num value="382">τπβ</num> κα<supplied reason="lost">ὶ</supplied> ἀντὶ τῶν 

    <lb n="8"/>τούτων τόκων συγχωρεῖ <expan>καρπ<ex>ίζεσθαι</ex></expan> 

    <lb n="9"/><app type="editorial"><lem resp="BL 2.2.46"><expan>τὴ<ex>ν</ex></expan> Σαμβάθιον</lem><rdg>τῇ <expan>Σαμβαθί<ex>ῳ</ex></expan> ὃν</rdg></app> <app type="editorial"><lem resp="BL 2.2.46">περὶ Ψεναρψενῆσιν</lem><rdg>πει<gap reason="illegible" quantity="2" unit="character"/>εναρσι<gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="character"/>νιει<gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="character"/></rdg></app> 

    <lb n="10"/>ἐλαιῶνος <expan><ex>ἀρούρης</ex></expan> <num value="1/4" rend="tick">δ</num> <choice><reg>μέχρι</reg><orig>μέχρει</orig></choice> οὗ <choice><reg>ἀποδῷ</reg><orig>ἀποδῦ</orig></choice> τὸ 

    <lb n="11"/>προκείμενον κεφάλαιον. 

    <lb n="12"/>καὶ διὰ τοῦ προτέρου <app type="editorial"><lem resp="BL 2.2.47">γράπτου</lem><rdg>ῥάπτου</rdg></app> τοῦ γενομένου 

    <lb n="13"/><app type="editorial"><lem resp="BL 2.2.47">ὑπ<unclear>ὸ</unclear></lem><rdg><abbr>ὑπ</abbr></rdg></app> Κόμωνος <expan>Πασοκνοπ<ex>αίου</ex></expan> τῇ Ταπεθεῖ 

    <lb n="14"/><expan>Πασοκνοπαίο<ex>υ</ex></expan> <expan><ex>ἔτους</ex></expan> <num value="7"><hi rend="supraline">ζ</hi></num> <app type="editorial"><lem resp="PN W.G. Claytor (autopsy)">Τρα<hi rend="diaeresis">ι</hi>ανοῦ</lem><rdg>Τραιανοῦ</rdg></app> Ἁδριανοῦ 

    <lb n="15"/>Καίσαρος τοῦ κυρίου Τῦβι <num value="4">δ</num>. </ab></div>
         <div type="commentary" subtype="linebyline">
            <list>
               <item corresp="#lb2" xml:space="preserve"><ref>2</ref> <p>κθ is preferred to κε because of the clear crossbar that starts near the right side of kappa, is lost in the middle of the letter because of abrasion, and then continues to the right.  The crossbars of the writer's thetas habitually extend beyond both sides of the letter (e.g., Ταπεθεῦς, l. 3, just below).</p></item>
               <item corresp="#lb6" xml:space="preserve"><ref>6</ref> <p>Φαήσ̣ε̣ω̣(ς).  The ed. pr.'s rho does not seem likely because elsewhere the tail of rho comes straight down or has a slight hook (although cf. Τραιανοῦ, l. 14), and because the ligature to the next letter seems to come from high on the letter, which is unlikely for rho, but fits sigma (cf. Σαμβαθίῳ l. 4).  After the sigma I see the peak of a very cursive epsilon and omega, raised in abbreviation.  There is also a prosopographical argument for this reading of the patronymic.  In the Karanis Tax Rolls, we find a Phaesis, son of Pekmeis alias Heuremon and Sambathion (P.Mich. 4.2, p. 244; cf. BGU 15 2498 [143/144?] and l. 9 n.).  The Pekmeis here is said to be acting as kyrios for his wife Sambathion; one thus suspects that they were the parents of the Phaesis from the Tax Rolls, who would have been named after his paternal grandfather. </p></item>
            </list>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
