<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Matthew 6:5-6, 8-10, 13-15, 17</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">pts.apis.11</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NjPT)11</idno>
            <idno type="dclp-hybrid">p.oxy;9;1169</idno>
            <idno type="dclp">61804</idno>
            <idno type="TM">61804</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">SCR 1034 (Box 2), item 4</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Greek fragment of the Gospel according to Matthew containing 6:5-6, 8-10, 13-15, 17</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Hair side: 5 lines in col. i; 10 lines in col. ii</note>
                     <note type="general">Flesh side: 11 lines in col. i; 5 lines in col. ii</note>
                     <note type="general">Large upright uncials with carefully distinguished wide and narrow strokes</note>
                     <note type="general">Text is apparently divided into sense units, each one commencing with a new line and an enlarged first letter (cf. Codex A)</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Gregory-Aland no. 0170; Pap. 11, Special Collections, Luce Library, Princeton Theological Seminary, Princeton, N.J.</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>8 x 14.1 cm. One much-decayed, oblong fragment of a parchment leaf; the top has been cut off, the bottom worm-eaten; worm-holes across the bottom half; no traces of ruling; a series of very small, regularly spaced holes on one side, perhaps the result of binding.</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0400" notAfter="0599">V/VI c. CE</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Oxyrhynchus</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">St. Matthew</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Excavated by Grenfell and Hunt for the Egypt Exploration Fund (year unknown); donated to Princeton Theological Seminary in 1915 through an arrangment with Prof. William Park Armstrong.</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">parchment</term>
               <term type="genre_form">literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">New Testament</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[Side 1, col. i:] They have their reward. But whenever you pray, go into your closet... [Side 1, col. ii:] for your father knows what you need before you ask him. Therefore you pray in this way: Our father who is in heaven, let your name be sanctified... [Side 2, col. i:] us into trials, but deliver us from the evil one. For if you forgive people their trespasses, your heavenly father will also forgive you; if... [Side 2, col. ii:] but you, when you fast, anoint your head and wash your face</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Oxy. 9.1169 <note>K. Aland, Kurzgefasste Liste der griechischen Handschriften des Neuen Testaments (Berlin: De Gruyter, 1994), 34.</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Oxy.:9:1169</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
