<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Revelation 3:19-4:3</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">pts.apis.5</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NjPT)5</idno>
            <idno type="dclp">61643</idno>
            <idno type="TM">61643</idno>
            <idno type="dclp-hybrid">p.oxy;8;1080</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">SCR 1034 (Box 2), item 1</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Greek fragment of the Apocalypse of John containing 3:19-4:3</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Side 1: 16 lines written on the hair side, quite legible</note>
                     <note type="general">Side 2: 15 lines written on the flesh side, less legible</note>
                     <note type="general">Very regular mid-sized uncial hand, with some ornamentation; a few marginalia by a later corrector (e.g., rough breating mark (?) at l. 12; final letters of l. 19)</note>
                     <note type="general">Pages numbered LG (33) and LD (34), respectively, in upper outside corners; apparently a page from a pocket codex of the Apocalypse of John (cf. P.Oxy. 842, 1010, 1096; P.Rylands 28)</note>
                     <note type="general">Text is generally in agreement with codex B</note>
                     <note type="general">Homoioteleuton (thuran kai) at l. 3; the missing text is supplied by the original hand at bottom (ll. 15-16) of side 1</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Gregory-Aland no. 0169; Pap. 5, Special Collections, Luce Library, Princeton Theological Seminary, Princeton, N.J.</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>9.5 x 7.8 cm. A nearly complete leaf from a miniature parchment codex; three sizeable holes across the middle; some discoloration at edges; slight puckering at top and middle.</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0300" notAfter="0399">IV c. CE</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Oxyrhynchus</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">John of Patmos</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Excavated by Grenfell and Hunt for the Egypt Exploration Fund in 1906; donated to Princeton Theological Seminary in 1915 through an arrangment with Prof. William Park Armstrong.</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">parchment</term>
               <term type="genre_form">literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">New Testament</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[Side 1:] Be earnest, therefore, and repent. Behold, I stand at the door and knock. If anyone hears my voice and opens the door, I will come in to him, and I will dine with him, and he with me. The one who conquers, to him I will give to sit with me on my throne, just as I myself conquered and sat with my father on his throne. The one who has ears, let him hear what the spirit says to the churches. After [Side 2:] these things I saw, and behold, a door opened in heaven, and the first voice, which I heard speaking to me like a trumpet, saying, *Come up here, and I will show you what must happen after these things.* Immediately I was in the spirit, and behold, a throne stood in heaven, and one sitting on the throne, and the one sitting on the throne was like in appearance</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Oxy. 8.1080 <note>A. S. Hunt, The Oxyrhynchus Papyri, Part VIII (London: EEF, 1911), Plate I; B. M. Metzger, Manuscripts of the Greek Bible (New York: Oxford, 1981), 72; K. Aland, Kurzgefasste Liste der griechischen Handschriften des Neuen Testaments (Berlin: De Gruyter, 1994), 34.</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Oxy.:8:1080</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
