<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Isocrates, Panegyricus and De Pace</title>
            <author>Isocrates</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">pts.apis.6</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NjPT)6</idno>
            <idno type="dclp-hybrid">p.oxy;8;1096</idno>
            <idno type="dclp">61389</idno>
            <idno type="TM">61389</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">SCR 1034 (Box 2), item 2</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Greek fragment of Isocrates containing the concluding lines of Panegyricus (par. 189) and the beginning lines of De Pace (pars. 1-3)</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Side 1: 15 lines written on the hair side</note>
                     <note type="general">Side 2: 16 lines written on the flesh side</note>
                     <note type="general">Upright mid-sized uncials, literary hand of the so-called biblical type (Grenfell and Hunt); a few corrections, stops, and breathing marks in a darker ink by a later hand</note>
                     <note type="general">Contains the end of Panegyricus (ll. 1-3) with a concluding title line (l. 4), and the beginning of De Pace (ll. 6-33) with an initial title line (l. 5)</note>
                     <note type="general">Text is not a close match to any medieval MS of Isocrates</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Pap. 6, Special Collections, Luce Library, Princeton Theological Seminary, Princeton, N.J.</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>10 x 7.3 cm. A nearly complete leaf of very thin vellum; extensive surface puckering; severe discoloration at edges; one small, loose fragment has been rejoined to the body of the leaf.</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0300" notAfter="0399">IV c. CE</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Oxyrhynchus</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Excavated by Grenfell and Hunt for the Egypt Exploration Fund in 1906; donated to Princeton Theological Seminary in 1915 through an arrangment with Prof. William Park Armstrong.</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">vellum</term>
               <term type="genre_form">literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Isocrates</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[Side 1:] They regard them as the cause of great blessings to others. *PANEGYRIC* *CONCERNING THE PEACE* All those who customarily come forward here say that the greatest things and the things most worthy of attention by the city are the things that they are about to advise you. Nevertheless, even if it were appropriate to preface some other matters with such words, it seems fitting to me, with respect to the present state of affairs [Side 2:] to make a beginning in this way. For we have assembled today concerning war and peace, which have utmost power in the life of men, and concerning which those who are counseled rightly necessarily manage better than others. So great, then, is the magnitude of the things for which we have come together. But I see that you do not give an equal hearing to the speakers, but you give attention to some, while to others not</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P. Oxy. 8.1096 <note>B. P. Grenfell, The Value of Papyri for the Textual Criticism of Extant Greek Authors, *Journal of Hellenic Studies* 39 (1919): 16-36.</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Oxy.:8:1096</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
