<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Register of Contracts Prepared at the Grapheion</title>
            <author>Kronion, son of Apion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3234</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3234</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.238</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;238</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;238</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12078 78518</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12078 78518</idno>
            <idno type="filename">78518-4</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 968</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.674837-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>The seventh year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus the Emperor, in the month Sebastos.;On the 2nd. Agreement of mortgage on 2 arourai, (made) by Kronion to Apollonios. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Loan of 308 drachmai with the same (land as guaranty), (made) by Apollonios to the same Kronion. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;On the 5th. Lease of 7 arourai, (made) by Haryotes to Dios. (Fee:) 4 silver drachmai.;Acknowledgment of receipt of 92 silver drachmai, (made) by Papontos and another to Pastoous. (Fee:) 8 obols.;Acknowledgment of receipt of 420 silver drachmai, (made) by Hatres and his wife to Didyme. She owes the scribe's fee.;Agreement of mortgage on a share of a house, (made) by Thenkebkis to Papnebtynis. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Loan of 100 silver drachmai with the same (share as guaranty), (made) by Papnebtynis to Thenkebkis. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Lease of a garden, (made) by Galates to Tesenouphis and his wife. (Fee:) 4 silver drachmai.;Agreement of lease, by way of payment in advance, of (. .) arourai, (made) by Harmaeis and his mother to Paaus. (Fee:) 4 silver drachmai.;Agreement to furnish lodging for the sum of 200 silver drachmai, (made) by Thaubastis to Nestesis. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Lease of the same capital, (made) by Nestesis to Thaubastis. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;On the 7th. Lease of 6 arourai of fodder, (made) by Peteeus and another to Didymos. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Lease of 1 1/2 aroura of fodder, (made) by Peteeus and another to Alexandros. (Fee:) 6 obols.;On the 9th. Acknowledgment of deposit of 460 silver drachmai, (made) by Kronion to Herakles.  (Fee:) 4 drachmai, which he owes, {as the scribe's fee}.;Agreement of mortgage on 6 arourai of an allotment, (made) by Herakleides to Herodes, (and);loan of 832 silver drachmai with the same (land as guaranty), (made) by Herodes to the same. (Fee for both documents:) 12 drachmai.;On the 12th. Acknowledgment of receipt of the half share of a loan, (made) by Lysimachos to Herakleides. (Fee:) 4 silver drachmai.;Agreement of confirmation, (made) by Kames to Paches. He owes the scribe's fee.;Agreement of obligation to remain in service (paramone) for the sum of 48 drachmai, (made) by Hermas to Ptolemaios. (Fee:) 8 obols.;On the 14th. Acknowledgment of receipt of a maintenance, (made) by Thenmarsisouchos to Zoilos. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Agreement (of - - -) of 40 silver drachmai for the price of wheat, (made) by Orsenouphis to Haryotes. (Fee:) 7 obols.;Lease of 3 3/4 arourai of green fodder, (made) by Peteeus and his brother to Mieus. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Loan of 100 silver drachmai, (made) by Herakles to Harmaeis and his mother. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Agreement of lease of 8 arourai of fodder, (made) by Mieus and others to Didymos. He owes the scribe's fee.;Agreement of nursing a slave child, (made) by Tapontos and her husband to Kronion, (and),;on the 16th, loan of 100 silver drachmai, (made) by Kronion to Harmiysis and his wife. (Fee) for both (documents): 4 drachmai.;Loan of 56 silver drachmai, (made) by Maron to Orseus and his wife. (Fee:) 9 obols.;Agreement of mortgage on a slave (named) Athene, (made) by Thenkebkis to Potamon;(and) loan of 100 silver drachmai, (made) by Potamon to the same woman and her son. (Fee) for both (documents): 4 drachmai.;On the 22nd. Agreement of confirmation, (made) by Taorsenouphis to Kronion the manufacturer of oil. Gratis.;Agreement of lease by way of payment in advance, (made) by Haryotes to Orseus. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Lease of right to sell a crop, (made) by Herodion to Polemon. (Fee:) 12 obols.;Agreement guaranteeing immunity, (made) by Herakles to his sisters. (Fee:) 18 obols.;Agreement of release of claims, (made) by Thaubastis and others to Herakles. Gratis, for Lysas.;Lease of 8 arourai, (made) by Ptolemaios to Eutychos. (Fee:) 15 obols.;Agreement of lease, by way of payment in advance, of 1 3/4 aroura, (made) by Psenosiris to Phibion. (Fee:) 3 drachmai.;Agreement of lease, by way of payment in advance, of 4 arourai, (made) by Taorseus to Maron. (Fee:) 4 silver drachmai.;Agreement of lease, by way of payment in advance, of 4 arourai, (made) by Taorseus to Ptolemas. (Fee:) 4 silver drachmai.;Agreement of lease, by way of payment in advance, of 13 arourai, (made) by Haryotes and others to Maron. (Fee:) 4 silver drachmai.;On the 25th. Agreement of division (of property), (made) by Tephersos to his sons. (Fee:) 12 silver drachmai.;Acknowledgment of deposit of 200 silver drachmai, 5 artabai of wheat and 5 artabai of barley, (made) by Herakles and his wife to Kronion. (Fee:) 6 drachmai.;Lease &lt;Read: Agreement&gt; of partnership in farming 8 &lt;arourai&gt; of an allotment, (made) by Didymos to Herodion. (Fee:) 10 obols.;Agreement to furnish lodging for the sum of 20 silver drachmai, (made) by Orseus and his wife to Mareus. (Fee:) 7 obols.;Lease of 13 arourai, (made) by Kronides to Herakles and another. (Fee:) 4 silver drachmai.;Agreement of sale of a donkey, (made) by Thenatymis to Kronion. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Lease of 1 aroura, (made) by Peteeus and another to Peteeus. (Fee:) 4 obols.;Loan of 620 silver drachmai, (made) by Lysimachos to Horos and another. (Fee:) 6 silver drachmai.;Acknowledgment of receipt of 208 silver drachmai, (made) by Kronides to Patynis and another. (Fee:) 5 drachmai.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich V, 238, col. I, 1944 -- BL VII, 111 (bibliography); BL VIII, 213 (bibliography)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
