<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Decision of a Iudex  Datus  in an Intestate Inheritance</title>
            <author>Publius Matius, centurio</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1388</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1388</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.3.159</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;3;159</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;3;159</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">78513</idno>
            <idno type="TM">78513</idno>
            <idno type="filename">78513-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1320</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:26.51101-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Whereas between Dionysius, son of Manlius, a discharged cavalryman, whose cause in his absence was defended by Marcus Trebius Heraclides, a cavalryman in the ala Apriana, squadron of Acamas, the son of the said Dionysius, and Marcus Apronius and Marcus Manlius, cavalrymen in the ala of the Vocontii, squadron of Domesticus, there was a lawsuit concerning the nearness of relationship, as to which of them was the more nearly related so as to obtain possession of the property of Dionysius, the son of Manlius, a cavalryman in the ala Apriana, who was said to have died intestate; and whereas for that suit Lucius Selius Laetus, the camp prefect, had appointed as judge Publius Mattius, centurion in the third Cyrenaic legion, and had ordered him to give judgment, the said Publius Matius, centurion in the third Cyrenaic legion, employed  as his advisers [[Marcus]] 'Publius' Marcius 'Optatus', the son of [[Marcus]] 'Publius], of the Falernian Tribe, decurion in the ala Xoitana, and [[.]] 'Lucius' Herennius Valens, decurion in the ala Apriana, amd Octavius Domesticus, decurion in the ala of the Vocontii, and, after the pleading had been completed on both sides and the surety bonds had been read through, rendered decision, in accordance with which decision he announced that it seemed to him that Dionysius, the son of Manlius, was the brother of his brother(?) Dionysius who is said to have died, but that Apronius and Manlius were the sons of the sister of that Dionysius [according to the] bonds of near relationship [that] they have themselves furnished, and that the property of Dionysius, which is the subject of the suit, seems to belong to Dionyius, [the son of Manlius], a discharged cavalryman, and should be [assigned to him. Acted] in the camp [- - -] in the Heliopolite nome [- - -, . . .] of the month Neos Sebastos [or year . .  of - - -] Germanicus Imperator.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Arangio-Ruiz V;  Rep Ser. - Aegyptus 7;  1926;  Pg_No 295-297;Rep Editor - Cagnat R;  Rep Ser. - JSav;  1926;  Pg_No 268-270;Rep Editor - Sanders HA;  Rep Ser. - PMich III;  1936;  Pg_No 159;Rep Editor - Arangio-Ruiz V;  Rep Ser. - Negotia;  1943;  Pg_No 64;Rep Editor - Calderini A;    Rep Ser. - Papiri latini;   1945;   Pg_No 27;Rep Editor - Cavenaile R;  Rep Ser. - CPL;  1957;  Pg_No 212;Rep Editor - Bruckner A - Marichal R;  Rep Ser. - ChLA;  1975;  Pg_No 280 Sanders HA, TAPA 55, 21-34, 1924, pl. IV Meyer M.P. - Levy E, ZSav 46, 276-285, 1926</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
