<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Circular letter from Apollonios to the financial officials</title>
            <author>Apollonios</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">berkeley.apis.467</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(CU)467</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.tebt.1.35</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0206;1;35</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.tebt;1;35</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">78769</idno>
            <idno type="TM">78769</idno>
            <idno type="filename">78769-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Tebt.0035</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:20.268062-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Apollonios to the epistatai in the division of Polemon and the other officials, greeting. For the myrrh distributed in the villages no one shall exact more than 40 drachmas of silver for a mina-weight, or in copper 3 talents 2000 drachmas, and for carriage 200 drachmas on the talent; which sum shall be paid not later than Pharmouthi 3 to the collector sent for this purpose. Let the following proclamation be published with the concurrence of the komogrammateus, who shall append his signature to the edict together with yours. Any one disobeying these orders will render himself liable to accusation. We have therefore also sent the sword-bearers. Good-bye. The 6th year, Pharmouthi 2. Purchasers of myrrh from the epistatai of the various villages shall not pay more that 40 drachmas of silver for the mina-weight, or in copper 3 talents 2000 drachmas, and for carriage 200 drachmas on the talent; any one disobeying these orders will render himself liable to accusation.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Tebt., I.35; Chrest. Wilck., no. 309; Hunt, A.S. Sel. pap. v. 2, no. 223.</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
