<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Request for Transfer of Taxation</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">petra.apis.18</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(JoPe)18</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.petra.3.19</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.petra;3;19</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">112454</idno>
            <idno type="TM">112454</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Petra inv. 60.1</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Request from Leontios son of Valens and Theodoros son of Obodianos to transfer tax responsibility for a piece of land to the latter</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Top margin 0.5cm, left 0.5-1cm, right 2-3.5cm; with the fibers</note>
                     <note type="general">Reproduced in plates VIII-IX</note>
                     <note type="general">Written by same scribe as P.Petra III 23</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Field no. XXXIVa</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>36 x 17cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0539" notAfter="0540">539 AD, September 1 - 540 AD, August 31</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Petra (Tertia Palaestina Salutaris)</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Theodoros</persName>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>XXXIVa</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Legal Document</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Taxation</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(chi-rho) To the present and future most respectable tax collectors of gold of this metropolis and of the districts belonging to the administrative area of Augustopolis (managed) through it.  (We,) Flavii, Leontios, son of Valens, politeuomenos, and Theodoros, son of Obodianos, notify (you) of the following: I, Theodoros, own a plot of vineyard from my paternal inheritance called Mal Ouda, located in the uninhabited hamlet Baith el-Alkeb, which has been registered in the public codex of the city of the Augustopolitans through my, Leontios', late paternal grandfather, the most blessed Horion, son of Leontios, on behalf of his former oiketes, Magdios, son of Euzoios.  Nevertheless, both I, Theodoros, and the most blessed Obodianos, son of Obodianos, my father, paid for this piece of land the taxes that amount to one half, one third, one eighth, (and) on sixtieth (iugum?) for free iugerum, both to the blessed Valens, (who is) my, Leontios', father, and to me, Leontios, who have received the due (amount) of the taxes for the said piece of land until the past second indiction, concerning which I, Leontios, have no claim against Theodoros, the most honorable, because as much has been paid as stated above.  But since both of us have now found it good that I, Theodoros... the taxes for the mentioned vineyard through the public chartai, I request you, the most respectable Basileios and the present and future most respectable tax collectors to burden my account and [person] in each case (in the register) of the total holdings at Augustopolis by itself... for the iugerm of vineyard one half, one tihrd, one eighth, [(and) one sixtieth (iugum) — — —]</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Petra III 19</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Petra:3:19</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
