<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Donation</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">petra.apis.30</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(JoPe)30</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.petra.3.31</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.petra;3;31</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">112466</idno>
            <idno type="TM">112466</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Petra inv. 72+79</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Theodoros son of Obodianos donates property to his cousin Hierios son of Patrophilos</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Top margin at least 6cm, right ca. 1cm, bottom ca. 13cm; 313 lines; transversa charta</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Field no. XXXIVn (Inv. 72) + XXXIII (Inv. 79)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>ca. 23 x ca. 380cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0582" notAfter="0592">582 - 592 AD</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Petra (Tertia Palaestina Salutaris)</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Theodoros</persName>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Legal Document</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Donation</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Benefactor] and Emperor [Augustus]... (Lines 8-11) [This written donation has been drawn up on his own free will and voluntary] choice, [without] any treachery, [fear, violence, any] fraud, deceit or [compulsion or ignorance of law]... (Lines 14-18) ... by Theodoros, [son of Obodianos, the most God-pleasing archdeacon of the most holy catholic church in the region of this city,] from the same city..... containing the matters as [listed below]... gift... (Lines 22-26) ... to the most reverend [Hierios] ..... the matters which have been listed below and have come to the possession of..... the [cession?] made to him [by the most honorable Patrophilos, son of Bassos,] his uncle [and father-in-law] ... (Lines 31-34) ... the same most God-pleasing [Theodoros] this [written deed of gift] ... and without treachery and sincererly... [by which] he agrees to have today donated... as said above... (Lines 40-43) ... was allotted to the same most God-pleasing [Theodoros in the] ... written division or [partitions made between the] same most God-pleasing [Theodoros and] the most honorable... (Lines 47-51) ... to the most reverend] Hierios and that which belongs... of the inheritance... el-Chobi... to the most blessed Panolbios... part of the same [inheritance] ... of the most God-pleasing Theodoros... (Lines 54-60) ... the most God-pleasing Theodoros... two thirds of the inheritance, situated... and Ain Tolla(?), the settlements... and other areas... through this... land rights(?)... (Lines 63-67) ... to the [most God-pleasing] Theodoros from the said inheritance... written division [or] partition... (between?) the frequently mentioned most... and Ouaelos, son of Mouelos, free... to the same most honorable... (Lines 71-74) ... waters and... or all sorts of [other plants,] with or without fruits, and the entrance and [exit] ... slaves... of land right (?) ... Theodoros to the same most reverend Hierios... (Lines 78-81) ... revenues on everything..... each... with... to learn or... of Petra and Augustopolis as much as (?) ... transfers... the most God-pleasing [Theodoros?]... (Lines 86-89) ... the most blessed... [if] the most reverend [Hierios] dies... leaving children from the most virtuous... his lawful spouse... (Lines 93-96) ... either from the said most virtuous... to Georgios? ..... have the power with the... of all the above-written... (Lines 100-4) ... acting or the rights... going... any way, reason, or law... those which will be left behind or... by the most reverend [Hierios] ... (Lines 107-11) ... above-mentioned... have (other?) children... indisputably... and usage, to what was divided at that time... property... have the same things which will be left behind... gift... (Lines 114-18) ... transfer (?) and give away as dowry and transmit to [his heirs] and simply [govern] always... perpetually use them and manage them? with the owner's right... none... (Line 120) ...to use [it up to the end] of his life... (Lines 122-34) ... all rights... return... delay to the above-written [most God-pleasing] Theodoros then remaining in life or not remaining... at that time..... to have... of the most reverend Hierios... of the... estates and dwellings [and] land rights donated to him... to have authority and usage and to own perpetually... of the most reverend Hierios... death... or donate... to make on the whole. (Lines 136-38) ... altogether as long as he lives... these with all their rights... of his life on the previously declared... (Lines 143-46) ... the power included in... the things donated today by the same... [with] the consent of the most honorable [Patrophilos?] ... the most God-pleasing [Theodoros] ... (Lines 150-55) ... to have donated to the same most reverend Hierios and... the most God-pleasing Theodoros, dwellings and... land rights (?) in the surrounding common courtyard..... the said..... waters..... church... (Lines 157-59) ... facing south already... the dwellings allotted to the same most God-pleasing [Theodoros in the written] division or partition [made] ... (Lines 164-66) ... [the most God-pleasing] Theodoros to the most reverend Hierios... their use and possession and [ownership] for the whole time of his life on the condition that he... (Lines 170-72) ... and use..... the most reverend Hierios and... his children... agreed... (Lines 173-251: no translation since the text is so fragmentary and the order of the fragments insecure.) (Lines 252-56) (2.H.) [(chi-rho) I, the above-written Theodoros], son of Obodianos, have drawn up [this written deed of gift... in favor of you,] the above-mentioned most reverend Hierios, ... [through which] I agree... to have donated the above-written... (Lines 257-94: no translation.) (Lines 295-301) ... I have given you my word to cherish and... have determined the above-written fine of [thirty+ solidi and for this I have pledged to you all my] present and future [property and having been asked I have agreed] on every point as has been written above [accordingly] ..... having read it and signed [with my hand], I have delivered it. [(chi-rho)] (Lines 302-5) (3.H.) [(chi-rho) I, Flavius N,] son of Euthenios, [from this city of Petra, have been present when the most God-pleasing Theodoros, son of Obodianos, archdeacon, composed the written deed] of gift to the most reverend Hierios, [son of Patrophilos, and having read... ] and for the sake of testimony [I have signed with my hand. (chi-rho)] (Lines 305-8) (4.H.) [(chi-rho) I, Flavius N, son of N,] from this city of Petra, have been present when [the most God-pleasing Theodoros,] son of Obodianos, archdeacon, [composed the written deed] of gift to the most reverend Hierios, son of Patrophilos, and having read... and for the sake of testimony [I have signed with my hand. (chi-rho)] (Lines 308-11) (5.H.) [(chi-rho) I, Flavius N, son of N,] from this [city of Petra, have been present when the most God-pleasing] Theodoros, son of Obodianos, archdeacon, composed the written deed [of gift to the most reverend Hierios,] son of Patrophilos, [and having read] ... divine... [and] for the sake of [testimony] I have signed with my hand. (chi-rho) (Line 312) (6.H.) [(chi-rho) I, N, notary,] have completed. (chi-rho) (shorthand) (chi-rho)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Petra III 31</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Petra:3:31</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
