<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Request for Transfer of Taxation</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">petra.apis.3</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(JoPe)3</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.petra.1.3</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0256;1;3</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.petra;1;3</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">78721</idno>
            <idno type="TM">78721</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Petra inv. 13</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Patrikios, son of Diphilos, addresses Euthenios, a politeuomenos and tax collector, in an application for transfer of Panolbios' tax burden to Patrikios' account</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">2 margins extant: top (0.5-1.5 cm) and right (ca. 3 cm)</note>
                     <note type="general">Written by same scribe as P.Petra I 4</note>
                     <note type="general">For a reproduction, see plates XII-XIII</note>
                     <note type="general">Image tile 0-0 = left side; tile 1-0 = right side</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Field no. XXIXa</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>ca. 53 x 15 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0538" notAfter="0538">538 A.D., Aug. 24</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Petra (Tertia Palaestina Salutaris)</origPlace>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">taxation</term>
               <term type="genre_form">petition</term>
               <term type="genre_form">memorandum</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Lines 1-2) [(chi) (rho)]  In the twelfth year [of the reign of our Lord] Flavius Justinianus, Eternal and Emperor Augustus, in the consulship of the most glorious Flavius Ioannes, on the ninth before the Kalends of September, in the [four hundred thirty]-third year of the province, on the sixth of the month Gorpiaios, in the first indiction year, in Petra, Metropolis of the Salutaris Third Palestine. (Lines 2-11) I, Flavius Patrikios, son of Diphilos, [. . . from] this Metropolis to the most respectable Euthenios, son of Dusarios, the most respectable politeuomenos and tax collector of the same (city), notify (you) of the following: [As] it was agreed [in the previous ] memoranda between me and the most illustrious Panolbios that I give to the same most illustrious Panolbios on account of his expenses yearly. . . twelve golden solidi, but instead of this we, I and the most illustrious Panolbios himself, agreed that I relieve the whole property of the same most illustrious Panolbios of the one third [that had been allotted] to him, of the property in Petra four free koriaiai, and of the property in Augustopolis one and one-sixth free koriaiai, therefore I request [your Respectability] and the present and future most respectable tax collectors to relieve the account and person of the same most illustrious Panolbios of the one third that had been allotted to him, one and one-sixth free koriaiai of the property in Augustopolis, and to burden my person and account beginning with and including the coming, God willing, second [indiction year] and onwards for the whole lifetime of the same most illustrious Panolbios with the same one and one-sixth free koriaiai.  The power remains for [your Respectability] and for the present and future most respectable tax collectors, without a second notification, to burden the heirs of the said most illustrious Panolbios with one and one-sixth free koriaia [of the property in Augustopolis]...</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Petra I 3</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Petra:1:3</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
