<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Settlement of a Debt within the Family</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">petra.apis.28</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(JoPe)28</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.petra.3.29</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.petra;3;29</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">112464</idno>
            <idno type="TM">112464</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Petra inv. 20</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Settlement of debts between Theodoros son of Obodianos and his father-in-law, Patrophilos son of Bassos</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Top margin at least 14cm, left 2cm, right 1-2cm, bottom ca. 20-30cm; 310 lines; transversa charta</note>
                     <note type="general">Reproduced in plates XL-LX</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Field no. XXIXg + XXXa</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>29 x ca. 410cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0582" notAfter="0592">582 (?) - 592 AD</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Petra (Tertia Palaestina Salutaris)</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Theodoros</persName>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Legal Document</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Debt</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Lines 1-3) (chi-rho) [In the... year] of the reign of our Lord [Flavius Mauricius, who believes] in Christ, gentle, [greatest Benefactor and Emperor Augustus... (Lines 9-21) These mutual written agreements... dispute and... have been drawn up [of their own free will and] voluntary [choice, without any treachery, fear, violence, deceit, compulsion, any legal] fraud, ... [and ignorance of law,] on [the one hand by Theodoros, son of Obodianos, the most God-pleasing archdeacon of the most holy catholic church in the region of this city, on the other hand by the most honorable Patrophilos,] son of Bassos, the maternal uncle [and father-in-law of] the other contracting party, the same [most God-pleasing] Theodoros, [both] from this provincial metropolis..... question... [containing the matters] listed below... (Lines 28-31) ... of/in the village of Ogomon and in addition thirty-three and one-third [golden solidi] less thirty[-four] carats... which have been given to him, and also... crop... (Lines 36-40) ... which has been given to the most reverent Hierios [himself], and from the mentioned quantity of the above-written [seventeen solidi] the same... take severally... and not undivided... (Lines 44-57) ... to come to quit-claim between each other over the above-written capital sums [and] every other thing whatsoever... the settlement between them... they both [agreed] ..... Theodoros..... to the said [most honorable Patrophilos, his] uncle... thirty-three and one-third [golden solidi] less thirty-four carats... spent as has been stated before... necessary... him and the said most... return... [by the said] most honorable Patrophilos... (Lines 60-74) ... [and have been paid] to [the said] most honorable [Patrophilos] unfailingly and without reduction... [the same] most God-pleasing Theodoros asked [the same most honorable] Patrophilos..... [the said] most honorable [Patrophilos]... the same question..... [the same most God-pleasing] Theodoros through the mutual agreements... btoh... proceed... to him according to the..... guarantee and security... in gold and..... given by [the same most honorable Patrophilos] to the same most God-pleasing [Theodoros] ..... things..... to this day. (Lines 75-77) And hence it seemed good to them both and they decided to come to this mutual agreement... which has the full force of the [stipulatio] Aquiliana... (Lines 78-106) ... and investigation... [the most God-pleasing] Theodoros [agrees] according to the first..... and... [all] that has been said above [is truthful and] that not he or [his] heirs and successors or [anyone] acting [in his name has or will have, nor raises or will raise] any claim or inquiry or legal action [or] lawsuit or court case in any [way against the same] most honorable [Patrophilos or against] his [heirs] and successors or [his property regarding] any debt or promissory note which had remained with him (Theodoros) and has been returned; nor regarding the [written] promissory notes which had previously been given by the same most honorable Patrophilos to [the same most God-pleasing Theodoros, that is, a notarial] deed of a capital sum [of thirty-three solidi], and private deeds for other [seventeen solidi], which have been settled through the cession made a certain time ago to the same most God-pleasing Theodoros by the said most honorable Patrophilos, as his share [of the estate of the said] most blessed [Panolbios, son of Theodoros,] his deceased grandson, was then ceded to him (Theodoros) in return for these. [Nor (shall he have any claim) regarding any other] thing, movable and [immovable and self-movable], which could give rise to any legal action according to the laws from the past to the present time in any way. (Lines 107-16) The said most honorable [Patrophilos] agrees for his part... the truth according..... to have received in full... [from] the said most God-pleasing Theodoros [all] the above-written (items) which he (Patrophilos) had deposited with him (Theodoros) in gold and in different amounts and kinds and ceded to him, to have been owed to him through him... (Lines 117-36) ... and he promises that not he or [his heirs] and successors or anyone [acting] legally in his name ever [has] or will have, nor [raises] nor will raise any [claim or inquiry or legal action] or right of exaction or lawsuit or court case [in any] way... other... [or the said most reverend] Hierios, his son, against [the same most God-pleasing Theodoros] or against [his] heirs [and successors or against his] property concerning the above-written items which had been deposited with him (Theodoros) [and] given and ceded to him by him (Patrophilos) [or concerning] a part of them or concerning the return of the pledges [or a part of them] ... have taken back... have been paid unfailingly [by the most God-pleasing] Theodoros as has been made clear before... any... or... [Nor] (shall he have any claim) concerning  any other thing, movable and immovable and self-movable, which could give rise to any legal action [according to] the laws from the past [to the present time] in any way. (Lines 137-47) ..... in turn each [of them, the same most God-pleasing Theodoros and] most honorable Patrophilos, agrees..... [not to use any] other pretext and complaint [or] plea which he has or could have against the other one in any way because each party... every request... and could remain... to him... [from] the past time [to this] above-written day..... these mutual written agreements... (Lines 147-162) The same most God-pleasing Theodoros and the most honorable Patrophilos regard and will regard the present mutual agreements valid and firm and secure [and] unshakable and they do not overturn... (not) themselves or the heirs or [successors or anyone else] acting legally on their behalf..... command or public..... or imperial words or sacred adnotatio or through an imperial memorandum or imperial decree or highest instruction or any other decision of court... agree... them... or according to any other... [way or time] or law or reason... agreements, or... happen (or) can be thought of. (Lines 163-86) On these terms the most God-pleasing Theodoros, securing his good faith, has taken [an oath] for the most honorable Patrophilos, in compliance with the clerical dress he is wearing, according to the... imperial rules, [swearing by the Holy] Trinity and the Safety [and Victory and Constancy of our] most pious and God-protected [Lords] ... for the greater security of these mutual agreements the same most God-pleasing Theodoros and most honorable Patrophilos agreed and acknowledged in harmony and by stipulation that if one [or them] or of his heirs and successors or anyone else tried..... to overturn or undermine... included... to the other party, who abides in and keeps (the agreement), as a fine and for the mere attempt (to break the agreement) thirty-six golden solidi without a trial and a lawsuit in any court, [and in addition and after] the fine has been paid... overturning..... according to the laws and the imperial rulings... penalties against those who attempt to transgress their sworn written agreements; and the present mutual agreements are no less valid in any way or at any time or for any reason..... on the whole. (Lines 187-204) ... all the above-[written things, pledging to each other] ... all [their] present and future property in every kind and nature, movables, immovables and self-movables, which are fully liable and subject to the general principles governing the legal rights of securities [and pledges], and all the above-written..... and to be valid [and firm] ... and for the heirs and successors of them both.  And having been asked the formal question by each other regarding all the above-written, they agreed with each other on everything, as has been written above. ... of these mutual agreements..... received... [all the] above-mentioned will be valid and firm... wherever presented.  Good faith was asked and agreed upon [by] each party concerning all the above-written matters. (Lines 204-19) The most reverent [Hierios, son of the] co-agreeing party, the most honorable Patrophilos, being also present, assented and signed these mutual agreements and promised that he regards and will always regard them valid and firm and unshakable with all (the clauses which) [they include and] that he has jointly taken back from the [same most God-pleasing Theodoros] the above-mentioned pledges (which had been given) to him (Theodoros) by his [father] and that not he or his heirs and successors or anyone [acting legally in his] name ever has or will have, nor raises or will raise any claim or inquiry or legal action or lawsuit concerning the same [pledges or any other] thing which [belongs] or could belong to him in any way at all.  Good faith concerning these matters was again formally asked and agreed upon. (Lines 220-37) (2.H.) [(chi-rho)] I, the above-mentioned [Theodoros, son of Obodianos,] have drawn up this [written mutual agreement with] its [inherent full] force, [in favor of the most honorable] Patrophilos, son of Bassos, my maternal [uncle and] father-in-law, and all that has been said above is truthful and not me... [or my heirs] and successors or anyone [acting] legally in my name ever has or will have, nor raises or will raise any claim or inquiry or legal action or lawsuit or court case [in any way] against you or Hierios, the said [most reverent son of yours or against] your heirs and successors or against [your property regarding] any debt or promissory note which [had remained] with me and had been given to me by you; nor regarding the promissory notes which had previously been given by you to me, that is, a written notarial deed of a capital sum of thirty-three solidi, and [private deeds for other] seven[teen solidi], which have been settled [through] the written [cession made a certain] time [ago] to my by you, as your [share] ... of the estate of the most blessed Panolbios, son of Theodoros, your deceased grandson, was then [ceded to me]. (Lines 237-51) Nor (shall I have any claim) regarding any other thing, movable, immovable and self-movable, ... which could give rise to any legal action according to the laws [from the past time to the present] and above-written [day in any way; and] I shall abide by all [which has been written above] and which I have agreed upon... [and] I shall... forever and I regard and shall always regard (the mutual agreements) valid and firm and nothing... in any way.  And [for your security I have pledged all my] possessions; and for all (this) [I have sworn a venerable oath and] have determined the above-written [fine of thirty-six golden solidi]; and having been asked [by you, I have agreed on every point] as [has been written above] accordingly..... all that it includes, [I have signed with my hand.] (chi-rho) (Lines 251-66) (3.H.) [(chi-rho) I, the above-mentioned Flavius Patrophilos, son of Bassos, have drawn up these written mutual agreements with their inherent full force, in favor of the] most God-pleasing Theodoros, son of Obodianos, [my nephew and son-in-law] ... the truth according... [to have received in full all] the [above-written (items) which I had deposited with you] in gold and in different amounts [and kinds] and ceded [to you], and to have taken back from you also [the pledges which I had given to you]; my son, the above-mentioned most reverend Hierios, has taken [them back.  And I promise] to you that not me [or my heirs and successors] or the said most reverent [Hierios, my son, or anyone acting legally in my name ever has or] will have nor raises or will raise any claim or legal action or [inquiry or lawsuit or court case] in any [way against you or your heirs and] successors or against your property [concerning] the above-written items which had been deposited with you and ceded to you [or a part of them nor concerning the] return of the pledges or a part of them..... have been paid by you. (Lines 266-76) Nor (shall I have any claim) regarding [any] other [thing, movable, immovable and self-movable, which could] give rise to any legal action [according to the laws from the past] to the present [time] in any way; [and I shall abide by all] ..... and I shall... [and] I regard and shall always [regard (the mutual agreements) valid, unshakable] and firm... in any way.  And for all [this I have sworn a sacred] and venerable oath and have determined the above-written [fine of] thirty-[six golden] solidi.  I have pledged to you all my possessions; and having been asked] I have agreed with you on every point as has been written above [accordingly] ..... all that it includes, I have signed [with my hand. (chi-rho)] (Lines 276-89) (4.H.) [(chi-rho)] I, the above-mentioned [Hierios, son of Patrophilos,] assent to [and approve these mutual agreements] which have been made between the most God-pleasing [Theodoros], son of Obodianos, and the most honorable Patrophilos, son of Bassos, my father, and I promise [that I regard and shall always] regard them valid and firm and unshakable with all that they include [and that I have jointly taken back from you the] above-written [pledges] which had been given to you by my [father], and that not me or [my] heirs [and successors or anyone] acting [legally in my name] ever [has or will have, nor raises or will raise any claim or inquiry] or legal action or lawsuit against you or against [your] heirs [and successors or against your] property concerning the same [pledges or concerning any other] thing which belongs [or could belong] to me [in any] way.  And having been asked by [you I have agreed to every point as has been written above] accordingly, and I subscribe with [my] own [hand.] (chi-rho) (Lines 289-92) (5.H.) [(chi-rho) I, Flavius N,] son of Euthenios, politeuomenos, have been present in the making [and releasing of these] mutual agreements, which have taken place between the most God-pleasing Theodoros [and the] most honorable [Patrophilos, son of Bassos, with] the approval of the most reverent Hierios, [and for the sake of testimony, I have subscribed with my hand. (chi-rho)] (Lines 292-95) (6.H.) (chi-rho) I, Flavius Diphilos, son of Gessios, politeuomenos of the [city of] Petra, [have been present in the making and releasing of these] mutual agreements, which have taken place [between the most God-pleasing Theodoros,] archdeacon, [and] the most honorable Patrophilos, son of Bassos, [with the approval of the most reverent Hierios, and for the sake [of testimony,] I have subscribed with my hand. (chi-rho) (Lines 296-99) (7.H.) [(chi-rho) I, Flavius N, son of N,] ... of the city of Petra, have been present in the making and [releasing of these mutual agreements, which have taken place] between the most God-pleasing Theodoros, [son of Obodianos, archdeacon, and the most honorable Patrophilos, son of Bassos,] with the approval of the most reverent [Hierios, and] for the sake [of testimony,] I have subscribed with my hand. [(chi-rho)] (Lines 300-4) (8.H.) [(chi-rho) I, Flavius N, son of N,] ... from this [city] of Petra, [have been present in the making and releasing] of these [mutual agreements], which have taken place [between the] most God-pleasing Theodoros, archdeacon, and [the most honorable Patrophilos, son of Bassos,] with the approval of the most reverent [Hierios, and for the sake of testimony,] I have subscribed with my hand. (chi-rho) (Lines 305-9) (9.H. [(chi-rho) I, Flavius N, son of N] ..... have been present in the making and releasing of these [mutual agreements which have taken] place between the most God-pleasing Theodoros, son of Obodianos, archdeacon, and [the most honorable Patrophilos, son of Bassos, with the approval] of the most reverent Hierios, [and for the sake of testimony, I have subscribed] with [my] hand. (chi-rho) (Line 310) (10.H.) [(chi-rho)] I, Alpheios, notary, have completed. (chi-rho) (shorthand)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Petra III 29</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Petra:3:29</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
