<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Request for Transfer of Taxation</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">petra.apis.4</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(JoPe)4</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.petra.1.4</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0256;1;4</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.petra;1;4</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">78722</idno>
            <idno type="TM">78722</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Petra inv. 14</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Application addressed to Euthenios, a politeuomenos and tax collector, for transfer of Panolbios' tax burden to the account of the sender, whose name does not survive</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">2 margins extant: left (4 cm) and right (4.5 cm); the papyrus contains three kolleseis at intervals of approximately 20 cm</note>
                     <note type="general">Papyrus reproduced in Plates XIV-XVI</note>
                     <note type="general">cf. P.Petra I 3 and 5; scribe is same as in P.Petra I 3</note>
                     <note type="general">Image tile 0-0 = left side; tile 1-0 = middle; tile 2-0 = right side</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Field no. XXIXb</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>65.5 x 17.5 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0538" notAfter="0538">538 A.D., Aug.(?) 9</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Petra (Tertia Palaestina Salutaris)</origPlace>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">taxation</term>
               <term type="genre_form">petition</term>
               <term type="genre_form">memorandum</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Lines 1-2) [(chi)(rho)] In the twelfth year of the reign of our Lord Flavius Justinian, Eternal and Emperor Augustus, in the consulship of the most glorious Flavius Ioannes, on the fifth before the Ides of August, in the [four hundred thirty-third] year of the province, on the twenty-[first of the month Loos], in the first indiction year, in [Petra], Metropolis of Salutaris Third Palestine. (Lines 3-10) . . . official . . . to the most respectable Euthenios, son of Dusarios, politeuomenos [and tax collector] of the same (city) and to the present and future most respectable tax collectors, I notify [you] of the following: Since. . . between me [and] the most illustrious Panolbios. . . [I] took possession of two thirds of these. . . belonging to him in accordance with the previous memoranda between me and his Illustriousness, it was agreed in the same memoranda, that I not only pay to the public treasury two thirds of all the outstanding public dues and, in addition, coming, if it so happens, extraordinary taxes concerning the past tenth, eleventh, twelfth, fifteenth and the current first indiction year, but that I also pay two thirds of all his taxes beginning with the second indiction year and forever thereafter.  I request your Respectability and the present and future most respectable tax collectors through this communication of mine to relieve the person and the account of the said most illustrious Panolbios of two thirds of his outstanding (taxes) concerning the said indiction years and, in addition, coming, if it so happens, extraordinary taxes; and to burden my person [and] account with the same two thirds, since the most illustrious Panolbios already paid in full the public dues concerning the past thirteenth and fourteenth indiction years. (Lines 11-13) I request your Respectability [and] the present and future most respectable tax collectors to relieve (at the same time?) the person and the account of the same most illustrious Panolbios of two thirds of . . . of debts?. . ., that is, . . . sixty-eight and thirteen. . . free koriaiai? and ten iugera of the patrimonium and to burden my person and account. . . [from] the coming second indiction year. . .</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Petra I 4</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Petra:1:4</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
