<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Request for Transfer of Taxation</title>
            <author>Theodoros</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">petra.apis.24</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(JoPe)24</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.petra.3.25</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.petra;3;25</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">112460</idno>
            <idno type="TM">112460</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Petra inv. 64+66.1</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Request by Theodoros son of Obodianos to transfer tax responsibility on institutional land bought by Philoumenos</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Top margin 1cm, left 3cm, right ca. 3.5cm; 22 lines; with the fibers</note>
                     <note type="general">Reproduced in plates XXXI-XXXIV</note>
                     <note type="general">Wrapped up with P.Petra III 26 and 27</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Field no. XXXIVe + XXXIVg</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>72 x ca. 21cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0559">559 AD, January 30</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Petra (Tertia Palaestina Salutaris)</origPlace>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Legal Document</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Taxation</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Lines 1-2) [(chi-rho)] In the thirty-second year of the reign of our most divine and pious Lord Flavius Justinianus, eternal Augustus and Emperor, in the nineteenth year after the [consulship] of the most glorious Flavius Basilius, three days before the Kalends of January, in the four hundred and [fifty]-third year of the province, on the fifteenth of the month of Peritios, in the seventh indiction year, in Petra, Metropolis of the Third Palestine Salutaris. (Lines 2-9) To the most respectable Flavius Valens, son of Auxolaos, tax collector of the current seventh indiction and through you to the present and future tax collectors of this city of the Petraeans.  I, Theodoros, son of Obodianos, deacon of the most holy catholic church under (the control of?) this city, notify (you) of the following.  Since on this very day I sold to the most God-pleasing Philoumenos, son of Gerontios, [presbyter[ and... of the sacred shrine of the holy and glorious martyr Theodoros, located in Ammetha, on behalf (in the name) of the said holy place, [one] well-watered field that belongs to me [in] the hamlet [ ]aina, [situated] near Augustopolis, called Mal-el-Amoa[?] or Mal-[al]-Etherro[]eiba, with every right, and I surrendered corporeally its possessions on the condition that the said most God-pleasing [presbyter] and [ ] Philoumenos, son of [Gerontios] ..... the account and property..... And for the sake of this I request that I be [relieved of] the tax contribution for the said [field] ... [the present and future most respectable] tax collectors... of me... of the most blessed Theodoros, son of Patrikios, of [his] ceded, entire, field..... Ammetha (?)... Diphilos..... from the total landholdings of Augustopolis, [one (and) one ninth iugerum], between... (Lines 9-13) The present request has been addressed to your respectability through which I request you and through you [the present and future most respectable] tax collectors..... from the total landholdings of Augustopolis one (and) one ninth iugerum of the patrimonium, and this should be burdened to the account [and person and property of the] aforementioned [most God-pleasing] presbyter [Philoumenos, son of Gerontios, or rather of the aforementioned sacred] house of prayer [from] the current seventh indiction and for all following time..... ruled (?) the... in this town..... of Augustopolis... [And for] our own [security and] the public treasury, and for (on behalf) of the..... Philoumenos [agreed] having [subscribed].  (Lines 13-16) (2.H.) (chi-rho) (I,) the above-written Theodoros, son of Obodianos, have requested that... my person and property and account be relieved of the tax contribution assigned to me for the above-written [well-watered] field [called] place Mal [el-Amoa or] Mal al-[ ], that is, from the total landholdings of Augustopolis each [year] one (and) one ninth iugerum of the patrimonium, and (that) this be burdened to the name and property and account of the most God-[beloved] Philoumenos, son of Gerontios, presbyter, or rather of the aforementioned sacred [shrine, from the] current seventh indiction and for the following time, as is written above, having signed accordingly in my own hand. (chi-rho) (Lines 16-18) (3.H.) (chi-rho) (I,) Philounenos (sic), son of Gerontios, presbyter, (4.H.) the above-written have requested that the name and property and account of the most God-pleasing Theodoros, son of Obodianos, deacon, be relieved of the tax burden assigned to the above-written well-watered field called Mal-O... or Mal-[ ]omorr[ ], that is, from the [total landholdings] of Augustopolis [one] (and) one ninth iugerum of the [patrimonium], and (that) this be registered to my name and property and account, or rather of the aforementioned sacred shrine from the current seventh indiction and for [all following time], as written above, having used accordingly the hand of Flavius Sosamon, son of Alpheios, who was asked by me, I having written first in my own hand my and my father's name, because I am not accurate in order to write well and I am in great pain if (when) I write letter by letter. (chi-rho) (Lines 19-22) (5.H.) (chi-rho) [El.,.., son of ...]lios, deacon.  The most God-pleasing Philoumenos, son of Gerontios, presbyter, [asked] the most honorable Sosamon, son of Alpheios, to sign of his behalf in this notification, having inserted in his own hand his and his father's name, and I testify. (chi-rho) (6.H.) [(chi-rho) (I,) N., son of ]os, monk of the said holy place, have been present and testify. (chi-rho) (7.H.) ] from the total landholdings of Augustopolis one and one ninth iugerum; this..... accordingly. (chi-rho)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Petra III 25</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Petra:3:25</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
