<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Change of a Dowry Agreement</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">petra.apis.17</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(JoPe)17</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.petra.3.18</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.petra;3;18</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">112453</idno>
            <idno type="TM">112453</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Petra inv.63+65+75</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Change in marital assets negotiated between Theodoros, son of Obodianos, and his father-in-law Patrophilos</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Right margin 0.5-2.5cm; transversa charta</note>
                     <note type="general">Reproduced in plates I-VII</note>
                     <note type="local_note">Field no. XXXIVd + f + frags.</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>22.5 x ca. 117 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0539">539 AD, July 20 - August 18</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Petra (Tertia Palaestina Salutaris)</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Theodoros</persName>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Legal Document</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Dowry</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>﻿(Lines 1-7) ... memorandum of the... regarding debt and..... Because..... the most honorable [Theodoros] an amount of gold... the most honorable [Patrophilos]... to the aforesaid Theodoros... half of all his existing paternal property in Serila... (Lines 7-19) And now..... the said most honorable Patrophilos... half part... of the belongings... written security and [this] security of cession [which is produced in] two exact copies, and with the agreement of the most honorable Patrophilos and Theodoros regarding the guarantee of [the aforesaid] most illustrious Dusarios to [the said most honorable] Theodoros... so that in the month of Loos of [the present] four hundred and [thirty-]fourth [year] the most honorable Theodoros will bring back, [in order to exchange] the aforesaid marital assets of the most virtuous Stephanous, his wife, [three pounds] of gold in dowry... and similarly [three and a half pounds] in paraphernalia... the most honorable Patrophilos... the marital assets of the said most virtuous Stephanous.  (Lines 19-27) ... [the said] most honorable Theodoros in return acknowledged in these (identical copies) that he will... according to the... in the dotal contract, from [his] paternal and maternal property... [on the one hand, three] pounds [of gold in dowry and, on the other, three and] a half [pounds] in paraphernalia, and... exchange the aforementioned [marital assets]... along with the arra?... to the aforementioned most illustrious man, [Dusarios ... ] on the aforesaid... alll... and... this [security] of two exact copies.  (Lines 27-30) Because, then, all these things [have been agreed upon] between [them], as [written above], they both agree [to do] and fulfill and to bring to an end the aforementioned in the above-mentioned month of Loos without delay and unambiguously.  (Lines 30-50) [And in order that] none of them will attempt to [set at naught] or disturb any of the things mutually agreed upon as aforesaid, they swore [the oath by the Holy] divine Trinity and the Imperial Safety of our most divine and pious Lord Flavius Justinianus, the eternel Emperor Augustus, to do and fulfill all these, and [they determined the] fine of [twenty-four] golden coins for the security against the party that attempts to evade or overturn the [present] security in whatever manner, being paid from his own substance and property for the attempt alone... [in addition] and after the payment of the fine, [this] is valid and his its own force for each [party]..... the aforementioned Patrophilos and Theodoros [having pledged] to each other on account of all these [all] their property they now own, moveable [and immovable] and self-movable.  And for the sake of greater security they additionally agreed [on guarantors] for each other, on the one hand, the most honorable Theodoros (presenting) for the aforementioned most honorable Patrophilos the most honorable Eustathios, his nephew/cousin, and on the other hand, Patrophilos (presenting) for Theodoros the most illustrious Dusarios, son of Valens, his father-in-law... (Lines 50-58) Each one of them (the guarantors) [promised] on his own liability [and from his] own substance and property... to do what had been guaranteed by him, and fulfill all the above-written without delay and [unambiguously], having both pledged for it their belongings, [good faith] having been formally asked and agreed upon.  This memorandum is valid [and secure], executed in two identical copies which being undersigned will be valid and secure wherever presented, having the force of a notarial document.  (Lines 58-61) It was written [in the month of... ] of the four hundred and thirty-fourth year. (chi-rho) The previous mutual agreements [between] us and the security made by the most honorable Eustathios and Theodoros toward the most honorable Patrophilos will nevertheless be valid. (chi-rho) (Lines 62-72) (2.H.) (chi-rho) I, the aforementioned Flavius Patrophilos, son of Bassos, have made this memorandum to you, the most honorable Theodoros, son of Obodianos, [my] nephew and son-in-law, and I agree to do and fulfill and to bring to an end [all the] above-written; and I negotiated the above-mentioned exact copy of the security, on the condition that it remains fixed, as stated, after the marital assets have been exchanged, namely three pounds of gold as dowry and three and a half as paraphernalia; and I swore and determined the fine of twenty-four golden coins and have pledged; and having been asked the formal question I agreed upon each point accordingly and having reading it and having signed it with my own hand, I have released it.  (Lines 73-80) (3.H.) (chi-rho) I, the aforementioned [Flavius] Theodoros, son of Obodianos, have made this memorandum to you, the most honorable Patrophilos, son of Bassos, my uncle and father-in-law, and I agree to do and fulfill and [to bring] to an end all the aforementioned; and I negotiated the above-mentioned exact copy of the security, on the condition that it remains fixed, as stated, after three pounds of gold have been exchanged as dowry and three and a half pounds as paraphernalia; and I swore and determined the fine of twenty-four golden coins and have pledged; and having been asked the formal question I agreed upon each point accordingly and having read it and having signed it with my own hand, I have released it. (chi-rho)  (Lines 81-85) (4.H.) [(chi-rho)] I, the aforementioned Flavius Dusarios, son of Valens, have guaranteed the most honorable Patrophilos, son of Bassos, my son-in-law, and shall make him fulfill the aforementioned without delay; and the above-mentioned two identical copies were negotiated in my presence as stated, so that after [the marital assets] have been exchanged as stated earlier I will provide and fulfill, [and I have pledged] and having been asked the formal question, [I have agreed upon] each point accordingly, having signed with my own hand.  (Lines 86-89) (5.H.) [(chi-rho)] I, the aforementioned Flavius Eustathios, son of Theon, have guaranteed the most honorable Theodoros, son of Obodianos, our... and I shall make him fulfill the above-written [and I have pledged]; and, having been asked the formal question, I have agreed upon each point accordingly, having signed with my own hand. (chi-rho)  (Lines 90-94) (1.H.) (chi-rho) I, the aforementioned Flavius Theodoros, son of Obodianos, since after we heard together (the provisions of) this memorandum... we... these... this month of Gorpiaios...</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Petra III 18</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Petra:3:18</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
