<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Gift after Death </title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>APIS</authority>
                <idno type="apisid">petra.apis.55</idno>
                <idno type="controlNo">(JoPe)35</idno>
                <idno type="ddbdp">p.petra.5.55</idno>
                <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.petra;5;55</idno>
                <idno type="HGV">702382</idno>
                <idno type="TM">702382</idno>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <msDesc>
                    <msIdentifier>
                        <idno type="invNo">Petra Inv. 6a</idno>
                    </msIdentifier>
                    <msContents>
                        <summary>A signed donation by Obodianos, son of Obodianos, who had contracted a serious disease and wanted to give all his belongings for pious purposes after his death. One half was destined to the sacred house (i.e., church or monastery) of Aaron and the other half to the hospital of the martyr Cyricus.</summary>
                        <msItemStruct>
                            <note type="general">The text was written in eight wide columns (50+55+45+50+50+48+45+40 cm) along the ﬁbers with an appointed kalamos. The space between the columns is 2–5.5 cm, in most cases 5–5.5 cm. At the end of the roll, to the right of Col. VIII, there was a blank margin of ca. 12 cm. The Greek text is in a medium-sized sloping and practiced cursive hand with varying forms and sizes of letters and with many ligatures. The scribe tended to separate words with a blank space. The two-and-a-half very fragmentary Latin lines in the ﬁrst column were most probably written by the same scribe, using the same appointed kalamos, in an upright rounded cursive. In the last column, there seem to be a number of hands both in Greek and Latin.</note>
                            <note type="general">Reproduced in plates XXXVII-LVI</note>
                            <note type="local_note">Field no. XXVa</note>
                            <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                        </msItemStruct>
                    </msContents>
                    <physDesc>
                        <objectDesc>
                            <supportDesc>
                                <support>ca. 430 x ca. 20 cm</support>
                            </supportDesc>
                        </objectDesc>
                    </physDesc>
                    <history>
                        <origin>
                            <origDate notBefore="0573" notAfter="0573">June 15, 573 (?)</origDate>
                            <origPlace>Petra (Tertia Palaestina Salutaris)</origPlace>
                        </origin>
                    </history>
                </msDesc>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <encodingDesc>
            <classDecl>
                <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
                    <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
                </taxonomy>
            </classDecl>
        </encodingDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="en">English</language>
                <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
            </langUsage>
            <textClass>
                <keywords scheme="#apis">
                    <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
                    <term type="genre_form">Donation</term>
                </keywords>
            </textClass>
        </profileDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="translation">
                <ab>Col. I (Lines 2–5) (2. H. in Greek) … written (by) … (1. H. in Greek) [† In the 8th year of the reign of our Lord Flavius Justinus, eternal Augustus] Emperor, [seventeen days before the Kalends] of July in the four hundred [sixty-eighth year of the province], on the twenty-[sixth] of the month [Daisios], in the sixth indiction, in the Antonine imperial colony, the distinguished [and native] mother of colonies, Hadrianic [Petra], Metropolis of the Third Palestine Salutaris. (Lines 6–8) (3. H. in Latin) … of the sacrosanct and ….. I Flavius Obodianus, son of Obodianus, have made the [donation or rather (?)] I bequeath. Epiphanius, son of Damianus, presbyter, and Gymnasius, son of …rius, ex primiceriis … in the mentioned indiction. C(aius) Jul(ius) Eudaemon … and … and Cyricus, son of Petrus, presbyter ….. and (superior?) of the House of Aaron, [and Theodorus, son of] Obodianus, [archdeacon of Saint Mary (?)] … presbyter ….. (Lines 8–13) (1. H. in Greek) Indiction ….. of Leontios, son of O[bodianos, …..] … most holy of ….. presbyter ….. oikonomos ….. of this same ….. [Valens], son of Samiabion, ….. [Obo]dian[os ….. (4. H. in Latin) ….. O]bod[ianus (?) ….. (1. H. in Greek) ….. Col. II (Lines 14–30) (1. H.) [… of the Church of our sovereign, the most glorious God-bearer] and [ever virgin Mary, and] in our presence [he said as follows: “Indeed, in the ﬁrst place] my hope [has to be led in the Lord] and [benevolent God, who has the power] over living people and [dead bodies. However,] because, [as one can see,] I am lying in bed [and no one can] be set against [the command of God of all, therefore] having [the human destiny] in my thoughts, [I wish and order] in your presence [that, if, indeed, I do withdraw] from this present life through this illness [I am suffering from], all the belongings whatsoever I leave behind should be administered by Kerykos, [son of Petros], the most holy presbyter and superior of the Saint high priest Aaron, and by the aforementioned most God-pleasing Theodoros, son of Obodianos, who (now) effect a righteous and Christ-loving purpose and that, from those (belongings), Thaaious, my mother, be nourished and clothed during the whole time of her life, and that, after her [death,] what will be left of those belongings whatsoever I leave behind, one half (of it) should pass to the mentioned sacred House of our lord, the Saint high priest Aaron, and the other [half] to the most sacred Hospital of the [Saint] and gloriously triumphant [martyr] Kerykos, situated in this same city, and that an inventory should be made after my death of all this property, [because I give …] through the security of Leontios, [son of Obodianos], the most God-pleasing presbyter, to [Kerykos, son of Petros], the aforementioned most holy presbyter [and superior], ten [solidi,] (minus) ﬁve one-half [and one-fourth (carats each), and to Vales], son of Samiabion, [the deacon], three solidi, minus ﬁve [one-half and one-fourth] carats (each), and to [Bathyllos], son of Theodoros, [the deacon], one solidus, minus [ﬁve one-half and one-fourth carats]. It makes the total of my property [in gold folles …]” Col. III (Lines 31–47) (1. H.) [… and Sabinos, son of Alphios, and I, Leontios, son of Obodianos], the presbyter and [superior of this] Church [and Valens, son of Samiabion, the deacon and Gesios, son of Euthenios, and Gesios, son of Obodianos], the presbyter of the Church [of our blessed and] holy sovereign, [the most glorious God-bearer] and ever virgin [Mary, and in our presence] he said as follows: [“Indeed,] in the ﬁrst place ,[my hope] has to be led [in the Lord and benevolent] God, [who has the power over] living people and [dead bodies]. However, because, as one can see, [I am lying in bed and] no one can be set against the command of God of all, therefore having the human destiny in my thoughts, I wish and order in your presence that, if really I do withdraw from this present life through this illness I am suffering from, all the belongings whatsoever I leave behind should be administered by Kerykos, son of Petros, the most holy presbyter and superior of the Saint high priest Aaron, and by the aforementioned most God-pleasing Theodoros, son of Obodianos, who (now) effect a righteous and Christ-loving purpose and that, from those (belongings), Thaaious, my mother, be nourished and clothed during the whole time of her life, and that, after her death, what will be left of those belongings whatsoever I leave behind, one half (of it) [passes to the mentioned] sacred House of [our lord] the Saint high priest [Aaron] and [the other half] to the most sacred Hospital [of the Saint and gloriously triumphant] martyr [Kerykos] situated in this same city, and that an inventory [should be made after] my death [of all this] property, [because I give …] through the security of Leontios, son of Obodianos, the [most God-pleasing] presbyter, to Kerykos, [son of Petros, the aforementioned most holy] presbyter and superior, [ten solidi, (minus) ﬁve] one-half and one-fourth (carats each), [and to Valens, son of Samiabion], the deacon, three solidi, [minus ﬁve] one-half and one one-fourth carats (each), [and to Bathyllos, son ofTheodoros], the deacon, [one solidus, minus ﬁve one-half] and one-fourth carats, and [the total of my property in gold … two]folles, which I entrust to (them?) [… in order to (?) deliver (it)] to the mentioned [Kerykos, the most holy presbyter, and to the most God-pleasing] Theodoros … [my property] in gold […]” Col. IV (Lines 48–66) (1. H.) [… the most God-pleasing] Theodoros, son of Obodianos, [the archdeacon] of Saint Mary … presbyter … summoned … (a name of a person and his title in the genitive) … Sabinos, son of Alphios, [and I,] Leontios, son of Obodianos, [the presbyter and superior of this] Church [and] Valentinos, [son of Samiabion, the deacon and G]esios, son of Euthenios, … [and Gesios, son of] Obodianos, [the presbyter of the Church of our blessed and holy] sovereign, [the most glorious God-bearer] and ever virgin [Mary, and in our presence] he said as follows: “[Indeed,] in the ﬁrst place my hope has to be led in the Lord and benevolent God, who has the power over living people and [dead bodies]. However, [because,] as one can see, I am lying in bed and no one can be set against the command of God of all, therefore having the human destiny in my thoughts, I wish and order in your presence that, if really I do withdraw from this present life through this illness I am suffering from, all the belongings whatsoever I leave behind should be administered by Kerykos, son of Petros, the most holy presbyter and superior of the Saint high priest Aaron, and by the aforementioned most God-pleasing Theodoros, son of Obodianos, who (now) effect a righteous and Christ-loving purpose and that, from those (belongings), Thaaious, my mother, be nourished and clothed during the whole time of her life, and that, after her death, what will be left of those belongings whatsoever I leave behind, one half (of it) passes to the mentioned sacred [House of our lord,] the Saint high priest Aaron and the other half to the [most sacred] Hospital [of the Saint and gloriously triumphant martyr Kerykos, [because I give … through the security of] Leontios, son of Obodianos, the most God-pleasing presbyter, to Kerykos, [son of Petros, the most holy] presbyter and [superior], ten [solidi, (minus) ﬁve one-half and one-fourth (carats each),] and [to Vales, son of Samiabion, the deacon, three] solidi, minus ﬁve one-half and one-fourth [carats (each), and to Bathyllos], son of Theodoros, [the deacon, one solidus, minus ﬁve] one-half and one-fourth carats. It makes [the total of my property in gold … two] folles, which I entrust to (them?) … being present … (in order to?) deliver [to the aforementioned] my [property in gold] and to call (?) …” Col. V (Lines 67–83) (1. H.) …being present (?) … Theodoros, [son of Obodianos, the most God-pleasing] archdeacon … and [Leontios, son of Obodianos, the presbyter and superior … Bathyllos], son of Theodoros … the deacon … [and Gesios], son of Obodianos, [the presbyter] and Valens the deacon … [of the Church of our] holy and [blessed] sovereign, [the most glorious] God-bearer [and ever virgin Mary], and in our [presence] he said as follows: “Indeed, in the ﬁrst place my hope has to be led in [the Lord] and benevolent God, who has the power over living people and dead bodies. However, because, as one can see, I am lying in bed and no one can be set against the command of God of all, therefore having the human destiny in my mind, I wish and order in your presence that, if really I do withdraw from this present life through this illness I am suffering from, all the belongings whatsoever I leave behind should be administered by Kerykos, son of Petros, the most holy presbyter and superior of the Saint high priest Aaron, and by the aforementioned most God-pleasing Theodoros, who (now) effect a righteous and Christ-loving purpose and that, from those belongings, Thaaious, my mother, be nourished and clothed during the whole time of her life, and that, after her death, what will be left of those belongings whatsoever I leave behind, one half passes to the mentioned sacred House of our lord, the Saint high [priest] Aaron, and the other half to the most sacred Hospital of the Saint and gloriously triumphant martyr [Kerykos], situated in this same city, and that an inventory should be made after my death of all the property, because [I give through the security] of the most God-pleasing Leontios, [son of Obodianos], to Kerykos the aforementioned most holy presbyter and superior, ten [solidi,] (minus) ﬁve [one-half and one-fourth (carats each)] and to Valens, [son of Samiabion, the deacon, three] solidi, [minus] ﬁve one-half and [one-fourth carats (each),] and to Bathyllos, [son of Theodoros, the deacon,] one solidus, [minus ﬁve one-half and] one-fourth [carats], and the [total of my property] in gold … two folles I entrust [to (them?) … (in order to?)] deliver (it) to the aforementioned … Kerykos the most holy [presbyter] and the most God-pleasing [Theodoros] … which I leave behind …” Col. VI (Lines 84–98) (1. H.)… [Sabinos, son of] Alphios, [and I, Leontios, son of] Obodianos, [the presbyter and superior of this Church … and Valens, son of] Samiabion, [the deacon and] Gesios, [son of Euthenios, and Gesios, son of Obodianos, the presbyter of the Church of our blessed and holy sovereign, the most glorious] God-bearer [and ever virgin Mary, and in our presence he said as follows: “Indeed, in the ﬁrst place] my hope has to be led [in the Lord and benevolent God,] who has the power over living people and [dead bodies]. However, because, as one can see, I am lying in bed and no one can be set against the command [of God] of all, therefore having the human destiny in my thoughts, I wish and order in your presence that, [if] really I do withdraw from this present life through this illness I am suffering from, all the belongings whatsoever I leave behind should be administered by Kerykos, son of Petros, the most holy presbyter and superior of the Saint high priest Aaron, and by the aforementioned most God-pleasing Theodoros, [son of Obodianos], who (now) effect a righteous and Christ-loving purpose and that, from those (belongings), [Thaaious,] my mother, be nourished and clothed during the whole time of her life, and that, after her death, what will be left of those belongings whatsoever I leave behind, one half (of it) passes to the mentioned sacred House of our lord, the Saint high priest Aaron and the other half to the most sacred Hospital of the Saint and gloriously triumphant martyr Kerykos situated in this same city, and that, [after my] death, an inventory should be made [of all this property], because [I give] through the security of [the most God-pleasing] Leontios, son of Obodianos, [to Kerykos, son of Petros, the most holy presbyter and superior, ten solidi, (minus) ﬁve one-half and one-fourth (carats each)] and to] Vales, son of [Samiabion, the deacon, three solidi, minus ﬁve one-half and one-fourth carats (each), and to Bathyllos, son of Theodoros, the deacon,] one solidus, [minus ﬁveone-halfandone-fourth carats …” Col. VII (Lines 99–110) (1. H.)… [Theodoros, son of Obodianos, the archdeacon of Saint Mary (?)] and I, Leontios, son of Obodianos, the presbyter and [superior of this Church] and [Sabinos], son of Alphios (?), [and] Vales, son of Samiabion, the deacon, and Gesios, son of Euthenios, and Gesios, son of Obodianos, the presbyter ... of the Church of our holy sovereign, the [most] glorious God-bearer and ever virgin Mary, and in [our] presence [he said] as follows: “[Indeed], in the ﬁrst place my hope has to be led in the Lord and benevolent God, who has the power over living people and dead bodies. However, because, as one can see, I am lying in bed and no one can be set against the command of God of all, therefore [having] the human destiny [in my thoughts], I wish and order in your presence that, if really I do withdraw from this present life through this illness I am suffering from, all the belongings whatsoever I leave behind be administered by Kerykos, son of Petros, the most holy [presbyter and] superior of the Saint high priest Aaron, and by the aforementioned most God-pleasing Theodoros, son of Obodianos, who (now) effect a righteous and Christ-loving purpose [and that, from those (belongings), Thaaious, my mother,] be nourished and [clothed] during the [whole] time of her life, and that, after [her death, what will be left of those] belongings [whatsoever] I leave behind, [one half (of it) passes to the mentioned sacred House of our lord, the Saint high] priest [Aaron and the] other half [to the most] sacred Hospital [of the Saint and gloriously triumphant martyr Kerykos, situated in this same city, and that an inventory should be made after my death of all] … Col. VIII (Lines 111–17) (1. H. in Greek) ….. (3. H. in Latin) Flavius Obodianus ….. (5. H. in Greek) … of Kerykos …. (6. H. in Latin) I, … compelled of his (?) ….. made … the donation ….. (1. H. in Greek) We ask, after having gotten the conﬁrmation … in front of the holy …., that the matters will be given to us according to the receipt and ….. (7. H. in Greek) † …..</ab>
            </div>
            <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
                <listBibl>
                    <bibl>P.Petra V 55</bibl>
                </listBibl>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
