<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<bibl xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
      xml:id="b85258"
      type="article"
      subtype="book">
   <title level="a" type="main">Artemidoros of Ephesos and Strabo of Amasia. Common Traditions of Greek Cultural Geography and Strabo's Decisive Importance in the History of Reception of Artemidoros' Geographoumena.</title>
   <author>
      <forename>Johannes</forename>
      <surname>Engels</surname>
   </author>
   <date>2012</date>
   <relatedItem type="appearsIn">
      <bibl>
         <ptr target="http://papyri.info/biblio/84340"/>
         <!--ignore - start, i.e. SoSOL users may not edit this-->
         <title level="m" type="main">Intorno al Papiro di Artemidoro. II. Geografia e cartografia. Atti del Convegno internazionale del 27 novembre 2009 presso la Società Geografica Italiana, Villa Celimontana, Roma</title>
         <editor>
            <forename>Claudio</forename>
            <surname>Gallazzi</surname>
         </editor>
         <!--ignore - stop-->
      </bibl>
   </relatedItem>
   <biblScope type="pp" from="139" to="155">139-155</biblScope>
   <note resp="#BP">1. Artemidoros of Ephesos as Strabo's source, model and literary rival. - 2. Stephanos of Byzantion, Pliny the Elder, and Strabo as our main sources of Artemidoros' fragments. - 3. The decisive importance of Strabo's Geographika for any hypothesis about Artemidoros' Geographoumena.</note>
   <idno type="pi">85258</idno>
   <idno type="bp">2012-0569</idno>
   <seg type="original" subtype="index" resp="#BP">364 Artemidorus Geographus</seg>
   <seg type="original" subtype="titre" resp="#BP">Johannes Engels, Artemidoros of Ephesos and Strabo of Amasia. Common Traditions of Greek Cultural Geography and Strabo's Decisive Importance in the History of Reception of Artemidoros' Geographoumena.</seg>
   <seg type="original" subtype="publication" resp="#BP">Claudio Gallazzi, Bärbel Kramer &amp; Salvatore Settis (edd.), Intorno al Papiro di Artemidoro. II. Geografia e cartografia. Atti del Convegno internazionale del 27 novembre 2009 presso la Società Geografica Italiana, Villa Celimontana, Roma = Colloquium (Milano, 2012) pp. 139-155.</seg>
   <seg type="original" subtype="resume" resp="#BP">1. Artemidoros of Ephesos as Strabo's source, model and literary rival. - 2. Stephanos of Byzantion, Pliny the Elder, and Strabo as our main sources of Artemidoros' fragments. - 3. The decisive importance of Strabo's Geographika for any hypothesis about Artemidoros' Geographoumena.</seg>
   <seg type="original" subtype="nom" resp="#BP">Engels</seg>
</bibl>
