<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<bibl xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
      xml:id="b85421"
      type="article"
      subtype="book"
      xml:lang="en">
   <title level="a" type="main">Reconstructing Houses and Archives in Islamic Egypt.</title>
   <author>
      <forename>Tasha</forename>
      <surname>Vorderstrasse</surname>
   </author>
   <date>2013</date>
   <relatedItem type="appearsIn">
      <bibl>
         <ptr target="http://papyri.info/biblio/84358"/>
         <!--ignore - start, i.e. SoSOL users may not edit this-->
         <title level="m" type="main">Documents et histoire. Islam, VIIe-XVIe siècle. Actes des premières Journées d'étude internationales. École pratique des hautes études, IVe section, Musée du Louvre, Département des Arts de l'Islam. Paris, 16 et 17 mai 2008</title>
         <editor>
            <forename>Anne</forename>
            <surname>Regourd</surname>
         </editor>
         <!--ignore - stop-->
      </bibl>
   </relatedItem>
   <biblScope type="pp" from="281" to="311">281-311</biblScope>
   <note type="illustration">5 figg.</note>
   <note resp="#BP">1. Introduction. - 2. Houses in the papyri. - 3. Archive one: Archive of Rayḥān b. Našwān (Ašmūnayn, XIth century A.D./Vth century A.H.). - 4. Archive Two: Archive of Abnīle and Abū al-Badr b. Abū al-Sarī b. Helia (Bulǧusūq, XIth century A.D./Vth century A.H.). - 5. Archaeological Parallels: Domestic Architecture in Early Islamic Egypt. - 6. Conclusion. - Avec résumés en anglais et en français.</note>
   <idno type="pi">85421</idno>
   <idno type="bp">2013-0659</idno>
   <seg type="original" subtype="index" resp="#BP">146 840</seg>
   <seg type="original" subtype="titre" resp="#BP">Tasha Vorderstrasse, Reconstructing Houses and Archives in Islamic Egypt.</seg>
   <seg type="original" subtype="publication" resp="#BP">Anne Regourd (ed.), Documents et histoire. Islam, VIIe-XVIe siècle. Actes des premières Journées d'étude internationales. École pratique des hautes études, IVe section, Musée du Louvre, Département des Arts de l'Islam. Paris, 16 et 17 mai 2008 = École pratique des hautes études. Sciences historiques et philologiques. II. Hautes études orientales - Moyen et Proche-Orient. 5. 51 (Genève, 2013) pp. 281-311, 5 figg.</seg>
   <seg type="original" subtype="resume" resp="#BP">1. Introduction. - 2. Houses in the papyri. - 3. Archive one: Archive of Rayḥān b. Našwān (Ašmūnayn, XIth century A.D./Vth century A.H.). - 4. Archive Two: Archive of Abnīle and Abū al-Badr b. Abū al-Sarī b. Helia (Bulǧusūq, XIth century A.D./Vth century A.H.). - 5. Archaeological Parallels: Domestic Architecture in Early Islamic Egypt. - 6. Conclusion. - Avec résumés en anglais et en français.</seg>
   <seg type="original" subtype="nom" resp="#BP">Vorderstrasse</seg>
</bibl>
