<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>loan of money with interest in kind</title>
            <author>Aurelius Ammonios</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2142</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2142</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.14.12088</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;14;12088</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;14;12088</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">18184</idno>
            <idno type="TM">18184</idno>
            <idno type="filename">18184-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 406</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.477732-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>"The year after the consulship of Flavius Amantius and Flavius Albinus, clarissimi.;To Flavius Nilus, who is attached to the office of the praeses of the Augustamnica, Aurelius Ammonios, son of Ammonios, from the illustrious and most illustrious city of the Oxyrhynchites, greetings. I acknowledge that I have received from you as a loan from hand to hand out of your house the sum of fifty silver talents in imperial coinage; and in place of interest I will provide you daily and without interruption for the service of your household one and a half . . . of edible vegetables. And the fifty silver talents of the principal sum I will necessarily repay to you in the month Pauni of the present year 40, 22, 13 without any delay or argument; otherwise, I will pay to you for the period beyond the term of the loan the interest mutually agreed. You shall have the right of execution both against me and against all my property. This chirograph written in a single copy is valid, and in regard to the formal question, I have so declared. The aforesaid consulship, Phamenoth 9.;(2nd hd.) I, Aurelius Ammonios, have received as a loan the fifty talents of silver, and I will make repayment including also the daily service as aforesaid. And in response to the formal question, I have so declared. I, Aurelius Satornilos, have written for him since he says that he is illiterate.;(3rd. hd.) Validated by me, Chairremon."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, ZPE 23, 139-42, 1976 -- SB XIV 12088 Youtie HC, Scriptiunculae I, 383-386, 1981</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
