<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A deposit of money</title>
            <author>Herakleides, son of Herakleides</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1520</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1520</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">18201</idno>
            <idno type="TM">18201</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;24;16009</idno>
            <idno type="filename">18201-2</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 175</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.486816-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>"Heracleides, son of Heracleides, grandson of Archelaos, his mother being Sarap[], ex-gymnasiarch of the city of the Oxyrhynchites, to Heraclas, alias Heracleon, son of Archelaos, my paternal uncle, from the Iseion of Tryphon, greeting. I acknowledge that I have received from you on deposit in silver of imperial coinage six thousand drachmas, which are equal to one talent, which I will also return whenever you choose without any delay. If I do not (repay), it will be necessary for you to demand it of me in accordance with the law of deposits, and you will have the right of execution upon me and upon all my property as if in consequence of a court decision. Let this acknowledgement of deposit written by me, Heracleides, without erasure or addition, be valid as if it were registered in a public archive. In the twenty-[ ] year of the Emperor Caesar Markus Aurelius Commodus Antoninus Pius Felix Augustus Medicus Parthicus Sarmaticus Germanicus Maximus Britannicus, Hathyr 30.";On the back: "Acknowledgement of deposit by Heracleides, ex-gymnasiarch, to Heracleon.";At the top: remnants from the adress of a letter</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, ZPE 30, 175-177, 1978 -- SB XIV 12180 -- BL X, 212 (date); BL XI, 216 Gagos T, BASP 34, 39-43, 1997, Pl. 2-3</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
