<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Official correspondance </title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1513</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1513</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.18.13260</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;18;13260</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;18;13260</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">18373</idno>
            <idno type="TM">18373</idno>
            <idno type="filename">18373-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1718</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.80902-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>"[NN, logistesof the Heracleopolites)], [to NN (his assistant),] greetings. A copy of the petition [including the attached reply] to my lord Septimius Zenius, the most illustrious prefect of Egypt, is sent to You, in order for You to [bring before me] the persons [mentioned therein]. [I hope that You are well], my friend. Pharmouthi.;[To NN], the logistes of Heracleopolites, [from Aurelia Asklepias of] the village of Teis in the Oxyrhynchite Nome. I hereby send you a copy of the [petition] that I have adressed to my lord, the most illustrious prefect of Egypt, Septimius Zenus against the veteran Aemilianus, [holding the land plot of Philonikos, as well as against Kronios, the son of Menas,] and Sarapion, son of Pebaus, the former praktores of the same village Teis, concerning the [violent removal of a] jar (?) [with the weight of 4 minae] and a vessel with the weight of 4 minae. I also attach his answer adressed to Your Grace, and [ I make the petition and ask] that the aforementioned persons may be brought before an assistant and be forced to accept the tax payment and return our objects.;The following is a copy: [Septimius Zenus] to [the logistes] of the Herakleopolites, greetings. You will learn what events Sarapias has brought to the knowledge of my devotion when You [read] the attachment. If You establish that she is speaking the truth, please take care that her request is carried out in accordance with the laws. Be well. Latin. Leaf 96; Mesore 11.;To Septimius Zenius, the most illustrious prefect of Egypt, from the same aforementioned. Ten years ago, Lord Prefect, I was asked to pay my taxes by the tax-collectors, that is Kronios, son of Menas and Sarapion, son of Pebaus, of the same village, who collect the imperial taxes, and, as I was unable to pay right away, they illegally out of some plenitude of power forced their way into my house, forcefully taking possession of a jar fitted with copper all around with a weight of 4 minae and a and a vessel with the weight of 4 minae, although the total debt amounted to 2 talents. Soon after I was able to pay them and for that reason I approached them because I wanted to pay my debt in full and reclaim the objects which they had forcefully expropriated. They told me that they had pledged these objects over to a veteran by the name of Aemilianus [from the land plot] of Philonikos as security for that same tax debt. When I went to the aforementioned Aemilianus and offered him the money and when, because of his explanation that the tax collectors had sold the objects to him, the praktores went to him and showed that they had not sold the objects to him, he admitted in the presence of Horigenes, son of Myrtillos from the same village, that these objects were in his custody as a pledge. Therefore I ask Your Grace to make sure and to make arrangements to ensure that this same witness is brought before You [through the logistes (?)] and to let him force him to accept the two talents as the compulsory tax and to return these objects. When I achieve that, I shall owe You a large debt of gratitude. I, Aurelia Asklepias, have submitted this petition. ;Under the consulship of Flavius Januarius and Vettius Justus, the most illustrious, on Pharmouthi 9.;(Hand 2): I, Aurelia Asklepias, have submitted the petition."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Koenen L-Sijpesteijn PJ, Archiv 33, 55-62, 1987 -- SB XVIII, 13260</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
