<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Deed of surety</title>
            <author>Aurelius Peuthios</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2295</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2295</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.18.13949</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;18;13949</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;18;13949</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">18391</idno>
            <idno type="TM">18391</idno>
            <idno type="filename">18391-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 474</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.484699-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>"Year 15 of the reign of our most godly and pious lord Flavius Justinianus, the eternal Augustus and Imperator, after the consulship of Flavius Justinus, the most illustrious, Pharmouthi 8, indiction 4. To Flavius Philodemos and Flavius Johannes the most notable scholastici of the court (?) of the province of Arcadia and consangineous brothers, sons of Pelagon of illustrious memory, of the illustrious city of the Oxyrhynchites Aurelius Peuthios, son of Praus and the mother Lia, coming from the hamlet of Ammonianos of the Heracleopolite nome, of the estate of Your nobility, registered husbandman, greetings. I acknowledge of my own free will and deliberate choice, swearing by God Almighty and the piety and victory of the glorious triumphant genius, that I am surety and pledge to Your notability for Aurelius Victor, my consangineous brother of both parents, hsubandman, he too coming from the same estate and also registered husbandman, on the following terms. He shall stay and abide in the said estate and be responsible to Your notability for all that regards his person - - - correctly rendering and paying in full all the rents for cultivating the field under his charge, which belongs to the landlord, and the money-taxes for the D. V. fifth indiction - - -."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn PJ, ZPE 62, 145-8, 1986 -- SB XVIII, 13949</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
