<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Cair. Masp. 2, 67127</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">18874-1</idno>
            <idno type="TM">18874</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">18874</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.cair.masp;2;67127</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2023-10-23T06:01:28-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Finalized - Ready.</change>
         <change when="2023-10-23T05:22:00-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Looks good.</change>
         <change when="2023-10-23T05:12:30-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/marianowak">Submit - Tr. M. Nowak checked by Law in Social Networks Project</change>
         <change when="2023-10-23T05:07:28-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> χμγ
<milestone n="2" rend="break" unit="line"/> in the  17th year of the reign of our most divine lord Flavius Justinian, the eternal August and Emperor, after the consulate of the most glorious Flavius Basileios, on the 15th of Phamenoth, in the 3rd indiction.
<milestone n="6" rend="break" unit="line"/> To Flavius Dioskoros, son of Apollos, from the village of Aphrodite of the Antaiopolite nome, from Aurelius Apollos, son of Hermauos and Tsenyria, shepherd, from the same village, greetings.
<milestone n="9" unit="line"/> I acknowledge that I owe and have a debt to your dignity, pertaining to the price of the wool sold to me by your dignity, one-third gold solidus [i.e. a tremissis] according to the exchange rate of the said village, that is 1/3 gold solidus.
<milestone n="13" unit="line"/> And I am ready to pay it to your virtue on the first epagomenal day of the future, God willing, eighth indiction, without any dispute.
<milestone n="16" unit="line"/> To this end, all my current and future movable and immovable belongings are mortgaged with you as a pledge and according to the law governing mortgages.
<milestone n="19" unit="line"/> To secure your rights, I made this security document, bearing the signature of my agent signing on my behalf, and having been asked the formal question, I gave my consent.
<milestone n="21" rend="break" unit="line"/> (h. 2) I, Aurelius Apollos, son of Hermauos, the above mentioned, hereby agree, and shall repay you as above. I, Flavius Theoteknos, son of Psais [pap.: Psaios] the ex-praepositus, upon request, wrote on his behalf as he does not know letters.
<milestone n="25" rend="break" unit="line"/> (h. 3) I, Aurelius Mathias, son of Joseph, witness to the debt (acknowledgment) having heard declarations from theinitiator.
<milestone n="27" rend="break" unit="line"/> (h. 4) I, Aurelius Ioannes, son of Victor, witness to the debt (acknowledgment) having heard declarations from theinitiator.
<milestone n="30" rend="break" unit="line"/> (h. 1) ⳨ Written by me, Amais, son of Abraham [pap. Abraamios]
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="31" unit="line"/> on the first epagomenal day. <note>Translation: Law in Social Network Project (Warsaw)</note>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div><div type="bibliography"><listBibl><bibl>Law in Social Network Project (Warsaw)</bibl></listBibl></div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>