<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter from Chrysaris to Leontios</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">lund.apis.34</idno>
            <idno type="controlno">(SeUB)34</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invno">P. Lund. inv. 27</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Private letter from Chrysaris to Leontios</summary>
                  <msItem>
                     <note type="general">Source of description: Recto; Verso: Traces of document</note>
                     <note type="general">Recto: 25 lines with the fibres; Verso 4 lines against the fibres</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Lund University Library</note>
                     <note type="general">Recto: Mentions Elias</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItem>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>Pap.; 29 x 13 cm (i.e. = 13 x 29 cm)</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0450" notAfter="0550">ca 500 A. D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Provenance uncertain</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Recto: Chrysaris</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased in Berlin by Lund University Library in 1933, from prof. Carl Schmidt; Isabella Andorlini "Scavi e acquisti di papiri negli anni '30: il caso dei PLund" in Comunicazioni, Firenze 1995, Istituto papirologico G. Vitelli, p. 45-50</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>
                  <rs type="genre_form">Papyri</rs>
               </term>
               <term>
                  <rs type="genre_form">Letter</rs>
               </term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Recto: To my lord brother Leontios, Chrysaris, the daughter of Ambrosius, greeting. Be aware that I learned that you have been living in Narmouthis quite some time ago, and I did not want to come there to you because of the ejectment, even though I could also take with me Elias the baker who is my dependant and could collect from you. And many times the same Elias told me - I'm also going to get letters from the bishop or the vicarius to the councillors if they are going to collect from you.- And I did not want to for God's sake, lest you suffer ejectment. Please therefore send me the 2 solidi. If you want me to come there, write back to me, and I will come to you. If again you want to send me the half, 8,000 talents?, send it immediately, and the balance within a few days. I pray for your health for a long time, my lord. Verso: Deliver to Leontios the cumin seller from Chrysaris daughter of Ambrosios.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P. Lund. II 5 SB V 8092 <note>BL III 104 (line 10); BL VII, 198; BL VIII, 205 (lines 21, 1); Prâaux, C., Chronique de'–gypte 27 (1939) p. 183-184; P. Collart, Revue de philologie, Series III, 13, 1939, p. 86-87; TM 41035; R. S. Bagnall &amp; R. Cribiore, Women's letters from Ancient Egypt, 300 BC - AD 800, Ann Arbor 2006, p. 232; Archiv fír Papyrusforschung, Vol 13 (1939), p. 147</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Lund:2:5</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>