<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.10/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
     xmlns:ms="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:office:spreadsheet">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Namenliste</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">lund.apis.826</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(SeUB)     </idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">O. Lund. inv. 29</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">The O.Lund. inv. no is the number (written directly on the ostracon) given to each ostracon already by prof. Carl Schmidt, Berlin.</note>
                     <note type="general">O.Lund. inv. no 29 = Tsiparis' publ.no 27 = Knudtzon's publ.no 32</note>
                     <note type="general">Broken at the bottom; brown; partly effaced; ribbed on both sides; verso pitched</note>
                     <note type="general">3 lines on the recto (upper part of letters on 4th line); verso blank</note>
                     <note type="general">Mentions the names Georgi(os) and Abr..</note>
                     <note type="general">     </note>
                     <note type="local_note">Location: Lund University Library</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>Ostr.; 9.9 x 5.5 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0001" notAfter="0399">I-IV A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Georg(ios)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>According to the introduction to his licentiate dissertation Erik J. Knudtzon had acquired the ostracon collection through prof. Carl Schmidt, antiquities dealer and professor of Coptic studies in Berlin. Carl Schmidt, in his turn, had probably bought them in Cairo. In a letter from October 6th 1931 Schmidt writes from Berlin to Albert Wifstrand in Lund that he has aquired a small collection of 32 ostraca from Thebes, Fayum, letters and receipts, and that he is willing to sell these ostraca for the amount of 250 German marks. In a letter dated September 11th 1934 from Erik Knudtzon in Lund, most likely to professor Schubart in Berlin, we can read that Knudtzon bought the ostraca through Carl Schmidt at the same time, i.e. in 1932, as the university library in Lund bought the papyrus collection (registered in 1933 among acquisitions), also from Carl Schmidt. In 2009 Lund University Library acquired the collection, at that time owned by the Department of Archaeology and Ancient History at the same university.</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Ostraca</term>
               <term type="genre_form">List of names</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Ostraca Lundensia (O. Lund.). Ostraka aus der Sammlung des Instituts für Altertumskunde an der Universität zu Lund, herausgegeben und kommentiert von Christos Tsiparis, Lund 1979, doctoral dissertation Ostraca Lundensia, herausgegeben und bearbeitet von Erik J. Knudtzon, Lund 1933 (1946), licentiate dissertation, not printed <note>Gallazzi, C., Bibliotheca orientalis, 39, 1982, c. 578; Nachtergael, G., Sur la provenance de quelques ostraca de la Collection de Lund, Ricerche di egittologia e di antichità copte 6, 2004, p. 91, 96 (provenance); BL VIII, 525 (lines 1, 2); TM 74888</note>
               </bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>