<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A lease of land from the Tebtynis grapheion archive</title>
            <author>Polemon, son of Psenobastis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3966</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3966</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.bingen.59</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0254;;59</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.bingen;;59</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">43116</idno>
            <idno type="TM">43116</idno>
            <idno type="filename">43116-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich. inv. 672</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.417577-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Twentieth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, Sebastos 25, in Tebtynis of the Polemon district of the Arsinoite nome. Polemon, son of Psenobastis, about 55 years of age, with a scar on his right brow, has leased to Polemis, son of Petesouchos, about 20 years of age, with a scar on the right of his forehead {has leased to this Polemis} twelve arouras of public land from those which Polemon himself farms near Talei, or however many there are in two parcels around what are called Baralips (?) and Parembole, for ninety-three years and hereditarily from the present twentieth year. In return for these, Polemon will measure out to Polemis yearly for taxes twenty artabs of wheat and the attendant yearly expenses and half portion of for one month... Polemis will receive the seed given yearly from the treasury which also is yearly for the land and it will not be permitted for the lessees to ... nor the liturgy. Signatory for Polemon, herodes, about 40 years of age, with a scar on the left side of his neck, and for the other. (m. 2) I, Polemon, son of Psenobastis, agree to lease to Polemis, son of Petesouchos, from the public lands which I farm near Talei twelve arouras or however many there are in two plots in the areas called Baralips and Parembole for ninety-three years from the present twentieth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus for sowing with whatever crops the lessee chooses yearly ... artabs of wheat ... all which has been given ... upon the aforementioned terms. [I Herodes], son of Herodes, [have written] for [he does not know letters].;verso: in Baralips and Parambole.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Jenkins FW, PBingen , 245-248, no 59, 2000, Pl. 31 -- Morelli, CE 77, 2002, 317 (for ll. 7 "e" in the beginning and "si" in the beginning of l.14)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
