<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Address Concerning the Registration of a Loan of Money</title>
            <author>Unknown creditor</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1653</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1653</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.22.15325</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;22;15325</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;22;15325</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">43177</idno>
            <idno type="TM">43177</idno>
            <idno type="filename">43177-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 2833</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.254502-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>. . . soldier of the third Ituraean cohort of the century of [- - -, greeting. I acknowledge that I have received] from you a loan of two hundred fifty silver drachmai in capital, total [250 silver drachmai, at the interest of a drachme per mina every month which] I shall also pay you back in the month [- - -] of the present sixteenth year [of Aurelius Antoninus Caesar the lord. If I do not pay them back] within the appointed term you shall have the right of execution upon me and [all my] property [of every kind as if in consequence of a court decision. This cheirograph is legally binding as] though publicly registered and written without erasure or insertion. [Year 16 of aurelius Antoninus Caesar the lord, month, day].;    Since I desire this contract to be publicly registered, I request that, on receiving it from the person sent [by me, . . ., with his attestation] that it is the autograph of the said Marcus Sempronius Serenus, it also having my [subscription] regarding [its registration, you register it together with this memorandum at] both Libraries and write to the strategos of the Herakleides division of the Arsinoite nome to serve a copy of this declaration on Sempronius [Serenus, if he is alive, if not, on his adult heirs whose names] will be learned on the spot, as is proper, so that he may know about the publication [and may return to me the 250 drachmai as is proper. Year 16 of Aurelius Antoninus] Caesar the lord, on the 14th of the month Kaisareios. I have signed on Mesore 14.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn PJ, Archiv 41, 178-182, 1995, Pl. 27 -- SB XXII, 15325 -- BL XI, 236</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
