<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Acknowledgement of the return of a loan</title>
            <author>Dionysammon, son of Ision</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3126</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3126</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.22.15611</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;22;15611</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;22;15611</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">43208</idno>
            <idno type="TM">43208</idno>
            <idno type="filename">43208-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 780</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.803366-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>"The seventeenth year of Imperator Caesar Traianus Hadrian Augustus in the month of Gorpiaius, Epeiph twelfth, in Theadelphia in the Themistes division of the Arsinoite nome. Dionysammon, the son of Ision, about thirty-nine years old, with a scar on the little finger of the left hand, agrees with Hermas, the son of Heron, grandson of Hermas, registered in the second goose-farm quarter, about thirty-five years old, with a scar on the middle of his forehead, that he has has received from him one hundred twenty silver drachmas which Hermas owed to him in accordance with a contract drawn up through the grapheion in the village of Magais, of the same division, in the fouteenth year of Hadrian Caesar the Lord in the month of Mecheir (?) on the twenty-third, which contract he has also reurned to him for invalidation and annullment and that neither Dionysammon nor those acting on his behalf bring or shall bring charges against Hermas or those acting on his behalf concerning the money he has received, as above has been said, or about any other matter, written or unwritten, up to the present day in any way. The terns of the contract are valid. (2nd hand). I, Dionysammon, the son of Ision, have received from Hermas one hundred twenty silver drachmas, and I shall not proceed against him in any way as is stated above."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Warga RG, P.Sel.Warga (diss.), 5, 1988 -- SB XXII, 15611 Warga R, ZPE 100, 78-80, 1994, Pl III.2 -- SB XXII, 15611 -- BL XI, 239 (l. 8, 28)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
