<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter [mid III AD]</title>
            <author>Tourbon</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p311</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1235</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.10.278</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;10;278</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;10;278</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">31838</idno>
            <idno type="TM">31838</idno>
            <idno type="filename">31838-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 250</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:24.54723-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Tourbon to his brother Dioskoros many greetings. Before all else I pray that you are in good health. I am well myself. Every day I make obeisance for you in the presence of our lord Sarapis. I want you to know, brother, that having found an opportunity I deemed it necessary to write you this letter, indeed my second one. You yourself did not write back to me even a single letter. You should take thought, brother, as I enjoined you when I was leaving you, not to be careless, knowing that, if you neglect it a little, we will lose them and . . . you will communicate . . . (send me) a cloak and other things. Try to get busy and send me these things very quickly, if he (?) sends them to you. If not, then be more zealous: raise for me the pig of which I have talked to you until it . . . or when it happens, you will write to me. I greet your wife and your children.  I greet Herakles, I greet . . . Petaiesis and Thermouthas and her children. I greet also Sarapias and Keias and her children, I greet Pt(olemaios?) and his wife, I greet all the people who love us.
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. X 278 <note>Plates 33-34 in P.Col. X</note>
               </bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
