<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter from Herais to Lucretias</title>
            <author>Herais</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3964</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3964</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.bingen.74</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0254;;74</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.bingen;;74</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">78042</idno>
            <idno type="TM">78042</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich. inv. 3241</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Herais' letter, probably dictated to a scribe offers the usual difficulties. ;Herais' report of her travels beins somewhere upstream and ends with her probably in Alexandria, where she and her family lived (line 18). From the southern location she went down stream (north) to another place where she found the slave (or freedman) Eros in police custody. She went on to see her "sister" Lukretias' "brother", who had caused the incanceration of Eros because this slave (or freedman) had not paid "the orphans" the share of his profit from his service or work. She tried to persuade the "brother" to let Eros go to a place upstream, perhaps the place where Herais had began her trip downstream. But being unsuccessful, Herais continued her downstream travel to Alexandria where, three days later, Nephotianos arrived. His connection to the business is unclear. He seems to belong to Herais' family, and may have been brought new information. If so, then it was in Alexandria that Herais wrote the prsent lettr toher "sister" Lukretias who was living north of Antinoopolis. Herais asked her for a meeting in Antinoopolis, not in Lukretias' home (closer to Alexandria), probbaly because Antinoopolis was the place where they had to do business. Antinoopolis is the normal seat of the Epistrategos of Heptanomia and the place to do business in his office. As we are inclined to understand, this epistrategos is charged with matters concerning Alexandrians that lived in his jurisdiction. In this scenario, Herais and Lukretias are likely to have been Alexandrians, the latter living north of Antinoopolis. The entire matter seems to have resulted from quarrels about an inheritance, presumably located at the place in the south where Herais had began her travel home to Alexandria.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto + Verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 13.5 x 17.7 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The medium brown papyrus is almost without damage, except on its left side where two lacunae reach into the written text.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">recto:18 lines; verso, 1 line (address)</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto + Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The extant left margin measures between 1 to 1 cm, the top margin is 1 cm, and the irregularly broken bottom margin is up to 7.5 cm. The letter is written by a professional and experienced scribe of the 2nd century with sense for both aesthetics and clarity. The medium sized and relatively broad letters (however small omicron) are connected with each other, but remain distinct. Some letters, not necessarily at the beginning of words, are enlarged as if confessing their importance (alpha, epsilon, eta, theta); line 10, "enthen" takes the center of Herais' letter and is enlarged, especially epsilon and theta. Lines 2 and 3 are indented by the size of about three letters (0.9 cm), like 4 by about two letters, in order to create space for the huge initial epsilon of line 4 which, as it happens, stresses "emwn". The word groups of the opening greeting formula stretch over almost the entire line with spacing between them. The arrangement is clearly the result of planning and experience. The scribe's aesthetic sense was better than his spelling. Iotacism and similar spelling habits are ubiquitous: iota for "ei" and vice versa, eta for epsilon, epsilon for "ai", "ai for eta and vice versa, "ou" for omega and ypsilon of "ou". Omicron is omitted in ending -ion and -ios (lines 16 and 18).;There three corrections with crossed out words (ll. 5, 12, 17). In the first of these changes (5), the scribe replaced a half-written phrase by another. More significant is line 12 where the wrong "kai" has been crossed out. This looks like a misunderstanding between two persons. If so, then the letter was dictated by Herais to a scribe.Whether this conclusion can really be derived from the corrections, remains uncertain, but the conclusion itself is likely for general reasons. Finally, in line 17, the name of "Apollwnian" is eliminated from the list of those whom Herais wants to greet. She may kave recalled that Apollonia is presently not staying with Loukterias. In l. 9 the scribe corrected a half-written letter into an "MH"; and in line 15 the kappa of "kai" looks as if it were written over another letter. A dittography remains uncorrected in l. 6 as well as a missing letter in l. 10 ("geinw&lt;s&gt;ke).</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0100" notAfter="0199">IInd century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Alexandria (?), Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Herais</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Loukretia</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Antonios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Eros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nephotianos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Peteesis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Loukretios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Eutychos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apphys</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonia</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Koprous</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Antinoou (polis), city, Middle Egypt, province of Egypt;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Herais to sister Loukretias greetings. Before everything else I pray that you are in good health, too -and I prostrate before lord Sarapis on your behalf. Don't be concerned about Antonius. Until now, he has not yet enlisted in the army. I want you to know that those who sojourn in Egypt are under the authority of the epistrategos. If you travel up to Antinoopolis, write me at once so that I may come to see you. But if it turns out that you are not going, then write me too so that I won't go under difficulties (?) from this place to there. Know that, when I arrived downstream, I found Eros locked up, and I went to your brother. No matter how often I asked him, he did not want to set him free but said: "If he wishes to go upstream, then he shall pay profit to the orphans". On the forth day after I came to the city, Nephotianos came too. Write us whether you have received the purple dye from Peteesios, the boatman. Greet Lukretias, Eutychos, and Apphys [[and Apollonia]]. Antonios, Koprous and Nephotianos greet you.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Caldwell R - Koenen L, PBingen , 313-328, no 74, 2000, Pl. 44 and 45</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Bingen:74</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3964&amp;viewid=3241R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/4/1/R/3241R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3964&amp;viewid=3241R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3964&amp;viewid=3241R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/4/1/V/3241V.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3964&amp;viewid=3241V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3964&amp;viewid=3241V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
