<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3332</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3332</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 39 is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 39-40: 34.3 x 29.8 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 39: complete; cols. 36-38 cut off and missing</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 39: 55 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 39 (l. 790-844)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinus son of Sisois and Tapais grandson of Sokmenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Onnophris and Thermouthis grandson of Sambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Esouris and Thaesis grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dios (Deios) son of Petheus and Tapetheus grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 160)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus son of Esouris and Tkollauthis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras son of Onnophris and Sopas grandson of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Charidemos son of Petoraipis and Thaesis grandson of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Pnepheros and Tapetheus grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos son of Hatres and Tapetheus grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinus son of Petheus and Eserempis grandson of Heraklas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor son of Achillas and Aphrodous grandson of Kastor (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus son of Herieus and Tremenesis (Tlemenesis) grandson of Petaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Agathos Demon (Daimon) and Stiynchis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabous son of Phaesis and Philoumene grandson of Sarapion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 226)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptollas son of Satabous and Tapondos (Tapontos) grandson of Ptollas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 221)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pamonneios (Pamonneouis) son of Anchorymphis and Didymarion grandson of Pamonneios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron son of Petheus and Taonnophris grandson of Teos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kopaneus son of Polydion and Politta grandson of Kopaneus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 184)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles son of Apollonios and Tapetheus grandson of Petoraipis (Petsoraipis) (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron son of Sabinus and Gaia grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos son of Petheus and Tkollainis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petoraipis (Petsoraipis) son of Hatres and Soeris grandson of Imouthes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinus son of Pasoknopaios and Tapetheus grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harsiesis son of Petheus and Thatres grandson of Harsiesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 39;;On the 29th (of Phamenoth):;Sabinus, son of Sisois and Tapais, grandson of Sokmenis: 8 drachmai;    column 67;Onnophris, son of Onnophris and Thermouthis, grandson of Sambas: 8 drachmai;    column 68;Ptolemaios, son of Esouris and Thaesis, grandson of Heras: 4 drachmai;    column 69;Dios, son of Petheus and Tapetheus, grandson of Heras: 8 drachmai;    column 70;Petaus, son of Esouris and Tkollauthis, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai;    column 71;Heras, son of Onnophris and Sopas, grandson of Onnophris: 4 drachmai;    column 72;Charidemos, son of Petoraipis and Thaesis, grandson of Onnophris: 28 obols;    column 72;Pnepheros, son of Pnepheros and Tapetheus, grandson of Pnepheros: 28 obols;    column 82;Petesouchos, son of Hatres and Tapetheus, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai;    column 82;Sabinus, son of Petheus and Eserempis, grandson of Heraklas: 8 drachmai;    column 84;Kastor, son of Achillas and Aphrodous, grandson of Kastor: 8 drachmai;    column 90;Petaus, son of Herieus and Tremenesis, grandson of Petaus: 4 drachmai;    column 89;Ptolemaios, son of Agathos Daimon and Stiynchis, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai;    column 91;Satabous, son of Phaesis and Philoumene, grandson of Sarapion: 12 drachmai;    column 93;Ptollas, son of Satabous and Tapondos, grandson of Ptollas: 12 drachmai;    column 97;Pamonneios, son of Anchorymphis and Didymarion, grandson of Pamonneios: 8 drachmai;    column 98;Heron, son of Petheus and Taonnophris, grandson of Teos: 8 drachmai 28 obols;    column 39;Kopaneus, son of Polydion and Politta, grandson of Kopaneus: 12 drachmai 28 obols;    column 99;Total for the day: 132 drachmai 24 obols.;;On Pharmouthi 1:;Herakles, son of Apollonios and Tapetheus, grandson of Petoraipis: 12 drachmai 28 obols;    column 47;Heron, son of Sabinus and Gaia, grandson of Pnepheros: 8 drachmai;    column 45;Petesouchos, son of Petheus and Tkollainis, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai;    column 7;Petoraipis, son of Hatres and Soeris, grandson of Imouthes: 4 drachmai;    column 9;Sabinus, son of Pasoknopaios and Tapetheus, grandson of Horos: 4 drachmai;    column 9;Ptolemaios, son of Naaraus and Taorsenouphis, grandson of Horion: 4 drachmai;    column 12;Harsiesis, son of Petheus and Thatres, grandson of Harsiesis: 8 drachmai;    column 14</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 39 (l. 790-844), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3332&amp;viewid=4172_9RO.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/9/r/o/4172_9ro.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3332&amp;viewid=4172_9RO.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3332&amp;viewid=4172_9RO.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
