<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3336</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3336</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 49 is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 49-50: 36.7 x 29.8 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 49: complete; cols. 43-48 cut off and missing</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 49: 49 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 49 (l. 969-1017)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonis (Ammonios) son of Ammonios and Tninis grandson of Ammonios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 151)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hermation, doulos of Isidoros alias Longinus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Kollouthos and Thaesis grandson of Phaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Leonides and Thermouthis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sokmenis son of Sokrates and Tapetheus grandson of Phasis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 230)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaseis son of Dioskoros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Petaus and Segathis grandson of Orsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 203)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus son of Sisois and Thermouthis grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Karanos son of Orsenouphis and Tapetsiris grandson of Imouthes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon son of Heron and Didyme grandson of Orsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis son of Heras and Isidora grandson of Orsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois son of Limnaios and Thaesis grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion alias Sokrates son of Achillas and Tamaron grandson of Hatres (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron son of Petheus and Taonnophris grandson of Teos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis son of Phanomgeus and Tepheros grandson of Pakysis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Petheus and Thaesis grandson of Sokmenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Perigenes and Tanais grandson of Akousilaos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois son of Petesouchos and Tkonnos grandson of Herakles (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Pnepheros and Tapetheus grandson of Phanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Patron son of Sokmenis and Taonnophris grandson of Sokmenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 200)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras (= Heras alias Petheus?) son of Aphrodisios and Isidora grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Teos son of Mysthes and Tanais grandson of Anchophis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 242)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion son of Petoraipis (Petsoraipis) and Sambathion grandson of Demas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Donkeys--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Guards troops--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Slaves--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Real property tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 49;;In Pharmouthi,;on the 9th:;Ammonis, son of Ammonios and Tninis, grandson of Ammonios: 8 drachmai;    column 26;Hermation, slave of Isidoros also called Longinus: 24 drachmai 28 obols;    column 27;Petheus, son of Kollouthos and Thaesis, grandson of Phaesis: for the guards: 4 drachmai;    column 27;Ptolemaios, son of Leonides and Thermouthis, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai;    column 28;Sokmenis, son of Sokrates and Tapetheus, grandson of Phasis: 12 drachmai;    column 29;Phaseis, son of Dioskoros: for the five-drachm tax on donkeys, for year 14,  for the maintenance work of year 12: 5 drachmai, and supplements: 2 obols. Total 5 drachmai 2 obols. (In the left margin: 4 drachmai 14 obols);Petheus, son of Petaus and Segathis, grandson of Orsenouphis: 8 drachmai;    column 31;Petaus, son of Sisois and Thermouthis, grandson of Satabous: 4 drachmai;    column 34;Karanos, son of Orsenouphis and Tapetsiris, grandson of Imouthes: 4 drachmai 27 obols;    column 35;Chairemon, son of Heron and Didyme, grandson of Orsenouphis: 4 drachmai 28 obols;    column 35;Phaesis, son of Heras and Isidora, grandson of Orsenouphis: 4 drachmai;    column 36;Sisois, son of Limnaios and Thaesis, grandson of Satabous: 8 drachmai;    column 36;Sarapion also called Sokrates, son of Achillas and Tamaron, grandson of Hatres: 12 drachmai;    column 38;Heron, son of Petheus and Taonnophris, grandson of Teos: 28 obols;    column 39;Pakysis, son of Phanomgeus and Tepheros, grandson of Pakysis: 4 drachmai 28 obols;    column 40;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus and Thaesis, grandson of Sokmenis: 8 drachmai;    column 43;Sarapion, son of Perigenes and Tanais, grandson of Akousilaos: 8 drachmai;    column 45;Sisois, son of Petesouchos and Tkonnos, grandson of Herakles: 4 drachmai;    column 46;Onnophris, son of Pnepheros and Tapetheus, grandson of Phanomgeus: 4 drachmai;    column 58;Patron, son of Sokmenis and Taonnophris, grandson of Sokmenis: 4 drachmai;    column 50;Heras, son of Aphrodisios and Isidora, grandson of Petheus: 20 drachmai;    column 52;Teos, son of Mysthes andTanais, grandson of Anchophis: 4 drachmai;    column 52;Horion, son of Petoraipis and Sambathion, grandson of Demas: 8 drachmai 28 obols;    column 51</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 49 (l. 969-1017), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3336&amp;viewid=4172_11RO.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/1/r/o/4172_11ro.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3336&amp;viewid=4172_11RO.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3336&amp;viewid=4172_11RO.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
