<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3654</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3654</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.224</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso contains two columns of names</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 34.4 x 33 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at all sides except at the top where it has been torn off. Kollesis near the left edge. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-48</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 18 (ll. 691-739)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymos, son of Petheus, grandson of Heraklas, mother Eserempis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 161)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymos, son of Satabous, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Petheus, grandson of Teos, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herieus the older, son of Horos, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ninis, son of Asklas, grandson of Ninis, mother Tabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Didymos, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymos, son of Heron, grandson of Heras, mother Tasiaipis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 161)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabeinos, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Zoidous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Psenesis, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dioskoros, son of Aiaus, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Thases (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabeinos, son of Petheus, grandson of Sambas, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Sambas, grandson of Sabeinos, mother Aphrodous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Anchorimphis, grandson of Horos, mother Achillis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Petaus, grandson of Petaus, mother Tauris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Artemas, son of Heron, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Petermouthis, grandson of Apynchis, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis, son of Onnophris, grandson of Satabous, mother Soeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles, son of Petheus, grandson of Onnophris, mother Taseus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Ekysis, grandson of Menandros, mother Herais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes, son of Petheus, grandson of Mysthes, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis, son of Phasis, grandson of Esouris, mother Tanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon, son of Horos, grandson of Onnophris, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Perigenes, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Tanais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Aphrodisios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Didymarion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Polyndikes, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchophis, son of Mysthes, grandson of Anchophis, mother Tanais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Panesneus, son of Ischyras, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Satabous, mother Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Anchophis, grandson of Herakles, mother Teseuris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petsiris, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Petsiris, mother Heros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 211)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mystharion, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Euhemeros, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 188)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor, son of Onnophris, grandson of Maron, mother Tkollainis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Germanos, slave of Longinus Isidoros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 160)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Kames, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hatres, son of Apollonios, grandson of Heraklas, mother Taorsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 156)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Besis, grandson of Thoteus, mother Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Besis, son of Petheus, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 159)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabeinos, son of Sisois, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Tapais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Onnophris, grandson of Sambas, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 223)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>" (Column) 18:;Pnepheros, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tapetheus, obols 28;;Didymos, son of Petheus, grandson of Heraklas, mother Eserempis, drachmas 8;;Didymos, son of Satabous, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tanomgeus, drachmas 8;;Onnophris, son of Petheus, grandson of Teos, mother Segathis, drachmas 4;;Herieus the older, son of Horos, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8;;Ninis, son of Asklas, grandson of Ninis, mother Tabous, obols 28;;Petheus, son of Didymos, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaisas, drachmas 4;;Didymos, son of Heron, grandson of Heras, mother Tasiaipis, drachmas 4;;Sabeinos, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Zoidous, drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, son of Harmiysis, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Psenesis, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 12, obols 8;;12th year the same, drachmas 4, ? copper drachmas;;Dioskoros, son of Aiaus, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Thases, drachmas 4;;Sabeinos, son of Petheus, grandson of Sambas, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, son of Sambas, grandson of Sabeinos, mother Aphrodous, drachmas 4;;Horos, son of Anchorimphis, grandson of Horos, mother Achillis, drachmas 4;;Horos, son of Petaus, grandson of Petaus, mother Tauris, drachmas 4;;Artemas, son of Heron, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, son of Petermouthis, grandson of Apynchis, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 8;;Pakysis, son of Onnophris, grandson of Satabous, mother Soeris, drachmas 8;;in total for the day drachmas 196, obols 16, of which 12th year drachmas 12, obols 11;;(Mecheir) 6 likewise:   ;Herakles, son of Petheus, grandson of Onnophris, mother Taseus, drachmas 8;;Heron, son of Ekysis, grandson of Menandros, mother Herais, drachmas 12;;Mysthes, son of Petheus, grandson of Mysthes, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Thaisas, drachmas 8;;Pakysis, son of Phasis, grandson of Esouris, mother Tanomgeus, drachmas 4, obols 28;;Chairemon, son of Horos, grandson of Onnophris, mother Segathis, drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8;;Sarapion, son of Perigenes, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Tanais, drachmas 8;;Pnepheros, son of Aphrodisios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Didymarion, drachmas 4;;Phaesis, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Polyndikes, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;12th year Anchophis, son of Mysthes, grandson of Anchophis, mother Tanais, ? copper drachmas;;Panesneus, son of Ischyras, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Satabous, mother Heras, drachmas 4;;Horos, son of Anchophis, grandson of Herakles, mother Teseuris, drachmas 8;;Petsiris, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Petsiris, mother Heros, drachmas 4;;Mystharion, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Euhemeros, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 8;;Kastor, son of Onnophris, grandson of Maron, mother Tkollainis, drachmas 12;;12th year the same, copper drachmas 8, ? copper drachmas;;Germanos, slave of Longinus Isidoros, drachmas 12;;Sarapion, son of Kames, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Hatres, son of Apollonios, grandson of Heraklas, mother Taorsenouphis, drachmas 8;;Pnepheros, son of Besis, grandson of Thoteus, mother Heras, obols 28;;Besis, son of Petheus, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4, obols 28;;Sabeinos, son of Sisois, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Tapais, drachmas 8;;Sambas, son of Onnophris, grandson of Sambas, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 176, obols 12 of which the 12th year drachmas 12, obols 11."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3654&amp;viewid=4171_18R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3654&amp;viewid=4171_18R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3654&amp;viewid=4171_18R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
