<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Cession of Catoecic Land</title>
            <author>Didymos the younger, son of Lysimachos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2831</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2831</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.262</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;262</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;262</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12095</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12095</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 641</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract, lacking the customary heading and the subscriptions of the contracting parties, by which Didymos the younger, son of Lysimachos, acknowledges to his wife and sister Hero the cession of 10 arourai of a catoecic allotment near Theogonis, cession which was actually made on May 25, 33 A.D., and by which Hero agrees to a valuation of part of her dowry, which is to be given to Didymos to complete the price of the 10 arourai</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 29.4 x 28.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">broken off on the left side</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">32</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a large, upright cursive hand (Husselman)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0034" notAfter="0036">34-35 or 35-36 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">add P.Mich. XII, 632)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herodes son of Ptolemaios, kinsman and guardian of Hero (see also P.Mich. V, 266)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides son of Didymos (former owner) (see also P.Mich. V, 236</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">313?)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Theogonis, Polemonos meris; Alexandreinos</term>
               <term>Cession</term>
               <term>Dowry--Egypt-- Theogonis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Family</term>
               <term>Irrigation</term>
               <term>Jewels</term>
               <term>Land Ownership</term>
               <term>Land Status</term>
               <term>Marriage (Brother-sister marriage)</term>
               <term>Notary</term>
               <term>Taxation (Land)</term>
               <term>Woman (&amp;amp</term>
               <term>guardian)</term>
               <term>Theogonis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[Didymos] the younger, son of Lysimachos, about 41 years old, tall, with honey-colored skin, with a scar on his right shin, acknowledges to his wife, Hero, who is also his sister on both his father's and his mother's side, about 35 years old, of middle height, fair-skinned, with a scar in the middle of her forehead, with her guardian, her kinsman Herodes, son of Ptolemaios, about 30 years old, of middle height, with honey-colored skin, with a scar below his left temple, that he has ceded to her and to her heirs and assigns for transfer forever from the catoecic estates belonging to him near Theogonis in the division of Polemon ten arourai, or as many as there may be, of the catoecic allotment formerly belonging to Herakleides, son of Didymos, and all the appurtenances. The neighbors are: on the south the allotment of the acknowledging party, Didymos, and of his brothers; on the north the royal road; on the west the drainage canal of the designated ten arourai and of the aforesaid allotment of Didymos and his brothers which is on the south; on the east the irrigation canal of the same two allotments. He, Didymos, has already drawn up  the documents for the transfer and cession to Hero through the catoecic record office in the nineteenth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, Pachon 30, as was fitting. As for the price fixed for the ceded allotment Hero has therefore, in accordance with this agreement, agreed with Didymos to the sum of . . . drachmai of minted silver, which is the valuation of eight pairs of armlets of the sum of four minai, and of a chain of two and one-half minai, being a total of six and one-half minai of acceptable Alexandrian gold according to the Alexandrian standard, which Didymos received in the dowry given to him and to Hero by the father of both of them, Lysimachos, son of Didymos, who is dead . . ., in accordance with the contract of cohabitation executed through the notary's office in the tenth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus . . ., Didymos having received from Hero the other sum of money to complete the price of the allotment, likewise from hand to hand out of the house; and neither Hero nor anyone in her behalf shall proceed against Didymos or his representatives or bring any claim with regard to those aforesaid six and one-half minai of gold, and the contract of cohabitation shall remain valid and legal in regard to the rest of the property brought as dowry for Hero, in addition to the six and one-half gold minai, and in regard to all the other conditions designated in the said contract; and Didymos and his representatives also agree that they will guarantee to Hero and her representatives the ceded allotment with every guarantee from all public taxes and the artab tax and the naubion tax and the arithmetikon and the price of the land and the impost of the village and the surtaxes and all the imposts and every tax from past times up to the twenty-first year and for the twenty-first year also of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, and from private debts and every claim forever; and that they will present no one who will prevent Hero or her representatives from owning this property and from using the entrances and exits to it, and from working it and sowing it and leasing it, and from irrigating it and draining it as has been customary before, and from appropriating the proceeds of it and mortgaging it and ceding it to others and controlling it as they wish; and that they will bring no claims against the aforesaid conditions nor dispute nor attack them in any way. Otherwise, in addition to the fact that everything undertaken against them shall be invalid, Didymos shall also pay to Hero immediately the price of the allotment increased by one half and with interest, and as a private debt 2,000 drachmai and the damages, and an equal amount into the public treasury. Moreover, this agreement and the documents of the transfer and cession shall remain valid forever.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 262, 1944 -- BL VII, 111 (date)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:262</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2831&amp;viewid=641R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/4/1/R/641R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2831&amp;viewid=641R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2831&amp;viewid=641R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
