<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3338</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3338</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 51 is blank (except perhaps an offprint at the top)</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 51-52: 36 x 29.8 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 51: nearly complete (papyrus cut off left of col. 51 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 51: 51 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 51 (l. 1069-1119)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois son of Neilos and Taeuemeros grandson of Euemeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Sambas and Aphrodous grandson of Sabinus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois son of Naaraus deuteros and Thaisas grandson of Theabenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hatres son of Phanomgeus and Tapetheus grandson of Heraklas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 157)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Petheus and Eserempis grandson of Aunes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchophis son of Anchophis and Taorsenouphis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos son of Petheus and Thaesis grandson of Petaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Heras and Tasoucharion grandson of Ptolemaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Petesouchos and Charis grandson of Petesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Euemeros son of Euemeros and Tauris grandson of Keras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis son of Onnophris and Soeris grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kames son of Petheus and Tkonnos grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabous son of Petheus and Tapetaus grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 226)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus son of Tesenouphis and Thaesis grandson of Harphaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus son of Pnepheros and Thaesis grandson of Phanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron son of Petheus neoteros and Aplonous (Apollonous) grandson of Anchorimphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides son of Abykis and Herais grandson of Abykis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Satabous and Theonis grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 220)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Sisois and Thaesis grandson of Petsiris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">P.Cair.Mich. 359, vol. II, p. 25)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Deios (Dios) son of Philon (grandson of Deios) (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 160)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Osis (phylax) (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 251)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psenesis son of Petheus and Kommonis (Komonis) grandson of Esouris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Diodoros son of Thaisas, apator (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Baths, Roman--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Illegitimacy--Egypt</term>
               <term>Karanis (Extinct city)--Defenses.</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Dovecotes--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax exemption--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 51;;(Pharmouthi 10, continued);Sisois, son of Neilos and Taeuemeros, grandson of Euemeros: 28 obols;    column 94;Ptolemaios, son of Sambas and Aphrodous, grandson of Sabinus: 4 drachmai;    column 95;Sisois, son of Naaraus the second and Thaisas, grandson of Theabenis: 4 drachmai;    column 101;Hatres, son of Phanomgeus and Tapetheus, grandson of Heraklas: 8 drachmai;    column 103;Horos, son of Petheus and Eserempis, grandson of Aunes: 4 drachmai;    column 104;Anchophis, son of Anchophis and Taorsenouphis, grandson of Petheus: 12 drachmai;    column 98;Petesouchos, son of Petheus and Thaesis, grandson of Petaus: 12 drachmai;    column 98;Ptolemaios, son of Heras and Tasoucharion, grandson of Ptolemaios: 28 obols;    column 96;Ptolemaios, son of Petesouchos and Charis, grandson of Petesouchos: 16 drachmai;    column 14;Euemeros, son of Euemeros and Tauris, grandson of Keras: 12 drachmai;    column 105;Pakysis, son of Onnophris and Soeris, grandson of Satabous: 8 drachmai;    column 97;Total for the day: 188 drachmai 24 obols.;;On the 11th, similarly:;Kames, son of Petheus and Tkonnos, grandson of Petheus, over the age (of liability to the poll-tax), for the guard towers: 8 drachmai;    column 93;Satabous, son of Petheus and Tapetaus, grandson of Satabous: 4 drachmai;    column 1;Horos the younger, son of Hatres and Teraus, grandson of Horos: 4 drachmai;    column 2;Phanomgeus, son of Tesenouphis and Thaesis, grandson of Harphaesis: 4 drachmai;    column 3;Phanomgeus, son of Pnepheros and Thaesis, grandson of Phanomgeus: 4 drachmai;    column 5;Maron, son of Petheus the younger and Aplonous, grandson of Anchorimphis: 4 drachmai;    column 8;Herakleides, son of Abykis and Herais, grandson of Abykis: 8 drachmai;    column 9;Ptolemaios, son of Satabous and Theonis, grandson of Horos: 4 drachmai 27 obols;    column 10;Onnophris, son of Sisois and Thaesis, grandson of Petsiris: 4 drachmai;    column 12;Lucius Longinus Gemellus, for the third (of the revenue) of the bath establishment, for year14: 28  drachmai including extra charges.;Deios, son of Philon - (paid through) Osis: for the third (of the revenue) of a dovecote, for year 14: 3 drachmai, and supplements: 1 obol 2 chalkoi. Total: 3 drachmai 1 obol 2 chalkoi. (In left margin: 28 obols).;Psenesis, son of Petheus and Kommonis, grandson of Esouris: 4 drachmai;    column 20;Diodoros, of unknown father, his mother being Thaisas: 8 drachmai;    column 21</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 51 (l. 1069-1119), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3338&amp;viewid=4172_12RO.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/r/o/4172_12ro.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3338&amp;viewid=4172_12RO.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3338&amp;viewid=4172_12RO.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/v/o/4172_12vo.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3338&amp;viewid=4172_12VO.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3338&amp;viewid=4172_12VO.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
