<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3329</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3329</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 33 is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 33-34: 35.7 x 29.2 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 33: complete (papyrus cut off left of col. 33 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 33: 58 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 33 (l. 639-696)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Pnepheros and Thaesis grandson of Phanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis son of Pekmeis alias Heuremon and Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinus son of Pasoknopaios and Tapetheus grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabous son of Dioskoros and Taorion (Tahorion) grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 226)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Sisois and Thaesis grandson of Petsiris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psenesis son of Pharmennion (Parmenion) and Tkonnos grandson of Psenesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion son of Petheus and Komonis grandson of Esouris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Agathopous, doulos of Thermouthis alias Tpaietis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 148)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis son of Petheus and Tapetheus grandson of Horion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 194)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor son of Artemas and Thaesis grandson of Heron (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Priscus alias Pasoxis son of Satabous and Thermouthis grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 215)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes son of Petheus and Tasoucharion grandson of Mysthes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Limnais (Limaios) son of Onnophris and Ptolema grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 185)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petermouthis son of Kastor and Tasoucharion grandson of Heraklas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Esouris son of Kames and Thaesis grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Pnepheros and Tapetheus grandson of Phanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Thaisas, doulos of Syros alias Ptolemaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis son of Pasoxis and Thaesis grandson of Polyntikos (Polyndikos) (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpagathes son of Pnepheros and Tapetheus grandson of Pekmeis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus son of Onnophris and Tkateis grandson of Petaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horon (Horion) son of Aphrodisios and Tapetaus grandson of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Pasoxis and Thakiaris (Thakialis) grandson of Petesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Petheus and Thaisas grandson of Petesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Papeis (Papeeis) son of Ptolemaios and Heras grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Apollonios and Thermouthis grandson of Harpagathes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus son of Phanomgeus and Taptosiris grandson of Phanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Slaves--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 33;;On (Phamenoth) 23;Onnophris, son of Pnepheros and Thaesis, grandson of Phanomgeus: 8 drachmai;    column 4;Phaesis, son of Pekmeis also called Heuremon and Sambathion: 4 drachmai;    column 6;Sabinus, son of Pasoknopaios and Tapetheus, grandson of Horos: 4 drachmai;    column 9;Satabous, son of Dioskoros and Taorion, grandson of Satabous: 4 drachmai;    column 9;Onnophris, son of Sisois and Thaesis, grandson of Petsiris: 8 drachmai;    column 12;Psenesis, son of Pharmennion and Tkonnos, grandson of Psenesis: 8 drachmai;    column 16;Horion, son of Petheus and Komonis, grandson of Esouris: 4 drachmai;    column 18;Agathopous, slave of Thermouthis also called Tpaietis: 4 drachmai;    column 21;Orsenouphis, son of Petheus and Tapetheus, grandson of Horion: 8 drachmai;    column 22;Kastor, son of Artemas and Thaesis, grandson of Heron: 12 drachmai;    column 96;Priscus also called Pasoxis, son of Satabous and Thermouthis, grandson of Pnepheros: 8 drachmai;    column 33;Mysthes, son of Petheus and Tasoucharion, grandson of Mysthes: 4 drachmai;    column 36;Limnais, son of Onnophris and Ptolema, grandson of Satabous: 4 drachmai;    column 35;Petermouthis, son of Kastor and Tasoucharion, grandson of Heraklas: 8 drachmai;    column 40;Esouris, son of Kames and Thaesis, grandson of Heras: 4 drachmai;    column 41;Total for the day: 92 drachmai;;On the 24th, similarly:;Onnophris, son of Pnepheros and Tapetheus, grandson of Phanomgeus: 4 drachmai;    column 58;Sarapion, slave of Syros also called Ptolemaios, the offspring of Thaisas: 28 obols;    column 50;Phaesis, son of Pasoxis and Thaesis, grandson of Polyntikos: 4 drachmai;    column 51;Harpagathes, son of Pnepheros and Tapetheus, grandson of Pekmeis: 8 drachmai;    column 54;Petaus, son of Onnophris and Tkateis, grandson of Petaus: 8 drachmai;    column 57;Horon, son of Aphrodisios and Tapetaus, grandson of Onnophris: 8 drachmai;    column 58;Pnepheros, son of Pasoxis and Thakiaris, grandson of Petesouchos: 4 drachmai;    column 59;Pnepheros, son of Petheus and Thaisas, grandson of Petesouchos: 4 drachmai;    column 59;Papeis, son of Ptolemaios and Heras, grandson of Pnepheros: 4 drachmai;    column 59;Sarapion, son of Apollonios and Thermouthis, grandson of Harpagathes: 4 drachmai;    column 61;Phanomgeus, son of Phanomgeus and Taptosiris, grandson of Phanomgeus: 4 drachmai;    column 62;Chairemon, his son, (born of) Tbelles: 4 drachmai;    column 62</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 33 (l. 639-696), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3329&amp;viewid=4172_7RO.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/7/r/o/4172_7ro.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3329&amp;viewid=4172_7RO.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3329&amp;viewid=4172_7RO.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
