<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>petition</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2917</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2917</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.5.8010</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;5;8010</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;5;8010</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">25305</idno>
            <idno type="TM">25305</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 6659</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>this text is a petition submitted by a woman whose name is lost to the exegetes and the prytaneis. The woman is getting divorced from her husband and asks the officials to appoint to her a legal guardian (kyrios).</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 10.8 x 14 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This medium- to dark brown papyrus was reguarly cut at all sides. The damages to the sheet give it a more rugged appearance at the corners and in the top left middle section. (TC) A kollesis running through the middle of the sheet is the cause of a hole which increases from the middle towards the top of the sheet.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-28</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The hand is a small and very irregular cursive, which creates a major uncertainty estimating the number of letters missing in the holes of the papyrus. In the upper half of the text the ink is badly abraded, at places lost completely. In lines 27 and 28 the letters are so cramped together  that the character of the hand is noticeably changed, although there is no doubt that the hand in these lines is the same as that of the previous lines.To the left there is a free margin of 1-2 cm., and above line one there is a margin of 2 cm. Between lines 1-2 there is a free space of 1 cm. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0054" notAfter="0068">54-68 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Alexandria, province of Egypt (?)</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Tiberius Claudius Kronios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tiberius Claudius Caesar</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">A..., daughter of Ptolemaios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonios, son of Theonites . . .Ammonios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aristeas, son of Isidoros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aristeas, son of Aristeas</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Alexandria, province of Egypt (?)</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>-</term>
               <term>Divorce--Egypt--Alexandria.</term>
               <term>Dowry--Egypt--Alexandria.</term>
               <term>Guardian and ward --Egypt--Alexandria.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"To Tiberius Claudius Kronios, the Neokoroi of the great Sarapis of Tiberius Claudius . . . , to the priest,  the exegetes  and to the Caesarians and the other prytaneis.;From A..., daughter of Ptolemaios . . . acting with the assistance of Apollonios, son of Theonites . . .  of Ammonios . . . against my husband Aristeas, son of Isidoros from the phyle of Eirenophylakeia and the deme Eusebios; . . . about the fact that I have completed the divorce from my husband with him according to a settlement through the record office in Mecheir of the present year. [I am also . . .about the fact] that I am to receive the dowry which I brought along to him in the shape of clothes evaluated at around 300 silver drachmas and gold jewelry of the weight of 10.5 tetartoi as well as the other objects brought as dowry and named in the settlement after proportion of the other agreements, which according to normal procedure are to be added; that I, apart from the fact that I acquire these objects, so that I can keep them with me until I marry  another man. Furthernore, it has also been written in the settlement, which I attach, concerning my son Aristeas, who is still a baby, that he remains with me but acquires clothing and provisions from Aristeas: I am now prevented [to enjoy my rights of the settlement], since I cannot use Arsiteas as my guardian, because I have divorced him, since my son is a minor, since I do not have other children, and I simply do not have any other [male] relatives. Therefore I beg of You, that the legal guardian will be appointed . . . ."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Wolff HJ, Aegyptus 17, 463-70, 1937 -- SB V 8010 -- BL III, 197 on lines 2,19; BL X, 189 (l. 2; 3; 4); BL XI, 202 (l. 6, 7-8, 29-30) David M-Groningen BA, Papyr Primer 4, 29, 1965</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:5:8010</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2917&amp;viewid=6659R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/5/9/r/6659r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2917&amp;viewid=6659R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2917&amp;viewid=6659R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
