<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Christian literature: The Sphepherd of Hermas, Similitudines (GCS 48, 51, 8-82, 1)</title>
            <author>Hermas (?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3914</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3914</idno>
            <idno type="dclp">59985</idno>
            <idno type="TM">59985</idno>
            <idno type="dclp-hybrid">p.mich;2.2;129</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 917</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>The Sphepherd of Hermas, Similitudines, preserving the last part of VI, 5  (pages 27 and 28) and  end of VII and beginning of VIII, 1  (pages 33 and 34)</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">The translation is Roberts-Donaldson's as in the http://www.earlychristianwritings.com/shepherd.html</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Verso (pages 34 and 27) + Recto (pages 28 and 33)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 21.7 x 23.7 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Under this number 26 separate mounts are comprised. Of these, Nos 1 to 6 inclusive contain single leaves. No 7-8 contains in one mount a small part of each of two sepatate leaves. Nos 9 to 14 are sheets or double leaves containg four pages each; in all these cases the two leaves forming the sheet are still attached at the middle. Nos 15 to 25 are single leaves again, and no 26 contains four very small unplaced fragments, and two others which may not have belonged to the Hermas manuscript. The unplaced fragments show only two or three letters each.;The sheets or double leaves belonged to the middle of the book. But one side of every sheet, in most cases the left as it would lie with the book open at the middle, has suffered considerably, so that even in this part of the book some pages are adly frayed and lacerated. Of the single leaves a few are well preserved, but most of them have considerable portions broken away; and some are reduced to mere fragments. ;The papyrus used was of fine quality, thin and well polished, and it still retains something of its original toughness and pliability.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">p. 27: 30 lines; p. 28: 30 lines;p. 33: 31 lines; p. 34: 29 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Verso (pages 34 and 27) + Recto (pages 28 and 33)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The extreme measurements of the double leaves are at present 24.3 cm in height and 22.1 in breadth. Since all the margins have been broken away to a greater or less extent, the original size is somewhat uncertain; 25 by 22.5 or 23 cm is a reasonable estimate. Thus the book, when closed, was a tall volume, a little more than twice as high as it was wide. ;The columns of writing vary from 19 to 20 cm in height and are usually 8-9 cm wide, though some are no more than 7 cm. The space between the two columns on a sheet, which varies from 2 to 3 cm is rather narrow in view of the circumstances that the book appears. It  have consisted of one very large quire, each successive sheet lying inside the preceding ones. The scribe's practice was not very regular either in the number of lines allowed for a page or in the number of letters making a line. The commonest page-length is 30 lines; but the number runs as low as 28 and as high as 34, and there are several pages of 31 oe 32 lines. The variation in the length of the lines is even greater. Not taking into account several lines which have not been filled out completely, we find that there are lines with as few as 14 letters and as many as 24. The breadth of the columns and the distance between them are not much affected by the lessening of the number of letters in the line; the hand is simply more spreading. The variation in the length of the line considerably increases the difficulty of reconstructing the text when the right margin is broken away. ;The pages were numbered in the middle of the upper margin by a hand different from that which wrote the text, and certainly later.;When the book was closed, the side of the papyrus leaf where the fibers run vertically was out and the other side where the fibers run in a horizontal direction was in. ;At the time of the numbering of the pages, the book probably consisted of a single gathering of 43 sheets, or 172 pages. It had originally contained 6 more sheets, and it is probable that still another was added, outside of them all. This served as a cover to protect the written leaves.;The whole text of the manuscript is written in one hand, a fairly large, well-formed, moderately sloping uncial of the type which paleographers have somewhat vaguely called oval, because the curves of such letters as epsilon, theta, an sigma are elliptical or oval rather than circular. The writer was evidently an accomplished scribe, but it may be that his skill was acquired in professional letter writing rather than in the copying books.Certainly his work is even and regular, and lapses into a cursive style only in a few cases when alpha is made without lifting the pen, and is connected with the following iota.  He uses a relatively small omicron and a flat omega, which has only a slight wave in the base and occasionally none at all. Both omicron and omega are st slightly above the base line. Attention may be called to the deeply notched mu and to the beta in which the lower loop is closed by a straight line that is often carried on to the right beyond the descending curve. The scribe often uses a slight hook or starting stroke in making both horizontal and vertical strokes.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0250" notAfter="0300">second half of the IIIrd century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>probably Theadelphia (Batn-el-Hatit), Themistou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt or  Lycopolis (Assiut), Upper Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Literary; christian</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>The translation is Roberts-Donaldson's as in the http://www.earlychristianwritings.com/shepherd.html;;(page 27) (Sim. VI,5:)  He who indulges in luxury, and is deceived for one day, and who does what he wishes, is clothed with much foolishness, and does not understand the act which he does until the morrow; for he forgets what he did the day before. For luxury and deceit have no memories, on account of the folly with which they are clothed; but when punishment and torture cleave to a man for one day, he is punished and tortured for a year; for punishment and torture have powerful memories. While tortured and punished, therefore, for a whole year, he remembers at last a his luxury and deceit, and knows that an their account he suffers evil. Every man, therefore, who is luxurious and deceived is thus tormented, because, although having life, they have given themselves over to death." (page 28) "What kinds of luxury, sir," I asked, "are hurtful?" "Every act of a man which he performs with pleasure," he replied, "is an act of luxury; for the sharp-tempered man, when gratifying his tendency, indulges in luxury; and the adulterer, and the drunkard, and the back-biter, and the liar, and the covetous man, and the thief, and he who does things like these, gratifies his peculiar propensity, and in so doing indulges in luxury. All these acts of luxury are hurtful to the servants of God. On account of these deceits, therefore, do they suffer, who are punished and tortured. And there are also acts of luxury which save men; for many who do good indulge in luxury, being carried away by their own pleasure: this luxury, however ...;;(page 33) (Sim. VII:) every affliction will depart from you. And affliction," he added, "will depart from all who walk in these my commandments." (Sim. VIII, 1:) He showed me a large willow tree overshadowing plains and mountains, and under the shade of this willow had assembled all those who were called by the name of the Lord. And a glorious angel of the Lord, who was very tall, was standing beside the willow, having a large, pruning-knife, and he was cutting little twigs from the willow and distributing them among the people that were overshadowed by the willow; and the twigs which he gave them were small, about a cubit, as it were, in length. And after they had all received the twigs, the angel laid down the pruning-knife, and that tree was sound, as I had seen it at first. And I marvelled within myself, saying, "How is the tree sound, after so many branches have been cut off?" And the Shepherd said to me, "Do not be surprised if the tree remains sound after so many branches were lopped off; [but wait, ] and when you shall have seen everything, then it will be explained to you what it means." The angel who had distributed the branches among the people (page 34) again asked them from them, and in the order in which they had received them were they summoned to him, and each one of them returned his branch. And the angel of the Lord took and looked at them. From some he received the branches withered and moth-eaten; those who returned branches in that state the angel of the Lord ordered to stand apart. Others, again, returned them withered, but not moth-eaten; and these he ordered to stand apart. And others returned them half-withered, and these stood apart; and others returned their branches half-withered and having cracks in them, and these stood apart. [And others returned their branches green and having cracks in them; and these stood apart. ] And others returned their branches, one-half withered and the other green;</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Bonner C, HThR 18, 115-27, 1925 Bonner C, Shepherd of Hermas P.Mich. 129, 39-126, 1934, Pl I-V</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3914&amp;viewid=917_14R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/1/4/r/917_14r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3914&amp;viewid=917_14R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3914&amp;viewid=917_14R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/1/4/v/917_14v.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3914&amp;viewid=917_14V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3914&amp;viewid=917_14V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
