<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3342</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3342</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto + Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 55-56: 37.1 x 29.3 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 55: complete, but damaged at the kollesis (papyrus cut off left of col. 55 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 55, recto: 50 lines;;Verso: 2 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 55 (l. 1247-1296) + Verso of col. 55 (l. 3413-3414)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios son of Petheus and Taseus grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menches son of Satabous and Tkonnos grandson of Maron (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinus son of Pasoknopaios and Tapetheus grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Petaus and Thaesis grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Souchas son of Herakles and Helene grandson of Souchas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 231)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Heron and Eserempis grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis son of Panesneus and Tapetheus grandson of Pakysis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis son of Pakysis and Tapetheus grandson of Artemidoros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 194)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon son of Pasoxis and Tanephremis grandson of Pasoxis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis son of Phanomgeus and Tepheros grandson of Pakysis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Paoueites son of Petheus and Tapetheus grandson of Phasis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis son of Phasis and Tanomgeus grandson of Esouris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon son of Horos and Segathis grandson of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Petheus and Thaisas grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Patron son of Sokmenis and Taonnophris grandson of Sokmenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 200)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpagathes son of Pnepheros and Tapetheus grandson of Pekmeis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Harpagathes and Thaesis grandson of Pnepheros and Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Phanomgeus and Taptosiris grandson of Phanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Naaraus the elder and Tamares (Tamarres) grandson of Theabenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras son of Horos alias Karanos and Tamystha grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos son of Hatres and Tapetheus grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apitas son of Kastor and Petronia grandson of Apitas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 152)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Teos (son of Petheus and Taonnophris grandson of Teos)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 55;;On the 21st (of Pharmouthi), similarly:;Aphrodisios, son of Petheus and Taseus, grandson of Pnepheros: 4 drachmai;    column 3;Menches, son of Satabous and Tkonnos, grandson of Maron: 4 drachmai 28 obols;    column 5;Sabinus, son of Pasoknopaios and Tapetheus, grandson of Horos: 4 drachmai;    column 9;Onnophris, son of Petaus and Thaesis, grandson of Pnepheros: 8 drachmai;    column 11;Souchas, son of Herakles and Helene, grandson of Souchas: 8 drachmai;    column 16;Petheus, son of Heron and Eserempis, grandson of Pnepheros: 8 drachmai;    column 17;Pakysis, son of Panesneus and Tapetheus, grandson of Pakysis: 4 drachmai;    column 18;Orsenouphis, son of Pakysis and Tapetheus, grandson of Artemidoros: 8 drachmai;    column 30;Chairemon, son of Pasoxis and Tanephremis, grandson of Pasoxis: 28 obols;    column 40;Pakysis, son of Phanomgeus and Tepheros, grandson of Pakysis: 8 drachmai;    column 40;Paoueites, son of Petheus and Tapetheus, grandson of Phasis: 4 drachmai;    column 41;Pakysis, son of Phasis and Tanomgeus, grandson of Esouris: 8 drachmai;    column 42;Chairemon, son of Horos and Segathis, grandson of Onnophris: 8 drachmai;    column 42;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus and Thaisas, grandson of Heras: 8 drachmai;    column 42;Total for the day: 88 drachmai 27 obols.;;On the 22nd, similarly:;Patron, son of Sokmenis and Taonnophris, grandson of Sokmenis: 4 drachmai;    column 50;Harpagathes, son of Pnepheros and Tapetheus, grandson of Pekmeis: 8 drachmai;    column 55;Ptolemaios, his son, (born) of Thaesis: 8 drachmai;    column 55;Ptolemaios, son of Phanomgeus and Taptosiris, grandson of Phanomgeus: 4 drachmai;    column 62;Ptolemaios, son of Naaraus the elder and Tamares, grandson of Theabenis: 8 drachmai;    column 68;Total for the day: 32 drachmai.;;On the 23rd, similarly:;Heras, son of Horos also called Karanos and Tamystha, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai;    column 22;Petesouchos, son of Hatres and Tapetheus, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai;    column 82;Apitas, son of Kastor and Petronia, grandson of Apitas: 28 obols;    column 84;;(Verso);[[Teos:;Pharmouthi 1: 4 drachmai 27 obols.]]</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 55 (l. 1247-1296), with verso (l. 3413-3414), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3342&amp;viewid=55RO.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/5/r/o/55ro.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3342&amp;viewid=55RO.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3342&amp;viewid=55RO.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
