<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3798</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3798</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 28.8 x 29.3 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at the left and at the right. Kollesis at the left edge. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-35</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 49 (ll. 2013-2048)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. Traces of writing on the back have been washed out. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisia, daughter of Ischyrion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 157)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Plimiatis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tasoucharion, daughter of Ptolemaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 239)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Melanas, son of Pakysis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarouilla (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 226)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Julius Prolemaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 178)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maximimus (leper) (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Satabous, mother Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Mysthes, grandson of Petheus, mother Charis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mystharion, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 188)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(Pharmouthi) 9 likewise:</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apitas, son of Chairemon, grandson of Apitas, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 152)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Onnophris, grandson of Sambas, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sempronius Klemes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 228)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Panataeis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Sambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pkiatiap (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Sokmenis, grandson of Sambas, mother Tkollainis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 224)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Onnophris, grandson of Onnophris, mother Sopas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Petalos, grandson of Petaus, mother Taeuhemeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon, son of Chairemon, grandson of Sambas, mother Sokratiaine (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Phasis, grandson of Phasis, mother Helene (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymos, son of Heron, grandson of Heras, mother Tasiaipis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 161)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 49:;Aphrodisia, daughter of Ischyrion (Plimiatis);;orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 5, tax on the produce of olives obols 4 chalki 2, naubion obols 3, surcharges drachma 1 obol 1.5;;(in left margin: drachmas 24 obols 10)eparourion drachmas 3 obols 2, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2, kollybos obol 1 chalki 2, in total drachmas 11 obol 1.5 chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 12 obols 3, surcharges obols 4.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 13 obol 1.5 chalki 2;;Tasoucharion, daughter of Ptolemaios through the agency of Melanas, son of Pakysis (Sarouilla);;orchard taxes for the 12th year. apomoira drachmas 2 obols 4, tax on the produce of olives obols 2.5, naubion obol 1.5 chalki 2, surcharges obols 4 chalki 2;;(in left margin: drachmas 12 obols 27) eparourion drachma 1 obols 4.5 chalki 2, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5, in total drachmas 6 obol 1;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 6 obols 4, surcharges obols 2.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 7obol 0.5 chalki 2);;naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year obol 1.5, surcharges chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total obols 2;;tax on land in release likewise obols 3, surcharges obols 0.5 chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total obols 4;;Julius Prolemaios (Maximimus, leper);;orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 39 obol 1, tax on the produce of olives drachmas 5 obols 3, naubion drachmas 3 obols 5.5, surcharges drachmas 9 obols 4.5;;(in total: drachmas 88 obols 6) eparourion drachmas 26 obol 1, surcharges drachmas 2 obol 1.5, kollybos drachma 1 obols 2.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 88 obol 1 chalki 2;;Ptolemaios, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Satabous, mother Heras, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Mysthes, grandson of Petheus, mother Charis, drachmas 8;;Mystharion, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Heras, drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 284 obols 12;;(Pharmouthi) 9 likewise:;Apitas, son of Chairemon, grandson of Apitas, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 4 copper drachmas 4;;Onnophris, son of Onnophris, grandson of Sambas, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;Sempronius Klemes (Panataeis);;(in left margin: drachmas 8 obols 8) orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 3 obols 4.5, tax on the produce of olives obols 3.5, naubion obols 2.5, surcharges drachma 1;;eparourion drachmas 2 obols 3, surcharges obol 1 chalki 2, kollybos obol 1, in total drachmas 8 obols 3.5 chalki 2;;Ptolemaios, son of Sambas (Pkiatiap);;orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 5 obols 5.5 chalki 2, tax (in left margin: drachmas 28 obols 21)on the produce of olives obols 5, naubion obols 3.5, surcharges drachma 1 obols 3;;eparourion drachmas 4, surcharges obols 2, kollybos obol 1.5, 13 obols 2.5 chalki 2;;geometria drachmas 4, surcharges obols 2, kollybos obols 1.5, in total drachmas 15 obols 4.5 chalki 2;;naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year obols 2.5 chalki 2, surcharges chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total obols 3 chalki 2;;Sambas, son of Sokmenis, grandson of Sambas, mother Tkollainis, drachmas 4;;Heras, son of Onnophris, grandson of Onnophris, mother Sopas, obols 28;;Petaus, son of Petalos, grandson of Petaus, mother Taeuhemeros, drachmas 4;;Chairemon, son of Chairemon, grandson of Sambas, mother Sokratiaine, drachmas 16;;Sarapion, son of Phasis, grandson of Phasis, mother Helene, obols 28;;Didymos, son of Heron, grandson of Heras, mother Tasiaipis, drachmas 4."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3798&amp;viewid=4171_49R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/4/9/r/4171_49r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3798&amp;viewid=4171_49R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3798&amp;viewid=4171_49R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
