<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3803</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3803</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 34.5 x 29.6 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at the left and at the right. Kollesis to the left of the middle. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-36</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 53 (ll. 2169-2205)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Kephalas, son of Anchorymphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 183)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nausis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 190)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Horos, grandson of Horos, mother Taharmothes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Demo, daughter of Syrion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 161)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius Valerius Paulinus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 200)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion, son of Petheus, grandson of Kames, mother Zoidous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Tkollainis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabous, son of Dioskoros, grandson of Satabous, mother Taorion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 226)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psenesis, son of Parmenion, grandson of Psenesis, mother Tkonnos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Valerius, fatherless, mother Valeria (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 195)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambous, daughter of Phanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 224)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Touamkiamoul (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 243)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Limnaios, son of Onnophris, grandson of Satabous, mother Ptolema (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 185)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Pasoxis, mother Tanephremis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tepheros  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kames, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Ptollion, mother Tapetheus  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kames, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Polyndikos, mother Thaesis  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis, son of Kalatytes, grandson of Heras, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 195)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Perigenes, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Tanais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tkateis, daughter of Naaraus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 242)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, priest of Kolokasis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Anchophis, grandson of Herakles, mother Teseuris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mystharion, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Euhemeros, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 188)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Patsonis; see also electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 53:;Kephalas, son of Anchorymphis (Nausis);;orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachma 1 obol 1.5, tax on the produce of olives obol 1 chalki 2, naubion obol 0.5 chalki 2, surcharges obols 2;;(in left margin: obols 28) eparourion obols 5, surcharges obol 0.5, kollybos obol 0.5, in total drachmas 2 obols 5.5;;Horos, son of Horos, grandson of Horos, mother Taharmothes, drachmas 8;;Demo, daughter of Syrion (the son of Paulinus);;(in left margin: drachmas 60 obols 25) orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 10 obol 0.5 chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives drachma 1 obols 3, naubion drachma 1 obol 0.5, surcharges drachmas 2 obols 3.5 chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 14 obol 1, surcharges drachma 1 obol 1, kollybos obols 3 chalki 2, in total 31 obols 4 chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 26 obols 3.5, surcharges drachma 1 obols 4 chalki 2;;Gaius Valerius Paulinus;;naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year drachmas 2 chalki 2, surcharges obol 1 chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachmas 2 obol 1.5 chalki 2;;Pasion, son of Petheus, grandson of Kames, mother Zoidous drachmas 12 copper drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 196 obols 24;;(Pharmouthi) 14 likewise:;Petesouchos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Tkollainis, drachmas 4;;Satabous, son of Dioskoros, grandson of Satabous, mother Taorion, drachmas 4;;Psenesis, son of Parmenion, grandson of Psenesis, mother Tkonnos, drachmas 4;;Valerius, fatherless, mother Valeria, drachmas 4;;Sambous, daughter of Phanomgeus (Touamkiamoul);;orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 3, tax on the produce of olives obols 2.5, naubion obols 2, surcharges obols 5;;(in left margin: drachmas 12 obols 28) eparourion drachmas 2 obol 0.5, surcharges obol 1 chalki 2, kollybos obol 0.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 7;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 7 obols 3, surcharges obols 3, in total drachmas 8; ;Limnaios, son of Onnophris, grandson of Satabous, mother Ptolema, drachmas 4;;Chairemon, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Pasoxis, mother Tanephremis, obols 28;;Pakysis, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tepheros, drachmas 4;;Kames, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Ptollion, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 8;;Kames, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Polyndikos, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4 obols 28;;Pakysis, son of Kalatytes, grandson of Heras, mother Segathis, drachmas 8;;Sarapion, son of Perigenes, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Tanais, drachmas 4;;Tkateis, daughter of Naaraus (Petaus, priest of Kolokasis);;orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 8 obols 4.5, tax on the produce of olives drachma 1 obol 1.5, naubion obols 5 chalki 2, surcharges drachmas 2 obol 1 chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 5 obols 5, surcharges obols 3, kollybos obols 2, in total drachmas 19 obols 4.5;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 21 obols 5 chalki 2, surcharges drachma 1 obol 2.5, in total drachmas 23 obol 1.5 chalki 2;;Horos, son of Anchophis, grandson of Herakles, mother Teseuris, drachmas 4;;Mystharion, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Euhemeros, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 8."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3803&amp;viewid=4171_53R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3803&amp;viewid=4171_53R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3803&amp;viewid=4171_53R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
