<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Loan of money involving labour duties</title>
            <author>Aurelius, . . .</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2372</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2372</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.20.15043</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;20;15043</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;20;15043</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">38532</idno>
            <idno type="TM">38532</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 502</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>The document is a loan of money which involves the amount of five solidi, less six carats per solidus.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Transversa charta</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 31 x 29 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The papyrus in its present condition survives in two large, detached fragments which join exactly in l. 9 of the printed text. It has suffered severe mutilation at the top and the text before the formula acknowledging receipt of the loan is almost completely missing. The right segment has also suffered serious damage, whereas the left side is preserved in a good condition. As is to be expected in this late period, the papyrus is written on charta transversa in which writing and kolleseis run in the same direction. Three kolleseis are extant, the first along line 2 of the printed text, the second along line 9 and the third - the most clearly marked - is located right at the foot of the papyrus. Each kollema measures ca. 14cm. The damage of the papyrus at the top must have been caused by the separation of the upper kollema(ta) from its original location along the joint. The number of the kollemata lost at the top cannot be established.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-15</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The right segment has suffered serious damage, whereas the left side is preserved in a good condition and bears a margin which measures approximately 1.2 cm. At the bottom, the space between the signature of the last witness and the lower edge of the papyrus measures ca. 9.5 cm., and it contains a florishing and fluent notorial counter-signature.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0500" notAfter="0699">VI/VII century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Hermopolis, Hermopolite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius . .</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Iordanes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Phoibammon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Georgius, son of Achilleus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Victor</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Hermopolis, Hermopolite nome, province of Egypt (?)</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Hermopolis</term>
               <term>Loans--Egypt--Hermopolis Magna (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Vineyards--Egypt--Hermopolis Magna (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Irrigation650: 0:Vineyards--Egypt--Hermopolis Magna (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Hermopolis Magna (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"[From X to Y] greeting. I acknowledge that I have received [. . .] five gold solidi less six carats on the public standard of the said city, total 5 gold sol., which I will provide to you whenever I give up the irrigation of the said vineyard in stamped money as I received, without any delay or dispute or lawsuit or legal process, all my possession present and future being mortgaged to you as though by decree of court. The document (is) enforcceable and guaranteed and, having been questioned, I have given my consent. I, Aurelius . . ., the aforementioned, have drawn up this contract as writen above. I, Aurelius Iordanes, son of . . ., from Hermopolis, having been requested, have signed on his behalf because he does not know letters. (2nd hd) I, Aurelius Phoibammon, from Hermopolis, witness the document having had it read to me from the person who has drawn it up. (3rd hd) I, Aurelius Georgius, son of Achilleus, from Hermopolis witness the document having it read to me from the person who has drawn it up. (4th hd) Through Victor, by the Grace of God, public notary."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Gagos T, ZPE 79, 276-80, 1989, Pl VIII -- SB XX 15043 -- BL X, 233 (l. 16)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:20:15043</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2372&amp;viewid=502R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2372&amp;viewid=502R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2372&amp;viewid=502R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
