<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3833</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3833</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 35.2 x 29.6 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at the right and the left. Kollesis at the right. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-33</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 68 (ll. 2733-2766)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Onnophris, grandson of Petaus, mother Tkateis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Esouris, grandson of Onnophris, mother Zoidous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Papeis, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambous, daughter of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 224)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon, son of Apitas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Onnophris, grandson of Sambas, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 223)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Ptolemais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Didymos, grandson of Maron, mother Tauris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 204)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Phasis, grandson of Keras, mother Helene (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herieus the older, son of Horos, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois, son of Petesouchos alias Pnepheros, grandson of Sokrates, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dioskoros, son of Aiaus, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Thases (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapias, daughter of Ptolemaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius Valerius Martialis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 160)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thaseis, daughter of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 174)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes, son of Xistis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 68:;Petaus, son of Onnophris, grandson of Petaus, mother Tkateis, drachmas 4 obols 28;;Pnepheros, son of Esouris, grandson of Onnophris, mother Zoidous, drachmas 4;;Papeis, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Heras, obols 28;;Sambous, daughter of Onnophris (through the agency of Chairemon, son of Apitas;;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 21 obol 1.5, tax on the produce of olives drachmas 3 chalki 2, naubion drachmas 2 obol 0.5 chalki 2, surcharge drachmas 5 obols 2;;(in left margin: drachmas 48 obols 3) eparourion drachmas 14 obol 1, surcharges drachma 1 obol 0.5 chalki 2, kollybos obols 4.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 47 obols 5;;Sambas, son of Onnophris, grandson of Sambas, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 8;;in total for the day drachmas 84.;(Pachon) 28 likewise:;Herakleides, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Ptolemais, drachmas 4;;Petheus, son of Didymos, grandson of Maron, mother Tauris, drachmas 4;;Petheus, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Thermouthis, copper tetradrachmas 4;;Sarapion, son of Phasis, grandson of Keras, mother Helene, drachmas 4;;Herieus the older, son of Horos, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Sisois, son of Petesouchos alias Pnepheros, grandson of Sokrates, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 16;;Dioskoros, son of Aiaus, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Thases, drachmas 4 copper obols 28.;(Pachon) 29 likewise:;Sarapias, daughter of Ptolemaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225);;(in left margin: drachmas 192 obols 8) orchard taxes apomoira drachmas 34 obols 2, tax on the produce of olives drachmas 4 obols 5.5, naubion drachmas 3 obols 4 chalki 2, surcharges drachmas 8 obols 5;;eparourion drachmas 22 obols 5.5, surcharges drachma 1 obols 5.5, kollybos drachma 1 obols 2, in total drachmas 77 obols 5.5;;orchard taxes on those in valuation for the 12th year;;apomoira drachmas 3, tax on the produce of olives obols 2, naubion obol 1.5, surcharges obols 4.5;;eparourion drachma 1 obols 3 chalki 2, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 6 obol 1;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 86, surcharges drachmas 5 obols 2 chalki 2, in total drachmas 91 obols 2 chalki 2;;naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year drachmas 8 obols 3, surcharges obols 5 chalki 2, kollybos obol 1, in total drachmas 9 obols 3 chalki 2;;tax on land plots in release likewise drachmas 2 obol 0.5, surcharges obols 2.5 kollybos obols 0.5, in total drachmas 2 obols 3.5 chalki 2;;and to Gaius Valerius Martialis;;naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year drachma 1 obols 2, surcharges obol 1, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachma 1 obols 3 chalki 2;;12th year likewise drachma 1 obols 2, surcharges obol 1, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachma 1 obols 3 chalki 2;;Thaseis, daughter of Petheus (Mysthes, son of Xistis);;(in left margin: drachmas 56 obols 6) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 25, tax on the produce of olives drachmas 3 obols 3 chalki 2, naubion drachmas 2 obols 3, surcharges drachmas 6 obol 1 chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 16 obols 4, surcharges drachma 1 obols 2 chalki 2, kollybos obols 5.5 chalki 2."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3833&amp;viewid=4171_68R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3833&amp;viewid=4171_68R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3833&amp;viewid=4171_68R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
