<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Report of chaff collectors</title>
            <author>a: Gerontios, b:Ammonios ad Heron</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1563</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1563</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.cair.isidor.16</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1977</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>A report of chaff and hay delivered by Seuthes and isidoros, chaff collectors of Karanis in 310/311. The opening statement of the present report has been lost, and with it the name and title of the oficial to whom it was addressed. A reasonable guess is that it was addressed to the praepositus of the ffth pagus who was active in that office when Seutheus and Isidoros served as chaff collectors, i.e. in 310/311. The text that remains falls into three parts. Lines 1-25 contain a series of receipts issued by Gerontios, receiver of chaff, between Dec. 3 and 21, 311. These are duplicates, with minor verbal differences, of the receipts in no 13, 28-53, where the full name of the receiver is given as Aurelius Gerontius, son of demetrius. We learn also from no 13, 26 that he was stationed at Akanthon, not far from the harbor of Kerke. The quantities of chaff mentioned in both sets of receipts agree exactly, as do the totals receorded in No 13, 54 and line 25 of the present report. Lines 26-35 have copies of two receipts given to Setheus and isidoros by Ammonios and Heron, receivers of chaff at Arsinoe. They acknowledge delivery of 2700 lbr on Pachon 30 and 1950 lbs. in Payni, amking a total of 4650 lbs. Lines 36-42 contain two receipts for hay issued by collectors whose names are mutilated. they acknowledge receipt of 1200 lbs in all. These deliveries of chaff and hay reach a total of 5850 lbs, and added to the 45.7000 lbs covered in the receipts attributed to gerontios, they yield the grand total of 51.550 lbs. recorded in l. 44. the amount of chaff remaining to be collecetd is entered in l. 45 as 53.050 lbs. Together, the quantity delivered and the quantity outstanding equal the total levy of 104.600 lbs reported in no 13, 21. It is interesting to note that for a part of the levy, although a relatively small part, hay was accepted in place of chaff.;None of the receipts supplied by lines 26-42 is repeated in the later report submitted by Setheus and isidoros to the auditor of the Heptanomia on July 31, 314 (no 13). All deliveries apart from those made to Gerontios are there comprehended in the summary statement of line 56 that the remaining quantity -58.900 lbs- was "brought in subsequenly". Between Feb. 19 and July 314, the chaff collectors of 310/311 discgarged their liturgical obligations in full by delivering 53050 lbs to receivers.;Lines 46-50 give the date by the consuls of 314 and the subscription of the collectors written for them by a hypographeus. This feature of the document indicates that it was a report secially prepared, like no 13., for the scrutiny of some higher official, probably as we have said above the praepositus of the fifth papus.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 49 x 25 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This papyrus has suffered severrely from tearing and abrasion. An entire column is missing from the left side of the sheet, and much of Col. ii has been  lost. The portion which bears Col. iii has become detached from the rest of the papyrus. There are 6 more small fragment (joined from some even smaller) and are placed. Probably they belong to the bottom or middle part of col. ii (NL)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">3 columns:50 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0314">February 19, 314 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou division, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Maximinus, consul</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Seuthes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Isidoros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gerontios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Serenos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hermias</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Leipon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Rufius Volusianus, consul</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petronius Annianus, consul</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelios Kopres, son of Pannous</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pannous, father of Aurelios Kopres</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou division, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Karanis, Herakleidou division, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</term>
               <term>Tax collection;vRegisters--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Measures and weights, Ancient.</term>
               <term>Signatures (Writing)</term>
               <term>Crop residues--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>... receiver of chaff, to Seuthes and Isidoros, collectors of chaff for Karanis, greetings. I have received from you on account of the crop of the 19th year 4800 lbs of chaff, equal 4800 lbs. the 2nd consulship of Maximinus, Choiak 7. I, Gerontios, have signed the receipt.;And likewise on Choiak 7 through the same 2850 lbs of chaff, equal 2850 lbs. I, Gerontios, have signed the receipt.;And likewise  through the same collector on the same day 4800 lbs of chaff, equal 4800 lbs. I, Gerontios, have signed the receipt.;And likewise  through the same collectors on Choiak 9, 5800 lbs of chaff, equal 5800 lbs. I, Gerontios, have signed the receipt.;And likewise  on Choiak 9 through the same collector s 1650 lbs of chaff, equal 1650 lbs. I, Gerontios, have signed the receipt.; And likewise  on Choiak 11 through the same collector s 8400 lbs of chaff, equal 8400 lbs. I, Gerontios, have signed the receipt.;And likewise  on Choiak 13 through the same collector s 2700 lbs of chaff, equal 2700 lbs. I, Gerontios, have signed the receipt.;And likewise  on Choiak 14 through the same collector s 1650  lbs of chaff, equal 1650 lbs. I, Gerontios, have signed the receipt.;And likewise  on Choiak 15 through the same collector s 4200  lbs of chaff, equal 4200 lbs. I, Gerontios, have signed the receipt.;And likewise  on Choiak 22 through the same collector s 38 sarganai, 5700 lbs.  I, Gerontios, have signed the receipt.;And likewise  on Choiak 25 3150 lbs of chaff, equal 3150 lbs. I, Gerontios, have signed the receipt.;Grand total 45700 lbs;To Ammonios and Heron, receivers in the city, 4650 lbs of chaff. Copies of receipts for these: Setheus and Isidoros, collectors of KAranis for the 19th year, have delivered 2700 lbs of chaff, equal 2700 lbs. I, Ammonios, have signed the receipt. I, Serenos, have signed the receipt. Year 9, Pachon 30. And on behalf of the same village the same (collectors) have delivered 1950 lbs. of chaff, equal 1950 lbs. I, Ammonios, have signed the receipt. I, Serenos, have written for himsince he is illiterate. I , Heron, acting through Hermias, have signed the receipt. Year 9, Pauni ...;... 1200 lbs of hay. Copies of receipts for these: Isidoros and Seuthes, collectors of chaff in the 19th year have delivered on behalf of the village of Karanis ... I, Leipon, have signed the receipt. And on behalf of the same village the same (collectors) have delivered ... lbs of hay ...;Total delivery o chaff and hay: 51.550 lbs.;remainder in arrears: 53050 lbs of chaff;The consulship of Rufius Volusianus and Petronius Annianus, clarissimi. Mechir 25;(2nd hand) We, Aurelios Setheus and Aurelios Isidoros, have submitted this report. I, Aurelios Kopres, son of Pannous, have written for them since they are illiterate.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER-Youtie HC, PCair Isidor, 16, 1960 -- BL VIII, 69 (for l. 3; dating); BL IX, 40 (l. 36); Lines 34-35 "Heron" is written at the end of l. 34 and not at the beginning of l. 35. A small fragment is placed at the beginning of lines 39-41 of col. ii (uncertain position which does not prove the supllements of the ed. princ.). Two small fragments joined together and placed below the papyrus separately read "umestou"? (NL)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Cair.Isidor.:16</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1563&amp;viewid=1977R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/7/7/r/1977r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1563&amp;viewid=1977R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1563&amp;viewid=1977R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
