<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3651</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3651</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.224</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 29.5 x 32.4 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at all sides except at the top where it has been torn off. Kollesis in the left column of writing.  (TC).</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-41</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 15 (554-595)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Heron, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Eserempis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis, son of Panesneus, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymion, son of Petheus, grandson of Didymion, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 161)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Soeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 194)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dionysios, fatherless, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Euhemeros, son of Aunes, grandson of Aunes, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis, son of Kalatytes, grandson of Heras, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 195)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Nestosiris, grandson of Petheus, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hatres, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Heraklas, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 157)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Aphrodisios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Didymarion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus, son of Petheus, grandson of Satabous, mother Tamystha (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ischyras, son of Panesneus, grandson of Ischyras, mother Tamystha (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 179)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Taptosiris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Onnophris, grandson of Sambas, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Pakysis, grandson of Petheus, mother Tamaron (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Onnophris, grandson of Onnophris, mother Sopas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Euhemeros, son of Neilos, grandson of Euhemeros, mother Taeuhemeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Apollonios. grandson of Harpagathes, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Kastor, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 182)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Didymos, grandson of Maron, mother Tauris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Phaseis, grandson of Keras, mother Helene (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Valerius, grandson of Sarapion, mother Stotoetis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Erieus, mother Anthia (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois, son of Naaraus the younger, grandson of Theabennis, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Pasoknopaios, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron, son of Limnaios, grandson of Maron, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Isidoros, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 179)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Achillas, son of Ptollis, grandson of Hieranouphis, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis, son of Pekmeis alias Heuremon, mother Sampathios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petsraipis, son of Hatres, grandson of Imouthes, mother Soeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Lucius  Longinus Gemellus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 185)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Theon, son of Theon, grandson of Petheus, mother Zoidous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 177)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>" (Column) 1[5]:;Petheus, son of Heron, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Eserempis, drachmas 4, obols 3;;Pakysis, son of Panesneus, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Didymion, son of Petheus, grandson of Didymion, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 4;;Orsenouphis, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Soeris, drachmas 4;;Dionysios, fatherless, mother Tepheros, drachmas 4;;Phanomgeus, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8;;Euhemeros, son of Aunes, grandson of Aunes, mother Tepheros, drachmas 8;;Pakysis, son of Kalatytes, grandson of Heras, mother Segathis, drachmas 8;;in total for the day, drachmas 104, obols 2;;(Tybi) 21 likewise:;Heron, son of Sisois, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Didymarion, obols 28;;Petheus, son of Nestosiris, grandson of Petheus, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 12;;Hatres, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Heraklas, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 8;;Pnepheros, son of Aphrodisios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Didymarion, drachmas 4;;Phanomgeus, son of Petheus, grandson of Satabous, mother Tamystha, drachmas 4;;Ischyras, son of Panesneus, grandson of Ischyras, mother Tamystha, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Taptosiris, drachmas 8;;Onnophris, son of Onnophris, grandson of Sambas, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;Petheus, son of Pakysis, grandson of Petheus, mother Tamaron, drachmas 8;;Heras, son of Onnophris, grandson of Onnophris, mother Sopas, obols 28;;Euhemeros, son of Neilos, grandson of Euhemeros, mother Taeuhemeros, drachmas 4, obols 28;;in total for the day, drachmas 64, obols 25;;(Tybi) 22 likewise:;Pakysis, son of Kastor, grandson of Pakysis, mother Teseuris, drachmas 16;;12th year the same, copper drachmas 8, ? drachmas;;Sarapion, son of Apollonios. grandson of Harpagathes, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 8;;Kastor, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Kastor, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 4, obols 28;;Petheus, son of Didymos, grandson of Maron, mother Tauris, drachmas 4;;Sarapion, son of Phaseis, grandson of Keras, mother Helene, drachmas 4;;Sarapion, son of Valerius, grandson of Sarapion, mother Stotoetis, drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Erieus, mother Anthia, drachmas 4;;Sisois, son of Naaraus the younger, grandson of Theabennis, mother Thaisas, obols 28;;Petheus, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Pasoknopaios, mother Tepheros, drachmas 4;;12th year Maron, son of Limnaios, grandson of Maron, mother Thaisas, copper drachmas 8;;in total for the day, drachmas 76, obols 18 of which 12th year drachmas 16, obols 20;;(Tybi) 23 likewise:;Isidoros, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 8;;Achillas, son of Ptollis, grandson of Hieranouphis, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 8;;Phaesis, son of Pekmeis alias Heuremon, mother Sampathios, drachmas 8;;Petsraipis, son of Hatres, grandson of Imouthes, mother Soeris, obols 28;;Lucius  Longinus Gemellus, a third of the bath tax for the 13th year and additional charges drachmas 12;;Theon, son of Theon, grandson of Petheus, mother Zoidous, drachmas 16."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3651&amp;viewid=4171_15R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3651&amp;viewid=4171_15R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3651&amp;viewid=4171_15R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
