<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>antichretic loan</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2109</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2109</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.18.13154</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;18;13154</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;18;13154</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">2528</idno>
            <idno type="TM">2528</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 3783</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>this papyrus contains the lower part of an antichretic loan of 10 talents of copper taken by Olympias from Dionysios.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 16 x 16.8 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">A light-brown papyrus consisting of five joining fragments. It is regularly broken off at all four sides except the top. Seven vertical folds still visible.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-18</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a hand which points to IInd/Ist century B.C. for the dating of the text, cf. W. Schubart, Papyri Graecae Berolinenses, Bonn 1911, Tafel 9 [127 B.C.] and R. Seider, Palaeographie der griechischen Papyri I, Stuttgart 1967, Tafel 18 [101 B.C.]. At the left there is a margin of 1 cm. and at the bottom one of approximately 4 cm. The text is heavily abbreviated and a Ptolemaic date for this text appears to be confirmed by the occurence in the text of many words only attested in the Ptolemaic period.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="-0199" notAfter="-0001">II/Ist century B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>unknown</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Dionysios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Olympias</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>-</term>
               <term>Loans--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Contracts--Egypt.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>". . . Dionysios and whoever of his people the indicated (objects) during 5 years and for as long as she owes the loan with every warranty. After the 5 years Olympias must repay Dionysius the 10 talents of copper within an additional 30 days. If she does not act according to the above-written, Olympias must pay to Dionysios a fine of 20 talents of bronze coinage for not warranting and the loan with a surcharge of 50 % and interest for the overtime at the rate of 2 drachmas per each mina per each month. Dionysios shall also have the right of execution upon Olympias and upon all her property as if in accordance with a legal decision and, until he receives back (what belongs to him), he may live with his people on her property rent-free. If however Dionysios, having received back what belongs to him, does not vacate the house with his people within an additional 30 days from the day he receives (it), having handed over to Olympias or her people the property thoroughly clean and the five doors and the five keys which he received, he must pay Olympias for not vacating a fine of 20 talents of copper and for each door which he does not give back a price of 3,000 drachmas - but for the streetdoor 2 talents - [and for each key X bronze drachmas] and for not cleaning a fee of 2,000 bronze drachmas and necertheless he must be evicted [together with his people. To Olympias] will belong the 7 talents, the remainder of the 10 talents of bronze which Dionysios lent to Olympias in accordance with the agreement. . . .Dionysius against Olympias like they have agreed upon with eachother."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn PJ, Anagennesis 4, 131-5, 1986 -- SB XVIII, 13154</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:18:13154</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2109&amp;viewid=3783R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/8/3/r/3783r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2109&amp;viewid=3783R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2109&amp;viewid=3783R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
