<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3826</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3826</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 38.8 x 29.6 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at the right. Kollesis at the left and right sides; on the back to the right a small piece of blank papyrus has been glued on to the document, presumably to strengthen the sheet. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-38</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 62 (ll. 2498-2536)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Leontas, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Kastorous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 184)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpalos, son of Apion, grandson of Harpalos, mother Valeria (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marcus Valerius Julianus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Julianus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 178)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Poupin (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 215)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thermouthis, daughter of Sambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 176)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apolinarios, worker on irrigation machines (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 152)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Taonnophris, daughter of Horion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 234)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tasoucharion, wife of Mikallos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 239)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos, son of Hatres, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor, son of Apion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apitas, son of Kothon (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 152)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sempronia Petronia (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 228)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Skiphas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 230)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion, son of Sambas, grandson of Phaesis, mother Aphrodite (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psenesis, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Psenesis, mother Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hatres, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Heraklas, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 157)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois, son of Karanos, grandson of Heraklas, mother Artemis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Lucius Antonius Gemellus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 185)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gemella Tapeeis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 160)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tapeis, daughter of Ptolemaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 237)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kapiton alias Antonius (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 62:;Leontas, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Kastorous, drachmas 8 copper drachmas 4;;Harpalos, son of Apion, grandson of Harpalos, mother Valeria, drachmas 8 copper drachmas 4;;Marcus Valerius Julianus (Julianus (Poupin));;(in left margin: obols 28) naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year drachmas 2 obols 5 chalki 2, surcharge obol 1.5 chalki 2, kollybos obol 0.5, in total drachmas 3 obol 1.5;;Thermouthis, daughter of Sambas (wife of Apolinarios, worker on irrigation machines;;(in left margin: drachmas 68 obols 15)orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 14 obol 0.5, tax on the produce of olives drachmas 2, naubion drachma 1 obols 2.5, surcharges drachmas 3 obols 3;;eparourion drachmas 9 obols 2.5, surcharges obols 4.5 chalki 2, kollybos obols 3 chalki 2, in total drachmas 31 obols 4.5;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 15 obol 1 chalki 2, surcharges drachmas 2 obol 1 chalki 2, in total drachmas 37 obols 2.5;;Taonnophris, daughter of Horion through the agency of Tasoucharion, wife of Mikallos;;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 17 obols 3, tax on the produce of olives drachmas 2 obols 2.5 chalki 2, naubion drachma 1 obols 4.5, surcharges drachmas 4 obols 2 chalki 2;;(in left margin: drachmas 40)eparourion drachmas 11 obols 4, surcharges drachma 1, kollybos obols 4, in total drachmas 39 obols 2.5;;Petesouchos, son of Hatres, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 8;;Kastor, son of Apion (Apitas, son of Kothon);;(in left margin: obols 28) geometria for the 12th year drachmas 3 obol 1, surcharges obol 1 chalki 2;;Sempronia Petronia (Skiphas);;(in left margin: drachmas 48 obols 26) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 10, tax on the produce of olives drachmas drachma 1 obols 2.5, naubion drachma 1, surcharges drachmas 2 obols 3;;eparourion drachmas 6 obols 4, surcharges obols 3.5, kollybos obols 2 chalki 2, in total drachmas 22 obols 2 chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 25, surcharges drachma 1 obols 3.5, in total drachmas 26 obols 3.5;;naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year drachma 1 obol 0.5 chalki 2, surcharges obol 0.5 chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachmas drachma 1 obol 1.5 chalki 2;;Pasion, son of Sambas, grandson of Phaesis, mother Aphrodite, drachmas 8;;Heras, son of Petheus;;donkey tax for the 13th year, instalment from the 11h year drachmas 5, surcharges obols 2, in total drachmas 5 obols 2;;Psenesis, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Psenesis, mother Heras, drachmas 8;;Hatres, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Heraklas, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 464 obols 27;;(Pachon) 14 likewise:;Sisois, son of Karanos, grandson of Heraklas, mother Artemis, drachmas 40;;Lucius Antonius Gemellus (Gemella Tapeeis);;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 8 obols 2.5 chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives drachma 1 obol 1, naubion obols 5, surcharges drachmas 2 obols 0.5;;(in left margin: drachmas 136 obols 6) eparourion drachmas 5 obols 5.5 chalki 2, surcharges obols 2.5 chalki 2, kollybos obols 2, in total drachmas 18 obols 5.5 chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 21 obol 1, surcharges drachma 1 obols 2 chalki 2, in total drachmas 22 obols 3 chalki 2;;and Tapeis, daughter of Ptolemaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 237);;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 3 obols 3.5 chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives obols 3 chalki 2, naubion obols 2 chalki 2, surcharges obols 5.5;;eparourion drachmas 2 obols 2.5, surcharges obol 1 chalki 2, kollybos obol 1, in total drachmas 8 obol 1.5;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 9 obols 0.5, surcharges obols 4, in total drachmas 9 obols 4.5;;and Kapiton alias Antonius;;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 15, tax on the produce of olives drachmas 2 obol 0.5 chalki 2, naubion drachma 1 obols 3, surcharges drachmas 3 obols 4.5;;eparourion drachmas 10, surcharges obols 5, kollybos obols 3.5, in total drachmas 33 obols 4.5 chalki 2.";;;</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3826&amp;viewid=4171_62R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3826&amp;viewid=4171_62R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3826&amp;viewid=4171_62R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
