<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3316</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3316</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 19 is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 19: 21.2 x 30 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 19: complete (papyrus cut to the left of col. 19 when housed in glass); col. 20-26 cut off and missing</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 19: 59 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 19 (l. 229-287)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus son of Tesenouphis and Thaesis grandson of Harphaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Imouthes son of Keras and Tepheros grandson of Menandros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 177)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchophis son of Kanis and Thermouthis grandson of Anchophis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Sisois and Thaesis grandson of Petsiris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psenesis son of Parmenion and Tkonnos grandson of Psenesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dioskoros son of Petheus and Taorsenouphis grandson of Kollouthos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Valerius son of Valeria, apator (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 195)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras alias Aphrodisios son of Heras and Apollonarion, grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nemesas, doulos of Apollonous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 190)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Thaisas, doulos of Syros alias Ptolemaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nikephoros, doulos of Longinus Isidoros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus son of Esouris and Tkollauthis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Neilos son of Euemeros and Sambous grandson of Nilos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 190)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Agathopous, doulos of Taseus alias Isarion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 148)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Satabous and Aphrodous grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 220)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchophis son of Mysthes and Tanais grandson of Anchophis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles son of Apolonios (Apollonios) and &lt;Tapetheus&gt; grandson of Petoraipis (Petsoraipis) (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinus son of Sisois and Tapais grandson of Sokmenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron son of Ptolemaios and Taseus grandson of Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Zenas son of Phaesis and Tapasion grandson of Zenas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 165)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Sambas and Aphrodous grandson of Sabinus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Heron and Tasoucharion grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraklas son of Taonnophris, apator (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion son of Heraklas and Demarous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinus son of Petesouchos and Charis grandson of Petesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Illegitimacy--Egypt</term>
               <term>Slaves--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 19;;On the 19th (of Mecheir), similarly:;Phanomgeus, son of Tesenouphis and Thaesis, grandson of Harphaesis: 4 drachmai;    column 3;Imouthes, son of Keras and Tepheros, grandson of Menandros: 4 drachmai;    column 47;Anchophis, son of Kanis and Thermouthis, grandson of Anchophis: 8 drachmai;    column 4;Onnophris, son of Sisois and Thaesis, grandson of Petsiris: 28 obols;    column 12;Psenesis, son of Parmenion and Tkonnos, grandson of Psenesis: 12 drachmai;    column 16;Dioskoros, son of Petheus and Taorsenouphis, grandson of Kollouthos: 8 drachmai;    column 27;Valerius, of unknown father, the son of Valeria: 16 drachmai;    column 29;Heras also called Aphrodisios, son of Heras and Apollonarion, grandson of Petheus: 20 drachmai;    column 49;Nemesas, slave of Apollonous: 20 drachmai;    column 49;Total for the day: 92 drachmai 28 obols.;;On the 20th, similarly:;Sarapion, slave of Syros also called Ptolemaios, the offspring of Thaisas: 4 drachmai;    column 50;Nikephoros, slave of Longinus Isidoros: 8 drachmai;    column 57;Petaus, son of Esouris and Tkollauthis, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai;    column 71;Neilos, son of Euemeros and Sambous, grandson of Nilos: 12 drachmai;    column 75;Agathopous, slave of Taseus also called Isarion: 24 drachmai;    column 19;Ptolemaios, son of Satabous and Aphrodous, grandson of Petheus: 24 drachmai;    column 103;Anchophis, son of Mysthes and Tanais, grandson of Anchophis: 20 drachmai;    column 52;Herakles, son of Apolonios and &lt;Tapetheus&gt;, grandson of Petoraipis: 16 drachmai;    column 47;Total for the day: 116 drachmai.;;On the 23rd, similarly:;Sabinus, son of Sisois and Tapais, grandson of Sokmenis: 8 drachmai;    column 67;Ptolemaios, son of Harmiysis and Tasoucharion, grandson of Pnepheros: 8 drachmai;    column 92;Maron, son of Ptolemaios and Taseus, grandson of Sambathion: 12 drachmai;    column 101;Zenas, son of Phaesis and Tapasion, grandson of Zenas: 8 drachmai;    column 103;Ptolemaios, son of Sambas and Aphrodous, grandson of Sabinus: 8 drachmai;    column 95;Ptolemaios, son of Heron and Tasoucharion, grandson of Horos: 8 drachmai;    column 96;Heraklas, of unknown father, the son of Taonnophris: 8 drachmai;    column 16;Horion, his son, (born) of Demarous: 8 drachmai;    column 16;Sabinus, son of Petesouchos and Charis, grandson of Petesouchos: 8 drachmai;    column 14;Total for the day: 76 drachmai.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 19 (l. 229-287), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3316&amp;viewid=4172R3.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/R/3/4172R3.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3316&amp;viewid=4172R3.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3316&amp;viewid=4172R3.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
