<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Medical Catechism</title>
            <author>Unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2914</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2914</idno>
            <idno type="dclp">63560</idno>
            <idno type="TM">63560</idno>
            <idno type="dclp-hybrid">p.turner;;14</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 6657</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>A single column, numbered 18, of a roll containing a medical catechism.  It contains the end of the answer to a question now lost, a new question, and the beginning of its answer. The first question in all probability asked for the properties of olive oil, that made from unripe olives,and that made from fully ripe olives, and the powers of each. The second question -"What is the best time for a catabrocation?- concerns illnesses characterized by paroxysms. Reminiscent of our questions are those found in Orib., Coll. Med. vi 12, 15; vii 1, 2, 5-12, 23, 24; viii 1, 4, 6, 34, 38; et. al.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is P.Turner 43</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 9.3 x 20.6 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The sheet was cut from the roll to receive a private letter on its unused reverse side. Partly broken above. Many holes all over the sheet.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">29 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The format is the usual generous one of well-written literary and sub-literary texts, commercially produced. There is a wide upper margin of 4 cm and an intercolumnar space on the left of 2 cm. The right margin is lost, together with 4-6 letters from the end of each line. Small remnants of the preceding column are visible opposite lines 1, 6, 7. There are no accents or breathings, and only one instance of diaeresis, l. 13. Punctuation is effected in the following way at lines 16-17, where a new question and answer begin. In l. 16 a colon and blank space of 1.6 cm follow the concluding word of the preceding section. Between lines 16 and 17 is a forked paragraphos and in the margin at this point, to augment it, is a very black filled-in wedge, the latter most probably by a second hand. In l. 17 the new question ending with "[kata]broches"(16-17) is followed by another colon and a longer blank space of 2.2. cm. The hand is slanting and rapid and the letters vary in size. "mu", "nu" and "pau" are wide, while "epsilon" and "sigma" are usually narrow. "beta", "rho", "tau", "ypsilon" and "phi" often extend below the line. "alpha" and "delta" are regular and made very much alike. "omicron" is usually small and "omega" often appears with no centre stroke.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0150" notAfter="0200">(second half of the) IInd century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Literary; subliterary; medical</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[... But when the fruit is still unripe, the] oil pressed from the olive is able to produce the contrary effect. For it (i.e. the unripe olive) yields omphakinon, an astringment. It draws together and constricts the bodily organs, for it holds in check those that are being dispersed. But sweet oil loses astringment power with the ripening of the fruit, and it has a suppling effect. For we use omphakinonoil on the parts that are inflamed when we desire to inhibit the immoderate activity of the ailment in the constricted areas, so that the lowered tension may relax the organs. And it is necessary that these be scanned to determine the virulence of the condition, so that one neither employs embrocation at a late stage, for such treatment is of no avail, nor too often, for that provokes the ripening of the disease.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC-Youtie LC, PTurner, 14, 1981, Pl VI</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Turner:14</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2914&amp;viewid=6657R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/5/7/r/6657r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2914&amp;viewid=6657R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2914&amp;viewid=6657R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
