<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lease of Land</title>
            <author>Sokrates, son of Ptolemaios</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2811</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2811</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.16.12539</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;16;12539</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;16;12539</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14610</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14610</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 632</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract by which Sokrates, son of Ptolemaios, leases to Horos, son of Horos, four arourai of a catoecic allotment near Theogonis</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 13.5 x 27.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">torn along a vertical fold and at times abraded very badly</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">30</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Extremely fast hand</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0026">September 22, 26 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Tiberius, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sokrates son of Ptolemaios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Horos, Perses tes epigones</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Horos grandson of Horos</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome; Theogonis; Perses</term>
               <term>Theogonis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Ethnicity</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Land Ownership</term>
               <term>Lease</term>
               <term>Iranians--Egypt</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>The thirteenth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, the twenty-fifth of the month of Sebastos, in Tebtynis in the division of Polemon of the Arsinoite nome. Sokrates, son of Ptolemaios, about sixty-two years old, with a scar on his left cheek, has leased to Horos, son of Horos, from Theogonis, a Persian of the epigone, about fifty-five years old, with a scar on his left shin, the catoecic allotment of four arourai, or however many there are, in two parcels, belonging to him near Theogonis, for four years, from the thirteenth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus: the first year of the lease, with the crops(?) of Sokrates remaining(?), without rent and charges; the second and last years of the lease for the sowing of wheat, the rent - together with four artabai of wheat as seed yearly for the two years - for the whole area being fifty-six artabai of wheat; the third year of the lease for the sowing of crops other than wheat. the rent - together with seed for whatever crops he chooses - for the whole area being twenty-eight artabai of the crops and a gratuity and libation of one keramion of wine, all free from every risk and deduction for the three years. Let it therefore not be permitted the lessee to withdraw from the lease within this time. Let the lessee yearly attend to all the work {and the customary work} of this allotment at his own expense, also seeing to the care of the green crops, and let the owner Sokrates receive yearly the specified rents for the three years in the month of Pauni yearly in Theogonis in the treasury, measured by the measeure of the treasury. But if the lessee does not pay or owes anything according to these specifications, let him pay Sokrates the whole annual rent for the three years {from what the lessee will receive} and a fine of &lt;one hundred&gt; twenty-two &lt;silver drachmai&gt; and a like sum to the treasury, the right of execution belonging to Sokrates on both the lessee and all his property as if in accordance with legal action {of the lease for all the years}. The lease is guaranteed for all the years by Sokrates.;(2nd hand) I, Horos, son of Horos, Persian of the epigone, have leased the aforementioned four arourai on all the aforementioned terms. Horos, his son, writes on his behalf for he does not know letters.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Jenkins FW, StudPap 21, 23-30, 1982, Plate -- SB XVI 12539 -- B.L. VIII, 384 (l. 4); B.L. IX, 286 (date)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB:16:12539</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2811&amp;viewid=632R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/3/2/R/632R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2811&amp;viewid=632R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2811&amp;viewid=632R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
