<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Loan of Money</title>
            <author>Flavius Christodoros, son of Theodoros, praikon</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2309</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2309</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.11.607</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;11;607</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;11;607</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21361</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21361</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 478</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract by which Flavius Christodoros, herald of the officium of the praeses in Antinoopolis, acknowledges to have borrowed from a widow one gold solidus minus six carats at the interest of 250 silver talents per month, to be repaid on the creditor's demand</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 14.5 x 29.5 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">35</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0569">March 1, 569 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Antinoopolis, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Flavius Iustinus, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Flavius Christodoros son of Theodoros, praikon tes hegemonikes taxeos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelia Euphemia daughter of Theodoros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelia Magistor son of Horouonchis (Horouanchis)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Antinoopolis, Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Antinoou polis = Antinoeon polis (Antinoopolis); Tarsikos; Aigyptios</term>
               <term>Clothing</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Antinoȵpolis  (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Loan</term>
               <term>Mortgage</term>
               <term>Woman</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Cross) Year four of the kingship and consulship or our most God-like lord Flavius Justin, the eternal Augustus, Emperor. Phamenoth fifth of the present second indiction, in Antinoopolis the most glorious.;(Cross) Flavius Christodoros, son of Theodoros, herald of the officium of the praeses in this city of Antinoopolis, which is also the city of my origin, to Aurelia Euphemia, daughter of Theodoros, widow, from the same city of Antinoopolis, greetings.;I, the afore-mentioned Christodoros, herald, acknowledge by this written bond that I have received in loan from you, from (your) hand to my hands, for my private and necessary needs, the capital sum of one gold solidus less six carats on the public standard of Antinoopolis, total 1 gold solidus less 6 carats on the same publix standard. And this I am prepared to return to you, both I myself and my heirs of whatever degree, whenever you desire, through any agent with power to act in your behalf, along with the monthly interest thereon, that is, two hundred fifty silver talents, without any unpleasantness or delay. All my property present and future is mortgaged to you for this, and for your security I have drawn up for you and signed this document, valid and guaranteed wherever presented; and when asked the formal question concerning all this I so declared. (Cross) And it is understood that on this account I have turned over to you in pledge a garment made in Egypt after the Tarsic fashion and an undergarment-shirt(?).;(2nd hand) Crosses (drawing of 3 crosses) of Christodoros.;(3rd hand) (Cross) Flavius Christodoros, son of Theodoros, the afore-mentioned herald of the officium of the praeses: this agreement is satisfactory to me and I will return the above-mentioned solidus with the interest thereon whenever you desire, so that I may recover my pledge as stated. I, Aurelius Magistor, son of Horouonchios, from Antinoopolis, wrote on his behalf at his request, as he is illiterate; but he first drew the crosses with his own hand. (Cross).</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Shelton JC, PMich XI, 607, 1971, pl. II -- BL VII, 115 (l. 4-5, 31)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:11:607</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2309&amp;viewid=478R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/7/8/R/478R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2309&amp;viewid=478R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2309&amp;viewid=478R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
