<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Copy of a Petition to an Epistrategos and of the Latter's Subscript</title>
            <author>unknown scribe (for the copy); Gaius Apolinarius Niger (original of lines 2-35); Iulius Lucullus (original of lines 35-38)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1689</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1689</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.5.7558</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;5;7558</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;5;7558</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14029</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14029</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 2922</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Copy of a petition addressed to the epistrategos Iulius Lucullus by Gaius Apolinarius Niger, asking to be relieved from the duty of being guardian of a deceased veteran's daughter, according to earlier decisions taken in similar cases, which are cited; after this comes a copy of the subscript which contained the approval of Lucullus</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Gaius Apolinarius Niger</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 28 x 29.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">upper left corner and lower left side broken off; numerous small holes, but otherwise well preserved</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">38</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>writing very distinct</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0173">173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>probably Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">. . . (Gaius?) Iulius Lucullus, epistrategos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius Apolinarius Niger, Antinoeus, Osorantinoeios (Osirantinoeios) alias Hermaieus, designated epitropos for Valeria Tertia alias Thaisarion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marcus Anthestius Gemellus, deceased veteran</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Valeria Tertia alias Thaisarion, daughter of Marcus Anthestius Gemellus, aphelix</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Valerius Komon, designated epitropos for Valeria Tertia alias Thaisarion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Valeria Sempronilla, grandmother of Valeria Tertia alias Thaisarion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herennius Philotas, former epistrategos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Antonius Makron, former epistrategos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Antoninus Pius, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Eudaimon son of Hermaios, designated epitropos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dionysios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonios neoteros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) Romaios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) exegetes of Hermou polis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dioskoros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hermias, former agoranomos &amp; former kosmetes (of Hermou polis)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios, enarchos exegetes of Antinoou polis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hadrianus, Emperor</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Antinoeus; Osorantinoeios (Osirantinoeios); Hermaieus; Arsinoite nome; Romaios; Ibion Panykteris (IbionPanektyreos); Hermou polis; Antinooupolis</term>
               <term>Administrative law--Egypr--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Guardian and ward--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Administrative responsibility--Egypt;Karanis (Extinxt city)</term>
               <term>Citizenship--Egypt--Antinoȵpolis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Administrative remedies--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Citizenship--Rome.</term>
               <term>Wills--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Inheritance and succession--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Veterans--Rome.</term>
               <term>Orphans--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Copy of a petition;    To . . . Iulius Lucullus, the honorable epistrategos, from Gaius Apolinarius Niger, Antinoite, of the Osirantinoan tribe and of the Hermaian deme. Marcus Anthestius Gemellus, a veteran, expressed in the will which he drew up his dying wish that his daughter Valeria Tertia, also called Thaisarion, a minor, be heir of his property left in the Arsinoite nome. As guardians of her orphan state he left me, Apolinarius Niger, and Valerius Komon, and as associate the child's grandmother Valeria Sempronilla. Now as it has been enjoined, my lord, by Herennius Philotas the former epistrategos and by Antonius Makron likewise that an Antinoite shall not act as guardian for any one else than an Antinoite who is in the nomarchy, therefore, being myself unable to undertake this guardianship which has been entrusted to me, I have submitted, my lord, a copy of the decisions in like cases, and ask to be relieved of this according to the judgements, and beg you to order your decision to be carried out, so that I may receive relief. Farewell.;The copy is:;    The eleventh year of the Emperor Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrianus Antoninus Augustus Pius, Mesore 6. When Eudaimon, son of Hermaios, had been summoned in accordance with a petition, and Dionysios had come forward and the petition presented by him had been read before the court, Philotas said: "Whence was he who left Eudaimon as guardian?" Apollonios the Younger said: "He was a Roman [who dwelt] in Ibion Panykteris." Philotas said: "Your contention would be just even if [the person who appointed] him guardian were an Antinoite, for he is not obliged to act as guardian for anyone other [than an Antinoite] in the nomarchy." Apollonios said: "We shall show that they undertook [the guardianship] and have done everything like guardians." Philotas said: "It has been decided that Eudaimon is not obliged to act as guardian except only for an Antinoite. But if he undertook this guardianship, I shall appoint [a judge and] auditors." Apollonios the Younger said: "Eudaimon son of Hermaios did not accept it, his . . . accepted it." Philotas said: "Is he an Antinoite? Is he an Antinoite?" He replied: "Yes, [and I ask] your clemency." Philotas said: "I shall appoint the same person as judge and auditor [who] shall investigate who accepted the guardianship and shall examine the accounts and shall compel that which is shown to be in the hands of the (present) guardians [to be given] to him who will be appointed [guardian]. And the exegete of Hermou polis shall see to it that the guardian is appointed." Thracidas said: "Lest we should seem to have remained silent we guarantee that we owe . . . and a half talents to the orphan girl." Philotas said: "What you have said has been written." Dioskoros [said]: "We ask that he who is to be appointed guardian be appointed upon the same conditions [as] Eudaimon was appointed according to the will." Philotas said: "He is to be appointed on the same terms." [Dioskoros] said: "If you please, give us the auditor." Philotas said: "Hermias the former market commissioner [and] former cosmete.";(Copy) of another:;     Antonius Makron to Aphrodisios officiating exegete of Antinoou polis, [greeting]: For whatever property of the Antinoite orphans, about whom you write, is in that nome appoint as guardians [reputable] and suitable persons, but for what is in other nomes notify the strategoi so that [for each of them] they too may choose suitable and reputable persons. Twenty-second year of the Emperor Caesar Trajan [Hadrian Augustus], Phamenoth 9.;Copy of subscription:;     Announce to the relatives of the [orphan, who also] petitioned me, that your request is approved. The upshot of the decision: If you accept the guardianship [in the future], you are not unaware that you indeed neglected [it] in the past at your own risk. Year 13, Pauni 12. Deliver it.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Arangio-Ruiz V;    Rep Ser. - F.I.R.A. III. Negotia;   1943;   No. 30;;Rep editor - Youtie HC;   Rep Ser. - ZPE 13;   1974;   pg. 241-248 and Taf. XV (photo of lines 35-38) Boak AER, JEA 18, 69-76, 1932 -- SB V 7558 -- BL III, 189 (line 23, bibliography); BL IV, 80 (line 38); BL VII, 195 (lines 2, 8, 16, 18, 21, 24-26, 31-32, 34, 36-38). Hunt AS-Edgar CC, Select Papyri II, 260, 1934</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB:5:7558</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1689&amp;viewid=2922R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/2/R/2922R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1689&amp;viewid=2922R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1689&amp;viewid=2922R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
