<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3349</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3349</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 62 is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 61-62: 34.5 x 29.5 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 62: nearly complete (papyrus cut off right of col. 62 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 62: 54 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 62 (l. 1608-1661)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras son of Melanas and Tamystha grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Petheus and Thaisas grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Chairemon and Stotoetis grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Petheus and Thaesis grandson of Sokmenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Perigenes son of Zoilos and Sambathion grandson of Ptolemaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios son of Anchophis and Melanous grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 157)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras alias Aphrodisios son of Heras and Apollonarion grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nemesas, doulos of Apollonous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 190)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion (son of Thaisas), doulos of Syros alias Ptolemaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion son of Petoraipis (Petsoraipis) and Sambathion grandson of Demas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpagathes son of Ptolemaios and Tasiaipis grandson of Harpagathes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasoxis son of Pasoxis and Taseus grandson of Panther (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 199)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Harpagathes and Thaesis grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Anchophis and Teseuris grandson of Herakles (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor son of Mares and Soeris grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Harphaesis and Tapondos (Tapontos) grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpalos son of Pnepheros and Tepheros grandson of Harphaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Besis son of Petheus and Thermouthis grandson of Akousilaos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 159)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas son of Onnophris and Thermouthis grandson of Sambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 223)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Charidemos son of Petoraipis and Thaesis grandson of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nekpheraus son of Euemeros and Taonnophris grandson of Nekpheraus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 190)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nilos son of Euemeros and Sambous grandson of Nilos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 190)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides son of Petheus and Ptolemais grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Ptolemaios and Thaesis grandson of Sarapion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Slaves--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 62;;(Pachon 5, continued);Heras, son of Melanas and Tamystha, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai;    column 42;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus and Thaisas, grandson of Heras: 8 drachmai;    column 42;Ptolemaios, son of Chairemon and Stotoetis, grandson of Horos: 8 drachmai;    column 42;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus and Thaesis, grandson of Sokmenis: 4 drachmai;    column 43;Total for the day: 164 drachmai 27 obols.;;On the 6th, similarly:;Perigenes, son of Zoilos and Sambathion, grandson of Ptolemaios: 4 drachmai;    column 46;Aphrodisios, son of Anchophis and Melanous, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai;    column 48;Heras also called Aphrodisios, son of Heras and Apollonarion, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai;    column 49;Nemesas, slave of Apollonous: 8 drachmai;    column 49;Sarapion, slave of Syros also called Ptolemaios: [[. . .]] 28 obols;    column 50;Horion, son of Petoraipis and Sambathion, grandson of Demas: 8 drachmai;    column 51;Harpagathes, son of Ptolemaios and Tasiaipis, grandson of Harpagathes: [[. .]] 4 drachmai;    column 52;Pasoxis, son of Pasoxis and Taseus, grandson of Panther: 4 drachmai;    column 53;Ptolemaios, son of Harpagathes and Thaesis, grandson of Pnepheros: 8 drachmai;    column 55;Horos, son of Anchophis and Teseuris, grandson of Herakles: 4 drachmai;    column 55;Kastor, son of Mares and Soeris, grandson of Heras: 4 drachmai 28 obols;    column 56;Pnepheros, son of Harphaesis and Tapondos, grandson of Pnepheros: 8 drachmai;    column 74;Harpalos, his son, (born) of Tepheros: 8 drachmai;    column 74;Besis, son of Petheus and Thermouthis, grandson of Akousilaos: 4 drachmai;    column 65;Sambas, son of Onnophris and Thermouthis, grandson of Sambas: 4 drachmai;    column 68;Charidemos, son of Petoraipis and Thaesis, grandson of Onnophris: 4 drachmai;    column 72;Nekpheros, son of Euemeros and Taonnophris, grandson of Nekpheraus: 4 drachmai;    column 75;Nilos, son of Euemeros and Sambous, grandson of Nilos: 12 drachmai;    column 75;Total for the day: [[104]] 108 drachmai [[..]] 27 obols.;;On the 7th, similarly:;Herakleides, son of Petheus and Ptolemais, grandson of Heras: 4 drachmai;    column 76;Sarapion, son of Ptolemaios and Thaesis, grandson of Sarapion: 16 drachmai;    column 78</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 62 (l. 1608-1661), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3349&amp;viewid=4172_17RO.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/7/r/o/4172_17ro.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3349&amp;viewid=4172_17RO.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3349&amp;viewid=4172_17RO.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
