<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Division of Property</title>
            <author>Orseus alias Herodes, son of Nestnephis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1370</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1370</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.321</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;321</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;321</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">15167</idno>
            <idno type="TM">15167</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1285</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Will made in the form of a contract for the division of property by a father, Orseus, son of Nestnephis, among his four children; although the legal division is to be made after the death of Orseus, the heirs actually take over their inheritance at once, as is clear from what the eldest son, Nestnephis, agrees to pay for his father. The body of the contract is left unfinished; the signalments of Orseus and Nestnephis are given in a note in the left margin.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 40.5 x 29 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">nearly complete</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">6 + 18 + 8</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0042">December 2, 42 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Claudius, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orseus alias Herodes son of Nestnephis, husband of Taorseus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Taorseus son of Patron, wife of Orseus alias Herodes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nestnephis alias Ischyrion son of Orseus alias Herodes and of Taorseus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Papontos son of Orseus alias Herodes and of Taorseus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Esouris son of Orseus alias Herodes and of Taorseus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Taapollos daughter of Orseus alias Herodes and of Taorseus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides son of Herakleides (former owner)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chaires son of Mieus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Soueris daughter of Chrates</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nestnephis (son of Nestnephis), brother of Orseus alias Herodes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) hermeneus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menemachos son of Alexandros (see also P.Mich. V, 305)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome; Theogonis; he kyle (koile) legomene; Tali (Talei)</term>
               <term>Talei (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Home ownership--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Inheritance and succession--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Land tenure--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Musicians--Taxation--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Professions--Taxation--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Women--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Theogonis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>The third year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, on the fifth of the month Ioulieu, that is, Choiak, in Tebtynis in the division of Polemon of the Arsinoite nome. Orseus, also called Herodes, son of Nestnephis, about sixty-five years old, with a prominent right eye and with a cataract on the left eye, and with a scar at the tip of the left eyebrow beside the eyelid, acknowledges that he has made a division, to take effect after his death, among the four children borne to him of the wife with whom he lives, Taorseus, daughter of Patron, the children being Nestnephis, also called Ischyrion, and Papontos and Esouris and Taapollos, (as follows): to Ischyrion, also called Nestnephis, the &lt;two arourai&gt; of catoecic allotment that belong to him, Orseus, also called Herodes, near Theogonis in the same division, in the so-called valley . . .;;;;;(2nd hand) I, Orseus, also called Herodes, son of Nestnephis, acknowledge that I have made a division, to be effective after my death, among my aforesaid four children borne of my wife Taorseus, daughter of Patron, with whom I live according to contract, the children being Nestnephis, also called Ischyrion, and Papontos and Esouris and Taapollos, (giving) to Ischyrion, also called Nestnephis, the catoecic allotment near Theogonis in the so-called valley, consisting of two arourai, or as many as there may be, in one parcel; the neighbors being on the south the allotment, formerly belonging to Herakleides, son of Herakleides, but now belonging to others, on the north the allotment of Chaires, son of Mieus, on the west the allotment of Soueris, daughter of Chrates, on the east the allotment of Nesnephis, my brother. And I acknowledge (that I have given) to Nestnephis, also called Ischyrion, one fourth of the building sites that belong to me in the village of Talei, which are all common and undivided, and of which the neighbors have been stated in the documents dealing with previous ownerships. And I give to him also one third of the furniture and household goods, and of all the sums due me of any kind whatsoever. And I also acknowledge that I have made a division, to take effect after my death, among the aforesaid Papontos and Esouris and Taapollos, (giving) to each of them one quarter of the building sites alone; and to Papontos and Esouris also one third of the furniture and household goods that I shall leave and of the sums due me of any kind whatsoever; and also to the same two, Papontos and Esouris, sixty drchmai of silver apiece, which Ischyrion, also called Nestnephis, shall pay from his own purse, without delay or subterfuge, in the year in which I die. Ischyrion, also called Nestnephis, shall also pay all the public taxes in money and in kind on the two arourai, and he shall provide me as long as I live, from the present day annually in the month Drousilleios, on account of food and payments in kind, with twelve artabai of new, pure, and unadulterated wheat, measured in the six-choinix measure of the broker in Talei, and with twelve drachmai of silver annually on account of clothers and oil and expenses; and he shall pay all the public charges in my behalf both for the tax on flute players and the tax on music. And (I acknowledge that) as long as I live, I, Orseus, also called Herodes, shall not have the power to sell any of the aforesaid property or to mortgage it or to give any part of it to any children except the aforesaid. I agree that anything that shall be done illegally by me contrary to these conditions shall be null and void as aforesaid. Menemachos, son of Alexandros, wrote for him since he is illiterate.;;(In the left margin) Orseus, about 65 years old, with a scar at the tip of the left eyebrow beside the eyelid and with a prominent right eye and with a cataract on the left eye. Nestnephis, about 40 years old, with a scar on his left foot.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 321, 1944</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:321</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1370&amp;viewid=1285R_1.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/1/1285R_1.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1370&amp;viewid=1285R_1.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1370&amp;viewid=1285R_1.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/2/1285R_2.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1370&amp;viewid=1285R_2.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1370&amp;viewid=1285R_2.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
