<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3849</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3849</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 36.9 x 30.7 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at the right and the left. Kollesis in center and in the right side. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-37</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 82 (ll. 3258-3295)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron, son of Limnaios, grandson of Maron, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Horos, grandson of Horos, mother Taharmouthes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petheus, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 203)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kephalon, son of Isidoros, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 183)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Charidemos, son of Leonides, grandson of Papeis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Achillas, son of Ptollis, grandson of Hieranouphis, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron, son of Satabous, grandson of Maron, mother Tkonnos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes, son of Patkonnis, grandson of Harobrotos, mother Ptolema (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabous, son of Dioskoros, grandson of Satabous, mother Tahorion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 226)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, his son, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Naaraus, grandson of Horion, mother Taorsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Tauris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Petheus, grandson of Onnophris, mother Taphaseis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 203)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harsiesis, son of Petheus, grandson of Harsiesis, mother Thatres (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petsiris, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Petheus, mother Apia (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 211)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thaesis, daughter of Maron (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 172)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Longinia Kyrilla (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 185)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Longinius, physician (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 185)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Leonides, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 184)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos alias Karanos, son of Petheus, grandson of Herakles, mother Tauris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, his son, mother Tamystha (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Horos, grandson of Petheus, mother Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonios, son of Ammonios, grandson of Ammonios, mother Tninis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 151)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anoubas, son of Horos, grandson of Anoubas, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 151)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Valerius, fatherless, mother Valeria (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 195)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, fatherless, mother Taeuhemeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Pasoxis, mother Tanephremis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Paoueites, son of Petheus, grandson of Phasis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Leonides, grandson of Papeis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Imouthes, son of Keras, grandson of Menandros, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 177)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 82:;Maron, son of Limnaios, grandson of Maron, mother Thaisas, drachmas 16 obols 28;;Horos, son of Horos, grandson of Horos, mother Taharmouthes, drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 216 obols 25.;Epeiph 21 likewise:;Petheus, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petheus, mother Segathis, drachmas 4 copper drachmas 4;;Kephalon, son of Isidoros, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 8;;Charidemos, son of Leonides, grandson of Papeis, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 24;;Achillas, son of Ptollis, grandson of Hieranouphis, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 8;;Maron, son of Satabous, grandson of Maron, mother Tkonnos, copper drachmas 4;;Mysthes, son of Patkonnis, grandson of Harobrotos, mother Ptolema, drachmas 4;;Satabous, son of Dioskoros, grandson of Satabous, mother Tahorion, copper drachmas 4;;Petaus, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8;;Pnepheros, his son, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Naaraus, grandson of Horion, mother Taorsenouphis, copper drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Tauris, copper drachmas 4;;Petheus, son of Petheus, grandson of Onnophris, mother Taphaseis, drachmas 8;;Harsiesis, son of Petheus, grandson of Harsiesis, mother Thatres copper drachmas (of priests) 4;;Petsiris, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Petheus, mother Apia, drachmas 32;;Thaesis, daughter of Maron, mother of Longinius, physician, through the agency of Longinia Kyrilla;;(in left margin: drachmas 8 obols 16) orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira drachma 1 obols 5 chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives obols 2, naubion obol 1 chalki 2, surcharges obols 3;;eparourion drachma 1 obol 1.5, surcharges obol 0.5, kollybos obol 0.5, in total drachmas 4 obols 2;;geometria of year 12 drachmas 4 obols 4 chalki 2, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 5;;Leonides, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother of Heras, drachmas 4;;Horos alias Karanos, son of Petheus, grandson of Herakles, mother Tauris, drachmas 4 copper drachmas 4;;Heras, his son, mother Tamystha, drachmas 4 copper drachmas 4;;Petheus, son of Horos, grandson of Petheus, mother Sambathion, drachmas 8;;Ammonios, son of Ammonios, grandson of Ammonios, mother Tninis, drachmas 4 copper drachmas 4;;Anoubas, son of Horos, grandson of Anoubas, mother Tepheros, drachmas 4;;Valerius, fatherless, mother Valeria, copper drachmas 4;;Onnophris, fatherless, mother Taeuhemeros, drachmas 8;;Chairemon, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Pasoxis, mother Tanephremis, drachmas 4;;Pakysis, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tepheros, drachmas 4 obols 20;;Paoueites, son of Petheus, grandson of Phasis, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Leonides, grandson of Papeis, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 8;;in total for the day drachmas 212 obols 7;;(Epeiph) 22 likewise:;Imouthes, son of Keras, grandson of Menandros, mother Tepheros, copper drachmas 8."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 -- CPJ 3, 492 (lines with Sambathion) Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3849&amp;viewid=4171_82R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/8/2/r/4171_82r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3849&amp;viewid=4171_82R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3849&amp;viewid=4171_82R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
