<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of Sacred Land</title>
            <author>Psenkebkis, son of Psyphis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1345</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1345</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.263</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;263</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;263</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12097</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12097</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1262</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract by which Psemkebkis, son if Psyphis, sells to Pnebtynis, son of Psyphis, four arourai of sacred land of Soknebtynis, near Tebtynis, with the addition of one-half aroura of the impost of the village (epibole komes); in l. 2, a blank space was left for the insertion of the month and day</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto + Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 15.2 x 30 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">complete, except for a few letters cut off from the right</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto - 41;;Verso - 1</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto + Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0035" notAfter="0036">35-36 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Tiberius, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psenkebkis son of Psyphis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnebtynis son of Psyphis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chomenis (see Geographica)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marepsemis son of Marepsemis (see also P.Mich. V, p. 386 for possible parallels)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome; Chomeniake dioryx</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Irrigation</term>
               <term>Land Ownership</term>
               <term>Land Status</term>
               <term>Religion</term>
               <term>Sale</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Recto);;The twenty-second year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus in the month              , in Tebtynis in the division of Polemon of the Arsinoite nome. Psenkebkis, son of Psyphis, about 31 years old, with a scar on the outside of his right hand, acknowledges to Pnebtynis, son of Psyphis, about 45 years old, with a scar on the first finger of his left hand, that he has sold him the sacred land belonging to him, Psenkebkis, from the land of Soknebtynis, near the aforesaid village of Tebtynis, consisting of four arourai, with one-half aroura from the impost of the village, or as many as there may be in one parcel. The neighbors are on the south the state canal through which the allotment is watered and drained, on the north the dyke of the canal of Chomenis, on the west the allotment of the purchaser Pnebtynis, on the east the allotment of Marepsemis, son of Marepsemis. And he has received from Pnebtynis the entire price agreed upon, in full, from hand to hand, out of the house, and [he acknowledges] that he, Psenkebkis, and his representatives, guarantee the conditions of the sale to Pnebtynis and his representatives with every guarantee, from all public debts and every impost for former times up to the past twenty-first year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus and for the twenty-first year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus as well, and from all private debts and every claim forever. The signatory is Marepsemis, son of Marepsemis, about 35 years old, with a scar below his right shin.;(2nd hand) I, Psenkebkis, son of Psyphis, acknowledge that I have sold to Pnebtynis, son of Psyphis, from the present day forever, the sacred land that belongs to me from the land of Soknebtynis, near the aforesaid village of Tebtynis, amounting to four arourai, with the half aroura of the village impost, or as many as there may be in one parcel. (The neighbors are) on the south the state canal through which the allotment is watered and drained, on the north the dyke of the canal of Chomenis, on the west the allotment of the purchaser Pnebtynis, on the east the allotment of Marepsemis, son of Marepsemis. And I have received from Pnebtynis the entire price agreed upon, in full, from hand to hand, out of the house, and I guarantee the sale with every guarantee from public and private debts and every impost for past times up to the past twenty-first year and for the twenty-first year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, and from private debts and every claim forever as aforesaid.;(3rd hand) Pnebtynis, son of Psyphis. The sale was made to me as aforesaid. Marepsemis, son of Marepsemis, wrote for him because he is illiterate.;;(Verso);;Sale of sacred land, (made) by Pnebtynis to Alkippos.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 263, 1944</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:263</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1345&amp;viewid=1262R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/6/2/R/1262R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1345&amp;viewid=1262R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1345&amp;viewid=1262R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/6/2/V/1262V.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1345&amp;viewid=1262V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1345&amp;viewid=1262V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
