<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Official correspondence</title>
            <author>Aurelius Apollonius, also called Sarapion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1537</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1537</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.turner. 34</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">15695</idno>
            <idno type="TM">15695</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.turner;;34</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 183</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>If the text is the whole document, it cannot have included the imperial constitutio, which is said to have been prefixed (4-5) nor the copy of the will, which is said to have been appended; no doubt this is to be explained by the fact that we have is explicity described as a copy. The text consists of a petition to Vettius Gallianus, acting-epistrategos (of the Thebaid), from a certain Aurelius Apollonius also called Sarapion, an Alexandrian citizen and landholder in Diospolis Parva. It thus enhanced value since it comes from an unusual provenance. In his petition the writer complains that Osaeus, whom he describes as his father's wife and who must therefore have been his step-mother, has cheated him in respect to the property left in his father's will. A copy of the subscriptio follows, dated to a year 25. The emperor is referred to in col. ii can only be Caracalla.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Verso; Recto is unpublished</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 44.7 x 17.7 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The papyrus preserves two columns of writing, the second complete and the first incomplete at the left and foot; it is clear, however, that in neither place is a great deal missing and no doubt virtually the whole document is preserved.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">col. I: 21 lines; col. II: 8 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>One curious feature of the text is that l. 3 has been quite certainly been written after 4, much more hurriendly and squashed into an inadequate space, overrunning into the margin at the right. The same seems to have happened with 2, though here it is not certain that the whole line (which also overruns into the margin) was added subsequently. Most probably, "antigrafon" was written first, then, after a space, the name and title of the addressee as far as "orous", and then the petition, beginning in 4; the words "diadechomeno kai thn epistrategian" and the whole of the next line are to be regarded as a later addition. As already remarked, they are written much more hurriendly and indeed the letters are often badly made. What is not at all clear is whether this adition is by a second jand or by the first hand writing more rapindly and carelessly, possibly with a different pen. It is quite certain that 30 is in a different hand from the rest of the papyrus.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origPlace>Diospolis Parva (?), Thebaid, Upper Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Apollonios alias Sarapion, son of Drako</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Drako, father of Aurelius Apollonios alias Sarapion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Philemon. father of Osaeus</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Diospolis Parva (?), Thebaid, Upper Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Diospolis Par va, Thebaid, Province of Egypt</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Col. i;Copy.;To Vettius Gallanus, the most excellent praefectus montis and acting-epistrategos, from Aurelius Apollonios alias Sarapion, son of Drako, of the Althaean demos, landowner in Piospolis Parva of the Thebaid.;You are aware, greatest of procurators, that the imperial decree transcribed above (the very one indeed that I transcribed above) indicated the unlawful intention of my father, who leaves a will that is ..., but provides guarantees if a son has taken possession of his proper share justly and legally, having also declared it to the local archive of real property. Having come into ownership..., and having paid my share of public dues to the most sacred fiscus, both the amounts owed for customary rents and those needful to the sacred annona, with the consequence that no debts continue to accumulate against me, so that I may have a quiet mind, I know well also your evil-hating concern for those who have been overreached. My father's wife, by name Osaeus, daughter of Philemon, after my father's deification, when she obtained a legacy from an illegal will, having then taken under her control, as was evidents, all contracts of loan regarding household abjects as well as produce and money, of which I compiled the itemized list only with great difficulty and after many searches, has desired to have the sole right of possession with respect to these, having tried from the first to obtain possession of the property and to use it as she may choose ...;Col.  ii;(so that I) may be able to render eternal gratitude (for the benefactions bestowed) by the genius of our undefeated lord and emperor Antoninus and to your just right hand, having obtained in full my legal share of the paternal estate, than which nothing is sweeter to sons. I have appended also a copy of the will.;Year 25, Choiak 29;When you have given due notice to your opponent, you may petition;deliver (this).;From Aurelius Apollonios alias Sarapion, son of Drako</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Thomas JD, PTurner, 34, 1981, Pl XIV-XV -- BL VIII 498. Also, in col. II, l. 28 at the end of line add "moi" after "ent[u]ch[e]in" (JD Thomas by letter to TG)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Turner. 34</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1537&amp;viewid=183R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/8/3/r/183r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1537&amp;viewid=183R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1537&amp;viewid=183R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/8/3/v/183v.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1537&amp;viewid=183V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1537&amp;viewid=183V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
