<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of land</title>
            <author>Aurelia Iuliana</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2226</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2226</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.22.15618</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;22;15618</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;22;15618</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">47267</idno>
            <idno type="TM">47267</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 455</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Sale of a property of an unspecified size for the price of 25 gold solidi.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>2 papyri ; 54.9 x 24.4 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The papyrus seems to be of a good quality. Two sheet-joins 16 cm from the left and c. 19.7 cm from the right. The papyrus is broken off at the top, but there is not much missing because only a consular date is missing. There is virtually no margin to the left of the text, but the scribe left a large area (c. 16 cm) blank to the right of it (such a lavish use of papyrus recalls earlier days). Below the text is a margin of 4 cm.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-21</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The hand responsible for the main part of this text appears to be practised. It is a rather elegant specimen also represented by P. Mich. inv. 456. The scribe hardly ever made any corrections, however badly needed. The crude but not inelegant hand of the subscription by the priest is more like the hand of P. Mich. inv. 472, but the Greek is not always apt. Both hands are specimens of 5th-c. writing.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0427" notAfter="0428">427/428 A.D. [?]</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Alabastrine, Antinoite nome, province of Egypt (?)</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelia Iuliana, daughter of Hymis, son of N. N., her mother being N. N.</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Serenus, sailor (?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dius, son of Peuot</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Bekis, son of Hymis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Antoninus, son of Valentinous, priest</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Alabastrine, Antinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Alabastrine, village in the Antinoite nome,;Terythis Ebythis, Hermopolite nome,;Toou Neaniskon, Hermopolite nome,;The cistern of the farmers' guild of the village of Alabastrine</term>
               <term>Land titles;XRegistration and transfer--Hermopolite Nome (Egypt)</term>
               <term>Suretyship and guaranty--Hermopolite Nome (Egypt)</term>
               <term>Land tenure--Hermopolite Nome (Egypt)</term>
               <term>Vendors and purchasers--Hermopolite Nome (Egypt)</term>
               <term>Liens--Hermopolite Nome (Egypt)</term>
               <term>Claims--Hermopolite Nome (Egypt)</term>
               <term>Money--Hermopolite Nome (Egypt)</term>
               <term>Inheritance and succession--Hermopolite Nome (Egypt)</term>
               <term>Tax assessment--Hermopolite Nome (Egypt)</term>
               <term>Tillage--Hermopolite Nome (Egypt)</term>
               <term>Revenue--Hermopolite Nome (Egypt)</term>
               <term>Literacy--Hermopolite Nome (Egypt)</term>
               <term>Water rights--Hermopolite Nome (Egypt)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"[Date].;Aurelia Iuliana, daughter of Hymis, son of N. N., her mother being N. N., from the village of Alabastrine in the Antinoite nome, to Aurelius Serenus, sailor (?), from the same village.;I acknowledge that I have sold to you and that I have conveyed to you from now on with full proprietary rights forever and ever my property, which has come to me by right of inheritance from my father and which formerly belonged to the inhabitants of Terythis Ebythis in the Hermopolite nome in the taxing unit of the village [blank], consisting of as many arouras as it does, together with the unsown dry land and the cistern and trees of every kind, the boundaries being, as the seller dictated, to the north Dius son of Peuot from Alabastrine, to the west the community of Toou Neaniskon in the Hermopolite nome, to the south Bekis, son of Hymis, from the same Toou, to the east the cistern of the farmers' guild of the village of Alabastrine, for the price and cession money agreed upon between us to the amount of 25 gold solidi of good weight, = 25 gold solidi, which I have received from you on the spot, the price in full from hand to hand. You shall therefore possess and own with your children and descendants and successors the property sold to you by me, consisting of as many arouras as it does, with the dry land and the cistern and the small enclosure as aforesaid forever as well as the revenues from them counting from the tax assessment of the blessed eleventh indiction, whereas you pay all the annual taxes on them of every kind counting from the tax assessment of the blessed eleventh indiction, and power may be upon you to use it, both by cultivating and administering it, and to cede it in any way you may choose unhindered, and I will not lay any claim on it nor anyone else on my behalf in any way, but I will of necessity deliver it to you guaranteed against all claims with every guarantee and free from both public and private debt and lien and from everything else for ever and from everything, and everyone who proceeds, or lays a claim, against you on account of this property, I will at once repel at my own cost and expense, and I will pay back double the price as if it were a personal debt. And as to the question whether this has been rightly and fairly done, I gave my consent after formal interrogation. The sale is valid whereever it is produced for your security.;I, Aurelia Iuliana, daughter of Hymis, the aforesaid, have sold the aforesaid plot of land in accordance with this document together with the cistern and I have received the price in full, twenty five gold solidi, and I will guarantee it as aforesaid. I, Aurelius Antoninus, son of Valentinous, priest, signed on her behalf at her request because she is illiterate, and I witness."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Gagos T-van Minnen P, JRA 5, 188-196, 1992, Plate -- SB XXII, 15618</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.22:15618</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2226&amp;viewid=455R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2226&amp;viewid=455R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2226&amp;viewid=455R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
