<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Contract for a Loan of Wheat</title>
            <author>Aurelii Heron &amp; Apphys &amp; Ammonas &amp; Pannous</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2375</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2375</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.9.573</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;9;573</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;9;573</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12065</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12065</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 5061</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Acknowledgment, made by four sitologoi of Karanis to two apodektai of the harbor of Leukogion, that they have received from them a loan of 417 artabai of wheat for a few days, probably a legal device to allow the sitologoi additional time in which to collect and pay tax grain due in arrears</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Cancellation of the document by crosshatching indicates that the payment was made.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">linked to the archive of Aurelius Isidorus</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 25.4 X 21.2 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">(slightly) broken off on the left side; much damaged along the folds</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">25</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>See electronic version of PMich IX, 573</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0316">October 19, 316 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Apphys son of Pannes (Pannous), sitologos of Karanis (see also P.Cair.Isid. 10, 81</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">17, 128)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Ammonas son of Papeei (Papeeis), sitologos of Karanis (see also P.Cair.Isid. 6, 48</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">9, 79</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">10, 212</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">17, 18)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Palemon son of Palinios, surety of Ammonas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Pannous (Pannes) son of Timotheos, sitologos of Karanis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Herakles son of . . .eros, surety of Pannous</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Ptolemaios son of Ptollarion, apodektes hormou Leukogeiou (Leukogiou)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Apolinarius (Apollinarius) son of Paeianos (Paianos), apodektes hormou Leukogeiou (Leukogiou)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Ision son of Paesis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Caecinius Sabinus &amp; Vettius Rufinus, consuls</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Karanis; Leukogeion (Leukogion)</term>
               <term>Tax administration and procedure--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Discharge of contracts--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Family--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Karanis(Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Wheat--Transportation--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Suretyship and guaranty--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Land value taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Debtor and creditor--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Aurelius Heron, son of Ptolemaios, with as his surety 'for the repayment' his blood brother Aurelius Isidorus, and Aurelius Apphys, son of Pannes, with his surety also for the repayment Aurelius . . ., son of Apion, and Aurelius Ammonas, son of Papeeis, with his surety also for the repayment Aurelius Palemon, son of Palinios, and Aurelius Pannous, son of Timotheos, with his surety also for the repayment Aurelius Herakles, son . . .erus, the four of them from the village of Karanis, sitologoi of the same village for the crop of the fourth indiction, to Aurelius Ptolemaios, son of Ptollarion, and Aurelius Apollinarios, son of Paianos, both from the same village of Karanis, receivers at the harbor of Leukogion, greetings.;We acknowledge in accordance with this chirograph that we have from you on loan four hundred and seventeen artabai of wheat, 417 art. wheat, by the public modius measure, which four hundred and seventeen artabai of wheat we shall of necessity repay on mutual security on the following 28th of the present month Phaophi at the harbor of Leukogion without any delay; and the right of execution on demand shall rest with you against us and against our aforesaid sureties and against whichever one of us you may choose and against all our property, as if in accordance with a legal decision. In response to the formal question, we have so declared.;(2nd hand) We, Aurelius Apphys and his surety . . . and Aurelius Heron and his surety Isidoros and Aurelius Ammonas and his surety Palemon, acknowledge that we have received, together with our aforesaid associate, Pannous, the four hundred and seventeen artabai of wheat and we shall repay them on mutual security at the appointed time as aforesaid. I, Apphys, son of Pannes, wrote for the rest also, since they are illiterate.;(3rd hand) I, Aurelius Pannes, with my surety, Herakles, acknowledge that I have received, together with my aforesaid associates, the four hundrred and seventeen artabai of wheat, and we shall repay them on mutual security at the appointed time as aforesaid. I, Aurelius Ision, son of Paesis, wrote for them because they are illiterate.;(4th hand) In the consulship of the most illustrious Caecinius Sabinus and Vettius Rufinus, Phaophi 22.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich IX, 573, 1971</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:9:573</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2375&amp;viewid=5061R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/6/1/r/5061r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2375&amp;viewid=5061R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2375&amp;viewid=5061R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
