<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3845</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3845</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 33.3 x 30.1 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at the right and the left. Kollesis at left and right sides. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-39</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 80 (ll. 3179-3218)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois, son of Onnophris, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Petheus, grandson of Aunes, mother Eserempis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harsiesis, son of Petheus, grandson of Harsiesis, mother Thatres (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Onnophris, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetsooukis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Sisois, grandson of Petsiris, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles, son of Sokrates, grandson of Phasis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis, son of Heras, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Isidora (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabous, son of Petheus, grandson of Satabous, mother Tapetaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 226)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phasis, son of Tesenouphis, grandson of Harphaesis, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 246)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion, son of Petsiris, grandson of Pasion, mother Thases (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Esouris, son of Petheus, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Ptolema (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Satabous, grandson of Horos, mother Theonis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Ptolema (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Stiynchis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, his brother with the same mother (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Onnophris, grandson of Theabennis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Komonis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Euhemeros, son of Aunes, grandson of Aunes, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Tanesneus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Sisois, grandson of Satabous, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Perigenes, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Tanais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Sabeinos, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Gaia (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Herakles, mother Tkonnos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Nestosiris, grandson of Petheus, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Syros, son of Onnophris, grandson of Maron, mother Tkollainis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 231)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Thakialis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Taptosiris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraklas, son of Apollonios, grandson of Heraklas, mother Taorsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 166)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Abykis, son of Demas, grandson of Abykis, mother Taonnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 148)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Pakysis, grandson of Petheus, mother Tamaron (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 80:;Sisois, son of Onnophris, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4 copper drachmas 4;;Horos, son of Petheus, grandson of Aunes, mother Eserempis, copper drachmas 8;;Harsiesis, son of Petheus, grandson of Harsiesis, mother Thatres, drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 16 obols 28.;(Epeiph) 11 likewise:;Petheus, son of Onnophris, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetsooukis, copper drachmas 4 obols 28;;Onnophris, son of Sisois, grandson of Petsiris, mother Thaesis, copper drachmas 4;;Herakles, son of Sokrates, grandson of Phasis, mother Tapetheus, copper drachmas 4;;Phaesis, son of Heras, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Isidora, drachmas 4;;in total drachmas 16 obols 28.;(Epeiph) 18:;Satabous, son of Petheus, grandson of Satabous, mother Tapetaus, copper drachmas 4;;Phasis, son of Tesenouphis, grandson of Harphaesis, mother Thaesis, copper drachmas 4;;Pasion, son of Petsiris, grandson of Pasion, mother Thases, copper drachmas 4;;Esouris, son of Petheus, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Ptolema, obols 28;;Ptolemaios, son of Satabous, grandson of Horos, mother Theonis, drachmas 4;;Onnophris, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Ptolema, drachmas 4;;Petesouchos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Stiynchis, drachmas 8;;Petaus, his brother with the same mother, obols 12 copper obols 16;;Heron, son of Onnophris, grandson of Theabennis, mother Tapetheus, copper drachmas 4;;Horion, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Komonis, copper drachmas 4;;Heron, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 8;;Euhemeros, son of Aunes, grandson of Aunes, mother Tepheros, copper drachmas 4 obols 28;;in total for the day drachmas 56 obols 26.;(Epeiph) 19 likewise:;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Tanesneus, drachmas 4 copper obols 28;;Petaus, son of Sisois, grandson of Satabous, mother Thermouthis, copper drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Thaisas, drachmas 8;;Sarapion, son of Perigenes, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Tanais, copper drachmas 4;;Heron, son of Sabeinos, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Gaia, drachmas 12;;Sisois, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Herakles, mother Tkonnos, drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, son of Nestosiris, grandson of Petheus, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4 copper drachmas 4;;Syros, son of Onnophris, grandson of Maron, mother Tkollainis, drachmas 8 copper drachmas 4;;Pnepheros, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Thakialis, copper drachmas (that of priests) 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Taptosiris, copper drachmas (that of priests) 4;;Heraklas, son of Apollonios, grandson of Heraklas, mother Taorsenouphis, drachmas 4 copper drachmas 4;;Abykis, son of Demas, grandson of Abykis, mother Taonnophris, drachmas 4;;Petheus, son of Pakysis, grandson of Petheus, mother Tamaron, drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 84 obols 28."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3845&amp;viewid=4171_80R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3845&amp;viewid=4171_80R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3845&amp;viewid=4171_80R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
