<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3856</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3856</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 33.9 x 30.3 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Regularly cut at top, left and right. 2 kolleseis, one in the left center and one near the right edge of the document. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-37</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 89 (ll. 3537 - 3574)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Petheus, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Taseus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didyme, daughter of Pakysis  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 161)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menas  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 188)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius Lucillius Priscus  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 159)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Longina, daughter of Lucillius  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 185)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Taonnophris, daughter of Horion  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 234)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 239)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Euhemeros  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 223)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kabnounis  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Kastor, grandson of Heraklas, mother Taseus  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraklas, his son, mother Ammonous  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Polis, son of Petheus, grandson of Keras, mother Herais  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Petheus, grandson of Teos, mother Segathis  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Heras the older, grandson of Herakles, mother Thermouthis  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Horos, mother Tapetheus  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 223)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Vettius, son of Petheus, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Taseus  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 195)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, his brother with the same mother  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabeinos, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Zoidous  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpochratiaina, daughter of Apollonios  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptoleminos, son of Takases  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 221)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Sambas, grandson of Sabeinos, mother Aphrodous  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Petaus, grandson of Petaus, mother Tauris  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pamonneouis, son of Anchorimphis, grandson of Pamonneuis, mother Didymarion  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Polydeukes, son of Heras, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapasion  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 214)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tapetheus, daughter of Pasoknopaios  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 236)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apynchis, son of Pethermouthis, grandson of Apynchis, mother Thermouthis  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 154)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>-</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 89:;(Epeiph) 29 likewise:;Karanos, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Imouthes, mother Tapetsiris, drachmas 4;;Limnaios, son of Onnophris, grandson of Satabous, mother Ptolema, copper drachmas 4;;Mysthes the younger, son of Dioskoros, grandson of Mysthes, mother Tepheros, drachmas 20;;Ptolemaios, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Horos, mother Eserempis, drachmas 20;;Ptolemais, daughter of Apollonios (Ischyras, chief of police);;orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira drachmas 17 obols 3, tax on the produce of olives drachmas 2 obols 2.5 chalki 2, naubion drachma 1 chalki 3.5, surcharges drachmas 4 obols 2.5;;(in left margin: drachmas 40) eparourion drachmas 11 obols 3, surcharges drachma 1, kollybos obols 3, in total drachmas 39 obols 2.5 chalki 2;;Paoueites, son of Petheus, grandson of Phasis, mother Tapetheus, copper drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Thaisas, copper drachmas 4;;Petheus, son of Onnophris (wife of Petenas ?);;orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira drachmas 2 obols 2 chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives obols 2.5 chalki 2, naubion obol 1.5, surcharges obols 4;;(in left margin: drachmas 36 obols 16) eparourion drachma 1 obols 4, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 5 obols 4 chalki 2;;geometria of year 12 drachmas 5 obols 5 chalki 2, surcharges obols 2 chalki 2, in total drachmas 6 obol 1.5;;and to Akousarion, son of Euhemeros through the agency of Tapetheus, daughter of Euhemeros;;orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira drachmas 5, tax on the produce of olives obols 4 chalki 2, naubion obols 3, surcharges drachma 1 obol 1.5;;eparourion drachmas 3 obols 2, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2, kollybos obol 1.5, in total drachmas 11 obol 1.5 chalki 2;;geometria of year 12 drachmas 12 obols 3, surcharges obols 4.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 13 obol 1.5 chalki 2;;Chairemon, son of Horos, grandson of Onnophris, mother Segathis, drachmas 4 copper drachmas 4;;Petaus, son of Petheus, grandson of Petaus, mother Tapasion, obols 28;;Aphrodisios, son of Anchophis, grandson of Petheus, mother Melanous, drachmas 4 copper drachmas 4;;Phanomgeus, son of Petheus, grandson of Satabous, mother Tamystha, copper drachmas 4;;Heron, son of Horos, grandson of Petheus, mother Taharpagathes, drachmas 12;;Panesneus, son of Ischyras, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaesis, copper drachmas 8;;Sarapion, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Sarapion, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4 obols 20 copper drachmas 4 obols 8;;Petheus, son of Kanis, grandson of Petheus, mother Tkollainis, drachmas 8;;Petheus, son of Kanis, cultivator in the 70th cleruchy;;orchard taxes of year 12 in the dioikesis of Patsontisapomoira drachma 1 obol 1.5, naubion obol 0.5 chalki 2, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2;;(in left margin: drachmas 12 obols 28) eparourion obols 5, surcharges obol 0.5, kollybos obol 0.5, in total drachmas 2 obols 4;;geometria of year 12 drachmas 3 obol 0.5 chalki 2, surcharges obol 1 chalki 2, in total drachmas 3 obols 2;;rent of year 12 drachmas 8, surcharges obols 3, in total drachmas 8 obols 3;;Lucius Antonius Pomp()anus (Marinus, son of Kelaulis);;(in left margin: drachmas 64) orchard taxes of year 12 drachmas 4 obol 0.5, tax on the produce of olives obols 3.5 chalki 2, naubion obols 2.5, surcharges drachma 1 chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 2 obols 4 chalki 2, surcharges obol 1.5, kollybos obol 1, in total drachmas 9 obol 1.5 chalki 2;;geometria of year 12 drachmas 7, surcharges obols 3, in total drachmas 7 obols 3;;and Marcus Sempronius Clemens through the agency of Marinus;;orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira drachmas 8 obols 4.5, tax on the produce of olives drachma 1 obol 1.5, naubion obols 5.5, surcharges drachmas 2 obol 1 chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 5 obols 5, surcharges obols 3, kollybos obols 2, in total drachmas 19 obols 4.5 chalki 2;;geometria of year 12 drachmas 21 obols 5 chalki 2, surcharges drachma 1 obols 2.5, in total drachmas 23 obol 1.5 chalki 2;;naubion of katoikoi of year 13 drachmas 2 chalki 2, surcharges obol 1 chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachmas 2 obol 1.5 chalki 2."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3856&amp;viewid=4171_89R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/8/9/r/4171_89r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3856&amp;viewid=4171_89R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3856&amp;viewid=4171_89R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
