<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Contributions to a Guild of Harpokrates</title>
            <author>Pasipsemis, son of Orseus, and other members of the guild</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2926</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2926</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.246</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;246</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;246</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">25172</idno>
            <idno type="TM">25172</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 671</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>List of contributions, mainly in money, made (or to be made) by the president and other members of a guild of Harpokrates (for which see also P.Mich. II, 127, col. I, l. 30); this was clearly intended as an appendix to an ordinance passed by the guild, the body of which was left to be written in later by a clerk of the grapheion. In the list, the names of the members of the association (some of them left blank or washed out) are divided in three groups of five, probably arranged in the order in which they took their seats at the banquet tables.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 20 x 26 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">somewhat damaged at the bottom</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">23</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>First hand: hand of the Kronion documents from the Tebtynis grapheion; the other hands are all cursive, but vary greatly in penmanship (Boak)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0001" notAfter="0099">(Middle of the) Ist century A.D. (probably ca. 43-49 A.D.)</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasipsemis son of Orseus, hegoumenos synodou Harpochratou</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orseus son of Herakles (alias?) Besis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Eutychos son of Soterichos (see also P.Mich. II, 123, recto, col. VI, l. 15</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">col. XI, l. 17</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">V, 352?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos son of Herakles (alias?) Besis (see also P.Mich. V, p. 311)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sylias</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios prosbyteros (presbyteros), son of Akousilaos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herodes son of Marion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Papnebtynis son of Paanouphis (see also P.Mich. V, 306)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Narkissos, apeleutheros of the sons of Maron alias(?) Marous son of Herakles &lt;or: of the sons of Maron and of Marous son of Herakles&gt;</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) sons of Maron alias(?) Maron son of Herakleides</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herodes son of Eutychos (see also P.Mich. II, 121, recto, col. IV, abstract 3?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Serapas (Sarapion) son of Ptolemaios (see also P.Mich. II, 126, l. 27 and P.Mich. V, p. 394)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pastoous son of Pastoous</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios neoteros son of Akousilaos (see also P.Mich. V, 259</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">354)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Guilds;--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Dinners and dining--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Freedmen--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(1st). Pasipsemis, son of Orseus, president of the guild of Harpochrates, about 45 years old, with a scar on the middle of his nose, (contributes) for each two (kinds of) spices, two wafers, a vetchy dish, apart from the victuals.;2nd. Orseus, son of Herakles also called(?) Besis, about 39 years old, with a scar on his forehead to the left, (contributes) ten silver drachmai.;3rd. Eutychos, son of Soterichos, about 45 years old, with a scar on his right shin, (contributes) twenty-two silver drachmai.;4th. Petesouchos, son of Herakles also called(?) Besis, about 33 years old, with a scar on his left shin, (contributes) nineteen silver drachmai.;5th.;Last. Mese(--);(1st) Sylias twenty-four silver drachmai.;2nd. N[[- - - - - - - - - - - - - - -]] twenty-two silver drachmai.;3rd. Ptolemaios the elder, son of Akousilaos, about 45 years old, with a scar on his right forearm, (contributes) twenty silver drachmai.;4th. Herodes, son of Marion, about 45 years old, with a scar in the middle of his forehead, (contributes) eighteen silver drachmai.;5th.;Last at the table of Heron, Papnebtynis, son of Paanouphis, about 60 years old, with a scar on the middle of his nose, (contributes) sixteen silver drachmai.;Master of the banquet. K[[- - - - - - - - - - - -]] twenty silver drachmai.;2nd. Narkissos, freedman of the sons of Maron and Maron, son of Herakleides, about 36 years old, with a mole on his nose on the right side, (contributes) twenty-one silver drachmai.;3rd. Herodes, son of Eutychos, about 46 years old, with a scar on his nose below the eyebrows, (contributes) seventeen drachmai.;4th. Serapas, son of Ptolemaios, about 36 years old, with a scar on the left side of his neck, (contributes) fourteen drachmai 3 obols.;5th.;Last, master of the banquet. Pastoous, son of Pastoous, about 38 years old, with a scar on his left shin, (contributes) twelve silver drachmai.;(2nd hand) I, Narkissos, freedman, have voted. (3rd hand) I, Sarapion, son of Ptolemaios, have voted. (4th hand) I, Herodes, son of Eutychos, have voted. (5th hand) I, Ptolemaios the elder, son of Akousilaos, have voted. (6th hand) I, Ptolemaios the younger, son of Akousilaos, have voted.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich V, 246, 1944 -- BL VIII, 213 (l. 14; 19)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:246</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2926&amp;viewid=671R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/7/1/R/671R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2926&amp;viewid=671R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2926&amp;viewid=671R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
