<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>literature; Old Testament</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2636</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2636</idno>
            <idno type="dclp">113559</idno>
            <idno type="TM">113559</idno>
            <idno type="dclp-hybrid">tm;;113559</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 607</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>This papyrus contains parts of the Sahidic version of Kingdoms IV not hitherto known in Coptic. The text preserved may be tabulated as follows:;folio I recto col. i:1.18-2.2 (19 lines);                         col. ii: 2.3-2.4 (2 lines);            verso col. i: 2.6 (5 lines);                           col. ii: 2.8-2.10 (20 lines);folio 2 recto col. 1: 2.11-2.14 (19 lines);                           col. ii: lost;              verso col. i: lost;                            col. ii: 2.19-2.21 (18 lines)</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto +Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Copt">Coptic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 15.5 x 20.1 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">A llittle bit of the string attaching the leaves of the original codex remains attached in the inner margins of folio 1. Masses of salt crystals deeply embeded between the fibers all over the sheet.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-46</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: folio 1; Recto + Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>A llittle bit of the string attaching the leaves of the original codex remains attached in the inner margins of folio 1. (TC) Two fragmentary leaves of what was originally a large and beautiful papyrus codex. The text was written in two columns, only the inner columns of each folio being preserved. Both sheets of this codex are broken off at the top, but we may establish the original number of lines with some degree of certainty. A tentative reconstruction of the Coptic, based upon Maspero's text, suggests that four lines have been lost at the beginning of Folio I Verso Col.  ii, which would therefore have originally contained 24 lines. Only a small amount of text is missing between the end of Folio I Verso Col. ii and the beginning of Folio 2 Recto Col. 1; as a likely reconstruction of the Coptic indicates, no more than five lines have vanished from the beginning of this column, and thus, like the preceding, when complete it would have held 24 lines of writing.;Writing may be assigned to the ninth century of our era, perhaps to the second half: the hand is somewhat similar to that of a Vienna papyrus of Kingdoms IV, recently edited by T. Orlandi, Koptische Papyri theologischen Inhalts, MPER, N.S. 9 (Vienna, 1974), I (K 7549a-h, containing portions of 4  Kgs. 1.6-17.15). Despite the affinity of subject matter, it is clear that the Michigan and Vienna papyri do not come from the same codex: the writing styles. though similar, are obviously the work of different scribes, and the line lengths of the Vienna text are characteristically shorter than those of the Michigan piece.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0850" notAfter="0900">second half of IXth century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>White Monastery, Upper Egypt, Egypt</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>White Monastery, Upper Egypt, Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Copt">Coptic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>-</term>
               <term>Bible--O.T.-- Kings, 2nd--Coptic.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">literary; Old Testament</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Folio 1 R i: (1.18d) "And the Lord was enraged in anger at the house of Nachaab (sic). (2.1) And it happened, when the Lord was about to take up Helias the prophet in an earthquake up to heaven, Helias proceeded with Elisaios out of Galgalon. (2.2) Helias said Elissaios (sic), "Sit here, because it is to Baithel that the Lord has ordered me to go." Elisaios said to him, "The Lord lives, and your soul lives . . . ";R ii: (2.3) ". . . I also know. Be silent." (2.4) Helias . . . ;V i: (2.6) . . . "Sit here, because it is to the Iordanes that the Lord has told me to go." And Elisaios said to him . . . ;V ii: . . . [He] struck the water with it; the water separated on this side and that, and they crossed the dry sea together. (2.9) And when they had crossed, Helias said to Elisaios, "Ask me for a thing, and I shall do it for you before I am taken up from your sight." Elisaios said to him, "Let your spirit become doubled upon me." (2.10) Helias said to him, "You have exceeded the measure for requesting. If you see me being taken up from your sight, this shall happen to you. But if I am not taken up, this thing shall not happen to you.";Folio 2 R i: (2.11) . . . They separated them from one another. Immediately Helias was taken up in an earthquake up to heaven. (2.12) And Elisaios saw, and he cried out, saying, "My father, charioteer of Israel and its horseman!" And he no longer saw him. Immediately he laid his hands upon his clothes; he tore them; he made them two broken pieces. (2.13) And he raised up the sheepskin of Helias, the one which had fallen upon Elisaios. And he turned; he stood by the bank of the Iordanes. (2.14) He took the sheepskin . . . ;V ii: (2.19) ". . . [The situation of] the city is good, just as the Lord sees it. But the waters are bad, and the land does not produce." (2.20) Elisaios said to them, "Bring me a new little pitcher, and throw salt into it." They got it; they brought it to him. (2.21) And Elisaios arose; he came forth to the channels of the waters; he threw the salt there, saying, "This it is that the Lord says: 'these waters I have cured, and I . . . ' "</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Browne GM, Illinois Class Stud 3, 196-206, 1978, Photo</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2636&amp;viewid=607_1R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/_/1/r/607_1r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2636&amp;viewid=607_1R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2636&amp;viewid=607_1R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/_/1/v/607_1v.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2636&amp;viewid=607_1V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2636&amp;viewid=607_1V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
