<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of a Share of a Corn-Measure</title>
            <author>Aurelia Ioudith, daughter of Ioannes</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3016</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3016</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.13.664</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;13;664</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;13;664</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21376</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21376</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 6904</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract by which Aurelia Ioudith, daughter of Ioannes, sells to the syntelestes Aurelius Christophoros, son of Apollos, a seventh share in a corn-measure containing 100 modii xysti, which her son had formerly inherited from his father and then sold to her</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto (written across the fibres); Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Dioskoros of Aphrodito.</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>2 papyri ; 45.5 x 30.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">broken off at the top</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">50</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0599" notAfter="0600">599/600AD</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Aphrodite (Aphrodito), Antaiopolite nome, province of the Lower Thebais, Thebais, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelia Ioudith (Judith) daughter of Ioannes (John) [Cornelius(?)] (see J. Gascou, CE 52 [1977] p. 364)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Christophoros son of Apollos, syntelestes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mauricius Tiberius, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Kyriakos son of Kollouthos and Ioudith (see also P.Lond. V, 1899?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kollouthos, deceased husband of Ioudith and father of Kyriakos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Daueit (David) son of Andreas, presbyteros (see also P.Mich. XIII, 667)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Theodoros son of Paulos, iatros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Senouthes son of Apollos, presbyteros (= Senouthes son of Apollos, protokometes?) (see P.Mich. XIII, 669 etc.)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Synterichos son of Panymphios, presbyteros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Constantinus, tabellion (see also P.Vat.Aphrod. 4)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Aphrodite (Aphrodito), Antaiopolite nome, province of the Lower Thebais, Thebais, Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Aphrodite, Antaiopolite nome</term>
               <term>Building</term>
               <term>Family</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Aphrodito (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Inheritance</term>
               <term>Medicine</term>
               <term>Metrology</term>
               <term>Notary</term>
               <term>Priest (Christian)</term>
               <term>Profession</term>
               <term>Sale</term>
               <term>Tax Collection</term>
               <term>Woman</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Cross) Aurelia Ioudith, daughter of Ioannes [Cornelius(?) and - - -, - - -], of the village of Aphrodite in the Antaiopolite nome to (cross) Aurelius Christophoros, son of Apollos, the most admirable syntelestes, from the same village of Aphrodite, greetings. I, the afore-said Ioudith, daughter of Ioannes, acknowledge that with this my written deed of sale, of my own free will and with [voluntarily] intent and with straight-forward intention and swearing by the Almighty God and by the victory and safety of our most [pious] &lt;or: [gentle]&gt; master Flavius Mauricius Tiberius, the perpetuous Augustus, Imperator, I have sold out to you, the afore-mentioned Christophoros, son of Apollos, the most admirable syntelestes, and have devised to you and have ceded and have given up to you from now on for all continually succeeding time for ever with all the most complete rights of ownership a seventh share of a bequest of a corn-measure of the auspicious containing a hundred modii xysti of corn that belongs to me and has come down to me according to a written deed of sale from my son Kyriakos, having come down to him by right of inheritance from his departed father Kollouthos, my husband, for the full and fitting price agreed and jointly approved by us with one another of two approved imperial gold nomismatia in number, each less one carat by the goldsmith's scales of the same village of Aphrodite, i.e. 2 g.nom. less 2 car., which goldpieces of the price I, the vendor, Ioudith, daughter of Ioannes, have received from you, Christophoros, son of Apollos, the purchaser, from your hand into my hands in the sight of the lawful witnesses who have written their attestations below in order, for all time from the present for ever, of full number and weight, at the time the sale was effected; with which price I am satisfied. Upon the condition that hence-forward you the same purchaser Christophoros, son of Apollos, syntelestes, possess, own and are master of the afore-said complete seventh share of the same bequest of the same corn-measure of the same auspicious corn-shipment according to the force of our written rights of documents as I said before, of which I handed over to you the possession and the ownership from now on and you may manage and exploit it and transmit it to your own heirs and assigns and successors and use it and enjoy it in whatever proprietary way you may please, without hindrance or let, starting with the assessment of the D.V. fourth indiction inclusive and throughout  succeeding time continually and for ever, free from opposition present or future from any of those who are heirs or co-heirs after me or of my relations by birth or my connections; and I shall defend you at my own expense and costs from whoever shall in future take proceedings aganst you concerning this; and I shall confirm your possession with every confirmation at all times and on every occasion, compulsorily, against everyone who shall attack you; and if I am negligent in the confirmation, I shall pay three times the price together with costs and damages, in order that this deed of sale may be valid and inviolable wherever it is produced; which deed, written in one copy, I have of my own free will and consent executed at the Public Registry without any violence, compulsion, deceit or fraud, without any intimidation or guile, and for your security I have given you this copy completed according to the laws with the subscription of him who subscribes for me, followed in order by those of the customary witnesses; and for all that is herein written and for the guarantee of confirmation of this sale and for its freedom from encumbrances all my possessions present and future, movable, immovable and live-stock, generally and severally, are submitted to you as a pledge and with the force of a mortgage as though by decree of court. And being asked the formal question concerning all that is herein written I agreed that the things were so, and so to give, do and keep. (Cross).;(2nd hand) (Cross) I, the aforesaid Aurelia Ioudith, daughter of Ioannes, have executed this deed of sale, and have received the afore-said price in two nomismatia, and shall confirm your possession with every confirmation, and I agree with all that is herein written; and I have sworn the divine oath as afore-said. I, Daueit, son of Andreas, D.V.presbyter, have written it for her at her request. (Cross).;(3rd hand) (Cross) I, Aurelius Theodoros, son of Paulos, physician, bear witness to the deed of sale, having heard declarations from the person executing it and bear witness also to the payment of the two gold nomismatia of the price. (Cross).;(4th hand) (Cross) I, Senouthes, son of Apollos, most humble presbyter, bear witness to the deed of sale, having heard declarations from the person executing it and bear witness also to the payment of the two gold nomismata of the price. (Cross).;(5th hand) (Cross) I, Aurelius Kyriakos, son of the aforementioned Ioudith, consent with and have approved of this deed of sale as aforesaid. (Cross).;(6th hand) (Cross) I, Synterichos, son of Panymphios, presbyter, bear witness to the deed of sale, having heard declarations from the persons executing it and bear witness also to the payment of the two gold nomismata of the price. (Cross).;(7th hand) (Cross) Written by me, Constantinus, D.V. tabellio. (Tachygraphy). (Three crosses).</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn PJ, PMich XIII, 664, 1977, Pl. XVI-XVII -- BL VII, 116 (date; l. 1; 12); BL VIII, 217 (l. 1; 6; 4); BL XI, 133 (identification of persons); Bagnall-Worp, ZPE 148 (2004), 250-252 (dating: AD 599/600)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:13:664</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3016&amp;viewid=6904R_1.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/1/6904R_1.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3016&amp;viewid=6904R_1.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3016&amp;viewid=6904R_1.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/2/6904R_2.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3016&amp;viewid=6904R_2.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3016&amp;viewid=6904R_2.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
