<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Receipt for a Gift of Land</title>
            <author>Haryotes, son of Lysimachos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3076</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3076</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.341</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;341</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;341</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12151</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12151</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 709</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Subscriptions of a receipt by which Haryotes, son of Lysimachos, acknowledges that he has received as a gift from his father-in-law, Didymos, son of Maron, in addition to an earlier dowry, two and three-quarters arourai of a catoecic allotment which formerly belonged to himself, Haryotes. - See also P.Mich. V, 341, verso, an incomplete draft concerned with one of the clauses of this receipt.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">The image shows only the Michigan fragment.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.S.I. VIII, 904; see also P.Mich. V, 340, verso (draft of the end of the body of the contract for which we have here the authentic subscriptions). - Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; Total size: ca. 54 x 28 cm. (P.S.I. VIII, 904, frg. a: 23 x 26 cm; P.Mich. inv. 709: 20.2 x 28.2 cm; P.S.I. VIII, 904, frg. b: 11 x 26 cm)</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Complete, but broken in three fragments; only the central portion is in the Michigna collection</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">12</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0047">August 26, 47 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Rhodous (alias?) Tamaron daughter of Herakleides, wife of Didymos (see PMich. V, p. 332)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Claudius, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Patynis son of Apollonios (see P.Mich. II, p. 227</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Ibion Eikosapentarouron (Eikosipentarouron), Polemonos meris; Hellenikos; Aigyptios</term>
               <term>Dowry--Egypt--Ibion Eikosipentatouron (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>House Ownership</term>
               <term>Land Ownership</term>
               <term>Marriage</term>
               <term>Sale</term>
               <term>Woman (&amp;amp</term>
               <term>guardian)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(On top of the left fragment) 7th year of Claudius, 3rd intercalary day. Official copy.;;;;I, Haryotes, son of Lysimachos, have as an additional gift from Didymos, son of Maron, father of my wife Herakleia, in accordance with this contract, in the interest of Herakleia, without valuation, two and three-quarters arourai, or as many as there may be, of a catoecic allotment near Ibion Eikosipentarouron in the division of Polemon, the neighbors of which are set forth in the documents concerning them, and which formerly belonged to me, the aforesaid Haryotes, apart from the other dowry of silver and gold and the catoecic allotments and the two slaves formerly brought to me as dowry for Herakleia by her parents, Didymos and Rhodous, and by Herakleia herself, in accordance with the two other alimentary contracts executed through the same record office, in the second year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, in the month Kaisareios, on the third intercalary day, one of which  contracts is Greek and the other Egyptian. And if any separation takes place between us, &lt;I agree&gt; to return to Herakleia the allotment brought as dowry in accordance with this deed of additional gift, together with all the others brought as dowry according to the two former contracts; and all the specifications made in them are valid, except that concerning the share of building sites given as dowry by the said Didymos for Herakleia, and sold by Herakleia acting with me, her husband Haryotes, as her guardian, in the past sixth year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, to Patynis, son of Apollonios, for 320 drachmai of minted silver, which are also a charge upon me, Haryotes, apart from the dowry of silver and gold given through the marriage contracts and apart from the other possessions, as aforesaid. And the parents of Herakleia, Didymos, son of Maron, and Rhodous, daughter of Herakleia, shall suffer no loss whatever with regard to the relinquishment which they have from Herakleia in the matter of paternal or maternal inheritance, made through the same record office, in the second year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, in the month                       , and with regard to the matters set forth in that relinquishment, out of the good will and regard of Didymos towards his daughter Herakleia. The gift of this allotment made &lt;to me&gt; shall remain valid, and I will do everything as aforesaid.;(2nd hand) I, Didymos, son of Maron, have given as additional dowry for my daughter Herakleia to her husband Haryotes the aforesaid two and three-quarters arourai, or as many more as there may be, of a catoecic allotment near Ibion Eikosipentarouron, in addition to the dowry previously given in the interest of the said Herakleia to Haryotes by me, and by my wife, who is the mother of Herakleia, Tamaron, and by Herakleia herself, in accordance with all the previously designated conditions.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 341, 1944</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:341</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3076&amp;viewid=709R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/0/9/R/709R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3076&amp;viewid=709R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3076&amp;viewid=709R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
