<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>a love charm</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3030</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3030</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.16.757</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.15.</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich. inv. 6925</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Obverse;  Reverse is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>Lead ; 29.5 x 20 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The plate is well preserved and, aside from a crack slightly off center to the left, undamaged. Sand and calcium deposits obscure very little of the writing in parts of the lower edge and upper right hand side. The creases running vertically at regular intervals indicate that the tablet was rolled up.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Obverse</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The script resembles W. Schubarts P. Berol. 43a (4th century A.D.) and the hand of the Bodmer Menander texts (3rd/4th century A.D.; cf. e.g. the specimen of Dyskolos in R. Seider, Palaeographie der griechischen Papyri II # 51, pl. XXVI).</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0200" notAfter="0399">IIIrd/IVth century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>unknown</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Kopria</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kopria</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Taesis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ailourion</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>-</term>
               <term>Charms--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Chastity.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Lead</term>
               <term type="genre_form">subliterary; magic</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>chapters J &amp; K:;"aberamenthooulerthexanaexthreluoothnemareba;II.A I deposit with you this binding spell, gods of the underworld, Pluto and Kore yesenmeigadon, and Koure Persephone Ereschigal and Adonis, who is also barbaritha, and underworld Hermes-Thoth phokensepseu earektathou misontaich and mighty Anubis pseriphtha, II.B who holds the keys to the (gates) of Hades, and (with you,) chthonic spirits, gods and goddesses who suffered an untimely death, boys and maidens. Year after year, month after month, day after day, night after night, hour after hour, I adjure you, all spirits in this place to assist the nekydaimon. II.C. (Rouse yourself for me, nekydaimon, ) whoever you are, whether male or female, and go into every place, into every quarter, into every house, and bind Kopria, whom her mother Taesis bore, the hair of whose head you have, for Ailourion, whom his mother named Kopria bore, that she may not submit to vaginal nor anal intercourse, nor gratify another youth or another man except Ailourion only, whom his mother named Kopria bore, and may she not even be able to eat nor drink nor ever get sleep nor enjoy good health nor have peace in her soul or mind for her desire of Ailourion, whom his mother named Kopria bore, until Kopria, whom her mother Taesis bore, whose hair you have, spring up from every place and every house, burning with passion, and come to Ailourion, whom his mother named Kopria bore, loving, adoring Ailourion, whom his mother named Kopria bore, with all her soul, with all her spirit, with unceasing and unremitting and constant loving affection, with a divine love, from this very day, from the present hour, for the rest of her, Kopria's life. II.C 2 For I adjure you, nekydaimon, by the fearful and dreadful name of him at the hearing of whose name the spirits tremble with fear, at the hearing of whose name the rivers and seas are tossed, at the hearing of whose name the rocks are cleft, by the name barbaritham barbarithaam chelombra barouchambra Adonai and by the name ambrath Abrasax sesengen barpharanges and by the name Iao Saabaoth Iaeo pasenpsoth pakenbraoth sabarbatiaoth sabarbatiane sabarbaphai mari glorious marmaraoth and by the name marmarauoth marmarachtha marmarachthaa anarda maribeoth. II.C 3 Do not disobey my commands, nekydaimon, whoever you are, whether male or female, but rouse yourself for me and go into every place, into every quarter, into every house, and bind Kopria, whom her mother named Kopria bore, that she may not submit to vaginal nor anal intercourse, nor gratifying another youth or another man; and may she not even be able to eat nor drink nor get sleep nor be at peace in her soul or mind because of her constant longing, day and night, for Ailourion, whom his mother named Kopria bore, loving, adoring him as her own life, with all her heart, with all her spirit, Kopria, whose hair you have, loving AIlourion, whom his mother named Kopria bore, with a divine love until death. Now now quickly quickly. (26-28 letters and magical symbols).;K. aeo...oaeoaiuaueoiaemarza;maribeoth. Do not disobey my commands, nekydaimon, whoever you are, but rouse yourself for me, and go into everyplace, into every quarter, into every house and bring Kopria, whom her mother Taesis bore, whose hair you have, to Ailourion, whom his mother named Kopria bore, burning, blazing, melting away in her soul, her spirit, her feminine part, loving, adoring with a divine love until death Ailourion, whom his mother named Kopria bore. Now now quickly quickly! II.C 4 I am Barbadonaiai Barbadonaiwho conceals the stars, who preserves heaven, who establishes the kosmos in truth. iattheoun iatreoun salbiouth aoth aoth sabathiouth iat'therath Adonaiai isar suria bibibe bibiouth nattho Sabaoth aianapha amourachthe satama Zeus atheresphilauo/"</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor- Martinez DG;   Rep Ser. - PMich XVI;   1991;   pg.757 Martinez DG, Diss, 10, 1985 Daniel RW-Maltomini F, Supplementum Magicum 1, 181-92, 1989</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:16:757</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:15:</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3030&amp;viewid=6925.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3030&amp;viewid=6925.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3030&amp;viewid=6925.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
