<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>private letter</title>
            <author>Dionysios</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1969</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1969</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.16.12607</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;16;12607</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;16;12607</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">26741</idno>
            <idno type="TM">26741</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 341</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Dionysios writes to Hermes and Dioskoras concerning a matter of business.Dionysios appears to be general manager of extensive properties belonging to Theodora. He writes to two of his subordinates, who are described on the verso as estate managers (phrontistai). He has heard that the year's crop are going at very low prices, and wheat specifically in their locality at 12 drachmas per artaba. Since Theodora wishes them to buy up as much wheat as they can, Dionysius instructs them to spend two talents for this purpose. The only condition he imposes is that what they obtain in this way be "good clean seed."</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto + Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>2 papyri ; 3.4 x 14 cm.; 7 x 13 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This papyrus, as we now have it, consists of two substantial fragments. Their measurements are given above. The narrower piece preserves on its lower half the left edge of the text and a small portion of the blank margin. The wider one presents intact the right side of the text, with a margin of ca. 2 cm. Above the text is a truly generous margin of 3.5 cm., but unfortunately the sheet has lost perhaps as much as half its length at the bottom. Also missing is a strip of papyrus extending the entire height of the sheet, luckily narrow but increasing in width toward the bottom. The consequent loss of text is for the most part not irreparable. The address on the verso, of which only one word survives, runs parallel with the fibers, not far below the present left edge of the smaller fragment, which however was not the original left edge of the papyrus (cf. above).</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-14</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto + Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The writer of this letter shows the effect of a good education in Greek. His hand is impressive, with letters well structured but not pedantically so. Each letter is separate and distinct, in reasonably close contact with its fellows but without ligatures. Although the alignment is far from perfect, the script is natably legible. As happens not infrequently in private letters, the text is addressed to two persons, but singular pronouns and verbs were used throughout in the first writing. Noteworthy is the care with which the writer went through the entire text entering interlinear corrections of all singulars to plurals.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0100" notAfter="0299">IInd/IIIrd century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>unknown</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Dionysios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hermes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dioskoros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Theodora</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>-</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"Dionysios to the most esteemed Hermes and Dioskoros, greeting. I learned from the inspector . . . that the majority of those who are being dunned for taxes do not respond because of the cheapness of the crops. For he was saying that wheat is going in your locality for twelwe drachmas. And when she heard this, the little Theodora wished you to get for her as much as you can. If then this is the situation, buy however many artabas of wheat as you can for two talents, but only good clean seed, and let me know with what measure you receive it. However much therefore you buy let me know so that I may enter the price in the account of daily expenses in your name . . .";(Verso): "To Hermes and Dioskoras, the estate-managers."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, ZPE 36, 77-81, 1979, Pl Ic -- SB XVI 12607 -- l. 6: {a soi}; l. 9 {e} umein; l. 10: {tai}?; l. 12: apolambane{is}te; l. 13: agorase{s}te. (TC)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:16:12607</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1969&amp;viewid=341R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/4/1/r/341r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1969&amp;viewid=341R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1969&amp;viewid=341R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/4/1/v/341v.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1969&amp;viewid=341V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1969&amp;viewid=341V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
