<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3694</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3694</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 29.4 x 33 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at left and right. Kollesis near the left edge. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-52</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 21 (ll. 839-891)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Charidemos, son of Petoraipis, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion, son of Kanis, grandson of Anchophis, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Tapsais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchorimphis, son of Petheus the younger, grandson of Anchorimphis, mother Apollonous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Theagenes, son of Theagenes, grandson of Ammonios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 176)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Harsiesis, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Akoution, son of Heron, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Tauris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 150)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptollas, son of Petsiris, grandson of Heras, mother Isidora (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 221)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, brother, with the same mother (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis, son of Panesneus, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Agathopous, slave of Thermouthis alias Tpaietis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 148)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Melanas, grandson of Petheus, mother Tamystha (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Chairemon, grandson of Horos, mother Stotoetis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Kastor, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 182)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabeinos, son of Petheus, grandson of Heraklas, mother Eserempis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraklas, son of Petheus, grandson of Heraklas, mother Eserempis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pammoneouis, son of Anchorimphis, grandson of Pammoneouis, mother Didymarion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois, son of Naaraus the younger, grandson of Theabennis, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Petheus, grandson of Aunes, mother Eserempis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Horos, grandson of Horos, mother Taharmothes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 251)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Thakialis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Komon, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Satabous, mother Tkollautis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 183)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois, son of Limnaios, grandson of Satabous, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabous, son of Petheus, grandson of Satabous, mother Tapetaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 227)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes, son of Patkonnis, grandson of Harobros, mother Ptolema (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabeinos, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Horos, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron, son of Petheus the younger, grandson of Anchorimphis, mother Apollonous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petoraipis, son of Hatres, grandson of Imouthes, mother Soeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Menches, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thases (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Sisois, grandson of Petsiris, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Heron, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Eserempis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymion, son of Petheus the older, grandson of Didymion, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 161)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anoubas, son of Horos, grandson of Anoubas, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 151)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Petaus, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 203)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Paouetis, son of Petheus, grandson of Phasis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Horos, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 223)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Menandros, grandson of Anchophis, mother Soeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nekpheraus, son of Euhemeros, grandson of Nekpheraus, mother Taonnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 190)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"[(Column) 21]:;Charidemos, son of Petoraipis, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;in total for the day, drachmas 64, obols 27;;(Mecheir) 13 likewise: ;Horion, son of Kanis, grandson of Anchophis, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Tapsais, obols 28;;Anchorimphis, son of Petheus the younger, grandson of Anchorimphis, mother Apollonous, drachmas 8;;Theagenes, son of Theagenes, grandson of Ammonios, drachmas 8;;Petheus, son of Harsiesis, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Akoution, son of Heron, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Tauris, guard tax, drachmas 8;;Ptollas, son of Petsiris, grandson of Heras, mother Isidora, drachmas 12;;Heras, brother, with the same mother, drachmas 4;;Pakysis, son of Panesneus, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Agathopous, slave of Thermouthis alias Tpaietis, drachmas 8;;Heras, son of Melanas, grandson of Petheus, mother Tamystha, drachmas 4;;Horos, son of Chairemon, grandson of Horos, mother Stotoetis, drachmas 8;;in total for the day drachmas 76, obols 28;;(Mecheir) 14:;Kastor, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Kastor, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 8;;Sabeinos, son of Petheus, grandson of Heraklas, mother Eserempis, drachmas, 8;;Heraklas, son of Petheus, grandson of Heraklas, mother Eserempis, drachmas 8;;Pammoneouis, son of Anchorimphis, grandson of Pammoneouis, mother Didymarion, drachmas 4;;Sisois, son of Naaraus the younger, grandson of Theabennis, mother Thaisas, obols 28;;Horos, son of Petheus, grandson of Aunes, mother Eserempis, drachmas 8;;Horos, son of Horos, grandson of Horos, mother Taharmothes, drachmas 8;;Pnepheros, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Thakialis, drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 48, obols 28;;(Mecheir) 15 likewise:;Komon, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Satabous, mother Tkollautis, drachmas 8;;Sisois, son of Limnaios, grandson of Satabous, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8;;Satabous, son of Petheus, grandson of Satabous, mother Tapetaus, drachmas 4;;Horos the younger, son of Hatres, grandson of Horos, mother Teraus, drachmas 4;;Mysthes, son of Patkonnis, grandson of Harobros, mother Ptolema, drachmas 8;;Sabeinos, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Horos, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Maron, son of Petheus the younger, grandson of Anchorimphis, mother Apollonous, drachmas 8;;Petoraipis, son of Hatres, grandson of Imouthes, mother Soeris, drachmas 4;;Onnophris, son of Menches, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thases, drachmas 8;;Onnophris, son of Petaus, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8;;Onnophris, son of Sisois, grandson of Petsiris, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Petheus, son of Heron, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Eserempis, drachmas 4;;Didymion, son of Petheus the older, grandson of Didymion, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 4;;Anoubas, son of Horos, grandson of Anoubas, mother Tepheros, drachmas 4;;Petheus, son of Petaus, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Segathis, drachmas 4;;Paouetis, son of Petheus, grandson of Phasis, mother Tapetheus, obols 28;;in total for the day drachmas 84, obols 28;;(Mecheir) 16 likewise:;Sambas, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Horos, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Aphrodisios, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetesouchos, obols 28;;Horos, son of Menandros, grandson of Anchophis, mother Soeris, obols 28;;Nekpheraus, son of Euhemeros, grandson of Nekpheraus, mother Taonnophris, drachmas 4, obols 26;;in total for the day drachmas 20, obols 26."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3694&amp;viewid=4171_21R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3694&amp;viewid=4171_21R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3694&amp;viewid=4171_21R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
