<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Collection of Abstracts of Contracts (Eiromenon)</title>
            <author>Unknown scribe</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2720</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2720</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;121</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11964 11965</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11964 11965</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 622</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Day by day register of abstracts of the contracts recorded at the record-office (grapheion) of Tebtynis during the four last months of the 2nd year of the Emperor Claudius. - Col. II, abstract 2 records a (demotic) alimentary contract, registered on May 11, 42 A.D. (see also Verso, col. II, 6); the so-called alimentary contract is in reality a property settlement entered into by persons already united in marriage (here the husband's parents with the wife), fixing the sum which the husband was obliged to pay to his wife in case of his divorcing her and describing the real properties which would become sureties for the payment of this sum</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this papyrus roll, its content has been divided in the present database into several cards: one for each column of the Verso (register of contracts), one for each abstract on the Recto (collection of abstracts of contracts, or eiromenon).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso: list of contracts (index of the Recto)</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis; see also note</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; Total size of the roll: 2.39 m x 29 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Large roll containing writing on both sides; broken off at the left of the Recto</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto, col. II, abstract 2: 11</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. II, abstract 2</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The four columns of the Recto have an unusual widh of about 70 cm. - The writing is a small upright cursive, different from the Verso. (Boak)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0042">(After) August 28, 42 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Dionysios, son of Petsiris and Thaesis, husband of Thenamounis daughter of Marres</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thechnous daughter of Maron</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) sons of Thasis, daughter of Herakles (= Heraklides?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psenosiris son of Dionysios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraklides son of Papos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tamaron daughter of Maron</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) sons of Thasis, daughter of Heraklides (= Herakles?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Akousilaos son of Apollonios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orseus son of Petepmoueis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Arabakis (see Geographica)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraklas laxos (former owner)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon (son of Marres and Thenamounis), brother of Thenamounis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Leontiskos (see Geographica)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petsiris son of Phamounis and Taopis, husband of Thaesis daughter of Psosneus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thaesis daughter of Psosneus and Esermipis, wife of Petsiris son of Phamounis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thenamounis daughter of Marres and Thenamounis, wife of Dionysios son of Petsiris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Pakebkis (see P.Mich. II, p. 224)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Theogonis; Tali, Talei; legomene Arabakios epaulis; Leontiskou legomenos kleros</term>
               <term>Theogonis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Archives--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Dowry--Egypt--Tebtynis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Antenuptial contracts--Egypt--Talei (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Inheritance and succession--Egypt--Theogonis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Land tenure--Egypt--Theogonis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Housing--Egypt--Talei (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Stone-cutters--Egypt--Talei (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Jewelry--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Notaries--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Theogonis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Bronze implements--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Clothing and dress--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Talei (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Chests--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tin--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Alimentary contract for money of the value of 21 gold pieces, and the contract of surrender and preliminary sale; and we affirm that we have bequeathed to our aforesaid son Dionysios for immediate possession after our death the allotment of catoecic land which belongs to me in the neighborhood of Theogonis, 8 arourai, and besides these 3/4 of an aroura of land with a further claim on it, making altogether eight arourai and three-fourths, or however many there may be, in four parcels; in the 1st parcel 3 arourai of the arourai inherited from my father, of which the neighboring plots are: on the south the allotment of Psenosiris, on the north the allotment of Patynis his brother, on the west revenue estates, on the east a public field; and in the second parcel, which is 2 3/4 arourai, of which the neighbors are: on the south the allotment of Thechnous, daughter of Maron, on the north the allotment of the sons of Thasis, daughter of Herakles, on the west the allotment of Psenosiris, son of Dionysios, on the east the allotment of Heraklides, son of Papos; and of the 3rd parcel, which is of 1 aroura, on the south is the allotment of Tamaron, daughter of Maron, on the north the allotment of the sons of Thasis, daughter of Heraklides, on the west the allotment of Akousilaos, son of Apollonios, on the east the allotment of Psenosiris, son of Dionysios; and in the fourth parcel the remaining 2 arourai, of which the neighbors are: on the south revenue estates, on the north a public estate, on the west the allotment of Orseus, son of Petepmoueis, on the east the allotment of Psenosiris, son of Dionysios; and from what belongs to me in Talei, of the same section, a new house of two stories inherited from my father, in which are a cellar and a court on the south side; and in the same Talei of another parcel a half-share of one and a half bikoi common and undivided in the so-called square of Arabakis; and likewise to the same son Dionysios in Talei in another parcel from vacant plots which belong to me two bikoi from four bikoi common and undivided formerly belonging to Heraklas, the stone-cutter; and likewise to the same Dionysios also up to the half-share of whatever I may leave of cattle of all sorts and movables and household furnishings and all that is owing to me; and of whatever property I may acquire from now on, likewise to the same son Dionysios in every possible way up to the half-share.;And the dowry given is 200 drachmai of silver,a nd as parapherna without evaluation a golden ear-ring of 4 quarters and a golden lunette of 2 quarters and a gold ring of 1 1/2 quarters and a silver ring of a weight of 2 drachmai of uncoined metal and a pair of silver armlets of a weight of 19 drachmai of uncoined metal and 2 silver bracelets &lt;or: one silver bracelet&gt; of a weight of 8 drachmai of uncoined metal and 2 bronze bowls of a weight of 7 minai amd 2 bronze water jars and women's utensils of tin of a weight of 5 minai and a wooden chest(?) and 2 women's robes,one dyed and the other one white, and 4 cloaks of various colors.;And in gift without evaluation from the coming year the land in her possession with a further claim on it &lt;or: with her retaining her rights on it&gt;, one aroura from two arourai, or however many there may be, held common and undivided in one parcel with her brother Chairemon at Tali in the so-called allotment of Leontiskos.;With contract, (I,) Petsiris, son of Phamounis, his &lt;read: my&gt; mother being Taopis, about 55 years old, with a scar on the right shin, and my wife Thaesis, daughter of Psosneus, her mother being Esermipis, about 50 years old, with a scar on the forehead on the right side below the hair, make with Thenamounis, daughter of Marres, her mother being Thenamounis, about 28 years old, with a scar on the right knee, who is the wife of their &lt;read: our&gt; son Dionysios.;Signatory: Apollonios, about 40 years old, with a scar on the wrist of the right hand, and for the other party, Onnophris, son of Pakebkis, about 32 years old, with a scar on the right knee.;The rest in conformity.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, JEA 12, 100-109, 1926 -- SB III 7260, col. IIb -- BL II, 132 (l. 10-11) Boak AER, PMich II, 121, Recto, col. II, ii, 1933, Pl. II -- BL VI, 80 (l. 1 and 9); BL VII, 107 (l. 8)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:2:121</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2720&amp;viewid=622R_2.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/2/622R_2.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2720&amp;viewid=622R_2.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2720&amp;viewid=622R_2.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/3/622R_3.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2720&amp;viewid=622R_3.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2720&amp;viewid=622R_3.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
