<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3632</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3632</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.224</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 29.7 x 29.5 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at all sides. 2 kolleseis. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-37</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 3 (ll. 79-116)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis, son of Onnophris, grandson of Satabous, mother Soeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 106)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras alias Aphrodisios, son of Heras, grandson of Petheus, mother Apolonarion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nemesas, slave of Apollonous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 190)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor, son of Petheus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Herakleia (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phasis, son of Tesenouphis, grandson of Harphaesis, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 246)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron, son of Satabous, grandson of Maron, mother Tkonnous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menches, brother, of the same mother (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Tapsas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchoryphis, son of Petheus the younger, grandson of Anchoryphis, mother Apollonous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Petheus, son of Heras, mother Didymarion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron, son of Maron, grandson of Petoraipis, mother Herois (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Leonides, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 184)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Levas, son of Petheus, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Tapapeis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 184)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dioskoros, son of Petheus, grandson of Kollouthos, mother Taorsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petermouthis, son of Kastor, grandson of Heraklas, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides, son of Esouris, grandson of Kollouthos, mother Taonnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Perigenes, son of Zoilos, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Herakles, mother Tkonnous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaseis, son of Pakysis, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tanebkenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 246)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ischyras, son of Panesneus, grandson of Ischyras, mother Tamysthas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 179)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mystharion, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 188)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisis, son of Sisois, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Pakysis, grandson of Petheus, mother Tamaron (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Esouris, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Apynchis, grandson of Aunes, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Onnophris, grandson of Onnophris, mother Sopas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kopaneus, son of Polyntion, grandson of Kopaneus, mother Politta (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 184)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymos, son of Petheus, grandson of Heraklas, mother Eserempis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 161)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Polis, son of Petheus, grandson of Keras, mother Herais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Petheus, grandson of Teos, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>" Column 3;Pakysis, son of Onnophris, grandson of Satabous, 4drachmas,;the total for the day, 112 drachmas;;The 14th of the same (month);  ;Heras alias Aphrodisios, son of Heras, grandson of Petheus, mother Apolonarion, 12drachmas;;Nemesas, slave of Apollonous, 12 drachmas;;Kastor, son of Petheus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Herakleia, 8 drachmas, 8 obols;;The same12th year, 8 bronze drachmas,  the remainder is the administrator fee;;Phasis, son of Tesenouphis, grandson of Harphaesis, mother Thaesis, 4 drachmas;;Onnophris, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis, 4 drachmas;;Maron, son of Satabous, grandson of Maron, mother Tkonnous, 4 drachmas;;Menches, brother, of the same mother, 4 drachmas;;Phanomgeus, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Tapsas, 8 drachmas;;Anchoryphis, son of Petheus the younger, grandson of Anchoryphis, mother Apollonous, 12 drachmas;;Heras, son of Petheus, son of Heras, mother Didymarion, 4 drachmas;;Maron, son of Maron, grandson of Petoraipis, mother Herois, 12 drachmas;;Leonides, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Heras, 8 drachmas;;Levas, son of Petheus, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Tapapeis, 8 drachmas;;Dioskoros, son of Petheus, grandson of Kollouthos, mother Taorsenouphis, 8 drachmas;;Petermouthis, son of Kastor, grandson of Heraklas, mother Tasoucharion, 16 drachmas;;The total for the day, 136 drachmas of which for the12th year 8 drachmas, 20 obols;;The 15th of the same (month);;Herakleides, son of Esouris, grandson of Kollouthos, mother Taonnophris, 20 drachmas;;The same12th year, the remainder is the administrator fee;;Perigenes, son of Zoilos, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Sambathion, 4 drachmas;;Sisois, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Herakles, mother Tkonnous, 8 drachmas;;The12th year: Phaseis, son of Pakysis, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tanebkenis, 8 bronze drachmas;;Ischyras, son of Panesneus, grandson of Ischyras, mother Tamysthas, 8 drachmas;;Mystharion, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Thaesis, 8 drachmas;;Aphrodisis, son of Sisois, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaisas, 8 drachmas, 27 obols;;Petheus, son of Pakysis, grandson of Petheus, mother Tamaron, 8 drachmas;;Ptolemaios, son of Esouris, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis, 8 drachmas;;Ptolemaios, son of Apynchis, grandson of Aunes, mother Tapetheus, 16 drachmas;;Heras, son of Onnophris, grandson of Onnophris, mother Sopas, 4 drachmas;;Kopaneus, son of Polyntion, grandson of Kopaneus, mother Politta, 16 drachmas;;Didymos, son of Petheus, grandson of Heraklas, mother Eserempis, 4 drachmas;;Polis, son of Petheus, grandson of Keras, mother Herais, 8 drachmas;;Onnophris, son of Petheus, grandson of Teos, mother Segathis, 8 drachmas."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3632&amp;viewid=4171_3R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3632&amp;viewid=4171_3R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3632&amp;viewid=4171_3R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
