<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3304</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3304</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer paying the poll-tax is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>6 papyri ; col. 163-164: *** cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 164 damaged by many tears and holes, but with little text missing; papyrus torn or cut off on the right of col. 164, with several of the next columns missing (see columns P.Mich. IV/2, 358B, with remnants of two columns, which could have been columns 168-169)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 164: 27 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 164 (l. 2963-2989)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus son of Petheus and Taseus grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymos son of Satabous and Tanomgeus grandson of Pakysis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Pnepheros and Tapetheus grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ninis son of Asklas and Tabous grandson of Ninis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor neoteros son of Achillas and Aphrodous grandson of Kastor (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marcus Longinus Valerianus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Didymos and Thaesis grandson of Maron (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sokmenis son of Apynchis and Thatres grandson of Sambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 230)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Orsenouphis and Anthia grandson of Herieus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psenesis son of Petesouchos and Heras grandson of Psenessi (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Petheus and Eserempis grandson of Aunes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tesenouphis son of Aiaus and Thases grandson of Orsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 241)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Heron and Tasoucharion grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Akousilaos and Thatres grandson of Pasoknopaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Apollonios and Thermouthis grandson of Harpagathes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Pnepheros and Thaesis grandson of Phanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Protarchos son of Leonides and Herois (Herais) grandson of Anchophis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 215)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabous son of Dioskoros and Taorion (Tahorion) grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 226)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptollis son of Akousilaos and Aphrodous grandson of Ptollis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 221)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Karanis (Extinct city)--Defenses.</term>
               <term>Real property tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Women--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Guards troops--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 164;;(Mesore 20, continued);Petaus, son of Petheus and Taseus, grandson of Pnepheros, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Didymos, son of Satabous and Tanomgeus, grandson of Pakysis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Pnepheros, son of Pnepheros and Tapetheus, grandson of Pnepheros, for ch(--): 4 drachmai, (and the) remainder of the ch(--);Ninis, son of Asklas and Tabous, grandson of Ninis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Kastor the younger, son of Achillas and Aphrodous, grandson of Kastor: 8 drachmai;Marcus Longinus Valerianus - (through the) sister-in-law of Hieronikes - for garden land of year 13: for apomoira, 10 drachmai 2 1/2 obols; for olive (transportation), 1 drachme 2 1/2 obols; for naubion, 1 drachme 2 chalkoi; for supplements, 2 drachmai 3 1/2 obols 2 chalkoi; for eparourion, 6 drachmai 5 1/2 obols; for supplements, 3 1/2 obols; for kollybos, 2 1/2 obols. Total: 23 drachmai 2 1/2 obols.;(And) for the naubion of the catoeci, for year 14: 5 1/2 obols 2 chalkoi; for supplements: 1/2 obol 2 chalkoi; for kollybos: 2 chalkoi. Total: 1 drachme 1/2 obol 2 chalkoi. (In left margin:) 24 drachmai 10 obols.);Petheus, son of Didymos and Thaesis, grandson of Maron, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Sokmenis, son of Apynchis and Thatres, grandson of Sambas: 8 drachmai;Ptolemaios, son of Orsenouphis and Anthia, grandson of Herieus, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Psenesis, son of Petesouchos and Heras, grandson of Psenesis: 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(--): 28 obols;Horos, son of Petheus and Eserempis, grandson of Aunes, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Tesenouphis, son of Aiaus and Thases, grandson of Orsenouphis: 8 drachmai;Ptolemaios, son of Heron and Tasoucharion, grandson of Horos, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Total for the day: 136 drachmai 27 obols.;;On the 21st, similarly:;Pnepheros, son of Akousilaos and Thatres, grandson of Pasoknopaios, for guards: 5 drachmai; (and) for guard towers: 1 drachme. Total: 6 drachmai.;Sarapion, son of Apollonios and Thermouthis, grandson of Harpagathes, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Onnophris, son of Pnepheros and Thaesis, grandson of Phanomgeus, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Protarchos, son of Leonides and Herois, grandson of Anchophis: 4 drachmai [. .] obols;Satabous, son of Dioskoros and Taorion, grandson of Satabous, for ch(--): [- - -];Onnophris, son of Petaus and Thaesis, grandson of Pnepheros, for ch(--): [- - -];Ptollis, son of Akousilaos and Aphrodous, grandson of Ptollis, [for ch(--): - - -]</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 164 (l. 2963-2989), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3304&amp;viewid=4172_41RO.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/1/r/o/4172_41ro.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3304&amp;viewid=4172_41RO.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3304&amp;viewid=4172_41RO.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
