<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3827</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3827</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 33.8 x 29.6 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at the right and the left. Kollesis near the right edge of the document. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-36</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 63 (ll. 2537-2573)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Serenos, son of Sokrates, grandson of Pakysis, mother Satornilaine (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hermes, slave of Saturnilus Nigerinus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kerdon, slave of Maronis, daughter of Areios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 182)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Agathopous, another slave of the woman (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 148)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion alias Sokrates, son of Achillas, grandson of Hatres, mother Tamarron (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Melas, son of Serenos, soldier (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 188)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptollas, son of Sabeinos, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Vettia (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 221)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kames, son of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kames , son of Ouamaes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tamarres, daughter of Apynchis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 233)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tamarron, daughter of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 233)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Zoidous, daughter of Mysthes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 165)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Peteesis, son of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Isidoros, son of Koulax (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 179)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Valerius alias Heron, son of Dioskoros, grandson of Mysthes, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 195)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Neilammon alias Isidoros, his son, mother Tapasion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 190)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dioskoros, son of Dioskoros, grandson of Chairemon, mother Tapasion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabeinos, son of Petheus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Herakleia (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios, son of Sisois, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 63:;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 37 obols 3, surcharges drachmas 2 obols 2 chalki 2, in total drachmas 39 obols 5 chalki 2;;naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year drachma 1, surcharges obol 0.5 chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachma 1 obol 1.;Serenos, son of Sokrates, grandson of Pakysis, mother Satornilaine, drachmas 8;;Hermes, slave of Saturnilus Nigerinus, drachmas 12;;Kerdon, slave of Maronis, daughter of Areios, drachmas 12;;Agathopous, another slave of the same woman, drachmas 12;;Sarapion alias Sokrates, son of Achillas, grandson of Hatres, mother Tamarron, drachmas 12;;Melas, son of Serenos, soldier (son of Sokrates, son of Pakysis);naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year drachmas 4, surcharges obols 2.5, kollybos obol 0.5, in total drachmas 4 obols 3;;(in left margin: drachmas 12 obols 25) tax on land plots in release likewise drachma 1  obols 2.5,  surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachma 1 obols 4.5;;grammateia drachmas 4 obol 0.5, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 4 obols 2 chalki 2;;dovecote tax for the 13th year drachmas 3, surcharges obol 1 chalki 2, in total drachmas 3 obol 1 chalki 2;;Ptollas, son of Sabeinos, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Vettia, drachmas 16;;Kames, son of Petheus (Kames , son of Ouamaes);;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 4 obols 2 chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives obols 4, naubion obols 2.5 chalki 2, surcharges drachma 1 obol 0.5 chalki 2;;(in left margin: drachmas 40)eparourion drachmas 2 obols 3.5, surcharges obol 1.5, kollybos drachmas 9 obols 3.5 chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 10 obols 5.5, surcharges obols 4 chalki 2, in total drachmas 11 obols 3.5 chalki 2;;and Tamarres, daughter of Apynchis;;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira obols 5, naubion obol 0.5, surcharges obol 1 chalki 2;;eparourion obols 3.5, surcharges obol 0.5, kollybos 0.5, in total drachmas 1 obols 5 chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 2 obol 0.5, surcharges obol 1, in total drachmas 2 obol 1.5;;and Tamarron, daughter of Onnophris, formerly Zoidous, daughter of Mysthes;;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 2 obols 3, tax on the produce of olives obols 2 chalki 2, naubion obol 1.5, surcharges obols 3.5 chalki 2;;eparourion drachma 1 obols 4, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 5 obols 4 chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 6 obol 1.5, surcharges obols 2.5, in total drachmas 6 obols 4;;in total for the day drachmas 304 obols 2.;(Pachon) 15 likewise:;Peteesis, daughter of Satabous through the agency of (Isidoros, son of Koulax);;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 7 obols 3, tax on the produce of olives drachma 1 obol 0.5, naubion obols 4.5, surcharges drachma 1 obols 5 chalki 2;;(in left margin: drachmas 36 obols 18) eparourion drachmas 5, surcharges obols 2 chalki 2, kollybos obol 1.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 16 obols 5 chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 18 obols 4.5, surcharges drachma 1 obol 1 chalki 2, in total drachmas 19 obols 5.5 chalki 2;;naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year obols 2 chalki 2, surcharges chalki 2, kollybos obols 2.5 chalki 2;;Valerius alias Heron, son of Dioskoros, grandson of Mysthes, mother Tepheros, drachmas 20;;Neilammon alias Isidoros, his son, mother Tapasion, drachmas 20;;Dioskoros, son of Dioskoros, grandson of Chairemon, mother Tapasion, drachmas 20;;Sabeinos, son of Petheus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Herakleia, drachmas 8 copper drachmas 4;;Aphrodisios, son of Sisois, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaisas drachmas 12 copper drachmas 4."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3827&amp;viewid=4171_63R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3827&amp;viewid=4171_63R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3827&amp;viewid=4171_63R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
