<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Register of Contracts Prepared at the Grapheion</title>
            <author>Kronion, son of Apion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3235</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3235</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.238</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;238</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;238</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12078 78518</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12078 78518</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 968</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Quadrimestrial financial register (anagraphe) of all the contracts drawn up day by day in the record-office (grapheion) of Tebtynis during the first four months of the 4th year of the Emperor Claudius (Aug. 29-Dec. 26, 46 A.D.); the writing fee (grammatikon) charged for the preparation of each document is indicated at the end of each line. - Col. II records the contracts drawn up between Sept. 22-Oct. 2, 46 A.D.; most entries are duplicated in another register of the same year (P.Mich. II, 124 verso, partly unpublished)</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this papyrus, its content has been divided in the present database into several cards, one for each column.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso bears only a brief memorandum</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 28 x 81 cm (total size)</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Complete</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. II - 56</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. II</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Hand of Kronion, son of Apion</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0046">(After) December 26, 46 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Papontos (&amp; unnamed wife)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Haryotes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tephersos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Onnophris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Papnebtynis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herodes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sotas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mieus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nepheros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Onnophris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Siaiepis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tapetsoykis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Mieus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Herodes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thenpatynis, wife of Panomieus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Panomieus, husband of Thenpatynis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Lysimachos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos (&amp; unnamed wife) (see also P.Mich. II, 124, verso, col. I, l. 12)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psosneus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marepsemis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psyphis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Herakles</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kronion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orseus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Soterichos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tamysthas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Kronion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Herakles (&amp; unnamed wife)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harmiysis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pollous</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Cheos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Kronion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petemennophris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Galates</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Polemon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Galates</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Polykrates</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hermas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Herakles</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Kronion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Didymos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Galates</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Papontos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Kronion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Siphon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Tephersos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Onnophris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Lysimachos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Agelas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Papnebtynis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Areios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apsemis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Mieus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Marepsemis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marsisouchos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thaubastios (Thaubastis) (see also P.Mich. II, 124, verso, col. I, l. 13)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thasos (see also P.Mich. II, 124, verso, col. I, l. 13)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Psyphis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Patynis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Epitynchanon (see also P.Mich. II, 124, verso, col. I, l. 10)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Papnebtynis (see also P.Mich. II, 124, verso, col. I, l. 10)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Apollonios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Galates (&amp; unnamed wife)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Galatiaine</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraklea</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon (see also P.Mich. II, 124, verso, col. I, l. 14)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymos (see also P.Mich. II, 124, verso, col. I, l. 14)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Orseus (see also P.Mich. II, 124, verso, col. I, l. 15)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Haryotes (see also P.Mich. II, 124, verso, col. I, l. 15)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tamieus (see also P.Mich. II, 124, verso, col. I, l. 17)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Kronion (see also P.Mich. II, 124, verso, col. I, l. 17)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Herakles (P.Mich. II, 124, verso, col. I, l. 18 has Phemnasis)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Maron (see also P.Mich. II, 124, verso, col. I, l. 18)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Herakles (&amp; unnamed wife) (see also P.Mich. II, 124, verso, col. I, l. 20)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Apollonios (see also P.Mich. II, 124, verso, col. I, l. 20)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herodes (see also P.Mich. II, 124, verso, col. I, l. 22)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos (see also P.Mich. II, 124, verso, col. I, l. 22)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Lysimachos (see also P.Mich. II, 124, verso, col. I, l. 25)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psentamieus (see also P.Mich. II, 124, verso, col. I, l. 25)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Herakles (see also P.Mich. II, 124, verso, col. I, l. 21)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, thesaurophylax (see also P.Mich. II, p. 224)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Orseus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pouoris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Mieus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mieus son of Phomsais (Phomsais) (see also P.Mich. V, 260)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Marsisouchos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Didymos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Tephersos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(another?) Lysimachos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tmarsis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Teues</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nestnephis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Archives--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city);vCatalogs.</term>
               <term>Contracts--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city);vCatalogs.</term>
               <term>Notaries--Fees--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Loans--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Deposits (Law)--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Receipts (Acknowledgments)--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Leases--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Sebastos 25, continued).;Loan of 68 silver drachmai, (made) by Herakles to Papontos and his wife. (Fee:) 12 obols.;On the 26th. Acknowledgment of deposit of 100 silver drachmai and 6 1/2 artabai of wheat, (made) by Onnophris to Haryotes. (Fee:) 3 drachmai.;Lease of 2 arourai, (made) by Tephersos and another to Onnophris. (Fee:) 8 obols.;Lease of 3 arourai, (made) by Papnebtynis to Herodes. (Fee:) 7 obols.;Agreement of obligation to remain in service (paramone) for the sum of 60 drachmai, (made) by Papontos and his wife to Herakles. (Fee:) 10 obols.;Agreement of lease, by way of payment in advance, of pasture lands and others, (made) by Sotas to Mieus. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Acknowledgment of deposit of 80 silver drachmai, 2 artabai of wheat and 6 artabai of barley, (made) by Nepheros to Onnophris. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Agreement to furnish lodging for the sum of 156 silver drachmai, (made) by Siaiepis to Tapetsoykis. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Agreement (of - - -) of 8 1/2 artabai of barley, (made) by Mieus to Herodes. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Agreement to nurse a slave child, (made) by Thenpatynis to Didymos, (and),;on the 28th, loan of 100 silver drachmai, (made) by Didymos to Panomieus and his wife. (Fee) for both (documents): 18 obols.;Loan of 28 silver drachmai, (made) by Lysimachos to Petesouchos and his wife. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Acknowledgment of deposit of 84 silver drachmai, (made) by Orsenouphis to Psosneus. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Concession of a pastophoros's cell, (made) by Marepsemis to Psyphis. (Fee:) 3 silver drachmai.;Lease of 7 3/4 arourai, (made) by Herakles to Kronion. (Fee:) 9 obols.;Acknowledgment of deposit of 60 silver drachmai and 3 artabai of wheat, (made) by Orseus to Soterichos. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Agreement of obligation to remain in service (paramone) for the sum of 20 drachmai, (made) by Tamysthas to Kronion. (Fee:) 7 obols.;Acknowledgment of deposit of 212 silver drachmai and 6 1/2 artabai of wheat, (made) by Herakles and his wife to Apollonios. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Agreement of obligation to remain in service (paramone) for the sum of 28 drachmai, (made) by Harmiysis to Didymos. (Fee:) 7 obols.;On the 29th. Lease of 8 &lt;arourai&gt; of an allotment, (made) by Herakleides to Pollous and another. (Fee:) 10 obols.;Acknowledgment of deposit of 120 silver drachmai and 15 artabai of barley, (made) by Cheos to Kronion. (Fee:) 4 drachmai.;Acknowledgment of deposit of 580 silver drachmai, (made) by Petemennophris and another to Galates. (Fee:) 8 drachmai.;On the 30th. Lease of right to sell a crop, (made) by Herodes to Sambathion. (Fee:) 9 obols.;Agreement of lease concerning a garden, (made) by Polemon and others to Galates. (Fee:) 19 obols.;Agreement (of - - -) of a reed mat with a garment with a double border(?), (made) by Polykrates to Hermas and another. (Fee:) 5 obols.;Acknowledgment of deposit of 56 silver drachmai, (made) by Herakles to Kronion. (Fee:) 1 drachma 4 obols.;Agreement of lease, by way of payment in advance of a ten-arourai estate, (made) by Didymos to Galates. He owes the fee.;Loan of 100 silver drachmai, (made) by Apolonios to Papontos and another. (Fee:) 18 obols.;Acknowledgment of receipt of the half part of a loan, (made) by Kronion to Siphon. (Fee:) 11 obols.;Acknowledgment of deposit of 40 silver drachmai and 3 artabai fo wheat, (made) by Tephersos to Onnophris. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Acknowledgment of deposit of 20 silver drachmai and 4 artabai of wheat, (made) by Posidonios to Didymos. (Fee:) 8 obols.;Loan of 128 silver drachmai, (made) by Lysimachos to Agelas and another. (Fee:) 3 drachmai.;Agreement to furnish lodging for the sum of 100 silver drachmai, (made) by Papnebtynis and another to Areios. (Fee:) 20 obols.;Agreement of lease of 7 arourai, (made) by Apsemis to Mieus. (Fee:) 30 obols, of which he owes 4 obols.;Concession of a pastophoros's cell, (made) by Marepsemis to Marsisouchos. (Fee:) 4 silver drachmai.;Acknowledgment of receipt of 120 silver drachmai, (made) by Thaubastis to Thasos and another. (Fee:) 3 drachmai.;Lease of 3 arourai of fodder, (made) by Psyphis to Patynis and another. (Fee:) 5 obols.;Lease of 6 arourai, (made) by Epitynchanon to Papnebtynis. (Fee:) 11 obols.;Agreement (concerning) a contract of marriage, (made) by Apollonios and another to Galates and his wife. (Fee:) 40 drachmai.;Agreement of release of claims, (made) by Galatiaine to her parents. She owes the scribe's fee.;Contract (for a dowry?) of 600 silver drachmai), (made) by Maron to Heraklea and another. (Fee:) 8 drachmai.;On Phaophi 2. Acknowledgment of deposit of 2,040 drachmai, (made) by Chairemon and another to Didymos. (Fee:) 8 drachmai.;Agreement of lease of 6 arourai of fodder, (made) by Orseus to Haryotes. (Fee:) 7 obols.;Agreement of release of claims, (made) by Tamieus to Kronion and another. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Agreement of lease of 3 1/4 arourai of fodder, (made) by Herakles to Maron. He owes the scribe's fee.;On the 3rd. Acknowledgment of deposit of 100 drachmai and 5 artabai of wheat, (made) by Herakles and his wife to Apollonios. (Fee:) 2 drachmai.;Lease of 2 arourai, (made) by Herodes and another to Petesouchos. (Fee:) 12 obols.;On the 4th. Agreement (of - - -) of 12 artabai of wheat, (made) by Lysimachos to Psentamieus. (Fee:) 10 obols.;Agreement of lease, by way of payment in advance, of 1 aroura, (made) by Herakles to Onnophris the granary guard. He owes the scribe's fee.;Agreement of sale of 2 cattle, (made) by Orseus to Pouoris. (Fee:) 10 obols.;Lease of partnership in farming, (made) by Mieus and another to Mieus son of Phomsaeis. He owes the scribe's fee.;On the 5th. Agreement of obligation to remain in service (paramone) for the sum of 24 drachmai, (made) by Marsisouchos and another to Didymos. (Fee:) 8 obols.;Acknowledgment of deposit of 60 drachmai and 4 artabai of wheat, (made) by Tephersos and his wife to Lysimachos.;Agreement to furnish lodging for the sum of 24 silver drachmai, (made) by Tmarsis to Teues. (Fee:) 6 obols.;Agreement (of - - -) of 12 artabai of wheat, (made) by Nestnephis and another to Heron. (Fee:) 10 obols.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich V, 238, col. II, 1944 -- BL III, 115 (l. 77); BL VII, 111 (bibliography); BL VIII, 213 (bibliography). - L. 68 and 105: read 60 drachmai, instead of 7 drachmai. (PH)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:238</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3235&amp;viewid=968R_1.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/1/968R_1.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3235&amp;viewid=968R_1.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3235&amp;viewid=968R_1.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/2/968R_2.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3235&amp;viewid=968R_2.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3235&amp;viewid=968R_2.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/3/968R_3.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3235&amp;viewid=968R_3.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3235&amp;viewid=968R_3.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/V/_/1/968V_1.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3235&amp;viewid=968V_1.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3235&amp;viewid=968V_1.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/V/_/2/968V_2.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3235&amp;viewid=968V_2.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3235&amp;viewid=968V_2.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/V/_/3/968V_3.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3235&amp;viewid=968V_3.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3235&amp;viewid=968V_3.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
