<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of 1/3 of a Residence</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2519</idno>
            <idno type="controlno">(MiU)2519</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invno">P.Mich.inv. 5634</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>The opening; Two sisters; Buying the right in the residence; The share of the heir; boundaries; District of the Fayy»¶m; Sale according to the stipulation of Islam and its contract; Reading in Arabic and explain in foreign language; Witnesses; Date.</summary>
                  <msItem>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is Blank</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="ar-Arab">Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItem>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>Par ; 23.8 x 36.1 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The parchment is yellow, written on the hair side. The shape of the parchment is irregular, being much narrower (19 cm) at the bottom. The text is written to conform to the shape of the parchment with the ends of lines 19 and 20. No text has been lost. There is no writing on the Verso. (MA)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-20</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0962">20 April 962 A. D</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Probably Tut»¶n, Fayy»¶m</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Hurm√´da daughter of Babastalas son of Han»¶fah</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Fan»¶ra daughter of Babastalas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">M»¶nah the deaf</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">M»¶s»Ì the father of Sut»Ìr</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Damiyani son of T»Ìn»¶</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">√¨Umar son of M»¶s»Ì</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">√¨Al√´ son of Jabrayal</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">√¨Umar [son of  ]</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="ar-Arab">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Tut»¶n in the District of the Fayy»¶m</term>
               <term>
                  <rs type="genre_form">Documentary</rs>
               </term>
               <term>
                  <rs type="genre_form">Parchment</rs>
               </term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>In the name of Allah the Merciful, the Compassionate.;This is what Hurm√´da daughter of Babastalas son of Han»¶fah bought from her sister, Fan»¶ra daughter of Babastalas, from among;The residents of Tut»¶n in the District of the Fayy»¶m. She bought from her right in the residence from their father, and that is eight p[ar]ts;;of four and twenty parts, with its boundaries, and below it and above it, and inside and outside of it.;Its southern [bounda]ry is the residence of the heirs of M»¶nah the Deaf. Its northern boundary is the residence of M»¶s»Ì the father of Sut»Ìr. Its eastern boundary is the residence of the heirs of Damiyani;;son of T»Ìn»¶. Its western boundary is the residence of the heirs of the father of al-@usayn. She bought that from her for three dinars unadulterated, minted;;gold of full, new weight. Fan»¶ra daughter of Babastalas has taken (lit, Ç«£with the handsÇ«•) the price without any remainder and in full. And she has re[moved herself] fr[om] her [share];;in that residence described in this document. And she delivered that to Hurm√´da daughter;of Babastalas. She took it, and she took possession of it, and she took ownership of it and that became her property, possessed out of her right of possession. If she wishes;;she may sell, and if she wishes she may build, and if she wishes she may reside. There is not belonging to Fan»¶ra daughter of Babastalas in;;that residence after this recording any claim and no demand, not for any cause, not for any reason.;She sold that residence according to the stipulation of the sale of Islam and its contract. And whatever there may be by way of a claim for an attachment to the property, or should [someone come adventitiously];Because of a loan, the execution of that and the clearance of that will be the obligation of Fan»¶ra daughter of Babastalas for the worth to which it amounts, out of her clear property.;Testimony was given to the a&lt;ffirmation&gt; of Fan»¶ra daughter of Babastalas son of Han»¶fah as to all that is in this document, after it was read;;to her in Arabic and explained to her in the foreign language, she being of sound mind and body and her action legal, being willing,;without being averse, not being compelled, not being treated unjustly, she being the petitioner and the one Safar;desiring. And that is in Muharram of the year;fifty and three hundred. (2nd hand) √¨Umar son of M»¶s»Ì witnessed their testimony with respect to their affirmation;                  and its date is Safar.;in its entirety (on its date and he wrote) with his hand.;(3rd hand) Isma√¨√´l son of √¨Abd-Q»Ìhir testified respecting the affirmation of Fan»¶ra daughter of Babastalas to all (that which) is in this document, and he wrote his testimony on its date.;(4th hand) (Al-Munas»Ì son of Maqarr) bore witness to all that is in this document and he and he wrote his testimony with his on hand;                  al-[       ] their testimony;on the date of their [affir]mation. (5th hand) And wrote on her behalf;(6th hand) √¨Al√´ son of Jabrayal bore witness to all that which ;          √¨Umar [son of  ];is in this document and he wrote with his hand.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Frantz-Murphy G, JNES 40, 207-212, 1981, Plate</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2519&amp;viewid=5634R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2519&amp;viewid=5634R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2519&amp;viewid=5634R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>