<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of Parts of a House</title>
            <author>Maron, son of Hermas</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1294</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1294</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.10.583</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;10;583</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;10;583</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12270</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12270</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 101</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract by which Maron, son of Hermas, sells to Hermas, son of Ptolemaios, fourth ninths of an old house and courtyard in Bacchias (this house is mentioned in several pieces of the archive)</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">One small fragment, not belonging to this papyrus, was found and housed under the same inventory number.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso: some written fragments were used as patches</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Horos and Tapekysis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>7 papyri ; 34.5 x 26.8 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">slightly broken off on the right side; damaged along the folds. Bears ancient patches on the Verso.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">37</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0078">August 26, 78 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Bacchias, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Vespasian, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron son of Hermas grandson of Maron (see also P.Mich. XII, 635)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Katoites son of Menches (&amp; unnamed metochoi) (see P.Mich. X, p. 20)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Katoites grandson of Belles (&amp; unnamed brothers) (see P.Mich. X, p. 20</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">XI, p. 15)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed official) ho pros to grapheio of Bacchias and Hephaistias</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Bacchias, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Bacchias, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome; Hephaistias</term>
               <term>House Ownership</term>
               <term>Sale</term>
               <term>Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>3rd intercalary day.;The tenth year of the Emperor Caesar Vespasian August, in the month Kaisareios, on the third intercalary day, at Bacchias in the division of Herakleides of the Arsinoite nome.;Maron, son of Hermas and grandson of Maron, about forty-seven years old, with a scar in the middle of his forehead, acknowledges to Hermas, son of Ptolemaios and grandson of Ammonios, about forty-four years old, with a scar in the middle of his forehead, that he (Maron) has sold to him in accordance with this agreement from the present day for all time the following property which belongs to him, Maron, the party of the first part, in the aforesaid village of Bacchias: a third share inherited from his mother, and a purchased ninth share, making four ninths of a commonly owned house and old courtyard which has partly fallen in ruins, the measurements of the entire area being whatever they may be, with their ancient foundations and their boundaries, and in such condition as they are; of all of which the adjoining areas are: on the south lots belonging to Katoites, the son of Menches, and his associates, and for a certain distance a common entrance and exit, on which a door opens; on the north a royal road; on the west an old house belonging to the aforesaid Katoites, the son of Menches, and his associates; on the east, a courtyard of Horos, the son of Katoites and grandson of Belles, and his brothers, beyond which there is an old house. And he, the party of the first part, Maron, has received from Hermas the entire price agreed upon, in full, one hundred silver drachmai, forthwith from hand to hand out of the house; and both he, the party of the first part, Maron, and his representatives will guarantee to Hermas and his representatives the property sold in accordance with this sale with full guarantees for all time; and he will deliver the property unencumbered, unpledged, not offered as collateral, not alienated, and free from all debts, both public and private, and will see that it has been neither previously mortgaged nor previously sold to other persons, nor any part of it either, in any way whatsoever, and will see that no one hinders the purchaser, Hermas, or his heirs from exercising ownership and control over the purchases, as stated above, entering and departing, demolishing and constructing on the property however they choose, and furthermore, selling the property, mortgaging it to others, transferring it and using it in whatever way they choose, free from interference; and as regards the terms which have been set forth, let no one accuse or dispute with or proceed against the purchaser, Hermas, or his representatives in any way upon any pretext. And if the party of the first part, Maron, or his representatives violates any of the aforesaid terms or does not guarantee or deliver the property in accordance with the terms as they have been written, then, apart from the fact that any contrary action will be invalid and inadmissible in every way, let him further pay to Hermas forthwith the damages and double the price and a fine of an additional three hundred silver drachmai, and the same amount to the treasury, and none the less the sale be valid. Both the parties concerned [- - -].;(2nd hand) I, Maron, son of Hermas and grandson of Maron, acknowledge that I have sold to Hermas, son of Ptolemaios and grandson of Ammonios, in accordance with this agreement from the present day for all time the following property which belongs to me: a third share inherited from my mother, and a purchased ninth share, making four ninths of a commonly owned house and old courtyard which has partly fallen in ruins, the measurements of the entire area being whatever they may be, with their ancient foundations and their boundaries, and in such condition as they are; of all of which the adjoining areas are: on the south lots belonging to Katoites, the son of Menches, and his associates, and for a certain distance a common entrance and exit, on which a door opens; on the north a royal road; on the west an old house belonging to the aforesaid Katoites, the son of Menches, and his associates; on the east a courtyard of Horos, the son of Katoites and grandson of Belles, and his brothers, beyond which there is an old house, and I have received the entire price agreed upon, in full, one hundred silver drachmai, forthwith from hand to hand out of the house; and I will guarantee the sale with full guarantees r all time as stated above.;(3rd hand) I, Hermas, son of Ptolemaios and grandson of Ammonios, have received the sale of the four ninths of the old house and courtyard which has partly fallen in ruins, as stated above.;(1st hand) The tenth year of the Emperor Caesar Vespasian Augustus, in the month Kaisareios, on the 3rd intercalary day, registered through the chief of the record office of Bacchias and Hephaistias.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Browne GM, PMich X, 583, 1970 -- BL VI, 83 (bibliography); BL XI, 132 Zingali LM, Vita privata e vita pubblica, 26, 1992</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:10:583</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1294&amp;viewid=101R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/0/1/R/101R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1294&amp;viewid=101R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1294&amp;viewid=101R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/0/1/V/101V.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1294&amp;viewid=101V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1294&amp;viewid=101V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
