<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of Vacant Lots</title>
            <author>Eutychos the elder, Eutychos the third, Sisichales and Sisois, all sons of Eutychos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1361</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1361</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.305</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;305</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;305</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">25197</idno>
            <idno type="TM">25197</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1276</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Subscriptions to a contract by which four sons of Eutychos sell to Chrates, son of Akousilaos, an unstated number of bikoi from the walled vacant lots that belong to them; several spaces were left blank, to be filled later with information concerning the measurements and adjacent areas of the land sold</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">The passage giving the measurements (l. 3-6) is difficult to interpret, both because of the omitted measurements and because of the writer's lack of clearness in describing what must have been an irregular plot of ground. The interpretation in the translation is based on the assumption that Eutychos gives first the measurements of all the vacant lots, and then the measurements of the particular plot sold. This confusion is increased by the passage giving the neighbors (l. 6-12), which must be listed for all the vacant lots rather than for the portion sold.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 49.7 x 28 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">slightly damaged along the folds</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">27</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The first hand (that of Eutychos the elder, to be found in several other documents) is somewhat irregular, and in many places is so cursive that the individual letters cannot be distinguished. (Husselman) - 3rd hand: slow-writer</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0001" notAfter="0099">Ist century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Chrates son of Akousilaos and Taos (see also P.Mich. V, 248</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">280)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hatres son of Mieus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Panther (son of Mieus), brother of Hatres (former owner)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) sons of (the same?) Panther</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mieus son of Harmiysis (former owner) (see also P.Mich. II, 123, recto, col. V, l. 25</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">col. XIII, l. 19</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">and P.Mich. V, 243</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">301?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles (son of Akousilaos and Taos), brother of Chrates (see also P.Mich. II, 123, Recto, col. XIX</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">V, 280)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menemachos son of Alexandros (see also P.Mich. V, 321)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Tebtynis</term>
               <term>Family--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Land tenure--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Professions--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Sales--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Women--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Month Germanikeios 2.;;;;We, Eutychos the elder and Eutychos the third and Sisichales and Sisois the carpenter, the four sons of Eutychos, our mother being Thermouthis, acknowledge that we have sold to Chates, son of Akousilaos, his mother being Taos, in accordance with this sale from the present day forever, from the walled vacant lots that belong to us by inheritance from our father, from the part on the east side; that is, we acknowledge that we have sold to Chrates     bikoi on the east side of the lots belonging to us the sellers, extending from south to north, and all the appurtenances in Tebtynis. The measurements of these lots are            ells from south to north throughout,        ells from west to east; on the north side from west to east thirty ells, from south to north seven ells on the west side, on the east side from south to north three and one-half ells from the eighteen and one-half ells of those ells designated from south to north, and from west to east on the south side thirty-eight ells. The neighbors are on the south           ; on the north the house and lots of the purchaser, Chrates, and in part the court of Hatres, son of Mieus, now that of his brother Panther, and also in part the lots of the sons of Panther, and also in part on the north side the vacant lots of Mieus, son of Harmiysis, now belonging to others; on the west the vacant lots of Herakles the brother of Chrates, four ells from south to north from the existing wall of the court of Herakles which passes through them for twelve ells from west to east, and also in part on the west side the lots of Sisois the carpenter and of Sisichales, through which there is an entrance and exit three ells in width from west to east, passing through all these lots from south to north, by which Herakles and Chrates and Eutychos the third and Sisichales and Sisois the carpenter and their heirs and assigns shall enter and leave, that is, by the three ells of the entrance and exit; on the east the lots of the sons of Panther and in part the lots of Mieus, son of Harmiysis, now belonging to others, and in part the royal road and in part the other vacant lots of us the sellers. And we have received from Chrates the entire price agreed upon, in full, immediately, from hand to hand, out of the house, and we guarantee the sale on mutual security with every guarantee from public encumbrances from past times up to the present year and for the present year also, and from private debts and every claim forever, on condition that Herakles shall open for himself a door from the four ells up to those on the east of them into the designated three ells of the common entrance and exit. Our wives, that of me, Eutychos the elder, being Tesenouphis, daughter of Harmiysis, her mother being Thermouthis, and that of Eutychos the third being Tamaron, daughter of Haryotes, her mother being Thasos, that of Sisichales, Heraklous, daughter of Aunes, her mother being Tasouchion, and that of Sisois the carpenter, Thermouthis, daughter of Sigeris, her mother being Taorseus, consent to this sale and agree not to proceed against it forever or bring any claim, and that no one else shall in their behalf as aforesaid. And the other guarantee, given by us and by our dead brother Eutychos the second, for the other lots and house which Chrates and Herakles hold and which we sold to them previously shall remain valid for them as aforesaid. I, Eutychos, wrote also for my wife who is illiterate.;(2nd hand) We, Sisichales and Sisois the carpenter, the two sons of Eutychos, our mother being Thermouthis, acknowledge that we have joined in selling the aforesaid lots and in receiving the price and guaranteeing the sale with every guarantee; and our wives, that of Sisichales, Heraklous, daughter of Aunes, her mother being Tasouchion, and that of Sisois the carpenter, Thermouthis, daughter of Sigeris, her mother being Taorseus, consent to this sale and agree not to proceed against it forever and not to bring any claim, and that no one else shall in their behalf. And the other guarantee, given by us and by our other brother, who is dead, for the other lots and the house which Chrates and Herakles hold and which we sold to them previously shall remain valid for them as aforesaid. Menemachos, son of Alexandros, wrote for them because Sisichales writes slowly and the others are illiterate.;(3rd hand) I, Sisichales, son of Euychos, my mother being Thermouthis, have sold and received the price and given the guarantee, and have ordered him to write as aforesaid.;(4th hand) I, Eutychos the third, son of Euychos, my mother being Thermouthis, have joined in selling the aforesaid vacant lots and all the appurtenances in Tebtynis, and in receiving the price and guaranteeing the sale with every guarantee; and my wife, Tamaron, daughter of Haryotes, her mother being Thasos, consents to the sale and agree not to proceed against it forever and not to bring any claim, and that no one else shall in her behalf. And the other guarantee, given by us and by our other brother, Eutychos the second, who is dead, for the other lots and the house which Chrates and Herakles hold and which we sold to them previously shall remain valid for them as aforesaid. I, Eutychos, wrote also for my wife who is illiterate.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 305, 1944</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:305</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1361&amp;viewid=1276R_2.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/2/1276R_2.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1361&amp;viewid=1276R_2.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1361&amp;viewid=1276R_2.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/1/1276R_1.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1361&amp;viewid=1276R_1.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1361&amp;viewid=1276R_1.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
