<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3344</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3344</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 57 is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 57-58: 33.8 x 29.1 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 57: complete (papyrus cut off left of col. 57 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 57: 52 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 57 (l. 1348-1399)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Pasoxis and Segathis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 203)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios son of Petheus and Taseus grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Achillas son of Phaesis and Tasingonis (Tasigonis) grandson of Zenas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion son of Phasis and Tanomgeus grandson of Esouris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Menandros and Soeris grandson of Anchophis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Nestosiris and Thermouthis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Melanas son of Pnepheros and Tasoucharion grandson of Pakysis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 188)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ischyras son of Panesneus and Tamystha grandson of Ischyras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 179)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nikephoros, doulos of Longinus Isidoros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Petheus and Thaisas grandson of Petesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Esouris and Zoidous grandson of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Kames and Thaesis grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Besis and Heras grandson of Thoteus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Onnophris and Thermouthis grandson of Sambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas son of Sokmenis and Tkollainis grandson of Sambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 224)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Charidemos son of Petoraipis and Thaesis grandson of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Petalos and Taeuemeros grandson of Petaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Charmos son of Heron and Apollonous grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Isidoros son of (Tryphon alias) Panephremmis and Isidora grandson of Sambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 179)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Harpalos and Tapetheus grandson of Sarapion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ninis son of Asklas and Tabous grandson of Ninis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Eutyches, doulos of Sarapias (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 165)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus son of Herieus and Tremenesis (Tlemenesis) grandson of Petaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Guards troops--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Slaves--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 57;;On the 25th (of Pharmouthi), similarly:;Petheus, son of Pasoxis and Segathis, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai;    column 2;Aphrodisios, son of Petheus and Taseus, grandson of Pnepheros: 4 drachmai;    column 3;Achillas, son of Phaesis and Tasingonis, grandson of Zenas: 20 drachmai; (and) for ch(--), 4 drachmai;    column 49;Horion, son of Phasis and Tanomgeus, grandson of Esouris: for the guards, 28 obols;    column 51;Horos, son of Menandros and Soeris, grandson of Anchophis: 4 drachmai;    column 51;Ptolemaios, son of Nestosiris and Thermouthis, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai;    column 52;Melanas, son of Pnepheros and Tasoucharion, grandson of Pakysis: 4 drachmai;    column 53;Ischyras, son of Panesneus and Tamystha, grandson of Ischyra: 8 drachmai;    column 54;Nikephoros, slave of Longinus Isidoros: 4 drachmai;    column 57;Pnepheros, son of Petheus and Thaisas, grandson of Petesouchos: 4 drachmai;    column 59;Pnepheros, son of Esouris and Zoidous, grandson of Onnophris: 4 drachmai;    column 59;Sarapion, son of Kames and Thaesis, grandson of Heras: 4 drachmai;    column 63;Pnepheros, son of Besis and Heras, grandson of Thoteus: 8 drachmai;    column 64;Onnophris, son of Onnophris and Thermouthis, grandson of Sambas: 8 drachmai;    column 68;Sambas, son of Sokmenis and Tkollainis, grandson of Sambas: 4 drachmai;    column 69;Charidemos, son of Petoraipis and Thaesis, grandson of Onnophris: 4 drachmai;    column 72;Total for the day: 92 drachmai 28 obols.;;On the 26th, similarly:;Pnepheros, son of Petalos and Taeuemeros, grandson of Petaus: 8 drachmai;    column 77;Charmos, son of Heron and Apollonous, grandson of Horos: 8 drachmai;    column 78;Isidoros, son of Panephremmis and Isidora, grandson of Sambas: 32 drachmai;    column 79;Sarapion, son of Harpalos and Tapetheus, grandson of Sarapion: 4 drachmai;    column 85;Ninis, son of Asklas and Tabous, grandson of Ninis: 28 obols;    column 88;Eutyches, slave of Sarapias: 4 drachmai;    column 88;Petaus, son of Herieus and Tremenesis, grandson of Petaus: 4 drachmai;    column 89;Ptolemaios, son of Harmiysis and Tasoucharion, grandson of Pnepheros: 4 drachmai;    column 92</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 57 (l. 1348-1399), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3344&amp;viewid=4172_15RO.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/5/r/o/4172_15ro.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3344&amp;viewid=4172_15RO.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3344&amp;viewid=4172_15RO.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
