<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3347</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3347</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 60 is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 59-60: 36.1 x 29.3 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 60: complete (papyrus cut off right of col. 60 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 60: 53 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 60 (l. 1498-1550)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Apollonios and Thermouthis grandson of Harpagathes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinus son of Petesouchos and Charis grandson of Petesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Teos son of Mysthes and Tanais grandson of Anchophis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 242)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchophis son of Mysthes and Tanais grandson of Anchophis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Akousilaos and Thatres grandson of Pasoknopaios, hytrophylax (hydrophylax) (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis son of Pasoxis and Tapetsiris grandson of Phaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor son of Ptolemaios and Tapasion grandson of Phaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 182)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron son of Ptolemaios and Heras grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Pasoxis and Thakiaris (Thakialis) grandson of Petesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Kames and Thaesis grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Abykis son of Demas and Taonnophris grandson of Abykis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 148)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas son of Onnophris and Thermouthis grandson of Sambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 223)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Apynchis and Tapetheus grandson of Aunes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion son of Maron and Thermouthis grandson of Horion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Herakles and Didyme grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus son of Petheus and Taseus grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Ptolemaios and Thermouthis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 204)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinus son of Petheus and Eserempis grandson of Heraklas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Petheus and Segathis grandson of Teos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor son of Achillas and Aphrodous grandson of Kastor (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Didymos and Tauris grandson of Maron (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pamonneouis son of Anchorimphis and Didymarion grandson of Pamonneouis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Orsenouphis and Anthia grandson of Herieus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Karanis (Extinct city)--Defenses.</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Brothers--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Guards troops--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 60;;On the 3rd (of Pachon), similarly:;Sarapion, son of Apollonios and Thermouthis, grandson of Harpagathes: 4 drachmai;    column 61;Sabinus, son of Petesouchos and Charis, grandson of Petesouchos: 4 drachmai 28 obols;    column 14;Heron, son of Sisois and Didymarion, grandson of Petesouchos: 8 drachmai;    column 46;Teos, son of Mysthes and Tanais, grandson of Anchophis: 8 drachmai;    column 52;Anchophis, his brother, (born) of the same mother: 12 drachmai;    column 52;Pnepheros, son of Akousilaos and Thatres, grandson of Pasoknopaios, water guard, for the guard towers: 7  drachmai 2 obols;    column 59;Phaesis, son of Pasoxis and Tapetsiris, grandson of Phaesis: 8 drachmai;    column 58;Kastor, son of Ptolemaios and Tapasion, grandson of Phaesis: 8 drachmai;    column 58;Heron, son of Ptolemaios and Heras, grandson of Pnepheros: 4 drachmai;    column 59;Pnepheros, son of Pasoxis and Thakiaris, grandson of Petesouchos: 8 drachmai;    column 59;Sarapion, son of Kames and Thaesis, grandson of Heras: 4 drachmai;    column 63;Abykis, son of Demas and Taonnophris, grandson of Abykis: 4 drachmai;    column 65;Sambas, son of Onnophris and Thermouthis, grandson of Sambas: 4 drachmai;    column 68;Ptolemaios, son of Apynchis and Tapetheus, grandson of Aunes: 4 drachmai;    column 70;Horion, son of Maron and Thermouthis, grandson of Horion: 28 drachmai;    column 61;Total for the day: 116 drachmai 23 obols.;;On the 4th, similarly:;Petheus, son of Herakles and Didyme, grandson of Petheus: 12 drachmai; (and) for ch(---), 4 drachmai;    column 45;Petaus, son of Petheus and Taseus, grandson of Pnepheros: 4 drachmai;    column 80;Petheus, son of Ptolemaios and Thermouthis, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(---), 4 drachmai;    column 82;Sabinus, son of Petheus and Eserempis, grandson of Heraklas: 4 drachmai 28 obols;    column 84;Onnophris, son of Petheus and Segathis, grandson of Teos: 4 drachmai;    column 85;Kastor, son of Achillas and Aphrodous, grandson of Kastor: 4 drachmai;    column 90;Petheus, son of Didymos and Tauris, grandson of Maron: 4 drachmai;    column 80;Pamonneouis, son of Anchorimphis and Didymarion, grandson of Pamonneouis: 8 drachmai;    column 98;Ptolemaios, son of Orsenouphis and Anthia, grandson of Herieus: 4 drachmai;    column 99</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 60 (l. 1498-1550), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3347&amp;viewid=4172_16RO.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/6/r/o/4172_16ro.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3347&amp;viewid=4172_16RO.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3347&amp;viewid=4172_16RO.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
