<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Loan on Security</title>
            <author>Orseus, son of Kollouthos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3092</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3092</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.328</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;328</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;328</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">15160</idno>
            <idno type="TM">15160</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 723</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contracts of sale of a house and of loan of 420 drachmai, made between the same parties, Orseus, son of Kollouthos, and his brother, Orseus the elder; the two documents together constitute a mortgage, the house being the security for the loan. The puzzling note on the verso seems to mean that this copy of the subscription, intended for Kollouthos, son of Orseus and joint borrower with him, was to be held until something was received from him.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto +Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Mich. inv. 682. - Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 38.5 x 27.5 (total size)</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">damaged along the break and at the top and bottom; the writing on the verso is badly rubbed</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto, col. I - 7;;col. II - 11;;Verso - 3</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto + Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0029" notAfter="0030">29-30 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Orseus son of Kollouthos and Tereus, Perses tes epigones</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orseus presbyteros son of Kollouthos and Tereus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nestnephis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pelemasis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kollouthos son of Orseus grandson of Kollouthos, Perses tes epigones, Talites</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Patynion son of Herakles (see also P.Mich. V, 230)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) prostates of Matres(?) (= Orseus presbyteros?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tiberius, Emperor</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Perses; Talei; Talites; Matres(?)</term>
               <term>Ethnicity</term>
               <term>Family</term>
               <term>House Ownership</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Loan</term>
               <term>Mortgage</term>
               <term>Iranians--Egypt</term>
               <term>Sale</term>
               <term>Talei (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Recto, col. I);;I, Orseus, son of Kollouthos, acknowledge that I have sold to Orseus the elder, son of Kollouthos, whose mother is Tereus and who is my brother on both my father's and my mother's side, the three-story house that belongs to me, and the courtyard and all the appurtenances, in Talei, the neighbors of the house and court being on the south the house of Nestnephis, on the north the royal road, on the west the house of the same Nestnephis, and on the east the house of Pelemasis. And I have received from Orseus the entire price agreed upon, in full, from hand to hand, out of the house, and I guarantee the sale with every guarantee. My son Kollouthos consents to this sale and agrees not to proceed against it forever, or to make any claim as aforesaid. Patynion, son of Herakles, wrote for them because they are illiterate.;;(Col. II);I, Orseus, son of Kollouthos, and my son Kollouthos, both Persians of the epigone, sureties for each other for the payment, have received from Orseus the elder, son of Kollouthos, a loan amounting to four hundred and twenty drachmai of minted silver, at the interest of one drachme per mina per month, which money we will repay in the month of Neos Sebastos of the ensuing seventeenth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus as aforesaid. Patynion, son of Herakles, wrote for them because they are illiterate.;;(Verso);16th year. Contract (made) by Kollouthos, of Talei, to the president of Matres(?). Keep it until Mecheir to receive from . . . [- - -]</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 328, 1944, Pl. V (verso only)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:328</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3092&amp;viewid=1">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
