<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of Vine Land</title>
            <author>Kronion, son of Zoilos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1430</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1430</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.6.9109</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;6;9109</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;6;9109</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14109</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14109</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1431</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Second half of a contract for the sale by Kronion, son of Zoilos, to his brother Sokrates of two arourai of dry vine land near Lower Phnebie</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 17 x 35.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">broken (or cut) off at the top</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">19</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0031">August 28, 31 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Kronion son of Zoilos (see also P.Mich. V, 335?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sokrates son of Zoilos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tiberius, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion (former owner)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tryphon son of Ptolemaios, gymnasiarchos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kronion (son of Apion), ho pros to graphio of Tebtynis and Kerkesoucha Orous</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Phnebie kato, Polemonos meris; Tebtynis; Kerkesoucha Orous</term>
               <term>Family</term>
               <term>Irrigation</term>
               <term>Land Ownership</term>
               <term>Notary</term>
               <term>Sale</term>
               <term>Kerkesoucha Orous (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[- - -] that Kronion &lt;has received&gt; from Sokrates the entire sum of money established for the cession of the aforesaid two arourai, and that he, Kronion, and his heirs guarantee to Sokrates and his heirs the property in accordance with this cession with every guarantee from all public dues and all imposts and every tax from past times up to the present seventeenth year and including the present seventeenth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, and from private encumbrances and every claim forever, and &lt;he shall relinquish the arourai&gt; neither sold previously even in part nor mortgaged nor alienated in any way. If Kronion violates any of the aforesaid provisions, the prosecution or accusation or claim or hindrance or fraud which he or another on his behalf shall make with regard to this property shall be void in every respect, and he shall in addition pay to Sokrates double the amount of the damages and expenses and a fine of a thousand silver drachmai, and a like amount to the treasury. Moreover Kronion shall perforce turn over to Sokrates the tax receipts and the legal instruments &lt;made out&gt; to him. The agreement shall be valid as aforesaid.;(2nd hand) I, Kronion, son of Zoilos, acknowledge that I have sold to my full brother, Sokrates, the two arourai, or as many as there may be, in one parcel, of dry vine land, that belong to me near Lower Phnebie, of which the neighbors are on the south the vineyard formerly belonging to Sarapion but now belonging to Tryphon, son of Ptolemaios, the gymnasiarch, on the north the canal through which the designated two arourai are watered, on the west dry vine land, on the east the royal road. And I have received from Sokrates the entire price agreed upon in full from hand to hand out of the house and I guarantee the sale with every guarantee both from all public dues and all imposts and from every tax from past times up to  the seventeenth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus and including the present seventeenth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, and from private encumbrances and every claim forever, and I shall hand over to Sokrates the tax receipts and the legal instruments &lt;made out&gt; to me as aforesaid.;(3rd hand) Sokrates, son of Zoilos. The sale was made to me as aforesaid.;(1st hand) Registered in the seventeenth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, Mesore, fifth interecalary day, through Kronion, who is in charge of the grapheion of Tebtynis and Kerkesoucha Orous in the division of Polemon.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, TAPA 81, 70-3, 1950 -- SB VI 9109 -- BL VII, 202 (l.  7; 10); BL IX, 254 (l. 11)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB:6:9109</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1430&amp;viewid=1431R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/3/1/R/1431R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1430&amp;viewid=1431R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1430&amp;viewid=1431R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
