<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3646</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3646</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso contains traces</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 33.2 x 32.6 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is badly damaged in the left side, especially along its numerous vertical folds. There is a kollesis in the middle of the document, which is regularly cut at the left and right. At top and bottom the papyrus is broken. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-40</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 12 (ll. 428-468)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles, son of Petaus, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Perigenes, son of Zoilos, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios, son of Anchophis, grandson of Petheus, mother Melanous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 157)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis, son of Melanas, grandson of Pakysis, mother Taheuhemeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Anchophis, grandson of Herakles, mother Teseuris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Besis, son of Petheus, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 159)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor, son of Sisois, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 182)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Onnophris, grandson of Sambas, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Sokmenis, grandson of Sambas, mother Tkollainis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 224)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraklas, son of Apollonios, grandson of Heraklas, mother Taorsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 166)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Longinus alias Gemellus, fatherless, mother Taphois (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 185)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hermadion, slave of Isidoros alias Longinus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Petheus, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Taseus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Phasis, grandson of Keras, mother Helena (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymos, son of Satabous, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Petheus, grandson of Teos, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Valerius, grandson of Sarapion, mother Stotoetis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dioskoros, son of Aiaus, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Thases (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Herieus, mother Anthia (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Zenas, son of Phaesis, grandson of Zenas, mother Tapasion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 165)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Petermouthis, grandson of Apynchis, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Herakles, grandson of Petheus, mother Didyme (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles, son of Apollonios, grandson of Petoraipis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanemgeus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes, son of Phaesis, grandson of Mysthes, mother Aunchis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchorymphis, son of Petheus the younger, grandson of Anchorymphis, mother Apollonous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes, son of Teberis, grandson of Sambathion, mother Isidora (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Satabous, grandfather of Horos, mother Theonis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 220)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harsiesis, son of Petheus, grandson of Harsiesis, mother Thatres (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Didymarion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p.169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Komonis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymion, son of Petheus the older, grandson of Didymion, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 161)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>" [(Column) 12];Tybi 11:;Herakles, son of Petaus, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Segathis, obols 28;;Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis, drachmas 12;;Perigenes, son of Zoilos, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Sambathion, drachmas 4;;Aphrodisios, son of Anchophis, grandson of Petheus, mother Melanous, drachmas 4, obols 28;;Pakysis, son of Melanas, grandson of Pakysis, mother Taheuhemeros, drachmas 8;;Horos, son of Anchophis, grandson of Herakles, mother Teseuris, drachmas 8;;Besis, son of Petheus, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Thermouthis, obols 28;;Kastor, son of Sisois, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaisas, drachmas 4;;Onnophris, son of Onnophris, grandson of Sambas, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;Sambas, son of Sokmenis, grandson of Sambas, mother Tkollainis, obols 28;;Heraklas, son of Apollonios, grandson of Heraklas, mother Taorsenouphis, drachmas 8;;in total for the day, drachmas 64, obols 24;;(Tybi) 12 likewise:;Longinus alias Gemellus, fatherless, mother Taphois, drachmas 16;;Hermadion, slave of Isidoros alias Longinus, drachmas 16;;Petaus, son of Petheus, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Taseus, drachmas 4;;Sarapion, son of Phasis, grandson of Keras, mother Helena, obols 28;;Didymos, son of Satabous, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tanomgeus, drachmas 8;;Onnophris, son of Petheus, grandson of Teos, mother Segathis, drachmas 8;;Sarapion, son of Valerius, grandson of Sarapion, mother Stotoetis, drachmas 8;;Dioskoros, son of Aiaus, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Thases, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Herieus, mother Anthia, drachmas 4;;Zenas, son of Phaesis, grandson of Zenas, mother Tapasion, drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, son of Petermouthis, grandson of Apynchis, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 8;;Petheus, son of Herakles, grandson of Petheus, mother Didyme, drachmas 16;;Herakles, son of Apollonios, grandson of Petoraipis, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 20;;12th year the same, drachmas 4 copper drachmas 16, ? copper drachmas;;in total for the day drachmas 144, obols 19 of which 12th year drachmas 20, obols 20;;(Tybi) 14 likewise:;Onnophris, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanemgeus, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Mysthes, son of Phaesis, grandson of Mysthes, mother Aunchis, drachmas 8;;Anchorymphis, son of Petheus the younger, grandson of Anchorymphis, mother Apollonous, drachmas 8;;Mysthes, son of Teberis, grandson of Sambathion, mother Isidora, drachmas 4, obols 28;;Ptolemaios, son of Satabous, grandfather of Horos, mother Theonis, drachmas 12;;Harsiesis, son of Petheus, grandson of Harsiesis, mother Thatres, drachmas 4;;Heras, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Didymarion, drachmas 4;;Horion, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Komonis, drachmas 4;;Didymion, son of Petheus the older, grandson of Didymion, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 4. obols 28</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3646&amp;viewid=4171_12R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3646&amp;viewid=4171_12R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3646&amp;viewid=4171_12R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3646&amp;viewid=4171_12V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3646&amp;viewid=4171_12V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
