<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3326</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3326</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 30 is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 29-30: 34.5 x 29.5 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 30: nearly complete (papyrus cut off right of col. 30 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 30: 61 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 30 (l. 457-517)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus son of Petheus and Tamystha grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Mysthes and Charis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petsiris son of Pasoknopaios and Heros grandson of Petsiris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 211)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor son of Mares (Marres) and Soeris grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Pasoxis and Thakiaris (Thakialis) grandson of Petesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Kames and Thaesis grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apitas son of Chairemon and Tasoucharion grandson of Apitas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 152)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Charidemos son of Petoraipis and Thaesis grandson of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinus son of Petesouchos and Charis grandson of Petesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nekpheraus son of Euemeros and Taonnophris grandson of Nekpheraus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 190)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Petheus and Ptolema grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Petheus and Tapapeis grandson of Sokmenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pamoneios (Pamonneouis) son of Anchorimphis and Didymarion grandson of Pamoneios (Pamonneouis) (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Ptolemaios and Thermouthis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 204)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymos son of Petheus and Eserempis grandson of Heraklas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 161)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Pnepheros and Tapetheus grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraklas son of Petheus and Eserempis grandson of Heraklas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dioskoros son of Aiaus and Thases grandson of Orsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Petaus and Tauris grandson of Petaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Charmos son of Heron and Apollonous grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phasis son of Tesenouphis and Thaesis grandson of Harphaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 246)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron son of Satabous and Tkonnos grandson of Maron, brother of Menches (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menches son of Satabous and Tkonnos grandson of Maron, brother of Maron (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos son of Petheus and Tkollainis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Patkonnis son of Mysthes and Taonnophris grandson of Patkonnis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 200)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 30;;(Phamenoth 18, continued);Phanomgeus, son of Petheus and Tamystha, grandson of Satabous: 4 drachmai;    column 53;Ptolemaios, son of Mysthes and Charis, grandson of Petheus: 12 drachmai;    column 53;Petsiris, son of Pasoknopaios and Heros, grandson of Petsiris: 8 drachmai;    column 55;Kastor, son of Mares and Soeris, grandson of Heras: 16 drachmai 8 obols;    column 56;Pnepheros, son of Pasoxis and Thakiaris, grandson of Petesouchos: 28 obols;    column 59;Sarapion, son of Kames and Thaesis, grandson of Heras: 8 drachmai;    column 63;Apitas, son of Chairemon and Tasoucharion, grandson of Apitas: 8 drachmai;    column 65;Charidemos, son of Petoraipis and Thaesis, grandson of Onnophris: 28 obols;    column 72;Sabinus, son of Petesouchos and Charis, grandson of Petesouchos: 8 drachmai;    column 14;Nekpheraus, son of Euemeros and Taonnophris, grandson of Nekpheraus: 4 drachmai;    column 75;Total for the day: 112 drachmai 6 obols.;;On the 19th, similarly:;Onnophris, son of Petheus and Ptolema, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai;    column 13;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus and Tapapeis, grandson of Sokmenis: 16 drachmai 8 obols;    column 70;Pamoneios, son of Anchorimphis and Didymarion, grandson of Pamoneios: 4 drachmai;    column 98;Petheus, son of Ptolemaios and Thermouthis, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai;    column 82;Didymos, son of Petheus and Eserempis, grandson of Heraklas: 8 drachmai;    column 84;Pnepheros, son of Pnepheros and Tapetheus, grandson of Pnepheros: 8 drachmai;    column 82;Heraklas, son of Petheus and Eserempis, grandson of Heraklas: 16 drachmai 8 obols;    column 84;Ptolemaios, son of Harmiysis and Tasoucharion, grandson of Pnepheros: 4 drachmai;    column 92;Dioskoros, son of Aiaus and Thases, grandson of Orsenouphis: 4 drachmai;    column 95;Polydeukes, son of Heras and Tapasion, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai;    column 100;Horos, son of Petaus and Tauris, grandson of Petaus: 4 drachmai;    column 101;Charmos, son of Heron and Apollonous, grandson of Horos: 16 drachmai 7 obols;    column 78;Total for the day: 100 drachmai 23 obols.;;On the 20th, similarly:;Horos the younger, son of Hatres and Teraus, grandson of Horos: 4 drachmai;    column 2;Phasis, son of Tesenouphis and Thaesis, grandson of Harphaesis: 4 drachmai;    column 3;Maron, son of Satabous and Tkonnos, grandson of Maron: 4 drachmai;    column 5;Menches, his brother, (born) of the same mother: 4 drachmai;    column 5;Petesouchos, son of Petheus and Tkollainis, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai;    column 7;Patkonnis, son of Mysthes and Taonnophris, grandson of Patkonnis: 8 drachmai;    column 7</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 30 (l. 457-517), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3326&amp;viewid=4172R5.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/R/5/4172R5.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3326&amp;viewid=4172R5.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3326&amp;viewid=4172R5.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
