<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of Parts of a House</title>
            <author>Theodoros, son of Makarios</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3017</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3017</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">18403</idno>
            <idno type="TM">18403</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;18;13320</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 6905</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract by which Theodoros, son of Makarios, with the children of his deceased brother Kollouthos, sell parts of a house (a hall and two men's appartments) to Enoch, son of Psimanobet, and to the later's sister Maria and her husband Iakybios, son of Ioannes</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto (written across the fibres); Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P. Private Collection (Paris), without Inv. No. - Archive of Dioskoros of Aphrodito.</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; P.Mich. inv. 6905: 147.5 x 31 cm; P.priv.coll. (Paris): 15.5 x 35 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">broken off at the top</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">126</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written across the fibres</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0613" notAfter="0641">613-641 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Aphrodite (Aphrodito), Antaiopolite nome, province of the Lower Thebais, Thebais, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Theodoros son of Makarios, oinoprates</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(Aurelius) Kollouthos (son of Makarios), deceased brother of Theodoros (&amp; unnamed heirs)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Iakybius (Jacob) son of Ioannes (John), husband of Maria, syntelestes (see also P.Michael. 52</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">P.Herm.Rees 32)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelia Maria daughter of Psimanobet, wife of Iakybius, sister of Enoch</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Enoch son of Psimanobet, brother of Maria, syntelestes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Flavii Heraclius and Heraclius Novus Constantinus, Emperors</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Makarios alias Pamou Riu, deceased father of Theodoros and Kollouthos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anouphios, mageiros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ioannes (John), tabliton</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Solomon ...  (see Geographica)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Abraamios (Abraham) son of Horouonchis, orbiopoles (former owner)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) heirs of Andreas, poimen</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Promauos son of Isakios (Isaac), protokometes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psaios (Psais) son of Psenthaesis, presbyteros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Victor son of Ioannes (John), diakon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Phoibammon son of Paos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollos son of Senouthios, diakon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mathias son of Enoch, presbyteros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Ponnis son of Ieremios (Jeremy)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Andreas, symbolographos (see also P.Michael. 52</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">P.Vat.Aphrod. 19A)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Aphrodite (Aphrodito), Antaiopolite nome, province of the Lower Thebais, Thebais, Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Aphrodite, Antaiopolite nome; Panos polis (Panopolis); rhyme legomene Solomonos ...</term>
               <term>Family</term>
               <term>House</term>
               <term>House Ownership</term>
               <term>Inheritance</term>
               <term>Notary</term>
               <term>Personal status: minor children</term>
               <term>Priest (Christian)</term>
               <term>Profession</term>
               <term>Sale</term>
               <term>Topography (Aphrodite)</term>
               <term>Woman</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[- - -];Aurelius Theodoros, [son of Makarios - - -], managing and undertaking business for myself [and for - - -, the heirs] of the most blessed Kollouthos [. . ., my brother, . . . and willing at the risk of my whole property [to prepare them to be content, abide] and acquiesce in the force of this [. . . deed of sale, coming from the village of Aphrodite] of the Antaiopolite nome, now dwelling now [in Panopolis . . ., to the Aurelii] Iakybios, son of Ioannes, and his wife Maria, [daughter of Psimanobet and of . . .., and Enoch, brother] of the aforesaid Maria by the same parents, [. . ., syntelestai from the same village], greetings. I, the afore-said, [Theodoros, son of Makarios, the vendor], managing and undertaking to do everything for myself, the [afore-said, Theodoros, and in the name of the] heirs of the most blessed Kollouthos, my deceased brother, by this my written security or deed of sale of my own free will and of my voluntarily [intent and with unrepentant] and unchangeable and unalterable reckoning, with a very clear purpose [and with a clear conscience] and with a honest aim, with straight-forward intention, at the same time swearing by the Almighty God and by the victory and the life of our most pious, most serene and by God crowned masters Flavius Heraclius and Flavius Heraclius Novus Constantinus his by God protected legitimate son, the perpetual Augusti, Imperatores, and greatest Benefactors, that I have sold to you, the afore-said Iakybios, son of Ioannes, and your afore-said wife Maria half the portion of my afterwards mentioned paternal portion of a complete common house and to Enoch, son of Psimanobet, brother of the afore-mentioned Maria, daughter of Psimanobet, the other half portion of my afore-mentioned paternal portion of the same house and have devised to you and have ceded and have given up to you from now on for all continually succeeding time for ever with the most complete rights of ownership and in good faith and with every authority and with eternal proprietary possession, that belongs to me and has come down to me by right of inheritance from my deceased father, Makarios with the surname Pamou Riu, of the complete common house once called Pselch (now) named after Anouphios, the butcher, and Ioannes tabliton, located in the northern part of the afore-mentioned village of Aphrodite in the street of Solomon facing towards the west towards the public street, of my afore-said paternal portion of the afore-said complete common house that means one complete hall facing towards the East towards the inner court on ground level without air and also two complete men's appartments being open towards the West till the air above, one men's appartment above the room, the other men's appartment above the common terrace together with the proportionate share of the inner court on the same ground level and of the upper chamber thereof and of the terraces and of the space inside the gateway and of the cave under the terrace and of the veranda and of the other appurtenances of the same house from basement to attic, while there has no rights whatsoever been left (for me) in my afore-mentioned complete paternal portion of the afore-mentioned complete house once called Pselch (now) named after Anouphios, the butcher, and Ioannes, the coppersmith, that means the one complete hall and what is beneath it and without air above on and two men's appartments together with the appropriate share of the inner court on the same ground level and of the upper chamber thereof and of the terraces and of the space inside the gateway and of the cave under the terrace and of the veranda and of the other appurtenances of the same house from basement to attic as I managed it at the time when my blessed father was still alive and according to the force of the ancient transactions which are now also given by me to you for your security and for the confirmation of this written deed of sale as afore stated above; the boundaries of the aforesaid complete house on the four quarters are as follows: on the South the house once of Abraam, son of Horouonchios, the vetch-seller, now of the heirs of Andreas, the shepherd, on the East the farm of Promauos, son of Isakios, protokometes, on the North the house of Psaios, son of Psenthaesios, presbyter, on the West the public street on which opens the principal door, or whatever the boundaries may be, everywhere and on all sides, for the full and fitting price agreed and jointly approved by us with one another of two and one-third approved imperial gold nomismatia with a deduction of two (carats for a nomismation) by the goldsmith's scales of the same village, i.e. 2 g.nom. 1/3 with a deduction of 2; which goldpieces of the price I, the vendor, Theodoros, son of Makarios, managing and undertaking business for myself and in the name of my afore-mentioned nephews, have received from you, the purchasers, Iakybios, son of Ioannes, and Maria, his wife and daughter of Psimanobet, for one half and from Enoch, son of Psimanobet, brother of the afore-mentioned Maria, for the other half from your hand into my hands in the sight of the lawful witnesses who have written their attestations below in order, for all the time from the present for ever, of full number and weight, at the time when the sale was affected; with which price I am satisfied. Upon the condition that henceforward you, the purchasers of it, Iakybios, son of Ioannes, and his wife, Maria, daughter of Psimanobet, for one half and Enoch, son of Psimanobet, brother of the afore-mentioned Maria, for the other half, syntelestai, possess, own and are masters of my above-described complete paternal portion of the afore-said house called Pselch, that means the one complete hall and what is beneath it without air on and two men's appartments with the appropriate share of the inner court on the ground level and what is below it and of the upper chamber thereof and of the terraces and of the space inside the gateway and of the cave under the terrace and of the veranda and of the other appurtenances of the same house from basement to attic in general, as I manage it and according to the force of the ancient transactions according to the fore-going description and you may inhabit, manage and exploit it and build it and build to it and lease or sublease it and transmit it to your own heirs and assigns and successors and use and enjoy it in whatever proprietary way you may please, without hindrance or let, free from opposition present or future from any of those who are heirs after me or joint-heirs, or of my relations by birth or my connections; and I shall defend you from whoever shall take proceedings against you in the future concerning this at my own expense and costs, and I shall confirm your possession with every confirmation at all times and on every occasion, compulsory, against everyone who shall attack or take proceedings against you; and if I am negligent in the confirmation, I shall pay you three times the price together with costs and damages, in order that this deed of sale may be valid and inviolable wherever it is produced; which deed, written in one copy I have of my own free will and consent executed at the Public Registry without any violence, compulsion, deceit or fraud, without any intimidation or guile, and for your security I have given you this copy completed according to the laws with my own subscription, followed in order by those of the customary, trustworthy witnesses who have at my summons born witness to it; and for all that is herein written and for the guarantee of confirmation of this written deed of sale and for its freedom of encumbrances all my possessions present and future, movable, immovable and live-stock, generally and severally, in every class and kind are submitted to you as a pledge and with the force of a mortgage as though by decree of court. And being asked the formal question I agreed with all that is herein written that these things were so, and so to give, do and keep. (Cross).;(2nd hand) (Cross) I, Aurelius Theodoros, son of Makarios, wine-merchant from Panopolis managing and undertaking business for myself and in the name of the heirs of Kollouthos, my deceased brother, am willing at my own risk and that of my property to prepare them to be content, abide and acquiesce in the force of this current written deed of sale and I, the afore-mentioned, executed this deed of sale and received the afore-said full price of two and one-third of a gold nomismation and I shall confirm your possession with every confirmation and I agree with all that is herein written; and I have sworn the divine oath as afore said. (Cross).;(3rd hand) (Cross) I, Victor, son of Ioannes, D.V. deacon, bear witness to this deed of sale, having heard declarations from the persons executing it and bear witness also to the payment of the two and one-third of a gold nomisma of the price.;(4th hand) (Cross) I, Aurelius Phoibammon, son of Paos, bear witness to this deed of sale, having heard declarations from the person executing it and bear witness also to the payment of the two and one-third of a gold nomisma of the price. (Cross);(5th hand) (Cross) I, Apollos, son of Senouthios, deacon, bear witness to this deed of sale, having heard declarations from the persons executing it and bear witness also to the payment of the two and one-third of a gold nomisma of the price. (Cross);(6th hand) (Cross) I, Mathias, son of Enoch, D.V. presbyter, bear witness to this deed of sale, having heard declarations from the persons executing it and bear witness also to the payment of the two and one-third of a gold nomisma of the price.;(7th hand) (Cross) I, Aurelius Ponnis, son of Ieremias, bear witness to this deed of sale, having heard declarations from the persons executing it and bear witness also to the payment of the two and one-third of a gold nomisma of the price. (Cross);(8th hand) (Cross) Written by me, Andreas, D.V. notary. (Three crosses).</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn PJ, PMich XIII, 665, 1977, Pl. XVIII-XXIII -- BL VII, 117 (l. 21; 30; 60). Gascou J, CRIPEL 7, 129-135, 1985, Pl. 16 -- SB XVIII, 13320</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3017&amp;viewid=6905R_1.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/1/6905R_1.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3017&amp;viewid=6905R_1.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3017&amp;viewid=6905R_1.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/3/6905R_3.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3017&amp;viewid=6905R_3.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3017&amp;viewid=6905R_3.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/2/6905R_2.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3017&amp;viewid=6905R_2.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3017&amp;viewid=6905R_2.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/4/6905R_4.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3017&amp;viewid=6905R_4.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3017&amp;viewid=6905R_4.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
