<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3834</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3834</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 37.2 x 31.2 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at the right and the left. Kollesis at left center. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-36</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 69 (ll. 2767-2803)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Tauris, daughter of Zenon (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 240)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Euhemeros, son of Chairemon (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petalion, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Petalion, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Taskouis, daughter of Mysthes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 238)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios (water guard)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didyme, daughter of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 161)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hellen (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Onnophris, grandson of Theabennis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p.171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Diodoros, son of Hatres (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mystharion, son of Hatres, grandson of Pkiouki (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 188)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mystharion, son of Diodoros, grandson of Hatres, mother Zoidos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 188)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thermouthis, daughter of Papeis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 176)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Papeis the blind (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thatres, daughter of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 175)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Kerkes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harsiesis, son of Petheus, grandson of Harsiesis, mother Thatres (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonia, daughter of Teberis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 152)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Akoution (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 150)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Domitius Lucillianus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Harsiesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 69:;Tauris, daughter of Zenon;;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 32 obol 1.5, tax on the produce of olives drachmas 4 obols 5.5, naubion drachmas 3 obols 2.5 chalki 2, surcharges drachmas 8 obols 3.5;;(in left margin: drachmas 84 obols 28) eparourion drachmas 22 obols 3.5, surcharges drachma 1 obols 5.5, kollybos drachma 1 obol 1.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 77;;naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year drachma 1 obols 4, surcharges obol 1, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachma 1 obols 5 chalki 2;;and Euhemeros, son of Chairemon;;orchard taxes for the 12th year drachmas 2 obols 3, tax on the produce of olives obols 2 chalki 2, naubion obol 1.5, surcharges obols 3.5 chalki 2;;eparourion drachma 1 obols 4, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 5 obols 4 chalki 2;(in left margin: drachmas 8 obols 12) Petalion, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Petalion, mother Tepheros, drachmas 8 obols 4, swine tax obols 5 chalki 2;;Taskouis, daughter of Mysthes (Ptolemaios, water guard);;(in left margin: obols 10) naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year obols 2, surcharges chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachmas 2.5;;for the 12th year likewise: obols 2, surcharges chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total obols 2.5;;Didyme, daughter of Heras (Hellen);;(in left margin: drachmas 24 obol 1) geometria for the 12th year drachmas 22 obols 2.5 chalki 2, surcharges drachma 1 obols 2.5, in total drachmas 23 obols 5 chalki 2;;Heron, son of Onnophris, grandson of Theabennis, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Diodoros, son of Hatres (Mystharion, son of Hatres, grandson of Pkiouk);;(in left margin: drachmas 12 obols 2) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 5 obol 1, tax on the produce of olives obols 4.5, naubion obols 3 chalki 2, surcharges drachma 1 obols 2;;eparourion drachmas 3 obols 2.5 chalki 2, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2, kollybos obol 1.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 11 obols 4.5;;Mystharion, son of Diodoros, grandson of Hatres, mother Zoidos;;guard tax , obols 28;;Thermouthis, daughter of Papeis (Papeis the blind);;(in left margin: drachmas 8 obols 4) orchard taxes apomoira drachma 1 obols 2, tax on the produce of olives obol 1.5, naubion obol 1, surcharges obols 2 chalki 2;;eparourion drachma 1 obol 4.5, surcharges obol 1.5, kollybos obol 0.5, in total drachmas 4 obol 1 chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 3 obols 2, surcharges obol 1.5, in total drachmas 3 obols 3.5;;Thatres, daughter of Pnepheros (Ptolemaios, son of Kerkes);;(in left margin: drachmas 20) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 8 obol 0.5 chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives drachma 1 obols 5.5, naubion obols 5, surcharges drachmas 2 obol 1 chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 5 obols 2.5, surcharges obols 2.5 chalki 2, kollybos obols 2, in total drachmas 19 obol 1.5 chalki 2;;in total for thte day drachmas 420 obols 12.;(Pachon) 30 likewise:;Harsiesis, son of Petheus, grandson of Harsiesis, mother Thatres, drachmas 8;;Apollonia, daughter of Teberis (Akoution);;(in left margin: drachmas 8 obols 8) public rent 12th year drachmas 8, surcharges obols 3, drachmas 8 obols 3;;Domitius Lucillianus through the agency of Petheus, son of Harsiesis (priest of Harpochrates);;(in left margin: drachmas 36 obols 20) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 7 obols 4, tax on the produce of olives drachma 1 obol 0.5 chalki 2, naubion obols 5.5 chalki2, surcharges drachmas 2;;eparourion drachmas 5 obol 1, surcharges obols 2.5 chalki 2, kollybos obol 1.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 17 obols 4;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 19 obol 1 chalki 2, surcharges drachma 1 obol 1.5, in total drachmas 20 obols 2.5 chalki 2."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3834&amp;viewid=4171_69R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3834&amp;viewid=4171_69R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3834&amp;viewid=4171_69R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
