<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3700</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3700</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 25.7 x 32.8 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at left and right. Kollesis in the middle of the right column. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-43</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 26 (ll. 1089-1132)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. Unusually narrow left margin (max. 1.5 cm.) and wide right margin (at minimum5 cm.). (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Apollonios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, brother with the same mother (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 200)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Besis, son of Petheus, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 159)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Onnophris, grandson of Sambas, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 223)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Naaraus the older, grandson of Theabennis, mother Tamarres (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Apynchis, grandson of Aunes, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabeinos, son of Petheus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Herakleia (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Sambathion, mother Taseus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herieus the older, son of Horos, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sempronius, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Nilous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 228)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabeinos, son of Petheus, grandson of Sambas, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor alias Sabeinos, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Satabous, mother Melitous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 182)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois, son of Naaraus the younger, grandson of Theabennis, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Petaus, grandson of Petaus, mother Tauris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Neilos, son of Louppos, grandson of Horos, mother Ammonarion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 190)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles, son of Apollonios, grandson of Petoraipis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Heras the older, grandson of Herakles, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios, son of Onnophris, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Ptolema (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 157)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion, son of Petsiris, grandson of Pasion, mother Thases (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Tapsais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Sisois, grandson of Petsiris, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aunes, son of Aunes, grandson of Hermas, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 157)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Longinus alias Gemellus, fatherless, mother Taphois (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 185)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hermation, slave of Isidoros alias Longinus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anoubas, son of Horos, grandson of Anoubas, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 151)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Satabous, mother Tkollauthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 243)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Achillas, grandson of Onnophris, mother Didymarion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petermouthis, son of Kastor, grandson of Heraklas, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptollas, son of Sabeinos, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Vettia (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 221)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hatres, son of Petheus, grandson of Herakles, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 156)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles, brother with the same mother (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Samanelais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>" (Column) 2[6]:;Ptolemaios, son of Apollonios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 20;;Petheus, brother with the same mother, drachmas 12;;Besis, son of Petheus, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;Sambas, son of Onnophris, grandson of Sambas, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Naaraus the older, grandson of Theabennis, mother Tamarres, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Apynchis, grandson of Aunes, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 88, obols 28;;Sabeinos, son of Petheus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Herakleia, drachmas 8;;Maron, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Sambathion, mother Taseus, drachmas 8;;Herieus the older, son of Horos, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Harmiysis, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tasoucharion, obols 28;;Sempronius, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Nilous, drachmas 16;;Sabeinos, son of Petheus, grandson of Sambas, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4, obols 20;;Kastor alias Sabeinos, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Satabous, mother Melitous, drachmas 4;;Sisois, son of Naaraus the younger, grandson of Theabennis, mother Thaisas, obols 28;;Horos, son of Petaus, grandson of Petaus, mother Tauris, drachmas 4;;Neilos, son of Louppos, grandson of Horos, mother Ammonarion, drachmas 8;;in total for the day drachmas 64, obols 18;;Herakles, son of Apollonios, grandson of Petoraipis, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 8;;Sarapion, son of Heras the older, grandson of Herakles, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 28;;Aphrodisios, son of Onnophris, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Ptolema, drachmas 4;;Pasion, son of Petsiris, grandson of Pasion, mother Thases, drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Tapsais, drachmas 4, obols 28;;Onnophris, son of Sisois, grandson of Petsiris, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Aunes, son of Aunes, grandson of Hermas, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4, obols;;Longinus alias Gemellus, fatherless, mother Taphois, drachmas 16;;Hermation, slave of Isidoros alias Longinus, drachmas 16;;Anoubas, son of Horos, grandson of Anoubas, mother Tepheros, drachmas 4;;Chairemon, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Satabous, mother Tkollauthis, drachmas 40;;for the 12th year the same, copper drachmas 4;;Heron, son of Achillas, grandson of Onnophris, mother Didymarion, drachmas 12;;Petermouthis, son of Kastor, grandson of Heraklas, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 12;;Pakysis, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tepheros, drachmas 4;;Ptollas, son of Sabeinos, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Vettia, drachmas 20;;in total for the day drachmas 192, obols 27 of which for the 12th year drachmas 4;;Phamenoth;11;;Hatres, son of Petheus, grandson of Herakles, mother Thaesis, drachmas 28;;Herakles, brother with the same mother, drachmas 28;;Pharmouthi 13;;Heras, son of Samanelais, drachmas 12."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 -- CPJ 3, 492 (lines with Sambathion); BL III, 113 (on l. 1084). Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3700&amp;viewid=4171_26R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/6/r/4171_26r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3700&amp;viewid=4171_26R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3700&amp;viewid=4171_26R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
