<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>receipts</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1431</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1431</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.16.12332</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;16;12332</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;16;12332</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14587a 14587b 14587c 14587d 14587e 14587f 14587g 14587h</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14587 14587 14587 14587 14587 14587 14587 14587</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1434</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Recto contains five receipts forsyntaximon paid by three individuals: a. A shepherd, son of Mysthas and Aplonia from late in the reign of Nero; b. an unskilled laborer, Herakles, son of Pasion, grandson of Herakles, with a mother Thaesis, daughter of Nepheros, from year 13 of of Nero (= 66/67 A.D.). Nos. 4 and 5 (=col. I, lines 10-16; 17-20), dated to two different years early in the reign of Vespasian (line 10, note ad loc.); c.  a workman, (no. 3 = col. III, lines 31-43); the receipt is for year 2 of Galba (= 68/69 A.D.).; he first column of the verso contains two receipts for beer tax (nos. 6 and 7). Second column begins with an additional receipt for beer tax (no. 9). The last receipt in the second column is also severely damaged (no. 10 = ll. 60-64), yet it too may be a receipt for beer tax.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto + Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ 1961a</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 31 x 21.7 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The papyrus is a fragmentary roll with only its upper margins still intact. A kollesis occurs at 16.5 cm. from the left edge, and the right end of the first sheet extends 1.5 cm. over the left edge  of the succeeding sheet.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">64</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto + Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The five receipts for syntaximon were written on the recto by the same scribe in a large, elegant, and easy-to-read cursive. The scribe seems first to have set out the three columns across the top: these are the earliest receipts chronologically and a different column was alotted to each tax payer. In col. I, lines 10-20, the writing becomes more and more crowded within the two receipts dated to the reign of Vespasian (nos. 4 and 5), perhaps because by the time of their copying onto the roll, the top of col. II had already received its receipt (nos. 2). A space of 2.5 cm. was left blank at the top for margin, and 2 cm. for intercolumnar spaces. The first column, with right-hand portions of three receipts (nos. 1, 4, 5) is broken at left throughout its length, and at bottom in the middle of the third receipt in the column (no. 5). There is no space between receipts nos. 4 and 5 (lines 10-20); 6.5 cm. was left blank at the right end of line 9 at the close of receipt no. 11, thus separating it from those which follow below. The center column, with one nearly complete receipt (no. 2), is lost only at the bottom margin. The third column preserves the first four to nine letters of another receipt (no. 3).;The five receipts on the verso were written by three different scribes, with the same scribe apparently responsible for nos. 7, 8, 10. The scribes of the verso wrote in a more cramped and more cursive style than the scribe of the recto. The first column breaks off at bottom as another receipt (no. 8) commences. The individual receipts are separated both vertically and horizontally by blank spaces so that each is distinct; the final receipt (no. 10) is the most isolated, set 4.5 cm. below and 4 cm. to the right of the preceding receipt.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0066" notAfter="0071">66/71 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Philadelphia, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">[NN],  son of Mysthes, his mother Aplonia, daughter of [NN]</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Imperator Caesar Vespasianus Augustus, emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonios, cheiristes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles, son of Pasion, grandson of Herakles, with a mother Thaesis, daughter of Nepheros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Servius Galba Imperator Caesar Augustus, emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petermouthis, presbyter</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Philadelphia, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Philadelphia</term>
               <term>Receipts (Acknowledgments)--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Shepherds--Taxation--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Swine--Taxation--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Beer--Taxation--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>No. 1, recto, col. II, lines 1 - 9: "In the ? year of Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, Phaophi 24, [NN], a shepherd, son of Mysthes, whose mother was Aplonia, daughter of [NN], paid through [NN] the cheiristes hissyntaximon of Philadelphia for the same year in debased silver, eighth drachmas equal 8 drachmas; and on the ? of the month Neos Sebastou 8 drachmas equal 8 drachmas; and on the 24th of the month Neroneios Sebastos four drachmas equal 4 drachmas; and on the ? four drachmas equal 4 drachmas; and for the accounting on the 30th of Mecheir bu paid on 9th of Phamenoth eight drachmas equal 8 drachmas; and on the ? four dracmas equal 4 drachmas; and on the 29th of Pauni four drachmas equal 4 drachmas; and on the ? four drachmas equal 4 drachmas; . . .";No. 4, recto, col. I, 10-16: "In the ? year of Imperator Caesar Vespasianus Augustus , on the ?,  Herakles, son of Pasion, grandson of Herakles, with a mother Thaesis, daughter of Nepheros,;has paid through Apollonios, cheiristes, his syntaximon of Philadelphia for the same year in debased silver, eight drachmas and 2 chalkoi equal 8 drachmas and 2 chalkoi, and for swine tax   1 drachma and an obol; and on the ? of ? ? (= amount); and onthe 28th of Choiak four drachmas equal 4 drachmas; and on the ? of ? ? (= amount); and on the 30th of Phamenoth eight drachmas equal 8 drachmas; and on the ? of Pachon ? drachmas; and on the 14th of ? four drachmas equal 4 drachmas; and . . .";No. 5, recto, col. I, lines 17-20: "In the ? year of Imperator Caesar Vespasianus  Augustus, on the ? of Phaophi, Herakles, son of Pasion, grandson of Herakles, with a mother Thaesis, daughter of Nepheros, paid through Apollonios, cheiristes, his syntaximon of Philadelphia for the same year  in debased silver ? drachmas and two chalkoi, and his swine tax 1 drachma and an obol; and . . .";No. 2, recto, col. II, lines 21-30: "In the thirteenth year of Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, on 29 Phaophi, Herakles, son of Pasion, grandson of Herakles, ann unskilled laborer, whose mother was Thaesis, daughter of Nepheros, paid through Apollonios, cheiristes, his syntaximon of Philadelphia for the same year in debased silver, eight drachmas equal 8 drachmas; and on 24th of Neroneios Sebastos four drachmas and 2 chalkoi equal 4 drachmas 2 chalkoi, for pig tax 1 dracma 1 obol; and on the 17th of Tybi, four drachmas equal 4 drachmas; for the accounting on the 30th of Mecheir, but paid on the 9th of Phamenoth, eight drachmas equal 8 drachmas; and the 30th of Phamenoth four drachmas equal 4 drachmas, and . . .";No. 3, recto, col. III, lines 31-43: In the 2nd year of Servius Galba Imperator Caesar Augustus, on the ?th of ?, NN, an unskilled worker has paid through Apollonios, cheiristes, his syntaximon of Philadelphia of the same year. . . in the month of Neos Sebastos . . . and on the 21st of Choiak . . .; anon the ? of Mecheir . . . of Caesar Augustus . . .  the same . equal 8 drachmas, and for swine tax 1 drachma and 1 obol . . .";No. 6, verso, col. I, lines 44-47: (Hd. 2) "In the 14th year of Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, on the 4th of Tybi, Herakles, son of Pasion, paid his beer tax of Philadelphia in person through Petermouthis, one of the presbyters of the village, for the 13th year, four drachmas equal 4 drachmas; and on the21st of Phamenoth three drachmas and 4 obols equal 3 drachmas and 4 obols.";No. 7, verso, col. I, lines 48-53 (hd. 3): "In the 2nd year of Servius Galba Imperator Caesar Augustus, on the 29th of Choiak Herakles, son of Pasion, paid in person, through Petermuthis, his tax of Philadelphia on his account, four drachmas  equal 4 drachmas; and on Phamenoth 4 drachmas and 3 obols, in total 3 drachmas and 4 obols. . . ;No. 8, verso, col. I, line 53: ". . . of Vespasianus . . .";No. 9, verso, col. II, lines 54-58 (hd. 4): "In the 3rd year of Imperator Caesar Vespasianus Augustus, on the 1st of Tybi Herakles paid, through Pet[  , his beer tax (?) of Philadelphia for the same 3rd year, 4 drachmas equal 4 drachmas; and on the 20th of Mecheir three drachmas and 4 obols, equal 3 drachmas and 4 obols.";No. 10, verso, col. II, lines 59-64 (hd. 3): "In the year . . ."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Hanson AE, BASP 19, 47-60, 1982, Photo -- SB XVI 12332</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:16:12332</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1431&amp;viewid=1434R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/3/4/r/1434r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1431&amp;viewid=1434R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1431&amp;viewid=1434R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/3/4/v/1434v.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1431&amp;viewid=1434V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1431&amp;viewid=1434V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
