<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3295</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3295</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer paying the poll-tax is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 155-156: 37.5 x 30.4 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 156: nearly complete (papyrus cut off right of col. 156 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 156: 28 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 156 (l. 2766-2793)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius Iulius Maximus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 159)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maximion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor alias Sabinus son of Ptolemaios and Melidous (Melitous) grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 182)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois son of Onnophris and Tapetheus grandson of Akousilaos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron son of Ptolemaios and Taseus grandson of Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius Valerius Syros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed), hiereus of Zeus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apynchis son of Petermouthis and Thermouthis grandson of Apynchis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 154)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Petermouthis and Thermouthis grandson of Apynchis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Pnepheros and Thaesis grandson of Phanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion son of Kanis and Thermouthis grandson of Anchophis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron son of Pekmeis alias Heuremon and Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Patkonnis son of Mysthes and Taonnophris grandson of Patkonnis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 200)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Athenion son of Naaraus and Demarous grandson of Theabenis (Theabennis) (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 150)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinus son of Pasoknopaios and Tapetheus grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabous son of Dioskoros and Taorion (Tahorion) grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 226)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Satabous and Theonis grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 220)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(Ptolemaios alias) Kelleros (Celer) son of Aphrodisios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Guards troops--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Priests--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Zeus (Greek deity)</term>
               <term>Real property tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax exemption--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Diseases--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 156;;(Mesore 3, continued);;Gaius Iulius Maximus - (through) Maximion - 'for garden land' of year 13: for apomoira, 20 drachmai 3 obols; for olive (transportation), 3 drachmai; for naubion, 2 drachmai 1/2 obol 2 chalkoi; for supplements, 5 drachmai 1 obol 2 chalkoi; for eparourion, 13 drachmai 5 1/2 obols; for supplements, 1 drachme 1/2 obol; for kollybos, 4 1/2 obols 2 chalkoi. Total: 46 drachmai 5 1/2 obols 2 chalkoi.;(And) for the naubion of the catoeci, for year 14: 1 drachme; for supplements: 1/2 obol 2 chalkoi; for kollybos: 2 chalkoi. Total: 1 drachme 1 obol.;(And) for the naubion of owners of private land, similarly: 1 drachme 1 1/2 obols 2 chalkoi; for supplements: 1 1/2 obols 2 chalkoi; for kollybos, 2 chalkoi. Total: 1 drachme 3 1/2 obols 2 chalkoi. (In left margin: 48 drachmai 21 obols.);Kastor also called Sabinus, son of Ptolemaios and Melidous, grandson of Satabous, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Sisois, son of Onnophris and Tapetheus, grandson of Akousilaos, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Maron, son of Ptolemaios and Taseus, grandson of Sambathion: 4 drachmai;Gaius Valerius Syros - (through) the priest of Zeus - for garden land of year 13: for apomoira, 4 drachmai 1/2 obol; for olive (transportation), 1 drachme; for naubion, 21/2 obols 2 chalkoi; for supplements, 1 drachme 1 obol; for eparourion, 2 drachmai 4 1/2 obols; for supplements, 1 1/2 obols; for kollybos, 1 obol. Total: 9 drachmai 5 obols 2 chalkoi.;(And) for the naubion of the catoeci, for year 14: 4 obols; for supplements: 1/2 obol; for kollybos: 2 chalkoi. Total: 4 1/2 obols 2 chalkoi. (In left margin: 8 drachmai 26 obols.);Apynchis, son of Petermouthis and Thermouthis, grandson of Apynchis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Ptolemaios, his brother, (born) of the same mother, diseased, for the guards: 4 drachmai;Total for the day: 240 drachmai 7 obols.;;On the 4th, similarly:;Onnophris, son of Pnepheros and Thaesis, grandson of Phanomgeus, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Horion, son of Kanis and Thermouthis, grandson of Anchophis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Heron, son of Pekmeis also called Heuremon and Sambathion, for ch(--): 8 drachmai;Patkonnis, son of Mysthes and Taonnophris, grandson of Patkonnis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Athenion, son of Naaraus and Demarous, grandson of Theabenis: 12 drachmai;Sabinus, son of Pasoknopaios and Tapetheus, grandson of Horos, for ch(--): 28 obols;Satabous, son of Dioskoros and Taorion, grandson of Satabous, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Ptolemaios, son of Satabous and Theonis, grandson of Horos, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Kelleros, son of Aphrodisios, for garden land of year 13: for apomoira, 2 drachmai 3 obols; for olive (transportation), 2 obols 2 chalkoi; for naubion,  11/2 obols; for supplements, 3 1/2 obols 2 chalkoi; for eparourion, 1 drachme 4 obols; for supplements, 1 obol; for kollybos, 1/2 obol 2 chalkoi. Total: 5 drachmai 4 obols 2 chalkoi. (In left margin:) 4 drachmai 17 obols.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 156 (l. 2766-2793), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3295&amp;viewid=4172_37R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3295&amp;viewid=4172_37R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3295&amp;viewid=4172_37R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
