<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3819</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3819</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 31.4 x 29.7 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at the left and at the right. Kollesis in the middle of the sheet. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-34</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 56 (ll. 2280-2314)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Longinia Ptolemais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 185)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Euhemeros, son of Euhemeros, grandson of Keras, mother Tauris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Charis, daughter of Chairemon (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron (Arab archer) (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Satabous, grandson of Horos, mother Theonis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 220)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Menches, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thases (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Petaus, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Petsiris, grandson of Heras, mother Isidora (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor, son of Petheus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Herakleia (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Soeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 194)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Petheus, grandson of Petaus, mother Tapasion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Esouris, son of Kames, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Paouites, son of Petheus, grandson of Phaseis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis, son of Phaseis, grandson of Esouris, mother Tanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Artemis, daughter of Ammonios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 156)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambous, daughter of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 224)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kames, son of Elekis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 56:;tax on land plots in release likewise drachmas 2 obols 3.5, surcharges obols 3 chalki 2, kollybos obol 0.5, in total drachmas 3 obol 1 chalki 2;;tax on revenue from rent for the 12th year drachmas 20, surcharges drachma 1 obol 1 chalki 2, in total drachmas 21 obol 1.5 chalki 2;;And Longinia Ptolemais;;naubion for lots in release for the 13th year drachma 1 obols 2, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachma 1 obols 4;;Euhemeros, son of Euhemeros, grandson of Keras, mother Tauris, drachmas 16;;Charis, daughter of Chairemon (of Heron, Arab archer);;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 3 obols 4.5, tax on the produce of olives obols 3 chalki 2, naubion obols 2 chalki 2, surcharges obols 5.5 chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 2 obols 3, surcharges obol 1 chalki2, kollybos obol 1, in total drachmas 8 obols 3;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 9 obols 2 chalki 2, surcharges obols 3.5, in total drachmas 10;;naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year obols 2, surcharges chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total obols 2.5;;in total for the day drachmas 192 obols 14.;(Pharmouthi) 20 likewise:;Ptolemaios, son of Satabous, grandson of Horos, mother Theonis, drachmas 4;;Onnophris, son of Menches, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thases, drachmas 4;;Pnepheros, son of Petaus, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Tauris, obols 28;;Heras, son of Petsiris, grandson of Heras, mother Isidora, drachmas 8;;Kastor, son of Petheus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Herakleia, drachmas 16;;Onnophris, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Orsenouphis, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Soeris, drachmas 4;;Petaus, son of Petheus, grandson of Petaus, mother Tapasion, obols 28;;Esouris, son of Kames, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Paouites, son of Petheus, grandson of Phaseis, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Pakysis, son of Phaseis, grandson of Esouris, mother Tanomgeus, drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 60 obols 27.;(Pharmouthi) 21 likewise:;Artemis, daughter of Ammonios (Orsenouphis (auloi-player));;(in left margin: to Sarap(), drachmas 20 obols 7) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 4 obol 0.5, tax on the produce of olives obols 3.5, naubion obols 2.5, surcharges drachma 1 chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 2 obols 4.5, surcharges obol 1.5, kollybos obol 1, in total drachmas 9 obol 1.5 chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 10 obol 1, surcharges obols 4, in total drachmas 10 obols 5;;Sambous, daughter of Petheus (Kames, son of Elekis);;(in left margin: to Sarap() drachmas 8 obols 8) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachma 1 obol 4, tax on the produce of olives obol 1.5, naubion obol 1, surcharges obols 2.5;;eparourion drachma 1 obol 0.5 chalki 2, surcharges obol 0.5, kollybos obol 0.5, in total drachmas 3 obols 5;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 4 obol 1, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 4, obols 2.5 chalki 2."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3819&amp;viewid=4171_56R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3819&amp;viewid=4171_56R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3819&amp;viewid=4171_56R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
