<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Official Document</title>
            <author>Unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.5199</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)5199</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.Inv. 445</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; fr. 1: 15.4 x 22.3 cm; fr.2: 10 x 24.4 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">fr. 1: This dark brown papyrus is badly mutilated and suffered damages, severely frayed and misaligned fibers in many parts, especially at the right to top and bottom. It broken off at all sides, it seems likely that it has the top margin. Some parts of the text are lost, some are washed out and some are legible. There are two patches seems to have been glued on to the verso to strengthen the document. Some dark blots are on some spots on the papyrus. There is no kollesis.;fr. 2: Dark brown papyrus of good quality; broken off at the left as a result of a vertical fold and badly damaged at the right sides; top and bottom margins are preserved. It seems that the papyrus was diagonally folded three times: two at the top and one at the bottom; t also was horizontally folded at the middle and caused a severe damage and the fibers are removed or frayed at that part. A tiny black hard soil is being attached to the lower part; there is a vertical lacuna about 7.0 cm from the bottom. There is no kollesis.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">13</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>fr. 1: Written along the fibers in large-sized cursive letters with ligatures; the hand is fast but practiced and ornamental; it has the characteristics of both 4th and 5th century; delta is flourishingly formed by drawing a small curved stroke with a curved stroke in a shape of a bow facing right; Big omega; eta has two legs with curved peak and a vertical stroke invades the interlinear space. The text is written in two columns with intercolumniation of ca. 2 cm. Second column only few letters at the beginning are survived. There is no diacritical marks, abbreviations or stichometry. Verso is blank;fr. 2: Written in black ink along the fibers in large-sized cursive ligatured letters; The hand is fast and ornamental; it used relatively a thin pen. Some letters such as rho and iota and even lambda invade the interlinear space. It seems likely that the scribe has dipped his pen into the inkwell before writing line 10. The interlinear spaces are not even and varied from ca. 2.0 cm (i.e. line 1 - 2; 13 - 14). There are no diacritical marks or signs are attested. Verso is blank</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0300" notAfter="0499">IVth-Vth Century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5199&amp;viewid=1">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
