<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>sale of house</title>
            <author>Aurelius [   ]apion, son of Heras and Alexandra</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1428</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1428</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.10.10728</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;10;10728</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;10;10728</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">17431</idno>
            <idno type="TM">17431</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1428</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>acknowledgement by Aurelius [   ]apion to Aurelius [    ]ion, both of Oxyrhynchus, of the sale of a house and cellar in the cityapparently registered in the name of the vendor's daughter.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 23.5 25 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This medium-brown papyrus is somewhat damaged, especially along the four vertical folds. The worst damage to the papyrus has occurred in the center, where small pieces of papyrus are missing. The papyrus was damaged in antiquity and roughly repaired with some small pieces of papyrus glued on to the verso. The text is complete except for the beginning of lines (about eleven lines are missing on average).</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-27</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The body of the document is written in a formal upright documentary hand. The subscription of the vendor is in a more slanting and less formal cursive hand, while finally the document has been docketed by a notary in a cursive hand.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0318">318 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Oxyrhynchus, Middle Egypt, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Licinius Augustus, emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Crispus, emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius [   ]apion, son of Heras and Alexandra</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius [    ]ion, son of Didymos and Thaesis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelia Alexandra</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Papnouthis, son of . . . and Tainois, grandson of Pengoous (?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelia . . ., daughter of . . . and Irene</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Dionysios, son of Patermouthios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dioskoros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chaeremon</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Oxyrhynchus, Middle Egypt, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Oxyrhinchites,;North Quay quarter of Oxyrhynchus,;Taleei, village in the lower Apollonopolite nome of the Thebaid (Heptakomias)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"In the consulship of our masters Licinius Augustus for the fifth time and Crispus the most noble Caesar for the first time.;Aurelius [   ]apion, son of Heras and Alexandra, from the illustrious and most illustrious city of the Oxyrhynchites, to Aurelius [   ]ion, son of Didymos and Thaesis, from the same city, greeting. I acknowledge that I have sold to you from the present time for ever the . . . empty house, beneath which is a cellar, with all its appurtenances, belonging to me in the same city of the North Quay quarter, bought by me and registered (?) in the name of my daughter Aurelia Alexandra who is under my power according to Roman law, formerly the property of Aurelius Papnouthis, an honourably discharged veteran, before his military service known as Papnouthis, son of . . . and Taionis, grandson of Pengoous (?), from the village of Taleei in the lower Apollonopolite nome of the Thebaid, in accordance with a . . . agreement drawn up on the 23rd of the month Pharmouthi of the present consulship, and before him (?) the property of Aurelia . . . daughter of . . . and Irene, from the same city, acting without a guardian by the ius liberorum (?), acting jointly with her husband Aurelius Dionysios, son of Patermouthios, from the same city: of which the boundaries are, on the south a public street, on the north a storeroom used by . . ., on the east property of Dioskoros, oil-merchant, on the west a public street beyond which is the Augusteum: and I have also surrendered to you for your security the agreements made over to me relating to previous ownership. (I have sold this property to you) at the price mutually agreed upon for the same house and cellar and all appurtenances, namely fourteen talents and four thousand drachmas of silver of the Imperial coinage, tot. 14 tal.  4,000 dr., which I have received from you forthwith in full from hand to hand, and in response to your question concerning this payment I have made acknowledgement. Wherefore from now on you shall own and possess the property with your descendants and successors, and shall further have power to use and manage it as you choose without hindrance: and I will of necessity deliver it to you guaranteed perpetually against all claims with every guarantee, and free from every debt and lien public and private and municipal and senatorial (?) and all other liabilities whatsoever. And every one who in any manner whatsoever proceeds against or claims this property, whether the whole or a part of it, I am of necessity to repel forthwith at my own expense, as if in consequence of a legal decision. This sale, written in . . . copies, is valid, and you shall whenever you choose have it registered without requiring any further approval from me, because I now approve the eventual registration, and in answer to the question whether this is rightly and fairly done I have made acknowledgement. In the same consulship, Pharmouthi 24.;(2nd hd.) I, Aurelius [    ]apion, have sold the aforesaid empty house and cellar with all appurtenances, and I have received the fourteen talents and four thousand drachmas of silver of the price, and I will guarantee the sale and I approve the registration; and in all respects as aforesaid in answer to the formal question I have acknowledgement. (3rd hd.) By me, Chaeremon."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Coles RA, TAPA 97, 55-61, 1966 -- SB X 10728 -- BLVI, 170 on line 3; BL VIII, 360 (l. 10; 23); BL X, 205 (l. 8)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:10:10728</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1428&amp;viewid=1428R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/8/r/1428r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1428&amp;viewid=1428R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1428&amp;viewid=1428R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
