<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Petition to a Strategos</title>
            <author>Aurelius Patas and Aurelius Kiales, sons of Papontheus</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1609</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1609</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.11.614</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;11;614</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;11;614</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21366</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21366</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 264</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Petition addressed to Aurelius Sarapion, strategos of the Oxyrhynchite nome, by the sons and heirs of Aurelius Papontheus, who were trying to collect a 34-years old debt that an Aurelius Horos contracted from their father. By this petition, they forward to the strategos the directive from the archidikastes (l. 5-8), written in compliance with their request to him (l. 9-48), which itself included a copy of the original loan contract (l. 15-33). A copy of the present petition was to be served on the debtor, which would constitue an order to pay which the debtor was required to meet within ten days.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 13.4 x 21 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Broken off at the bottom, as well as on most of the left side; quite demaged along the folds</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">48</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0259">ca. 259 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Oxyrhynchus, Oxyrhynchite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Sarapion, strategos of the Oxyrhynchite nome</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Patas son of Papontheus and Kopria</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Kiales son of Papontheus and Kopria</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">. . .ius Titus alias Herakleides, hiereus, archidikastes kai (ho) pros te epimeleia ton chrematiston kai ton allon kriterion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Valerianus, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gallienus, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Valerianus (Saloninus), Caesar</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) hoi pros te dialoge</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Chairemon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) chrematistai</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Papontheus son of Aniketos and Tauris, deceased father of Patas and Kiales</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Horos son of Papontheus and Didyme</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Severus Alexander, (former) Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Androneikos (Andronikos) (apator) son of Phil[. . .]</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tiberius ... Dionysios</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>probably Oxyrhynchus, Oxyrhynchite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Oxyrhynchite nome; Oxyrhynchon polis (Oxyrhynchiton polis); polis (Alexandria); Hadriane bibliotheke; bibliotheke tou Nanaiou</term>
               <term>Administration</term>
               <term>Archives</term>
               <term>Debt</term>
               <term>Inheritance</term>
               <term>Justice</term>
               <term>Loan</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>To Aurelius Sarapion, strategos of the Oxyrhynchite nome, from Aurelius Patas and Aurelius Kiales, both sons of Papontheus and Kopria, from the city of Oxyrhynchus. Here is a copy I have obtained from the katalogeion of my application for inactment of publication.;  . . .ius Titus also called Herakleides, the priest and archidikastes, to the strategos of the Oxyrhynchite nome, greetings. Let a copy of the application that was submitted be served. Farewell. Year 3 of the Valeriani and Gallienus, Augusti, . . . Signed by those in charge of the dialoge of the city, acting through me, Aurelius Chairemon.;  To . . .ius Titus also called Herakleides, priest, archidikastes, and superintendent of the chrematistai and of the other courts, from Aurelius Patas and Aurelius Kiales, both sons of Papontheus and Kopria, from the city of Oxyrhynchus. Appended is a copy of the cheirograph in duplicate that was issued to our father, Aurelius Papontheus, whose heirs we are, including the subscription after the date.;  Aurelius Horos, son of Papontheus and Didyme, from the city of Oxyrhynchus, to Aurelius Papontheus, son of Aniketos and Tauris, from the same city, greetings. I acknowledge that I have received and have had measured out from you, from the wheat crop of the past 4th year, six and a half artabai, with interest on the principal of an equal amount; total, thirteen artabai. &lt;And these I will return by such-and-such a date&gt; without any delay or excuse. And if I do not make the repayment as I have had written, I will pay the stated capital plus one-half, and also an addition for the overtime, with the paralemptic measure of Nicias the agoranome, by which I received the loan. And you shall have the right of execution against me and all my property as if in consequence of a court decision. This cheirograph, written in duplicate, is valid wherever presented and for whoever presents it on your behalf. As for this being good and proper, I have been asked the formal question and have so declared. Year 5 of the Emperor Caesar Marcus Aurelius Severus Alexander Pius Felix Augustus, Choiak 8. I, Aurelius Horos, son of Papontheus, have received the six and a half artabai of wheat to be repaid at an increase of the same amount, total thirteen artabai, and I will return them by the said deadline and measure them as stated. I, Aurelius Andronikos, styled the son of my mother Phil..., have written for him, as he is illiterate.;  Desiring that of this cheirograph in two copies a single copy be made public, we give the city, because a single copy is being published, the fixed 12 drachmai and the fee for publication, and we ask that you take this document from our representative Tiberius . . . Dionysios, signed by him to the effect that the subscription after the date is in the hand of the illliterate Aurelius Horos's signatory Aurelius Andronikos, and register it together with this application, the original in the Library of Hadrian and a duplicate copy thereof in that of the Nanaion; and to have an order written to the strategos of the Oxyrhynchite nome to have a copy of this application served . . . to produce Aurelius Horos approving of the publication, so that he may be informed and may return to me the six and a half artabai of wheat plus the increase according to my notification, or may know that I willl take the next appropriate steps concerning distraint [- - -]</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Shelton JC, PMich XI, 614, 1971, pl. IV -- BL VIII, 216 (l. 7; 23; date)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:11:614</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1609&amp;viewid=264R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/6/4/R/264R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1609&amp;viewid=264R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1609&amp;viewid=264R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
