<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>petition</title>
            <author>Isidoros, son of Isidoros</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1434</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1434</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.16.12713</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14651</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14651</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;16;12713dupl</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1440</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>This papyrus contains a copy of the petition partly preserved in P. Mich. inv. 1436 (cf. palaeographical description): inv. 1436, lines 2-10 recur in inv. 1440, lines 11-17. In this petition Isidoros, son of Isidoros, from Sophthis in the Memphite nome, protests the illegal behaviour of Tryphon, the strategos of the Arsinoite nome. Through his agents, Tryphon appears to have forced Isidoros to make s sworn statement (cheirographia) regarding the sowing of seed grain land at Philadelphia. Although Isidoros submitted the cheirographia as directed (inv. 1440.16 = inv. 1436.8-9), he came to resent the compulsion put upon him by Tryphon and his agents, and to consider the imposition, because he was from Sophthis in the Memphite nome, which was Isidoros' idia, and where he was registered for tax purposes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of the strategos Tryphon concerning his dispute with Isidoros, son of Isidoros, of Psophthis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 21 x 19.5 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This papyrus is badly damaged, and it has suffered irreparable damage after the first three lines. Therefore the text is incomplete: the top and side margins are only partially preserved; bottom margin entirely lost. A kollesis appears at a distance of 17 cm. from left margin.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-17</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in an elegant and upright cursive which finds parallels among other documents of the Augustan period  (cp. P. Mert. 1.8 = R. Seider, Palaeographie 1, no. 21, and P. Med. inv. 68.41 = SB 12.11016, photo in O. Montevecchi, La Papirologia, tav. 35). Numerous corrections and interlinear additions in inv. 1436 are missing in inv. 1440. Furthermore, the writer's last thoughts on lines 6, 8 and 9 in inv. 1436, recorded interlinearly (lines 6a and 8a) or cancelled (line 9), are not incorporated at these same points in the text of inv. 1440. Rather, inv. 1440 agrees with the text of 1436 before correction. The more likely assumption, then, is that inv. 1440 was a subsequent copy of inv. 1436. It is also likely that there were additional rewritings, now lost; this notion receives further support from the fact that although inv. is without correction, this clean copy was apparently not dispatched, but was unearthed together with the much-corrected copy, inv. 1436, presumably at Philadelphia, the village in the Arsinoite nome where the petitioner suffered the wrong to which he draws the attention of the prefect in the hope of redress (inv. 1440.8-9 = inv. 1436.2-3).</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0006">January (?), 6 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Philadelphia, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Publius Ostorius Scapula</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Isidoros, son of Isidoros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tryphon, strategos of the Arsinoite nome</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Philadelphia, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt (?)</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Psophthis in the Memphite nome,;Arsinoite nome,;Philadelphia of the Herakleides meris,</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[This translation incorporates the revisions introduced in inv . 1436. 6a-11.] ;"To Publius Ostorius Scapula;from Isidoros, son of Isidoros, from the village of Psophthis in the Memphite (nome). I am registered for laographia at the aforementoned village; as the case is, . . . the agents of Tryphon, strategos of the Arsinoite nome . . . compelled me in a torturous manner (?) . . . in Choiak of the current year to present a cheirographiainvolving sowing the land at the village of Philadelphia of the Herakleides division . . . five arourai, although neither I nor the men associated with me farm at Philadelphia. Since this is illegal, I beg you, the benefactor of all, if it seems good, to assign that an order be written to Tryphon not to dun me about these matters, because I am not from the nome, but to turn over to me the cheirographia referred to, so that I may be benefitted. Farewell."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Hanson AE, ZPE 47, 233-43, 1982, Pl XIV -- BL VIII, 385 (l. 4; 5-6; 10-11; date) Hanson AE, BASP 21, 82-3, 1984 -- SB XVI 12713 -- BL IX, 290; BL XI, 220</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:16:12713</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1434&amp;viewid=1440R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/4/0/r/1440r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1434&amp;viewid=1440R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1434&amp;viewid=1440R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
