<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of a Slave</title>
            <author>Thenpetermouthis, daughter of Hatres</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3105</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3105</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich;5;264_265dupl</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12098</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12098</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;264_265dupl</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 741</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract by which Thenpetermouthis, daughter of Hatres, sells to her two children Takounais and Tesenouphis the fifth a female slave named Tasouchas</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">The date is given by P.Mich. V, 265.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Mich. inv. 677 + 732; P.Mich. V, 265 (inv. 644 + 694) gives a duplicate of the subscriptions. - Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 6 x 23 cm (total size: 32.2 x 23.5 cm)</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">deeply frayed at the top and bottom, with much damage also at the breaks between the three fragments</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">29</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0037">February 7[?], 37 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">[Tiberius], Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thenpetermouthis daughter of Hatres</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Triadelphos also called Psenthneus son of Petermouthis Sabakous and Thenphatres, nephew &amp; guardian of Thenpetermouthis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thenphatres (daughter of Hatres), sister of Thenpetermouthis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Takonaeis (Takonais) = Takounais daughter of Pomsais (Phomsaeis) and Thenpetermouthis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tesenouphis son of Tesenouphis and Takounais, guardian of Takounais</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tesenouphis pemptos, son of Pomsaeis (Phomsais) and Thenpetermouthis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tasouchas, paidiske doule</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chales deuteros, son of Chales aliasTamas</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>[Tebtynis?], Polemonos meris, [Arsinoite] nome</term>
               <term>Family</term>
               <term>House ownership</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Sale</term>
               <term>Slave</term>
               <term>Woman (&amp;amp</term>
               <term>guardian)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[The twenty-third year of Tiberius] Caesar Augustus, [- - - in . . . of the division of] Polemon, of [the Arsinoite] nome. [Thenpetermouthis, daughter of Hatres], about . . . years old, [with a scar] on her throat at the right . . ., with [her guardian, the son] of her sister Thenphatres, Triadelphos, also called Psenthneus, son of [Petermouthis] Sabakous, [about . . . years old], with a scar on the left side of his forehead, acknowledges to [her daughter] Takonaeis, about . . . years old, with a mole on her nose [. . .], with her guardian, her son [Tesenouphis], son of Tesenouphis, about [. . .] years old, with a scar on the right side of his forehead [beneath the hair], and to her other son Tesenouthis the fifth, about 40 years old with a scar on his right knee, both of them being children of Pomsais, that she has sold to Takounais and Tesenouphis the fifth the young female slave that belongs to her, Thenpetermouthis, whose name is Tasouchas, and who is about seventeen years old, with somewhat inflamed eyelids, with a scar on her forehead at the right, such as she is, not to be rejected except for external claims and epilepsy; and she, Thenpetermouthis, acknowledges that she has received from Takounais and Tesenouphis the fifth the entire price agreed upon, in full, from hand to hand, out of the house; and that she, Thenpetermouthis, and her representatives guarantee Takounais and Tesenouphis the fifth and their representatives in accordance with this sale with every guarantee both from private debts and from every claim forever, except from running away; and that she will hand her over free from seizure, distraint, and mortgage, and clear of debts, while the former sale of the half share of the house and court, which Thenpetermouthis made to Takounais and Tesenouphis the fifth, and all the things set forth in it shall remain valid. The signatory of Thenpetermouthis and her guardian is Chales the second, son of Chales also called Tamas, about . . . years old, of middle height, with honey-colored skin, a long face, straight nose, and a scar beneath the right knee. This contract shall be valid everywhere.;(2nd hand) I, Thenpetermouthis, daughter of Hatres, with my guardian, the son of my sister Thenphatres, Triadelphos, also called Psenthneus, son of Petermouthis Sabakous, acknowledge that I have sold to my children, Takounais and Tesenouphis the fifth, both children of Pomsais, with the guardian of Takounais, her own son Tesenouphis, son of Tesenouphis, the young female slave that belongs to me, whose name is Tasouchas, who is seventeen years old, with somewhat inflamed eyelids and a scar on the right side of her forehead, such as she is, not to be rejected except for external claims and epilepsy. And I have received from Takounais and Tesenouphis the fifth, the entireprice fixed and agreed upon, in full, [from hand to hand], out of the house; and I guarantee them in accordance with this sale with every guarantee, except against flight; and I shall relinquish her free from external claims, security, and mortgage, not sold before, either in part, or mortgaged, the former sale of one half of a house and courtyard remaining valid for us as aforesaid. Chales the second, son of Chales also called Tamas, wrote for them since they are illiterate.;(3rd hand) Tesenouphis, son of Pomsais. The sale was made to me as aforesaid.;(4th hand) Takounais, daughter of Pomsais, with my guardian, my son Tesenouphis, son of Tesenouphis. The sale was made to me as aforesaid. I, Tesenouphis, [wrote for her] as she is illiterate.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 264, 1944 -- L. 6: read ek dex[ion, instead of eks ar[isteron. (PH)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:264</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3105&amp;viewid=677R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/7/7/R/677R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3105&amp;viewid=677R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3105&amp;viewid=677R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
