<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lease of Land</title>
            <author>Kronion, son of [- - -]</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3096</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3096</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.12.633</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;12;633</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;12;633</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12297</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12297</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 728</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract by which Kronion, son of [- - -], leases to Horos, son of Horos, and his two sons, Hermas and Horos, 13 arourai located in the vicinity of Theogonis for two years; one of the two parcels has to undergo a rotation of crops</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Duplicate of P.Mich. inv. 724. - Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 14 x 21 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">broken off at the top; badly frayed at the top and bottom; damaged along several folds</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">35</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>1st hand: a skilled and rather graceful cursive, very close to that of P.Yale 67 of 31 A.D.; 2nd and 3rd hands in an awkward, angular style. (Browne)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0030">ca. 30 A.D.[?]</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Saturninus (see P.Mich. XII, p. 23)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios son of Herodes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Horos, Perses tes epigones</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hermas son of Horos grandson of Horos, Perses tes epigones</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Horos grandson of Horos, Perses tes epigones</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Theogonis; Aigyptios; Perses</term>
               <term>Leases-- Egypt--Theogonis(Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Rent-- Egypt--Theogonis(Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Wheat--Egypt--Theogonis(Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Irrigation--Egypt--Theogonis(Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Agriculture--Egypt--Theogonis(Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Crop rotation--Egypt--Theogonis(Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Iranians--Egypt--Theogonis(Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Theogonis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[- - -] for the sowing of grass and aracus for thegrazing of sheep, without rent, Kronion, son of . . ., providing them(?) with seed, and the lessees maintaining the irrigation and dike systems and assuming the supervision of the green crops; and in the second year of the lease, for the same eight arourai to be used for the sowing of wheat, the rent in entirety, including eight artabai ofwheat which the lessees will receive as seed, in entirety is one hundred artabai of new, pure, unadulterated wheat, with a gratuity of one artabe of bread. For the other five arourai the rent in entirety per year, including two and one-half artabai of wheat which the lessees will receive as seed, in entirety per year is forty artabai of new, pure, unadulterated wheat, with a gratuity of one-half artaba of bread per year, all measured by the six-choinix measure of the granary of Saturninus.;This lease is free from every risk and every deduction, and the lessees will perform each year at the right time all the work on the allotment, viz. the requisite work on the dike and irrigation systems and in weeding and all the other agricultural tasks, and will cause no damage. The lessees will pay the designated rents each year in the month of Pauni and will transport them to the village of Theogonis. At the expiration of the period the lessees will surrender the allotment free from rushes, coarse grass, and all dirt, with the Egyptian reeds cut and the canal built up. It will, accordingly, not be permissible for the lessees to abandon the lease during the period.;Kronion guarantees the lease against public charges, irrespective of other debts which the lessees owe in accordance with a contract of loan and except for any lease which he (Kronion) has with him (sic) and anyone else.;Signatory for the lessees: Aphrodisios, son of Herodes, about 35 years of age, with a scar below his right shin.;(2nd hand) I, Horos, son of Horos, and my sons, Hermas and Horos, all three Persians of the epigone and mutual sureties for recovery,have leased the above-mentioned thirteen arourai for the aforementioned two years, irrespective of other debts, either debts which we owe to Kronion with a contract of loan and (sic) apart from any lease which he has with us and anyone else, as stated above. Aphrodisios, son of Herodes, wrote for them, as they are illiterate.;(3rd hand) I, Kronion, son of . . ., have leased and will guarantee, as stated above.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Browne GM, BASP 6, 5-9, 1969 -- SB X 10535 Browne GM, PMich XII, 633 (second copy), 1975</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:12:633</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3096&amp;viewid=728R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/8/R/728R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3096&amp;viewid=728R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3096&amp;viewid=728R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
