<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3652</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3652</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; this column contains two lines of writing at the top edge.</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 30 x 32.6 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at all sides except at the top where it has been torn off. Kollesis in the left column of writing.  (TC).</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-46</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 16 (ll. 596-642)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Kommonis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonios, son of Ammonios, grandson of Ammonios, mother Tninis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 151)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes, son of Petheus, grandson of Mysthes, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion, son of Kanis, grandson of Anchophis, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petsiris, son of Pasion, grandson of Petsiris, mother Taonnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 211)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Tkollainis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anoubas, son of Horos, grandson of Anoubas, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 151)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Tauris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 203)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petaus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchophis, son of Anchophis, grandson of Petheus, mother Taorsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Petheus, grandson of Onnophris, mother Taphaseis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 203)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hatres, son of Apollonios, grandson of Heraklas, mother Taorsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 156)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Petheus, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Stiynchis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Sisois, grandson of Petsiris, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron, son of Satabous, grandson of Maron, mother Tkonnos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Sokrates, mother Soeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Artemas, brother with the same mother (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 156)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kames, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Polyndikes, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Harpalos, grandson of Sarapion, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Petaus, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpagathes, son of Satabous, grandson of Anchophis, mother Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchophis, son of Horos, grandson of Anchophis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Sabeinos, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Gaia (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Patron, son of Sokmenis, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Taonnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 200)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonios, son of Harpagathes, grandson of Heras, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 151)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Taptosiris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, brother with the same mother (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion, son of Petheus, grandson of Sambathion, mother Tathautis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron, son of Maron, grandson of Petoraipis, mother Herois (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Sokmenis, grandson of Sambas, mother Tkollainis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 224)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Esouris, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Esouris, grandson of Petheus, mother Tkollauthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>" (Column) 16:;Horion, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Kommonis, drachmas 8;;Ammonios, son of Ammonios, grandson of Ammonios, mother Tninis, drachmas 4;;Mysthes, son of Petheus, grandson of Mysthes, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 4;;Horos the younger, son of Hatres, grandson of Horos, mother Teraus, drachmas 4;;Onnophris, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis, obols 28;;Horion, son of Kanis, grandson of Anchophis, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;Petsiris, son of Pasion, grandson of Petsiris, mother Taonnophris, drachmas 8;;Petesouchos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Tkollainis, drachmas 8;;Anoubas, son of Horos, grandson of Anoubas, mother Tepheros, drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 28, obols 28;;(Tybi) 25 likewise:;Petheus, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Tauris, guard tax , drachmas 8;;Petesouchos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petaus, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8;;Anchophis, son of Anchophis, grandson of Petheus, mother Taorsenouphis, drachmas 8;;Petheus, son of Petheus, grandson of Onnophris, mother Taphaseis, drachmas 12;;Hatres, son of Apollonios, grandson of Heraklas, mother Taorsenouphis, drachmas 8, obols 28;;Petaus, son of Petheus, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Stiynchis, drachmas 16, obols 16;;12th year the same, ? copper drachmas of the priests;;Onnophris, son of Sisois, grandson of Petsiris, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Maron, son of Satabous, grandson of Maron, mother Tkonnos, drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 72, obols 27 of which 12th year obols 12;;Ptolemaios, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Sokrates, mother Soeris, drachmas 20;;Artemas, brother with the same mother, drachmas 20;;Kames, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Polyndikes, mother Thaesis, drachmas 12;;Sarapion, son of Harpalos, grandson of Sarapion, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 8;;Pnepheros, son of Petaus, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8;;Harpagathes, son of Satabous, grandson of Anchophis, mother Sambathion, drachmas 8;;Anchophis, son of Horos, grandson of Anchophis, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;In total for the day drachmas 76;;(Tybi) likewise:;12th year Heron, son of Sabeinos, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Gaia, copper drachmas 4;;Patron, son of Sokmenis, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Taonnophris, drachmas 4;;Ammonios, son of Harpagathes, grandson of Heras, mother Segathis, drachmas 4, obols 28;;Heron, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Heras, drachmas 4;;Phanomgeus, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Taptosiris, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, brother with the same mother, drachmas 4;;Pasion, son of Petheus, grandson of Sambathion, mother Tathautis, drachmas 12;;Maron, son of Maron, grandson of Petoraipis, mother Herois, drachmas 8, obols 28;;Sambas, son of Sokmenis, grandson of Sambas, mother Tkollainis, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Esouris, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Petaus, son of Esouris, grandson of Petheus, mother Tkollauthis, drachmas 4;;[in total for the day drachmas 60, obols] s (?)[7, of which 12th year drachmas 4].";(Verso): "Hadrianos 21 until Tybi 11."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 -- CPJ 3, 492 (lines with Sambathion); on the verso: line 1, ade. . . ; line 2, Tybi ia; Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3652&amp;viewid=4171_16R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3652&amp;viewid=4171_16R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3652&amp;viewid=4171_16R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3652&amp;viewid=4171_16V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3652&amp;viewid=4171_16V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
