<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3292</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3292</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer paying the poll-tax is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 153-154: 34.7 x 29.4 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 153: nearly complete (papyrus cut off left of col. 153 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 153: 28 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 153 (l. 2690-2717)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Pasoknopaios and Tapetheus grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron son of Maron and Herois grandson of Petoraipis (Petsoraipis) (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Diodoros son of Thaisas, apator (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Leonides son of Ptolemaios and Heras grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 184)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Agathopous, doulos of Taseus alias Isarion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 148)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis son of Petheus and Tapetheus grandson of Horion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 194)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis son of Heron and Zoidous grandson of Orsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 193)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymion son of Petheus presbyteros and Tasoucharion grandson of Didymion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 161)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron son of Petheus and Taorsenouphis grandson of Kollouthos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Artemidoros and Thaesis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Harpagathes and Segathis grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Petaus and Segathis grandson of Orsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 203)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus son of Petheus and Tapasion grandson of Petaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois son of Limnaios and Thaesis grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis son of Kalatoites (Kalatytes) and Segathis grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 195)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodous daughter of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apynchis son of Tiotiseitias (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 154)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Esouris son of Kames and Thaesis grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras son of Melanas and Tamystha grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Petheus and Thaesis grandson of Sokmenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles son of Apollonios and Tapetheus grandson of Petoraipis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides son of Esouris and Taonnophris grandson of Kollouthos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron son of Sabinus and Gaia grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Illegitimacy--Egypt</term>
               <term>Slaves--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Real property tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Women--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Elders (Church officers)--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col. 153);;(Mesore 1, continued);;Petheus, son of Pasoknopaios and Tapetheus, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Maron, son of Maron and Herois, grandson of Petoraipis: 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Diodoros, of unknown father, his mother being Thaisas, for ch(--): 8 drachmai;Leonides, son of Ptolemaios and Heras, grandson of Pnepheros, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Agathopous, slave of Taseus also called Isarion, for ch(--): 8 drachmai;Orsenouphis, son of Petheus and Tapetheus, grandson of Horion, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Orsenouphis, son of Heron and Zoidous, grandson of Orsenouphis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Didymion, son of Petheus the elder and Tasoucharion, grandson of Didymion, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Heron, son of Petheus and Taorsenouphis, grandson of Kollouthos, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Ptolemaios, son of Artemidoros and Thaesis, grandson of Petheus: 12 drachmai;Ptolemaios, son of Harpagathes and Segathis, grandson of Heras: 4 drachmai 28 obols;Petheus, son of Petaus and Segathis, grandson of Orsenouphis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Petaus, son of Petheus and Tapasion, grandson of Petaus, for ch(--): 28 obols;Sisois, son of Limnaios and Thaesis, grandson of Satabous: 4 drachmai, (and) for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Pakysis, son of Kalatoites and Segathis, grandson of Heras, for ch(--): 8 drachmai;Aphrodous, daughter of Horos - (through) Apynchis, son of Tiotiseitias - for garden land of year 13: for apomoira, 1 drachme 5 obols 2 chalkoi; for olive (transportation), 2 obols; for naubion, 1 obol 2 chalkoi; for supplements, 3 obols; for eparourion, 1 drachme 1 1/2 obols; for supplements, 1/2 obol; for kollybos, 1/2 obol. Total: 4 drachmai 2 obols.;(And) for the naubion of the catoeci, for year 14: 4 obols; for supplements: 1/2 obol; for kollybos: 2 chalkoi. Total: 4 1/2 obols 2 chalkoi (In left margin: 4 drachmai 14 obols.);Esouris, son of Kames and Thaesis, grandson of Heras, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Heras, son of Melanas and Tamystha, grandson of Petheus, for ch(--): 8 drachmai;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus and Thaesis, grandson of Sokmenis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Herakles, son of Apollonios and Tapetheus, grandson of Petoraipis, for ch(--): 8 drachmai;Total for the day: 252 drachmai 23 obols.;;On the 2nd, similarly:;Herakleides, son of Esouris and Taonnophris, grandson of Kollouthos, for ch(--): 12 drachmai;Heron, son of Sabinus and Gaia, grandson of Pnepheros: 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(--): 4 drachmai</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 153 (l. 2690-2717), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3292&amp;viewid=4172_36R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3292&amp;viewid=4172_36R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3292&amp;viewid=4172_36R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
