<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A school text</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3806</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3806</idno>
            <idno type="dclp">107875</idno>
            <idno type="TM">107875</idno>
            <idno type="dclp-hybrid">p.rain.unterrichtkopt;;207</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 926</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>The folio appears to be a school exercise book in Bohairic Coptic. The exercise consists of making syllables by combining the consonants with each of the seven vowels in order. On this sheet final consonants lambda, my, sigma, and kappa are added.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Copt">Coptic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 16.6 x 26.3 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The codex in its original form was probably made up of four double leaves. Of these, two have been broken away, but two remain together, sewed on the middle line with a single loop of light-brown two-strand cord, ca. 4.5 cm. long and 9 cm. from the bottom of the page, tied at the back with a rather elaborate knot. It is possible that more folios might have been included in the original quire, but from the contents it seems unlikely. The size of each folio is 17. 5 x 22 cm. where the complete width and height are preserved. The papyrus is light-brown in color and is of rather poor quality, being marred by strips of varying thickness and by discolored streaks. One would naturally not expect to papyrus of the highest quality used for a school work book.;Folios 1 and 8, 3 and 6, and 4 and 5 are joined. The blank piece of papyrus listed as folio 7 is probably the right half of the double spread of which folio 2 forms the left half, but it is not possible to be sure of this, since the edges of both are broken and the fibers cannot be traced across with certainty. Since folios 6 and 8 are entirely blank, it is entirely probable that folio 7 also was not used.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-126</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: folio 2</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The writing of folio 2r and of the first two lines of the first column on the verso is in a different and more cursive hand than the rest of the manuscript, perhaps the hand of the teacher, who may have written it as a sample for the pupil to copy. This hand is, indeed, very like Greek cursive hands of the late third-fourth century, although there are too many uncials and and too few ligatures to establish its character with certainty.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0300" notAfter="0399">IVth century A.D. (?)</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Theadelphia, Themistou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt (?)</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Theadelphia, Themistou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt (?)</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Copt">Coptic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>-</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">subliterary; school-exercise</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>-</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, JNES 6, 129-51, 1947</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3806&amp;viewid=926_2R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3806&amp;viewid=926_2R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3806&amp;viewid=926_2R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
