<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3821</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3821</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 36.7 x 29.8 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at the left and at the right. Kollesis left of center. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-34</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 57 (ll. 2315-2349)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petsiris, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Petsiris, mother Heros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Harphaesis, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tapontos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpalos, his son, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius Julius Petronianus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 159)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didyme, daughter of Pakysis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 161)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraklas, son of Leonides, grandson of Kastor, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 166)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion, son of Lupus, grandson of Horos, mother Ammonarion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herieus, son of Sambas, grandson of Peteesis, mother Tapapeis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Peteesis, grandson of Apollonios, mother Tanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 223)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius Julius Apolinarios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 159)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apolinarios, son of Sarapas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 152)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Theon, katandrographos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 177)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dioskoros, son of Aiaus, grandson of Orsenouohis, mother Thases (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thermouthis, daughter of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 176)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Protas, son of Paskouis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 215)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Petaus, grandson of Petaus, mother Tauris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptollas, son of Satabous, grandson of Ptollas, mother Tapontos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 221)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Papontos, son of Apynchis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hatres, porter (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 156)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 57:;Aphrodisios, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetesouchos, drachmas 4;;Petsiris, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Petsiris, mother Heros, drachmas 4;;Pnepheros, son of Harphaesis, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tapontos, drachmas 12;;Harpalos, his son, mother Tepheros , drachmas 12;;in total for the day drachmas 60 obols 15;;(Pharmouthi) 22 likewise:;Gaius Julius Petronianus (Apolinarios, son of Sarapas):;(in left margin: drachmas 24 obols 14) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 11obol 1.5, tax on the produce of olives drachma 1 obols 3.5, naubion drachma 1 obol 0.5 chalki 2, surcharges drachmas 2 obols 5;;eparourion drachmas 7 obols 3, surcharges obols 3.5 chalki 2, kollybos obls 2.5, in total drachmas 25 obols 2; ;Didyme, daughter of Pakysis (sister of Menas):;(in left margin: drachmas 12 obols 16) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 2 obols 4, tax on the produce of olives obols 2.5 chalki 2, naubion obl 1.5 chalki 2, surcharges obols 4.5 chalki 2;;eparourion drachma 1 obols 4.5 chalki 2, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 6 obol 1.5 chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 6 obols 4, surcharges obols 2.5, in total drachmas 7 obol 0.5;;Heraklas, son of Leonides, grandson of Kastor, mother Thaisas, drachmas 12;;Horion, son of Lupus, grandson of Horos, mother Ammonarion, drachmas 12;;Herieus, son of Sambas, grandson of Peteesis, mother Tapapeis, drachmas 4;;Sambas, son of Peteesis, grandson of Apollonios, mother Tanomgeus, drachmas 4;;Gaius Julius Apolinarios (daughter of Theon, katandrographos);;(in left margin: drachmas 16) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 2 obols 5, tax on the produce of olives obols 2.5, naubion obol 2, surcharges obols 4.5 chalki 2;;eparourion drachma 1 obols 5.5, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 6 obols 3.5;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 7 chalki 2, surcharges obols 2.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 7 obols 3;;naubion of the katoikoi for the 13th year obols 4, surcharges obol 0.5, kollybos chalki 2, in total obols 4.5 chalki 2;;Dioskoros, son of Aiaus, grandson of Orsenouohis, mother Thases, drachmas 8;;Thermouthis, daughter of Petheus (Protas, son of Paskouis);;(in left margin: drachmas 4 obols 23) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachma 1 obol 1.5, tax on the produce of olives obol 1 chalki 2, naubion obol 0.5 chalki 2, surcharges obols 2;;eparourion obols 5, surcharges obol 0.5, in total drachma 2  obols 5.5;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 3 obol 0.5 chalki 2, surcharges obol 1 chalki 2, in total drachmas 3 obols 2;;Horos, son of Petaus, grandson of Petaus, mother Tauris, drachmas 4;;Ptollas, son of Satabous, grandson of Ptollas, mother Tapontos, drachmas 4 obols 28;;Papontos, son of Apynchis (Hatres, porter);;(in left margin: drachmas 8 obols 8) apomoira drachma 1 obols 4, tax on the produce of olives obol 1.5, naubion obol 1, surcharges obols 2.5 chalki 2;;eparourion drachma 1 obol 0.5 chalki 2, surcharges obol 0.5, kollybos obol 0.5 , in total drachmas 3 obols 5;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 4 obol 1, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 4 obols 2.5 chalki 2;;in total for the day drachmas 124 obols 2."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3821&amp;viewid=4171_57R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/5/7/r/4171_57r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3821&amp;viewid=4171_57R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3821&amp;viewid=4171_57R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
