<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3289</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3289</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer paying the poll-tax is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 149-150: 30.7 x 30 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 150: nearly complete (papyrus cut off right of col. 150 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 150: 26 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 150 (l. 2612-2637)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon son of Horos and Segathis grandson of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Chairemon and Stotoetis grandson of Horos and Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois son of Petesouchos and Tkonnos grandson of Herakles (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisis son of Ptolemaios and Tapetesouchos grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Imouthes son of Keras and Tepheros grandson of Menandros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 177)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Petheus and Taphasis grandson of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 203)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchophis son of Petheus and Aphrodous grandson of Anchophis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisis (Aphrodisios) son of Anchophis and Melanous grandson of Petheus and Aphrodous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 154)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion (son of Thaisas), doulos of Syros alias Ptolemaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron son of Ekysis and Herais grandson of Menandros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Pasoxis and Heras grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petsiris son of Pasoknopaios and Heros grandson of Petsiris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 211)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Pasoknopaios and Heros grandson of Petsiris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mystharion son of Ischyrion and Tapetheus grandson of Euemeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 188)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Kanis and Tkollainis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Pasoxis and Thakiaris (Thakialis) grandson of Petesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Kames and Thaesis grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpalos son of Pnepheros and Tepheros grandson of Harphaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas son of Onnophris and Thermouthis grandson of Sambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 223)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Castrensis, doulos of Thaisarion alias Nebsosis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides son of Petheus and Ptolemais grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Slaves--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 150;;(Epeiph 27, continued);;Chairemon, son of Horos and Segathis, grandson of Onnophris, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Horos, his son, his mother being Stotoetis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Total for the day: 156 drachmai 20 obols.;;On the 28th, similarly:;Sisois, son of Petesouchos and Tkonnos, grandson of Herakles, for ch(--): 8 drachmai;Aphrodisis, son of Ptolemaios and Tapetesouchos, grandson of Petheus, for ch(--): 28 obols;Imouthes, son of Keras and Tepheros, grandson of Menandros, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Petheus, son of Petheus and Taphasis, grandson of Onnophris, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Anchophis, son of Petheus and Aphrodous, grandson of Anchophis, for ch(--): 8 drachmai;Aphrodisis, his son, his mother being Melanous, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Sarapion, slave of Syros also called Ptolemaios, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Heron, son of Ekysis and Herais, grandson of Menandros, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Ptolemaios, son of Pasoxis and Heras, grandson of Satabous, for ch(--): 28 obols;Petsiris, son of Pasoknopaios and Heros, grandson of Petsiris, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Onnophris, his brother, (born) of the same mother, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Mystharion, son of Ischyrion and Tapetheus, grandson of Euemeros: 4 drachmai 20 obols; (and) for ch(--): 8 obols;Petheus, son of Kanis and Tkollainis, grandson of Petheus, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Pnepheros, son of Pasoxis and Thakiaris, grandson of Petesouchos, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Sarapion, son of Kames and Thaesis, grandson of Heras, for ch(--): 8 drachmai;Harpalos, son of Pnepheros and Tepheros, grandson of Harphaesis: 4 drachmai 28 obols;Sambas, son of Onnophris and Thermouthis, grandson of Sambas, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Total for the day: 84 drachmai 25 obols.;;On the 29th, similarly:;Castrensis, slave of Thaisarion also called Nebsosis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Herakleides, son of Petheus and Ptolemais, grandson of Heras, for ch(--): 4 drachmai</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 150 (l. 2612-2637), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3289&amp;viewid=4172_34R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3289&amp;viewid=4172_34R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3289&amp;viewid=4172_34R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
