<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3801</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3801</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 31.5 x 29.6 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at the left and at the right. Kollesis at the left edge. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-36</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 52 (ll. 2132-2168)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. Traces of writing on the back have been washed out. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymion, son of Petheus the older, grandson of Didymion, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 161)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Petheus, grandson of Kollouthos, mother Taorsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thermouthis, daughter of Panther (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 176)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Germanus, son of Mersis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 160)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Papeis, grandson of Petheus, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Petaus, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 203)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois, son of Limnaios, grandson of Satabous, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon, son of Areios, grandson of Satabous, mother Tapetaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Areios, son of Sokrates, grandson of Limnaios, mother Tapetaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 154)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mystharion, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 188)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius Valerius Serenus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 160)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarap(), brother, Plakakert()</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraklas, son of Apollonios, grandson of Heraklas, mother Taorsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 166)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Naaraus the older, grandson of Thebennis, mother Tamarres (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Esouris, grandson of Petheus, mother Tkollauthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion, son of Maron, grandson of Horion, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Imouthes, son of Keras, grandson of Menadros, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 177)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Didymos, grandson of Maron, mother Tauris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sokmenis, son of Apynchis, grandson of Sambas, mother Thatres (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 230)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Herieus, mother Anthia (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius Saturnilus Longus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 160)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Sambathion, mother Taseus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Patsonis; see also electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 52:;Didymion, son of Petheus the older, grandson of Didymion, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 4;;Heron, son of Petheus, grandson of Kollouthos, mother Taorsenouphis, drachmas 4;;Thermouthis, daughter of Panther (Germanus, son of Mersis);;orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 3 obols 4.5, tax on the produce of olives obols 3 chalki 2, naubion obols 2 chalki 2, surcharges obols 5.5 chalki 2;;(in left margin: drachmas 16 obols 25)eparourion drachmas 2 obols 3, surcharges obol 1 chalki 2, kollybos obol 1, in total drachmas 8 obols 3;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 9 obols 2 chalki 2, surcharges obls 3.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 10;;Ptolemaios, son of Papeis, grandson of Petheus, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 8;;Petheus, son of Petaus, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Segathis, drachmas 8;;Sisois, son of Limnaios, grandson of Satabous, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8;;in total for the day drachmas 128 obols 25;;(Pharmouthi) 12 likewise:;Chairemon, son of Areios, grandson of Satabous, mother Tapetaus, drachmas 24;;Areios, son of Sokrates, grandson of Limnaios, mother Tapetaus, drachmas 24;;Mystharion, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Gaius Valerius Serenus, cultivator of the 55th clerouchy;;(Sarap(), brother, Plakakert());;orchard taxes in the 12th year for the district of Psenarpsenesis, apomoira drachmas 7 obols 3, tax on the produce of olives drachma 1 obols 4.5, naubion obols 4.5, surcharges drachmas 2;;eparourion drachmas 5, surcharges obols 2.5, kollybos obols 2, in total drachmas 17 obols 4.5;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 11, surcharges obols 4 chalki 2, in total drachmas 11 obols 4 chalki 2;;Heraklas, son of Apollonios, grandson of Heraklas, mother Taorsenouphis, drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, son of Naaraus the older, grandson of Thebennis, mother Tamarres, drachmas 4;;Petaus, son of Esouris, grandson of Petheus, mother Tkollauthis, drachmas 4 obols 28;;in total for the day drachmas 100 obols 16;;(Pharmouthi) 13 likewise:;Horion, son of Maron, grandson of Horion, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 28;;Imouthes, son of Keras, grandson of Menadros, mother Tepheros, drachmas 8;;Petheus, son of Didymos, grandson of Maron, mother Tauris, drachmas 4;;Pnepheros, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Sarapion, son of Valerius, grandson of Sarapion, mother Stotoetis, drachmas 8;;Sokmenis, son of Apynchis, grandson of Sambas, mother Thatres, drachmas 12;;Ptolemaios, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Herieus, mother Anthia, drachmas 4;;Gaius Saturnilus Longus (Slo);;orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 3 obols 4.5, tax on the produce of olives obols 3 chalki 2, naubion obols 2.5, surcharges drachma 1;;(in left margin: drachmas 20 obols 2) eparourion drachmas 2 obols 3, surcharges obol 1.5, kollybos obol 1, in total drachmas 8 obols 3.5 chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 9 obols 2 chalki 2, surcharges obol 0.5, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachmas 10;;naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year, obols 2.5, surcharges 0.5, kollybos obols 3 chalki 2;;Maron, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Sambathion, mother Taseus, drachmas 20."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 -- CPJ 3, 492 (lines with Sambathion) Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3801&amp;viewid=4171_52R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3801&amp;viewid=4171_52R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3801&amp;viewid=4171_52R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
