<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>List of names </title>
            <author>Nemeion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1201</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1201</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.corn.24</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0097;;24</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.corn;;24</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10600</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10600</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Corn. Inv. I 10</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>A list of names of delinquent taxpayers</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso contains an account</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 27.8 x 29.9</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown is in a good state of conservation. Regularly cut at all sides except at the top. Abrasions only significant in the left margin, which means that no text is lost. Seven vertical folds visible.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-49</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto + Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a regular semicursive sloping slightly to the right.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0056">56 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Philadelphia, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Nemeion, collector of the laographia in Philadelphia</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Autokrator, emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles, son of Pouris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Pnepheros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Pnepheros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phasis, son of Hatres</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phasis, a son</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos, son of Ischeis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas alias Ischeis, son of Ischeis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phasis, son of another Phasis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phasis, son of Phasis, the son</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Polyphantes, son of Polyphantes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Apollonios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petermotes, son of Peseris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harphaesis, son of Harphaesis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pylades, son of Herakleas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pemsas, Haryotes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pankrates, son of Haryotes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pebos, son of Herakleas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles, son of Pebos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles, son of another Pebos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kallis, son of Harphaesis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Another Kallis, son of Harpaesis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harphaesis, son of Mysthes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles, son of Petesouchos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Teos, son of Horos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Peinaus, son of Horos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Horos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pachnoubis, son of Horos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apynchis, son of Horos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Thbis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pete(mounis?), son of Akousilaos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Peteouchos, son of Petesouchos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Zoilos, son of Thyon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hatres, son of Kephalon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Peeris, son of Ptollis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petouchos, son of Panoubis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Praxias, son of Harpaesis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles, son of Herakles</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Aropos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion, son of Horion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabous, son of Horion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptollis, son of Dios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dios, son of Dios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pomes, son of Pomes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Protion, Praxion</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Philadelphia, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt (?)</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Philadelphia</term>
               <term>Tax administration and procedure--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Drachma.</term>
               <term>Taxation--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"From Nemeion, collector of the laographia in Philadelphia. Due for Epeiph of the 2nd year of Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Autokrator, emperor, are the unpaid taxes of the first year.;;Herakles, son of Pouris, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Horos, son of Pnepheros, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Onnophris, son of Pnepheros, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Phasis, son of Hatres, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Phasis, a son, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Petesouchos, son of Ischeis, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Sambas alias Ischeis, son of Ischeis, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Phasis, son of another Phasis, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Phasis, son of Phasis, the son, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Polyphantes, son of Polyphantes, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Horos, son of Apollonios, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Petermotes, son of Peseris, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Harphaesis, son of Harphaesis, 45 dracmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi;Pylades, son of Herakleas, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Pemsas, Haryotes, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Pankrates, son of Haryotes, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Pebos, son of Herakleas, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Herakles, son of Pebos, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Herakles, son of another Pebos, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi.;;Col. II;;Kallis, son of Harphaesis, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Another Kallis, son of Harpaesis, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Harphaesis, son of Mysthes, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Herakles, son of Petesouchos, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Teos, son of Horos, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Peinaus, son of Horos, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Sambas, son of Horos, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Pachnoubis, son of Horos, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Apynchis, son of Horos, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Horos, son of Abis, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Pete(mounis?), son of Akousilaos, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Peteouchos, son of Petesouchos, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Zoilos, son of Thyon, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Hatres, son of Kephalon, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Peeris, son of Ptollis, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Petouchos, son of Panoubis, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Praxias, son of Harpaesis, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Herakles, son of Herakles, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Sambas, son of Aropos, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Horion, son of Horion, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Satabous, son of Horion, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Ptollis, son of Dios, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Dios, son of Dios, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Pomes, son of Pomes, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi,;Protion, Praxion, 45 drachmas 1 diobolon, dike-tax 2 drachmas 6 tetraboloi."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Westermann WL - Kraemer CJ, PCorn, 24, 1926 -- BL VI, 32; BL III, 46 on ll. 1, 8, 11, 16 , 20 and 34; BL VII, 40.</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Corn.:24</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1201&amp;viewid=C1_10R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/1/0/r/c1_10r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1201&amp;viewid=C1_10R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1201&amp;viewid=C1_10R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
