<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Formal declaration of a shipper for transport of grain from various harbors</title>
            <author>Aurelius N. N.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2108</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2108</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb xviii, 13948</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">18378</idno>
            <idno type="TM">18378</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;18;13948</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 3781</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>A formal declaration in which Aurelius N. N. acknowledges the reception of the load of grain loaded at various harbors for its transportation to Alexandria.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto (col. 1; col. 2 contains a list of names) + Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 36.5 x 28 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This medium-brown papyrus is badly mutilated and consists of three joining fragments. It is partly regularly broken off at the top, bottom and left side. Approximately 1.5 cm. from the left edge there is a kollesis.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Front: 1-25;Back:1</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto (col. 1) + Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Both hands are early byzantine semi-cursive. On both sides the text runs along the fibers. At the top there is a free margin of approx. 1.5 cm., at the bottom one of 2 cm., and at the left one of 3 cm.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0407">September 14, 407 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Memphite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Johannes, stationarius of Buto</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius N. N., shipper fromSchedia</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Arcadius</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Honorius</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Theodori</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Memphite nome, province of Egypt (?)</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Buto,;Schedia,;Neapolis of Alexandria,</term>
               <term>Grain</term>
               <term>shipping</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary; formal declaration</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Front: "To Johannes, stationarius of Buto, from Aurelius N. N., shipper from Schedia. I acknowledge, swearing the divine and august oath by our lords Arcadius, Honorius, Theodosius, the eternal Augusti, that I have received and put aboard from the canon of the fortunate sixth indiction on behalf of the meris of N. N., one thousand six hundred and eighteen artabas of new, very fine and very pure, flawless, measured with the X measure, not damaged by water, safe, undamaged wheat, total 1,618 only, and the twentieth hereof, i. e. seventy-one artabas measured out immediately, which (quantity) I shall transport to the most illustrious Alexandria and deliver in the granaries of Neapolis and I shall produce the certificates of delivery of these to the office of the strategus in full. If I do not do so I shall be liable to the divine oath and the risk attaching and the stipulations - - - regarding it (?). I, the shipper, have received the hundredth of the ten artabas, the freight, i. e. ten artabas, the supplementary charges, and the porterage-tax in full and in reply to the formal question I have so declared. In the consulship of our masters, Honorius for the 7th time and Theodosius for the 2nd time, the eternal Augusti, Thoth 16. (2nd hd.) I, Aurelius N. N., son of N. N., shipper from Schedia have received and taken aboard upon the afore-mentioned ship in different harbors from the canon of the fortunate sixth indiction on behalf of the meris of the N. N. one thousand six hundred and eighteen artabas of new, very fine and very pure wheat, total 1,618 only, and the twentieth thereof, i. e. eighty-one artabas, total 81 only, which quantity I shall transport to the most illustrious Alexandria and deliver in the granaries of Neapolis and I shall produce the certificates of delivery thereof to the office of the strategus - - - written therein in full. If I do not do so I shall be liable to the divine oath and the risk attaching and undergo the penalty laid down concerning it. I, the shipper have received concerning this load the hundredth of ten artabas and the freight, i. e. ten artabas, and the supplementary charges and the porterage-tax in full. I, N. N., son of N. N., have on his request written it for him, since he does not know letters.";Back: "To my brother Johannes, stationarius."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn PJ, ZPE 62, 140-4, 1986 -- SB XVIII, 13948 -- BL IX, 309 (col. II, l. 12)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB XVIII, 13948</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2108&amp;viewid=3781R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2108&amp;viewid=3781R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2108&amp;viewid=3781R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/8/1/v/3781v.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2108&amp;viewid=3781V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2108&amp;viewid=3781V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
