<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter</title>
            <author>Sarapion alias Horigenes, strategus of the Herakleopolite nome.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2515</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2515</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.13958</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">18333</idno>
            <idno type="TM">18333</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;18;13958</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 5598</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Letter containing a copy of official correspondence regarding the registration of the property of Artemidoros.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>2 papyri ; main fragment:19.5 x 21.5 cm;small fragment: 5 x 5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">partly regularly cut off at the left (there is a free margin of 4 cm.). The smaller fragment is broken off at all sides and cannot be exactly located.At the bottom a piece of unknown length has broken away and the beginnings of lines 21-27 are only partly preserved. At the right approx. 18 letters are missing. The papyrus is badly damaged, especially at the numerous horizontal and vertical folds.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-28</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Fluent cursive hand-writing. Between lines 12 and 13 approx. 2 cm. have been left free.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0193" notAfter="0194">193/194 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Herakleopolite nome (?), province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion alias Horigenes, strategos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">N. N. et alii, assessors of (taxable) property</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">N. N., charged with farming out of taxes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">[Artemidoros], son of Herodes, son of Artemidoros alias Adrastos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Autokrator Caesar Lucius Septimius Se[verus Pertinax] Sebastos, emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraklammon, former gymnasiarch and now keeper of the property register</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Agcharous, alias N. N. daughter of Herodes (father) and Sarous (mother) alias T...</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">N. N., guard of Sarous</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tyrannos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Herakleopolite nome (?), province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Herakleopolis</term>
               <term>Administration</term>
               <term>ownership of property</term>
               <term>tax farming</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"Sarapion, alias Horigenes, strategus of the Herakleopolite nome, to N. N. and his colleagues assessors of property and to N. N. formerly in charge of the farming out of taxes who serve a nome, greetings. A copy of the official communication of the keepers of the property registers of the nome explaining the things that are made clear by them regarding the registration of the property of Artemidoros by the persons in charge of farming out taxes is sent to you in order that you, at your own risk, after having scrutinized it make very accurately clear what the next steps have to be. Farewell. Year 2 of Imperator Caesar Lucius Septimius Severus Pertinax Augustus [Month, Day].;Heraklammon, former gymnasiarch, keeper of the property registers of the Herakleopolite nome to Sarapion, alias Horigenes, strategus of the same nome, greetings. You have sent to both keepers of the property registers an official communication through which you have made clear that Agcharus, alias N. N. N., daughter of Herodes, former kosmetes, her mother being Sarapus, alias N. N. from Herakleopolis with as guardian N. N., son of Sarapion from the same city at her request appointed to her by the strategus before you had delivered a petition to you [ ] on account of her husband who lives with her and who is at the same time her brother, Artemidoros, son of Herodes, grandson of Artemidoros, alias  Adrastos. Since now because of the service of Herakleios [text too fragmentary].</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn PJ, ZPE 63, 297-302, 1986 -- SB XVIII, 13958 -- BL X, 224 (l. 20)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:13958</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2515&amp;viewid=5598R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2515&amp;viewid=5598R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2515&amp;viewid=5598R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
