<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Division of Property</title>
            <author>Horion, son of Horion, and Horos, son of Horos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3245</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3245</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.3.187</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;3;187</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;3;187</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11990</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11990</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 98</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract by which Horion, son of Horion, and Horos, son of Horos, divide between themselves some shares of property in the form of house lots and courtyards in the village of Bacchias which they inherited in joint ownership from their fathers</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto + Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Horos and Tapekysis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 18.5 x 26.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Damaged along the folds</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto - 46;;Verso - 1</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto + Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0075">August 25, 75 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Bacchias, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Vespasianus, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion son of Horion grandson of Menches, father of Horion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion son of Horion grandson of Horion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonios son of Ptolemaios (see also P.Mich. III, 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed official) ho pros to grapheio of Bacchias and Hephaistias</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Bacchias, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Bacchias, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome; he legomene Borris laura; Hephaistias</term>
               <term>House Ownership</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>The seventh year of the Emperor Caesar Vespasianus Augustus, the second of the supplementary days of the month Kaisareios, at Bacchias in the division of Herakleides of the Arsinoite nome.;Horion, son of Horion, the son of Menches, about seventy years old with a scar in the middle of his forehead, and Horos, son of Horos, the son of Peteuris, about forty-two years old with a scar on the right wrist, both acknowledge that they have divided between themselves from the present day for all time the portions which they have of house lots and courtyards inherited from their fathers, that is, a fourth and a third of a twelfth, which is a thirty-sixth, of these, which are common and undivided in three sections in the aforesaid village Bacchias, in the lane called "of Borritis"; the boundaries of all of which are set forth in the deeds relating to them.;And in accordance with the division by lot which they have made by agreement between themselves, Horion on the one hand has obtained as the share which falls to him the aforesaid common and undivided fourth part of the house lots and courtyards; and on the other hand Horos himself has obtained as the share falling to him the aforesaid third of a twelfth part, which is the common and undivided thirty-sixth part of the same house lots and courtyards; of which same house lots and courtyards Horos himself possesses another thirty-sixth part, and Horos himself and his brother, as the parties concerned declare, hold another twelfth part of the same house lots and courtyards inherited from their father, so that the total share of Horos himself alone is one eighteenth and one twenty-fourth of the same house lots and courtyards.;Accordingly, let the contracting parties, each of the two and their heirs, observe all the terms which are set forth in accordance with this division. And neither they nor their heirs may set aside any part of the terms of division, but each of them and their assigns shall hold and control what each has obtained by lot, just as is set forth, and each of them shall make use thereof in whatsoever way they may desire, without restriction.;And with respect to all the terms of division which have been set forth, let neither of them in the present or future accuse the other nor proceed against him in any way upon any pretext.;And if one of the contracting parties breaks any of the aforesaid terms, let the transgressor immediately pay to the one who abides by them double damages and a fine of three hundred drachmai in silver, and an equal sum to the treasury, the terms of agreement and division remaining none the less valid in every detail in perpetuity, just as they stand.;Signatories: for Horion, Horion his son, about fifty-five(?) years old with a scar on the right side of his forehead, and for the other, Ammonios, son of Ptolemaios, about fifty-two years old with a scar on his right cheek.;Let this division be valid.;(2nd hand) I, Horion, son of Horion, the son of Menches, acknowledge that I have made with Horos, son of Horos, the son of Peteuris, the division of the aforesaid parts of the house lots and courtyards. And I have received by lot the fourth part, and Horos (has received) the third of the twelfth, which is the thirty-sixth part, (of the properties) of which he himself possesses another thirty-sixth, and he and his brother another twelfth. And I agree to all the above terms. Horion, his son, wrote for him, because he is illiterate.;(3rd hand) I, Horos, son of Horos, the son of Peteuris, acknowledge that I have made the division of the parts of the house lots and courtyards. And I have obtained by lot the third of the twelfth, which is the thirty-sixth part (of the properties) of which I possess another thirty-sixth part, and I and my brother another twelfth part inherited from our father. And I agree to all the above terms. Ammonios, son of Ptolemaios, wrote for him, since he is illiterate.;(1st hand) The seventh year of the Emperor Caesar Vespasianus Augustus, the second of the supplementary days of the month Kaisareios. Registered though the chief of the record office of Bacchais and Hephaistias.;;(Verso);;Agreement of division (of properties), made between themselves by Horos and Horion.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, TAPA 52, 89-95, 1921 -- SB III 7032 Boak AER, PMich III, 187, 1936 -- BL VI, 80 (bibliography)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:3:187</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3245&amp;viewid=98R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/9/8/R/98R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3245&amp;viewid=98R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3245&amp;viewid=98R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/9/8/V/98V.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3245&amp;viewid=98V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3245&amp;viewid=98V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
