<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3337</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3337</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 50 is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 49-50: 36.7 x 29.8 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 50: complete (papyrus cut off right of col. 50 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 50: 51 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 50 (l. 1018-1068)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Panesneus son of Ischyras and Thaesis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Pasoxis and Heras grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Anchophis and Teseuris grandson of Herakles (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Kanis and Tkollainis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Papeis son of Ptolemaios and Heras grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Petheus and Ptolema grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hatres son of Apollonios and Taorsenouphis grandson of Heraklas, brother of Heraklas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 156)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraklas son of Apollonios and Taorsenouphis grandson of Heraklas, brother of Hatres (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 166)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios son of Sisois and Thaisas grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Besis and Heras grandson of Thoteus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas son of Ptolemaios and Taeuemeros grandson of Sambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 224)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Apollonios and Thermouthis grandson of Harpagathes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas son of Sokmenis and Tkollainis grandson of Sambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 224)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras son of Onnophris and Sopas grandson of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Charidemos son of Petoraipis (Petsoraipis) and Thaesis grandson of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Euemeros (Euhemeros) son of Neilos and Taeuemeros (Taeuhemeros) grandson of Euemeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor son of Kastor and Heraklous grandson of Apollonios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois son of Thaisas, doulos of Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Charmos son of Heron and Apollonous grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos son of Hatres and Tapetheus grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herieus presbyteros son of Horos and Thaesis grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ninis son of Asklas and Tabous grandson of Ninis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus son of Herieus and Tremenesis (Tlemenesis) grandson of Petaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Slaves--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 50;;Panesneus, son of Ischyras and Thaesis, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai;    column 54;Ptolemaios, son of Pasoxis and Heras, grandson of Satabous: 4 drachmai;    column 54;Horos, son of Anchophis and Teseuris, grandson of Herakles: 8 drachmai;    column 55;Petheus, son of Kanis and Tkollainis, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai;    column 56;Papeis, son of Ptolemaios and Heras, grandson of Pnepheros: 8 drachmai;    column 59;Onnophris, son of Petheus and Ptolema, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai;    column 13;Hatres, son of Apollonios and Taorsenouphis, grandson of Heraklas: 8 drachmai;    column 64;Heraklas, his brother, (born) of the same mother: 8 drachmai;    column 64;Aphrodisios, son of Sisois and Thaisas, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai;    column 65;Pnepheros, son of Besis and Heras, grandson of Thoteus: 28 obols;    column 64;Total for the day: 260 drachmai 6 obols.;;On the 10th, similarly:;Sambas, son of Ptolemaios and Taeuemeros, grandson of Sambas: 8 drachmai;    column 41;Sarapion, son of Apollonios and Thermouthis, grandson of Harpagathes: 4 drachmai;    column 61;Sambas, son of Sokmenis and Tkollainis, grandson of Sambas: 4 drachmai;    column 69;Heras, son of Onnophris and Sopas, grandson of Onnophris: 28 obols;    column 72;Charidemos, son of Petoraipis and Thaesis, grandson of Onnophris: 4 drachmai;    column 72;Euemeros, son of Neilos and Taeuemeros, grandson of Euemeros: 12 drachmai;    column 75;Kastor, son of Kastor and Heraklous, grandson of Apollonios: 20 drachmai;    column 66;Sisois, slave of Tasoucharion, the offspring of Thaisas: 20 drachmai;    column 66;Charmos, son of Heron and Apollonous, grandson of Horos: 28 obols;    column 78;Petesouchos, son of Hatres and Tapetheus, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai;    column 82;Sarapion, son of Valerius and Stotoetis, grandson of Sarapion: 8 drachmai;    column 85;Herieus the elder, son of Horos and Thaesis, grandson of Pnepheros: 4 drachmai;    column 87;Ninis, son of Asklas and Tabous, grandson of Ninis: 28 obols;    column 88;Petaus, son of Herieus and Tremenesis, grandson of Petaus: 4 drachmai;    column 89</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 50 (l. 1018-1068), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3337&amp;viewid=4172_11RO.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/1/r/o/4172_11ro.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3337&amp;viewid=4172_11RO.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3337&amp;viewid=4172_11RO.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
