<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lease of a Bath</title>
            <author>Herakleides, son of Isidoros</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2828</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2828</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.312</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;312</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;312</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">15163</idno>
            <idno type="TM">15163</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 639</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract for the lease, for three years, of a bath and an adjoining chaff bin on the property owned jointly by two Romans of equestrian rank, in the vicinity of Theogonis; the lessor, Herakleides, son of Isidoros, the collector or bailiff of the estate, unertakes to pay the taxes on the bath, while the lessees, Diodoros, son of Euphranor, and Patynis the younger, son of Philon, are to pay a rent of 265 artabai of wheat, as well as the operating expenses of the bath</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto + Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 11.5 x 28 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">nearly torn off horizontally just below line 35 of the text; in addition the ink is almost entirely rubbed off in some of the later lines</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto - 53;;Verso - 2</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto + Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>1st hand: same small upright cursive as in P.Mich. V, 311, but much more compact here</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0034">August 26, 34 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Talei, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Tiberius, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides son of Isidoros, eklemptor (of the revenues for Saturninus and Balbillus near Theogonis)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marcus Aponius Saturninus (see G.M. Parassoglou, Imperial Estates [Amsterdam, 1978], Appendix One, p. 65)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tiberius Claudius Balbillus (see among others G.M. Parassoglou, Imperial Estates [Amsterdam, 1978], Appendix One, p. 65)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Diodoros son of Euphranor, Perses tes epigones</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Patynis neoteros son of Philon, Perses tes epigones</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dios son of Dios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hermias, (ho) pros to grapheio of Talei and other villages (see also P.Mich. V, 311)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Talei, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome; Theogonis; Perses</term>
               <term>Baths, Roman--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Building</term>
               <term>Ethnicity</term>
               <term>Lease</term>
               <term>Iranians--Egypt</term>
               <term>Citizenship--Rome.</term>
               <term>Theogonis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Talei (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>With good hopes.;The twentieth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, on the third of the month Hyperberetaios, of Mesore the third intercalary day, in Talei of the division of Polemon of the Arsinoite nome.;Herakleides, son of Isidoros, about 40 years old, with a scar below his left cheek, collector of the revenues for Marcus Aponius Saturninus and Tiberius Claudius Balbillus in the neighborhood of Theogonis, has leased, in working order, to Diodoros, son of Euphranor, about 50 years old, with a scar on his left cheek, and Patynis the younger, son of Philon, about 40 years old, with a scar in the middle of his forehead below the hair, the two of them Persians of the epigone and mutual sureties for recovery, the bath belonging to the same estate in the village of Theogonis, in which there are three leaded vessels of bronze, and the chaff bin lying next to the bath, in which there is chaff. This lease is for three years from the coming twenty-first year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, upon condition that the said lessees shall operate the bath each month on alternate days and at the festivals, the lessees providing for themselves sufficient chaff and bath attendants, and the other requisites, at a rental for the whole of 265 artabai of new, clean wheat without blemish according to the measure of the same bath, free from deduction or claim. And let the lessees deliver the rental indicated from the month of Pauni to Mesore of the same year, each month the proper instalment, in the village, and the lessor Herakleides shall receive from the lessees immunity from the bath fee for ten men to be selected by him, and after the term they (the lessees) shall restore the bath as they received it and the bronze vessels in good condition, and if any damage shall have occurred to the bronze vessels through fault of the lessees, the repairs shall be a charge against them, the lessor Herakleides furnishing lead . . . upon Herakleides . . . of the bath which they shall also pay with the rental itself in a lump sum, and the same lessees shall surrender the chaff bin with the chaff in it as they received it, with the qualification that the same lessees shall be given two donkey loads without charge. Herakleides guarantees the lease against public charges.;Signatory for the lessees: Dios, son of Dios, about 45 years old, with a scar on his forehead . . .;(2nd hand) We, Diodoros, son of Euphranor, and Patynis . . .;(3rd hand) The twentieth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, Mesore the third intercalary day. Registered through Hermias, secretary of Talei and other villages.;;(Verso);;Lease of a bath, (made) by Diodoros and another to Herakleides (sic).</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich V, 312, 1944 -- BL VI, 82  (verso, l. 1); BL VII, 111 (l. 42); BL VIII, 213 (l. 6; 50; 17)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:312</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2828&amp;viewid=639R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2828&amp;viewid=639R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2828&amp;viewid=639R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2828&amp;viewid=639V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2828&amp;viewid=639V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
