<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3837</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3837</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 29.9 x 30.7 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at the right and the left. Kollesis at left center. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-36</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 72 (ll. 2856-2892)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Satabous, grandson of Petheus, mother Aphrodous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 220)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hatres, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Heraklas, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 157)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didyme, daughter of Argaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 161)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Titikas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 242)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thaubas, daughter of Sambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 175)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Akous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 150)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois, son of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nike (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis, son of Sokmenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Melanas, porter (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Apollonios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 200)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Valeria Felicla (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 194)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammon, son of Alimion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 150)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes, son of Teberis, grandson of Sambathion, mother Isidora (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios, son of Petheus, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Taseus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phasis, son of Tesenouphis, grandson of Harphaesis, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 246)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion, son of Petsiris, grandson of Pasion, mother Thases (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis, son of Pekmeis alias  Heremon, mother Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron, son of Petheus the younger, grandson of Anchorimphis, mother Apollonous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petoraipis, son of Hatres, grandson of Imouthes, mother Soeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabous, son of Dioskoros, grandson of Satabous, mother Tahorion, cultivator of the 4th cleruchy (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 226)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Sokmenis, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 204)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psenesis, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Komonis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Patsontis district; see also electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 72:;Pauni 3:;Ptolemaios, son of Satabous, grandson of Petheus, mother Aphrodous, drachmas 40;;Hatres, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Heraklas, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Didyme, daughter of Argaios (Titikas);;(in left margin: drachmas 40 obols 16) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 7 obols 3, tax on the produce of olives drachma 1 obols 4.5, naubion obols 4.5, surcharges drachmas 2;;eparourion drachmas 8 obols 2, surcharges obols 4 chalki 2, kollybos obols 2 chalki 2, in total drachmas 21 obols 2.5;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 18 obols 3.5, surcharges drachma 1 obols 2 chalki 2, in total drachmas 19 obols 5.5 chalki 2;;Thaubas, daughter of Sambas (Akous);;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 4 obol 1, tax on the produce of olives 3.5, (in left margin: drachmas 20 obols 24)naubion obols 2.5, surcharges drachma 1 chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 4 obols 2.5 chalki 2, surcharges obols 2.5, kollybos obol 1 chalki 2, in total drachmas 11 obols 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 10 obols 2.5, surcharges obols 4, in total drachmas 11 obol 0.5;;Sisois, son of Onnophris (husband of Nike);;(in left margin: drachmas 4 obols 12) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 2 obol 1 chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives obols 2 chalki 2, naubion obol 1.5, surcharges obols 3.5, chalki 2;;eparourion drachma 1 obols 2.5, surcharges obol 0.5 chalki 2, kollybos obol 0.5, in total drachmas 5 obol 0.5;;Pakysis, son of Kastor, grandson of Pakysis, mother Teseuris, drachmas 12;;Pakysis, son of Sokmenis (Melanas, porter);;(in left margin: drachmas 4 obols 27) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 3, tax on the produce of olives obols 2.5 chalki 2, naubion obols chalki 2, surcharges obols 5;;eparourion drachmas 2, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 6 obols 5.5 chalki 2;;Petheus, son of Apollonios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 20;;in total for the day drachmas 152 obols 21.;(Pauni) 4 likewise:;Valeria Felicla (Ammon, son of Alimion);;(in left margin: drachmas 24 obols 8) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 10 obols 5, tax on the produce of olives drachma 1 obols 3.5, naubion drachma 1 obol 0.5, surcharges drachmas 2 obols 4 chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 7 obol 1.5, surcharges obols 3.5 chalki 2, kollybos obols 2.5, in total drachmas 24 obols 3;;Mysthes, son of Teberis, grandson of Sambathion, mother Isidora, drachmas 4;;Aphrodisios, son of Petheus, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Taseus, drachmas 8;;Phasis, son of Tesenouphis, grandson of Harphaesis, mother Thaesis, copper drachmas 4;;Pasion, son of Petsiris, grandson of Pasion, mother Thases, drachmas 4 copper obols 28;;Phaesis, son of Pekmeis alias  Heremon, mother Sambathion, drachmas 8;;Maron, son of Petheus the younger, grandson of Anchorimphis, mother Apollonous, copper drachmas 4;;Petoraipis, son of Hatres, grandson of Imouthes, mother Soeris, copper drachmas 4;;Satabous, son of Dioskoros, cultivator of the 4th cleruchy;;geometria for the 12th year at the Patsontis district drachmas 2, surcharges obol 0.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 2 obol 0.5 chalki 2;;Satabous, son of Dioskoros, grandson of Satabous, mother Tahorion, drachmas 4;;Petheus, son of Sokmenis, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8;;Psenesis, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Komonis, drachmas 4."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 -- CPJ 3, 492 (lines with Sambathion) Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3837&amp;viewid=4171_72R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3837&amp;viewid=4171_72R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3837&amp;viewid=4171_72R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
