<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Petition to a Strategos</title>
            <author>Marepsemis son of Marepsemis and 8 other high-ranking priests of the temple of Kronos at Tebtynis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1352</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1352</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.226</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;226</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;226</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12067</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12067</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1269</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Petition addressed to Asklepiades, strategos of the division of Polemon, by nine men who represent the tribes of priests in the service of the god Kronos at Tebtynis, to complain of difficulties encountered by them in dealing with former lessees of a granary belonging to the temple</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc" otherLangs="egy-Egyd">Greek; Demotic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 13.5 x 29 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">nearly complete and in good condition</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">50</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The 1st hand is a neatly written upright cursive; the second is much less well formed and is irregular. (Boak)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0037">March 27-April 25, 37 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Asklepiades, strategos of the Polemonos meris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marepsemis son of Marepsemis, (hiereus), hegoumenos (of the priests of Kronos)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marsisouchos son of Sigeris (Sikeris), (hiereus), hegoumenos (of the priests of Kronos)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pachis son of Marepsemis, (hiereus), hegoumenos (of the priests of Kronos)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petosiris son of Pakebis (Pakebkis), (hiereus), grammateus (of the priests of Kronos)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Panesis (Panisis) son of Pakebkis, hiereus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marepkamis (Marepkemis, Marepakamis) son of Marepkamis, hiereus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marepsemis son of Marepsemis (alias) Pesouris, hiereus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Psyphis (Psoiphis), hiereus (see also P.Mich. V, 323a</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">P.Tebt. II, 383)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marsisouchos son of Marsisouchos (= Marres son of Marres), hiereus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thenapynchis (deceased), thesaurophylax, mother of Apynchis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apynchis, son of Harmiysis and Thenapynchis, husband of Thaesis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thaesis, wife of Apynchis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) hiereis of Kronos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tiberius, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) epistates of Tebtynis</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyd">Demotic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Polemonos meris; Tebtynis</term>
               <term>Agriculture</term>
               <term>Building</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Justice</term>
               <term>Lease</term>
               <term>Priest</term>
               <term>Religion</term>
               <term>Taxation (Land)</term>
               <term>Woman</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>To Asklepiades, strategos of the division of Polemon, from Marepsemis, son of Marepsemis, and Marsisouchos, son of Sigeris, and Pachis, son of Marepsemis, all three presidents, and Petosiris, son of Pakebkis, secretary, and Panesis, son of Pakebkis, and Marepkamis, son of Marepkamis, and Marepsemis, son of Marepsemis (also called) Pesouris, and Onnophris, son of Psyphis, and Marsisouchos, son of Marsisouchos, all nine presidents and secretary and (representative) of the tribes of the same priests of Tebtynis of Kronos the mighty god, great and greatest. Whereas for a long time past right up to the present year and day we have been renting to the deceased granary guard Thenapynchis and her living son Apynchis, son of Harmiysis, and his wife Thaesis, in the aforesaid village village of Tebtynis of Kronos the mighty god, great and greatest, the granary in use in which there are a tower and another tower adjacent to it and a gateway, and whereas when we and our other priests took back from the aforesaid Apynchis and his wife Thaesis the granary in which were some of the equipment and doors which he had received, we found in the present month Pharmouthi, of the present 23rd year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, that the doors which belonged there had been carried off by them and that the granary was not plastered as they received it, so that we have been prevented entirely from being able to bring into the said granary the wheat and barley which we measure out to the treasury as public taxes, therefore we beg you to write to the epistates of Tebtynis to come to the aforesaid granary and view the conditions and send the accused to you for the coming assizes.;(2nd hand) We, Onnophris, son of Psyphis, and Marepsemis, son of Marepsemis, and Marsisouchos, son of Sigeris, and Pachis, son of Marepsemis, and Petosiris, son of Pakebkis, and Panesis, son of Pakebkis, and Marepakamis, and Marepsemis, son of Pesouris, and the other priests, have deposited the foregoing petition. I, Onnophris, have written for them as they don't know (Greek) letters.;(Demotic) (3rd hand) The writer (of this subscription) is Panesis, son of Pakebkis, who says: I have submitted this petition, which Onnophris(?), son of . . ., has drawn up concerning the granary.;(4th hand) Marepkamis, son of Marepkamis.;(5th hand) Marepsemis(?), son of Marepsemis, says: I have submitted this petition.;(6th hand) Marres, son of the like-named, has written: I have submitted (this petition).</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich V, 226 (Greek text only), 1944 -- BL VII, 110 (lines 23, 34, 39, 42). - In an unpublished, handwritten  note, H.C. Youtie remarked that the nine priests are not 8 hegoumenoi and 1 grammateus, but 3 hegoumenoi, 1 grammateus, and 5 priests, each representing one of the 5 phylai. (PH) HC Youtie, Scriptiunculae I, 310-312, 1981</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:226</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1352&amp;viewid=1269R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/6/9/R/1269R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1352&amp;viewid=1269R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1352&amp;viewid=1269R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
