<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3851</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3851</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 35 x 30.3 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at the right and the left. Kollesis at right and left. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-39</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 84 (ll. 3334-3373)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Tkollainis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis, son of Pekmeis alias Heuremon, mother Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, his brother with the same mother (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes, son of Teberis, grandson of Sambathion, mother Isidora (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Agathopous, slave of Taseus alias Isarion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 148)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Ptolema (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psenesis, son of Parmenion, grandson of Psenesis, mother Tkonnos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius Julius Maximus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 159)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psenesis, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Kommonis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Leouas, son of Petheus, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Tapapeis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 184)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Soeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 194)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Papeis, grandson of Petheus, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon, son of Heron, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Didyme (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Achillas, his brother with the same mother (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apynchis, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 154)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabous, son of Petheus, grandson of Satabous, mother Tapetaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 226)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos the younger, son of Hatres, grandson of Horos, mother Teraus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petheus, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 203)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes, son of Phaesis, grandson of Mysthes, mother Aunchis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menches, son of Satabous, grandson of Maron, mother Tkonnos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Tkollainis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Sokrates, grandson of Phasis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 220)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petoraipis, son of Hatres, grandson of Imouthes, mother Soeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides, son of Abykis, grandson of Abykis, mother Herais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Menches, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thases (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Sisois, grandson of Petsiris, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpagathes, son of Satabous, grandson of Anchophis, mother Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Ptolema (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Theagenes, son of Theagenes, grandson of Ammonios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 176)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpalos, maimed (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptollous, daughter of Apion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 221)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 84:;Petesouchos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Tkollainis, drachmas 4;;Phaesis, son of Pekmeis alias Heuremon, mother Sambathion, copper drachmas 4;;Heron, his brother with the same mother, copper drachmas 4;;Mysthes, son of Teberis, grandson of Sambathion, mother Isidora, copper drachmas 4;;Agathopous, slave of Taseus alias Isarion, copper drachmas 8;;Horos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Ptolema, copper drachmas 8;;Psenesis, son of Parmenion, grandson of Psenesis, mother Tkonnos, copper drachmas 4;;Gaius Julius Maximus;;(in left margin: drachmas 2 obols 22) geometria of year 12 drachmas 6 obol 1.5, surcharges obols 2.5, in total drachmas 6 obols 4;;Psenesis, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Kommonis, copper drachmas 4;;Leouas, son of Petheus, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Tapapeis, copper drachmas 4;;Orsenouphis, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Soeris, copper drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Papeis, grandson of Petheus, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4 copper drachmas 8;;Chairemon, son of Heron, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Didyme, drachmas 8;;Achillas, his brother with the same mother, drachmas 8;;Apynchis, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tasoucharion, copper drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 88 obols 22.;(Epeiph) 27 likewise:;Satabous, son of Petheus, grandson of Satabous, mother Tapetaus, copper drachmas 4;;Petheus, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petheus, mother Segathis, copper drachmas 4;;Onnophris, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4 copper drachmas (of priests) 4;;Mysthes, son of Phaesis, grandson of Mysthes, mother Aunchis, drachmas 4 copper drachmas 8;;Menches, son of Satabous, grandson of Maron, mother Tkonnos, copper drachmas 4 obols 28;;Petesouchos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Tkollainis, copper drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Sokrates, grandson of Phasis, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 44 copper drachmas 4;;Petoraipis, son of Hatres, grandson of Imouthes, mother Soeris, copper drachmas 4;;Herakleides, son of Abykis, grandson of Abykis, mother Herais, copper drachmas 4;;Onnophris, son of Menches, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thases, copper drachma obols 28;;Onnophris, son of Sisois, grandson of Petsiris, mother Thaesis, copper drachmas 4;;Harpagathes, son of Satabous, grandson of Anchophis, mother Sambathion, copper drachmas 4;;Onnophris, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Ptolema, copper drachmas 8;;Theagenes, son of Theagenes, grandson of Ammonios, copper drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 120 obols 27.;(Epeiph) 28 likewise:;Ptollous, daughter of Apion;;(drachmas 4 obols 20) Ptollous, daughter of Apion (Harpalos maimed);orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira drachma 1 obols 5 chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives obol 1.5 chalki 2, naubion obol 1 chalki 2, surcharges obols 3;;eparourion drachma 1 obol 1.5, surcharges obol 0.5 chalki 2, kollybos obol 0.5, in total drachmas 4 obols 2;;geometria of year 12 drachma 1 obol 2 chalki 2, surcharges obol 0.5 chalki 2, in total drachma 1 obols 3."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 -- CPJ 3, 492 (lines with Sambathion); BL III, 113 (3370) Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3851&amp;viewid=4171_84R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3851&amp;viewid=4171_84R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3851&amp;viewid=4171_84R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
