<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Release of Inheritance</title>
            <author>Taorseus, daughter of Petermouthis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3174</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3174</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.351</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;351</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;351</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12161</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12161</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 942</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract by which Taorseus, daughter of Petermouthis, agrees to resign to her half-sister Taorseus, daughter of Ptolemaios, her share of some building sites left by their mother, Tapnebtynis.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 14 x 28.2 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Slightly broken off on the left side; damaged along the folds</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">37</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>1st hand: fine small hand, with the lines crowded together toward the end, showing that the body of the contract was inserted after the subscriptions were written; 2nd and 3rd hands are crude, with much misspelling (Husselman)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0044">July 24, 44 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Claudius, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Taorseus daughter of Petermouthis and Tapnebtynis, wife of Polydeukes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Polydeukes son of Polydeukes,husband and guardian of Taorseus daughter of Petermouthis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Taorseus daughter of Ptolemaios and Tapnebtynis, wife of Hatres</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hatres son of Hatres grandson of Cheos, husband and guardian of Taorseus daughter of Ptolemaios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tapnebtynis daughter of Lykos, deceased mother of Taorseus, daughter of Petermouthis, and Taorseus, daughter of Ptolemaios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Zoilos son of Horion</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome</term>
               <term>Family</term>
               <term>House Ownership</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Inheritance</term>
               <term>Woman (&amp;amp</term>
               <term>guardian)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>The fourth year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus, the thirtieth of the month Gorpiaios, Epeiph the thirtieth, in Tebtynis in the division of Polemon of the Arsinoite nome. Taorseus, daughter of Petermouthis, about twenty-seven years old, with a scar on her forehead at the right, with her guardian, her husband Polydeukes, son of Polydeukes, about thirty-nine years old, with a scar on his right shin, acknowledges to her sister by the same mother, Taorseus, daughter of Ptolemaios, about thirty-three years old, with a scar on her right knee, with her guardian, her husband Hatres, son of Hatres, son of Cheos, about thirty-seven years old, with a scar on his right forearm, that she has released to her all the shares of old building sites in the aforesaid village of Tebtynis, bequeathed by the mother of both of them, Tapnebtynis, daughter of Lykos, and that neither she, the acknowledging party, Taorseus, nor anyone else in her behalf, nor her assigns, will proceed against Taorseus, the daughter of Ptolemaios, or make any claim either in regard to the property or any other transaction or debt whatever, written or unwritten, up to the present day, because she is satisfied. If Taorseus, daughter of Petermouthis, should violate any of these terms, the act of aggression or accusation shall be invalid for her and for everyone acting in her behalf, and she shall pay twice the damages and expenses and a fine of two hundred drachmai in silver, and the same sum to the treasury, and the terms agreed upon shall be valid. Her husband, Polydeukes, wrote the subscription for the acknowledging party, Taorseus, and Zoilos, son of Horion, about twenty-two years old, with a scar on the right side of his forehead, (wrote) for the others.;(2nd hand) I, Taorseus, daughter of Petermouthis, with my guardian, my husband Polydeukes, son of Polydeukes, acknowledge that I have released to my aforesaid sister by the same mother, Taorseus, daughter of Ptolemaios, the shares of the old building sites in Tebtynis, bequeathed by the mother of both of us, Tapnebtynis, daughter of Lykos, and that I will not proceed against her or make any claim,a nd that no one else shall in my behalf, against Taorseus or against her assigns with regard to these shares or anything else, since I have consented as aforesaid. I, Polydeukes, son of Polydeukes, wrote for my wife since she is illiterate, and I have been registered as her guardian.;(3rd hand) I, Taorseus, daughter of Ptolemaios, with my guardian, my husband Hatres, son of Hatres, son of Cheos. The acknowledgment was made to me as aforesaid. Zoilos, son of Horion, wrote for them because they are illiterate.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 351, 1944 -- L. 17: read [he] ephodos kai he enklisis, instead of ephodos e enklisis. (PH)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:351</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3174&amp;viewid=942R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/4/2/r/942r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3174&amp;viewid=942R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3174&amp;viewid=942R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
