<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3639</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3639</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.224</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 31.3 x 32.5 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is torn at the top and at the bottom. One kollesis in the center. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-42</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 7 (ll. 228-269)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">"[Column 7]:</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Onnophris, grandson of Theabennis, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Sokmenis, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis, son of Heron, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Zoidous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 193)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchophis, son of Kanis, grandson of Anchophis, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonios, son of Ammonios, grandson of Ammonios, mother Tninis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 151)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron, son of Petheus the younger, grandson of Anchorymphis, mother Apollonous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis, son of Sisois, son of Phaesis, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Souchas, grandson of Heras, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Paouitis, son of Petheus, grandson of Phasis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Melanas, grandson of Petheus, mother Tamystha (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasoxis, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Panther, mother Taseus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 199)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Petheus, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Esouris, grandson of Onnophris, mother Zoidous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisis, son of Sisois, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophrios, son of Onnophris, grandson of Sambas, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Naaraus the older, grandson of Theabennis, mother Tamareios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Esouris, grandfather of Petheus, mother Tkollautis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Ptolemais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p.167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petalos, son of Petaus, grandson of Petaus, mother Soeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son, mother Taeuhemeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Charmos, son of Heron, grandson of Horos, mother Apollonous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Petheus, mother of Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 204)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dioskoros, son of Aiaus, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Thases (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Sambas, grandson of Sabinus, mother Aphrodous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pamonneouis, son of Anchorymphis, grandson of Pamoneouis, mother Didymarion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Herieus, mother Anthia (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois, son of Naaraus the younger, grandson of Theabennis, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Artemas, son of Heron, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apynchis, son of Petermouthis, grandson of Apynchis, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 154)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"Column 7;Heron, son of Onnophris, grandson of Theabennis, mother Tapetheus, 4 drachmas;;Petheus, son of Sokmenis, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Thaesis, 4 drachmas;;The same12th year; the remainder is the administrator fee;Orsenouphis, son of Heron, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Zoidous, 4 drachmas;;Anchophis, son of Kanis, grandson of Anchophis, mother Thermouthis, 4 drachmas;;Ammonios, son of Ammonios, grandson of Ammonios, mother Tninis, 4 drachmas;;Maron, son of Petheus the younger, grandson of Anchorymphis, mother Apollonous, 8 drachmas;;Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis, 8 drachmas;;The12th year, the remainder is the administrator fee; ;Phaesis, son of Sisois, son of Phaesis, mother Thaesis, 20 drachmas;;Heras, son of Souchas, grandson of Heras, mother Tapetheus, 8 drachmas;;Paouitis, son of Petheus, grandson of Phasis, mother Tapetheus, 4 drachmas;;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Thaisas, 4 drachmas;;Heras, son of Melanas, grandson of Petheus, mother Tamystha, 8 drachmas;;The total for the day 140 drachmas, obols 11 of which 12th year 8 drachmas, obols 11.;The 23rd of the same (month);Pasoxis, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Panther, mother Taseus, 8 drachmas;;Pnepheros, son of Petheus, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Thaisas, 8 drachmas;;Pnepheros, son of Esouris, grandson of Onnophris, mother Zoidous, 12 drachmas;;Heron, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Heras, 4 drachmas;;Aphrodisis, son of Sisois, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaisas, 8 drachmas;;Onnophrios, son of Onnophris, grandson of Sambas, mother Thermouthis, 8 drachmas;;Ptolemaios, son of Naaraus the older, grandson of Theabennis, mother Tamareios, 4 drachmas;;Petaus, son of Esouris, grandfather of Petheus, mother Tkollautis, 4 drachmas;;The total for the day 56 drachmas;;The 24th of the same (month);;Herakleides, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Ptolemais, 4 drachmas;;Petalos, son of Petaus, grandson of Petaus, mother Soeris, 8 drachmas;;Pnepheros, son, mother Taeuhemeros, 12 drachmas;;Charmos, son of Heron, grandson of Horos, mother Apollonous, 4 drachmas, obols 8;;12th year the same, ? copper drachmas: ;Petheus, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Petheus, mother of Thermouthis, 16 drachmas;;Dioskoros, son of Aiaus, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Thases, 16 drachmas;;Ptolemaios, son of Sambas, grandson of Sabinus, mother Aphrodous, 4 drachmas;;Pamonneouis, son of Anchorymphis, grandson of Pamoneouis, mother Didymarion, obols 28;;Ptolemaios, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Herieus, mother Anthia, 4 drachmas;;Sisois, son of Naaraus the younger, grandson of Theabennis, mother Thaisas, 4 drachmas;;Artemas, son of Heron, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaesis, 8 drachmas;;Apynchis, son of Petermouthis, grandson of Apynchis, mother Thermouthis, 8 drachmas;;in total for the day 92 drachmas, obols 26;of which 12th year obols [20]."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3639&amp;viewid=4171_7R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3639&amp;viewid=4171_7R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3639&amp;viewid=4171_7R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
