<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
           <title>Private Letter</title>
           <author>Ptolemaios</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1393</idno>
           <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1393</idno>
           <idno type="TM">27679</idno>
           <idno type="HGV">27679</idno>
           <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;18;13867</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                 <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1341</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                 <summary>Private letter sent by Ptolemaios to his mother and sister, in which he answers various points in a letter he received from them,  tells them of a four day episode spent with an irresponsible, impudent young man, somehow related to them, and complains a woman who treated him inconsiderably</summary>
                 <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso (of P.Haun. 15) bears illegible traces of writing (address?)</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Haun. II, 14 +15</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                 </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                       <support>1 + 2 papyri ; P.Mich. inv. 1341: 13 x 14.3 cm; P.Haun. II, 14: 12.5 x 13 cm; P.Haun. II, 15: 14.8 x 14 cm (total size: ca. 25.5 x 28.3 cm)</support>
                       <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Lower left corner missing; damaged along the breaks</ab>
                       </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                          <ab type="lines">Col. I (P. Haun. II, 14) - 20 lines;;col. II (all 3 fragments) - 42 lines;;col. III (P.Mich. inv. 1341 + P.Haun. II, 15) - 46 lines</ab>
                          <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                 <handDesc>
                     <p>A personal hand, relatively experienced, which had not developed beyond an early stage (McCarren); the writing is medium-sized, upright, rounded and neattly kept within two lines; most letters could be inscribed in a square (Bȭlow-Jacobsen)</p>
                 </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                    <origDate notBefore="0100" notAfter="0199">IInd century  A.D.</origDate>
                    <origPlace>unknown place, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                    <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios</persName>
                    <persName type="asn">Zosime, mother of Ptolemaios</persName>
                    <persName type="asn">Rhodous, sister of Ptolemaios</persName>
                    <persName type="asn">Karas (brother of Ammonios?)</persName>
                    <persName type="asn">(unnamed) sister of Ptolemaios</persName>
                    <persName type="asn">(unnamed) sister of Ammonios (and of Karas?)</persName>
                    <persName type="asn">Ammonios (brother of Karas?)</persName>
                    <persName type="asn">Tapsois</persName>
                    <persName type="asn">Isarous, mother of Tapsois</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                    <p>unknown place, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
              <term>Greek letters--Egypt.</term>
              <term>Sons--Egypt;vCorrespondence.</term>
              <term>Brothers--Egypt;vCorrespondence.</term>
              <term>Foot--Wounds and injuries--Egypt.</term>
              <term>Horses--Egypt.</term>
              <term>DonkeyszEgypt.</term>
              <term>Literacy--Egypt.</term>
              <term>Serapis (Egyptian deity)</term>
              <term>Documentary</term>
              <term>Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
           <ab>&lt;By&gt; Sarapis! You, whoever you are, who are reading the letter, make a small effort and translate to the women what is written in this letter and tell them. Ptolemaios to his mother Zosime and his sister Rhodous, greetings. You blame me through letters and through people as if I had done wrong, so I swear by all the gods that I have done nothing of what has been said, except only about the donkey of Karas. But you seemed to be lying in wait for me. And if you are angry because I did not send anything though I had heard, the reason is that I was kicked by a horse and was in danger of losing my foot [or even] my life. I blame you because you enquired about me neither by words nor by letters. The gods willing it would be well;;[ca. 20 lines lost];;but also I detained him and he enjoyed himself for four days, night and day. On the next day, when there was not even a bit to drink, he stood up saying to me: "Do you want a mina of meat bought for you?" I said: "Yes." At once I gave him two four-obol pieces for the mina of meat. Although he took the two four-obol pieces, he did not bring either the meat or the money nor has he been seen by me up to now. I write to you not for the sake of the money but in regard to his state of mind about my sister. On account of the respect for all of you I had forbidden her to speak to him about the money which he owed her. By the gods - - - I was distressed when I heard [where he ended up] because of a bit [of money]. I felt bad that you, Rhodous - - - did not come up for the twenty-fifth of the god. I entreat you to come for the seventieth of the god, to come to me as to your own home. The same affection remains. Entreat also the old woman to come. Concerning the letter which you sent to me, [I,] as [I] did [not] receive it, said: "No, by Sarapis, I did not tear it up; for I am not stupid. " ;;[6 lines very damaged; 1 or more lines missing];;though she - - - and took into account (?) that, at once, I might form an opinion. She is completely inconsiderate. Since you were away from me, I was in distress for four days lest she was sick or had experienced some other trouble, and I sent my sister, using Karas as a pretext. In learning about her health I revealed the entire matter. Her brother, Ammonios, &lt;told&gt; my sister that she was away. When I heard that she was away, it made me happy that she was not ill and no evil had befallen her, but I am angry because she did not bid me good-bye, but went away without me. But there is nothing unusual in their lack of consideration. For I wanted to send you everything. I pray that you are in good health. Greet Tapsois and her mother, Isarous.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
              <bibl>Rep Editor - McCarren VP-Bulow-Jacobsen A;   Rep Ser. - ZPE 58 ;   1985;   pg. 71-79 -- BL X, 224 (bibliography) -- SB XVIII, 13867 McCarren VP, Diss, 10 (Mich. fragment only), 1975 McCarren VP, PMich XIV, 679 (Mich. fragment only), 1980, Pl XII -- BL VIII, 218 (bibliography)</bibl>
            </listBibl>
           <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1393&amp;viewid=1341R.TIF">Original Record</ref>.
           </p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
           <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/4/1/R/1341R.jpg"/>
           </figure>
           <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1393&amp;viewid=1341R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
           </figure>
           <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1393&amp;viewid=1341R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
           </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
