<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>memorandum</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2020</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2020</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.14.11651</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;14;11651</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;14;11651</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">18169</idno>
            <idno type="TM">18169</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 3627</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>The papyrus contains a letter to the strategoi and royal scribes of the Eptanomoi and the Arsinoite, giving instructions concerning preparations for a visit of Severus Alexander and his mother, Iulia Mamaea. It apparently reinforces a previous communication from the epistrategos, refers to a schedule of requisitions previously sent to the same officials and which they are now instructed to post up in public places, and insists that all requisitions are to be made within the proper limits only, severe penalties being threatened if the officials are caught overstepping the mark.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: verso; recto is unpublished</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 13.5 x 22.5 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The papyrus is complete at the top and bottom and, for the most part, at the right, but a great deal is lost at the left, probably about two-thirds of the original document. Probably at least two-thirds of the papyrus has been lost in the best preserved lines, which indicates an original width of more than 40 cm.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-16</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The text is written in a commonplace cursive typical of the third century (though perhaps more typical late rather than early in the century), with no trace of chancery influence. At first sight the closing greeting (l. 16) appears to be in a different hand, suggesting that our text is an original to which the prefect added a greeting in his own hand. However, while undoubtedly written more hastily and cursively than the rest of the document, l. 16 need not have been written by a second hand. In fact the other side shows that the text on the verso is a locally produced copy, written on the back of an already used roll."</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0200" notAfter="0299">IIIrd century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Middle Egypt, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Imperator Caesar Marcus Aurelius Severus Alexander Pius Felix Augustus, emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Iulia Mamaia, mater Augusti</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Middle Egypt, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Eptanomoi,;Arsinoite nome.</term>
               <term>Severus Alexander, ;c Emperor of Rome, ;d 208-235.</term>
               <term>Visits of State--.Egypt;vGovernment correspondence.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>". . . to the strategoi and basilikoi of the Seven Nomes and the Arsinoite, greeting.   . . . necessary provisions being made ready for the imperial visit of our lord Imperator Caesar Marcus Aurelius Severus Alexander Pius Felix Augustus and of Iulia Mamaea mater Augusti, mother of the imperial soldiers and of the senate, sanctissima Augusta, as . . . the epistrategos, vir egregius, has already writtten to you (?), take good care, you, the basilikoi, having received the schedule of the requisitions (?), to put up a copy of this publicly in the metropoleis and the most prominent places in the nomes, so that everyone can see (?) whether the requisitions (?) have been made fairly and justly . . . , and you, the strategoi, when you now have all this collected together . . . taking care of the provisioning, both that for the present imperial visit (?) and that for . . ., to exact only such contributions as are fitting; and knowing that, if I find that you have disobeyed these instructions (?), . . . your life will be at stake . . . Take good care to put up publicly a copy of this letter of mine in the metropoleis and in the most prominent places in the nomes. Best wishes for your good health. [Date]"</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Clarysse W-Thomas JD, Ancient Society 8, 195-201, 1977 -- SB XIV, 11651 -- BL VIII, 374 (photo; ll. 5-6)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:14:11651</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2020&amp;viewid=3627V.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2020&amp;viewid=3627V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2020&amp;viewid=3627V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
