<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Contract for a Loan of Money</title>
            <author>Eirenaios &amp; Apollonia</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2629</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2629</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">5697</idno>
            <idno type="TM">5697</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;5;7532</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 6051</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Six-witness, double deed for a loan of 6,490 copper drachmai at 24%, for a term of two months; the name of the creditor is left blank</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">X: the creditor's name was not included, either in order to make the contract negotiable, that is, to permit its being transferred by the original lender to another person who, by the insertion of his name in the blank spaces, would become qualified to receive the repayment of the loan, or because the syngraphophylax was the creditor or a relative of the creditor.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto + Verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 11.5 x 29 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">broken off at the bottom; numerous holes. - Two very small clay seals were preserved, one placed between the the first two columns of names on the Verso, the other betweent the second two colums; neither of them has a design imprinted on it.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">recto - 42;;Verso - 2 + 4 columns of 2 lines each</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto + Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>(1st hand) small but well-formed, upright cursive, written with a fine-pointed pen; (3rd hand) heavier, less elegant, hand (Boak).;(1st hand) occasionally overcome by a strong cursive tendency, with considerable "Verschleifung" in the list of sealers; (2nd hand) very rapid, with no pretension to aesthetic effect (Youtie)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="-0074">April 13, 74 B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Neilou polis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Heirenaios alias Hergeus (Herieus), son of Heirenaios alias Hergeus, Perses tes epigones, husband and guardian of Apollonia</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonia alias Thaues, daughter of Ptolemaios alias Petesouchos, Persine, wife of Heirenaios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios (XII) (basileus) &amp; Kleopatra (V) epikaloumene Tryphaina (basileia), theoi Philopatores Philadelphoi</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Alexandros (deified)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Akousilaos son of Straton, Makedon, syngraphophylax</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Epiodoros, Makedon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Areios son of Heraklas, Makedon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Polydeukes son of Heraklas, Makedon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonios son of Amesystos(?), Makedon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dionysios son of Isidoros, Makedon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Theogenes</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Soknopaiou Nesos, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Alexandria; Neilou polis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome; Perses; Persine; Makedon</term>
               <term>Loans--Rome.</term>
               <term>Iranians--Egypt--Alexandria.</term>
               <term>Loans--Egypt--Alexandria.</term>
               <term>Deeds--Egypt</term>
               <term>Women--Economic conditions--Egypt--332 B.C.-640 A.D.</term>
               <term>Women--Finance, Personal.</term>
               <term>Ethnology--Rome.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Recto);;(Scriptura interior, sealed);(2nd hand) X has loaned to Eirenaios also called Hergeus, son of Eirenaios also called Hergeus, a Persian, and Apollonia also called Thaues, daughter of Ptolemaios also called Petesouchos, a Persian woman, in copper coinage 1 talent and 490 (drachmai) at two drachmai interest (per month). Let them repay in Thooth of the 8th year. 6 witnesses.;;(Scriptura exterior);(1st hand) In the seventh year of Ptolemy and Cleopatra called Tryphaina, his sister, Gods father-loving and brother-loving, the priest of Alexander and the others being as recorded in Alexandria, in the fifth of the month Gorpiaios, Epeiph fifth, in Neilou polis of the division of Herakleides of the Arsinoite nome. X has loaned to Eirenaios also called Hergeus, son of Eirenaios also called Hergeus, a Persian of the Epigone, and his wife Apollonia also called Thaues, daughter of Ptolemaios also called Petesouchos, a Persian woman, with her aforesaid husband as guardian, in copper coinage one talent and four hundred and ninety drachmai at two drachmai interest (per month). Let the borrowers repay both the loan and the interest to X in the month Thouth of the eighth year. And if they do not pay as has been written, let the borrowers pay fortwith as a penalty to X one and a half times the loan, but the interest without increase. The borrowers themselves are mutual sureties for recovery of this loan, and let the right of execution rest with X against the borrowers themselves and all their possessions, against one and against both and against whichever of them he may choose. The contract is valid. Witnesses: Akousilaos, son of Straton; Ptolemaios, son of Epiodoros; Areios (and) Polydeukes, both sons of Heraklas; Apollonios, son of Amesystos(?); Dionysios, son of Isidoros; the six Macedonians.;Guardian of the contract: Akousilaos.;(2nd hand) Year 7, Epeiph 5. It has been handed in for registration through Theogenes.;(3rd hand) We, Eirenaios also called Hergeus, son of Eirenaios [also called Hergeus], a Persian of the Epigone, and his wife Apollonia also called Thaues, daughter of Ptolemaios also called Petesouchos, a Persian woman, [acknowledge that we have received in copper] coinage one talent and [four] hundred and ninety [drachmai at [two drachmai] interest (per month), and we shall repay as it is written. [- - -];;(Verso);;(1st hand) (Seals of) Eirenaios; Apollonia; Akousilaos; Ptolemaios; Areios; Polydeukes; Apollonios; Dionysios.;;(Docket) Loan [- - -] to [Eirenaios - - -].</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, Aegyptus 13, 107-112, 1933, Photo -- SB V 7532 -- BL III, 188 (line 2); BL VI, 137 (lines 28a, 37); BL VII, 194 (lines 2a,3a,9,26,28,28a,30-1,35,36,3). Youtie HC, ZPE 12, 161-171, 1973, Pl. IV-VI</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2629&amp;viewid=6051R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/5/1/R/6051R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2629&amp;viewid=6051R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2629&amp;viewid=6051R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/5/1/V/6051V.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2629&amp;viewid=6051V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2629&amp;viewid=6051V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
