<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Division of Property</title>
            <author>Hermas, son of Ptolemaios; Petesouchos, son of Petosiris; Horos, son of Katoites; Hatres, son of Katoites</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1299</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1299</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.10.584</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;10;584</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;10;584</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12271</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12271</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 102</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract by which four parties - Hermas, son of Ptolemaios; Petesouchos, son of Petosiris; Horos, son of Katoites; and Hatres, son of Katoites - divide among themselves, by lot, an old house and courtyard which they own in Bacchias</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">See the diagram showing the topography of the property in P.Mich. X, p. 30</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto + Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Horos and Tapekysis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 21.5 x 27 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Damaged along the folds, particularly in the lower part</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto - 53;;Verso - 2</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto + Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>See P.Mich. X, 585 (inv. 103)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0084">August 12, 84 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Bacchias, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Domitian, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos son of Petosiris = Petsiris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Katoithes = Katoites (&amp; unnamed brothers) (see P.Mich. X, p. 20</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">XI, p. 15)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hatres son of Katoithes = Katoites</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menches son of Katoithes = Katoites (&amp; unnamed brothers)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron son of Dionysodoros</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Bacchias, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Bacchias, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome</term>
               <term>House Ownership</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>The third year of the Emperor Caesar Domitian Augustus, on the nineteenth of the motnh Mesore, at Bacchias in the division of Herakleides of the Arsinoite nome.;Hermas, son of Ptolemaios, about forty-nine years old, with a scar in the middle of his forehead, and Petesouchos, son of Petosiris, about sixty-two years old, with a scar on the right knee, and Horos, son of Katoites, about fifty-five years old, with a scar in the middle of his forehead, the four of them, acknowledge that they have divided among themselves from the present for all time their property in the aforesaid village, consisting of a house and courtyard, which has fallen in ruins, and all the appurtenances, of which the adjoining areas are: on the south a common entrance and exit; on the north likewise another common entrance and exit; on the west the house of Menches, son of Katoites, and his brothers; on the east the house of Horos, son of Katoites, and his brothers; of which property Hermas owns a third and a ninth share of the entire house and courtyard, acquired by purchase; Petesouchos and Horos own in common a third share, which they inherited from their fathers; and Hatres owns the remaining share, viz., two ninths.;And in accordance with this division by lot which they made among themselves by common consent, Hermas has obtained as the share which falls to him a third and a ninth, of which the third is in the middle and is seventeen cubits south to north, and from west to east it is five and one third cubits on the southern side, and six cubits on the northern side, and the remaining ninth part is held in common and undivided ownership with the two ninths of Hatres, as indicated below; and Petesouchos and Horos, the two of them, have likewise obtained in common as the share which falls to them too a third of the same house and courtyard, located on the eastern side, and running south to north through the whole property, being seventeen cubits south to north, and from west to east five and one third cubits on the southern side, and six cubits on the northern side; and Hatres himself has obtained as the share which falls to him too two ninths, common and undivided with the ninth portion of the aforesaid Hermas, as stated above, located on the western side and being seventeen cubits south to north, and from west to east five and one third cubits on the southern side, and six cubits on the northern side.;And each of the aforesaid parties shall hold and control the properties which he has obtained by lot with all the fixtures on each, and shall tear them down, build them up, repair them, and accomplish on them whatever they wish, and shall occupy the premises and lodge others therein, collect the rents, sell the property, mortgage it, and manage it in whatever way they choose without hindrance.;Accordingly let the contracting parties, each of them and their representatives and their heirs, abide by the terms which are set forth in accordance with this division, and let it not be permissible to . . ., and if anyone of them does not abide by the division, let the one who has transgressed it pay to the party who abides by it double the amount of the damages and expenses and a fine of one thousand silver drachmai, and the same amount to the treasury, and nevertheless the terms of the contract shall remain valid. Signatories: for Petesouchos and his associate Heron, son of Dionysodoros, age 36, without any identifying mark; for Hatres Apol(--), son of Melas, age 55, with a scar on the . . . shin; Hermas wrote with his own hand.;(2nd hand) I, Hermas, son of Ptolemaios, acknowledge that I have made with Petesouchos, son of Petsiris, and Horos, son of Katoites, and Hatres, son of Katoites, the division of the house and courtyard, and that I have obtained as the share which falls to me one third in the middle, extending seventeen cubits south to north, and from west to east five and one third cubits on the southern side, and six cubits on the northern side, &lt;and a ninth&gt; which is common and undivided with the share of Hatres, together with all the fixtures on them, and I shall do everything as stated above.;(3rd hand) We, Petesouchos, son of Horos, and Horos, son of Katoites, acknowledge that we have made with Hermas, son of Ptolemaios, and Hatres, son of Katoites, the division of the house and courtyard, and that we have obtained in common as the share which falls to us one third, located on the eastern side, and running south to north through the whole property, being seventeen cubits south to north, and from west to east five and one third cubits on the southern side, and six cubits on the northern side, &lt;and a ninth&gt; which is common and undivided with the share of Hatres, together with all the fixtures on them as stated above. Heron, son of Dionysodoros, wrote for them, as they are illiterate.;(4th hand) I, Hatres, son of Katoites, acknowledge that I have made with Hermas, son of Ptolemaios, and Petesouchos, son of Petosiris, and Horos, son of Katoites, the division of the house and courtyard, and that I have obtained as the share which falls to me two ninths, common and undivided with the ninth portion which fell to the aforesaid Hermas, located on the western side and being seventeen cubits south to north, and from west to east five and one third cubits on the southern side, and six cubits on the northern side, as stated above. Apollo(--), son of Melas, wrote for him, as he is illiterate.;(1st hand) The third year of the Emperor Caesar Domitian Augustus, Mesore 19, registered through the record office at Bacchias.;;(Verso) Agreement of division made by Hermas and others.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Browne GM, PMich X, 584, 1970 -- BL VI, 83 (bibliography)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:10:584</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1299&amp;viewid=102R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/0/2/R/102R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1299&amp;viewid=102R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1299&amp;viewid=102R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/0/2/V/102V.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1299&amp;viewid=102V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1299&amp;viewid=102V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
