<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>agreement in duplicate</title>
            <author>Chairas</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1522</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1522</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.14.12171</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;14;12171</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;14;12171</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14554</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14554</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 176</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>A certain Chairas acknowledges that he has surrendered or restored to Nilos certain properties, a part of which he specifically calls his own.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 25.8 x 18.5 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This medium-brown papyrus is rather regularly cut off at all sides. Some damage remains along the edges of the sheet along with some abrasions in the middle of the sheet. Numerous vertical folds are still visible as is akollesis 1.3 cm. from the right edge. Noticeably thicker than a standard papyrus sheet, and it appears that there are indeed at least three layers of papyrus. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-47</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The sheet originally held two complete copies of the document, each occupying a full column. The upper portion of both copies has been lost; the left side of the first copy, to a depth of ca. 6 cm., has been stripped away; the second has a width of 14.2 cm. Although the bottom of the sheet is considerably damaged, it nevertheless exhibits a margin of 2.5 cm., while a margin of 1.5 cm. remains along the upper half of the right side. The intercolumnar space varies from 2.5 cm. at the top to 1.5 cm. at the bottom. Both copies were written by the same hand.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0191">December 30, 191 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Kerkesoucha, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nilos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Lucius Aelius Aurelius Commodus Antoninus Caesar, emperor</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Kerkesoucha, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt (?)</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Kerkesoucha,;topos of Sokration,;topos of the Embankment,;topos of Herakleides,;Karanis,;.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>". . . that I, Chairas, have restored to Nilos, of the properties in the neighborhood of Kerkesoucha, in the topos of Sokration, two arouras; in the topos of the Embankment, one aroura out of three arouras of newly planted land and three-fourths aroura of an olive grove; and that I, Chairas, (have also restored to him) the remainder of my properties in the neighborhood of the village of Kerkesoucha, in all five arouras in two parcels - in the topos of Herakleides three (arouras) and two out of three arouras; and in the neighborhood of Karanis one aroura of a palm grove; and that I shall bring no charges against Nilos concerning the arouras that I have surrendered to him, nor shall I bring suit against him, nor will his agents bring charges against me in respect to the accusations and the submission of petitions which he made earlier, nor concerning any other matter at all in any way. Let this chirograph, written in duplicate, be valid wherever it is produced, as if it had been deposited in a public archive. And whenever he wishes, let him declare the arouras that belong to him to the bureau of property registration. The thirty-second year of Lucius Aelius Aurelius Commodus Antoninus Caesar, our lord, Tybi 3."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, ZPE 28, 259-261, 1978 -- SB XIV 12171</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:14:12171</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1522&amp;viewid=176R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/7/6/r/176r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1522&amp;viewid=176R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1522&amp;viewid=176R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
