<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of Part of Two Rooms</title>
            <author>Thermouthis daughter of Marepsemis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1350</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1350</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.253</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;253</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;253</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12088</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12088</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1267</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Demotic contract for the sale of a half share in two rooms, made by Thermouthis, daughter of Marepsemis, to her son, Eutychos the elder; the subscriptions are in Greek, as well as the date which was added at the top of the papyrus</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyd">Demotic and Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 19.7 x 31.1 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">frayed at the top; some damage along one of the folds</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Demotic - 16;;Greek - 1 + 14</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0030">August 28, 30 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Tiberius, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petenephies son of Orseus (alias?) Achis &lt;or: son of Orseus grandson of Achis&gt;</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kames (&amp; unnamed brothers)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) sons of Nephies</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyd">Demotic and Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome; canal of Moeris</term>
               <term>Family</term>
               <term>House</term>
               <term>House Ownership</term>
               <term>Religion</term>
               <term>Sale</term>
               <term>Woman (&amp;amp</term>
               <term>guardian)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Greek date) 16th year, 5th intercalary day of Mesore.;;(Demotic) Year 16 of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, fifth month of the third season, the (days of) illumination, day 5. The woman Thermouthis, daughter of Marepsemis, her mother being Demarion, has said to *Jijoj, the elder, (son of) *Jijoj, who is called *Takn-lain, her son being present and acting for her as guardian . . . who is called Eutos (sic), his mother being Thermouthis: "You have satisfied my heart (with the) silver of the price of my half share of this room which is built &lt;read: this room of a house?&gt; which is equipped with beams and doors downstairs . . ., together with my half share of the way of entrance and exit, together with my half share of this bedroom (in) the third story, he having authority against her in the gate of the courtyard (?), (in the) Souchos town of Tebtynis (in) the division of Polemon, on the south side of the canal of Moeris, (in the) Arsinoite nome. The boundaries of the entire, undivided house: south the house of Pete- - - together with its courtyard; north, (the) house of Kames and his brothers; west, the royal road; east, the courtyard of - - -. No man in the world, nor I likewise, shall be able to exercise authority over them, except you, from this date. He that shall come to you on account of them, I will cause him to be far from you in respect of them, of necessity, without delay, and I will cause it to be clear for you from every writing, every document, everything in the world. Yours is every writing [which has been made] concerning them and every writing which has been made (for) my father (or) my mother concerning them and every writing which has been made for me concerning them. Yours - - - together with their law. The oath (and the) confirmation which shall be required of you (to) cause that I make it, I will make it.;;(Greek subscriptions) (1st hand) I, Thermouthis, daughter of Marepsemis, my mother being Demarion, with my guardian, my son, Eutychos the third, son of Eutychos, acknowledge that I have sold to my elder son, Eutychos, son of Eutychos, the half share, belonging to me by inheritance from my mother, of a room on the ground floor, and on the roof another half share of a so-called bedroom, unplastered, and of all the appurtenances, in Tebtynis, and of the entrances and exits. The neighbors of the whole house are: on the south, the house and court of Petenephies, son of Orseus Achis; on the north the house and court of Kames and others; on the west the royal road; and on the east the lots of the sons of Nephies. In return for this property we have received from Eutychos the elder the entire price fixed and agreed upon, in full, from hand to hand, out of the house, and we shall guarantee the sale with every guarantee from both public and private encumbrances and from every impost as aforesaid. I, Eutychos the 3rd, son of Eutychos, wrote for my mother because she is illiterate, and I have been appointed her guardian.;(2nd hand) Eutychos the elder, son of Eutychos. The sale was made to me as aforesaid.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Edgerton WF - Husselman EM, PMich V, 253, 1944 -- L. 1 (of the Greek text): read heates for heautes; l. 2: read prosbytero for presbytero; l. 9: read Eutychou prosbyterou ten, instead of Eutychou presbyterou Eutychou ten; l. 12: read Eutychos 3- Eutychou, instead of Eutychos Eutychou; l. 14: read gegon' eis me, instead of gegone eis me. (PH)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:253</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1350&amp;viewid=1267R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/6/7/R/1267R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1350&amp;viewid=1267R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1350&amp;viewid=1267R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
