<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Epistles of Paul</title>
            <author>St. Paul</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3556</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3556</idno>
            <idno type="dclp">61855</idno>
            <idno type="TM">61855</idno>
            <idno type="dclp-hybrid">p.beatty;2;2</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 6238</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Romans XIII, 12 - XIV, 8</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 15.2 x 22.5 cm. (TC)</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Torn at all sides. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-25</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: 33; Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The ink is dark brown and has faded little. There has been little rubbing of the surface, so that almost every letter is still legible. The writing is of the book hand and the letters are carefully formed and well spaced. Sigma has a flattish top, which generally bends downward somewhat; this distinguishes it from a w in the page numbers, which is a regular uncial sigma.Epsilon and theta are rather oval than round, but epsilon usually has the middle stroke somewhat prolonged. Iota is often prolonged below the line, never above. Omicron, especially when initial, is often small though it does not degenerate to a mere dot. All of the other letters tend to be broad, yet without heaviness. In phi the central curve is a pointed oval, so as to give breadth without the appearance of height. The page numbers are made with a different pen, They are larger and coarser, but are probably contemporary. So are the infrequent corrections between the lines written in a smaller, more cursive hand. The reading marks seem later, but the stichometral notes at the ends of Epistles seem contemporary. If the manuscripts were written in a scriptorium for pay, these notes would have been inserted by the business manager when determining the price.;There are no line fillers at the end of lines, but a similar mark, probably as a paragraph mark, is used at the end of each epistle. Also the middle stroke of epsilon is sometimes prolonged as if to do duty as a line filler. Similar prolongations of alpha, kappa, and lambda are rare. Smaller letters, sometimes a little crowded, occur rarely at line ends, but there are no ligatures.;There are a few cases of punctuation by a single dot in high position. Double dots like a colon occur once, near the end of Romans, after XVI, 27 and before XVI, 1. This may be interpreted as setting off the last chapter of Romans as a separate letter.;There are many slight spaces left in the text, often where they serve admirably for punctuation. Some of these spaces are sufficiently large so that one may be sure that the scribe intended them to mark the ends of of paragraphs. Others are so narrow that they may be explained as accidental. There are also reading marks which were inserted by a later hand. These are generally shaped like an acute accent made with a broad-pointed pen, though rarely they are hardly more than dots. In the width and heaviness of stroke, these marks are most similar to the page numbering, but in the MIchigan portion they cannot be by the same hand, as the ink is always paler. They were probably inserted by some later reader for his convenience, when readig in church. This view is somewhat supported by the fact that the reading marks were inserted only in Romans and Hebrews of the preserved parts of the manuscript. These reading marks are very irregularly placed even in the part of the manuscript where they are used.;Only one accent occurs, an acute over peras in Hebr. VI, 16. An angular rough breathing generally in the form of half an H occurs nine times. The apostrophe is used six times. Diaeresis seems to be emloyed somewhat irregularly for initial iota and ypsilon; also within a word, the occurrence of diaeresis for iota and ypsilon is irregular.;In general, words are divided at line ends so that as many consonants are attached to the following vowels as can be easily pronounced. Yet sometimes compound words are divided at the point of compounding.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0150" notAfter="0250">End of IInd century - first half of IIIrd century A.D. (?)</origDate>
                     <origPlace>unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>-</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">literary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sanders HA, Epistles of Paul, 51-52, 1935 -- l. 18: [o]s men . . . ; l. 23. ] kai eucharistei . . . ; l. 25: zome]n to . . . Kenyon FG, C.Beatty Biblical Papyri, Fasc III,sup, 1936, Table f. 17. r.</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3556&amp;viewid=6238_33.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/_/3/3/6238_33.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3556&amp;viewid=6238_33.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3556&amp;viewid=6238_33.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
