<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3786</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3786</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso contains two lines with amounts paid in tax; the name of  the individuals who paid these amounts are not preserved</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 32.4 x 29.3 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at all sides except the bottom. Kolleais near right margin. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-34</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 39 (ll. 1655-1689)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolema, daughter of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tanouris, daughter of Isidoros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 234)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Polydeukes, son of Heras, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapasion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 214)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Pasoknopaios, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Leontas, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Kastorous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 184)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpalos, son of Apion, grandson of Harpalos, mother Valeria (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petheus, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes, son of Phaesis, grandson of Mysthes, mother Aunchis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Ptolema (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petheus, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 203)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptollous, daughter of Mesoeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Koulas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 184)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sempronius Gemellus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 228)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemais, daughter of Apollonios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 220)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Euphrosyne (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 165)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phasis, son of Tesenouphris, grandson of Harphaesis, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 246)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios, son of Onnophris, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Ptolema (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 157)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion, son of Petsiris, grandson of Pasion, mother Thases (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis, son of Pekmes alias Heuremon, mother Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Achillas, son of Ptollis, grandson of Hieranouphis, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Patkonnis, son of Mysthes, grandson of Patkonnis, mother Taonnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 200)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchorimphis, son of Petheus the younger, grandson of Anchorimphis, mother Apollonous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petsaraipis, son of Hatres, grandson of Imouthes, mother Soeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Sisois, grandson of Petsiris, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sokmenis, son of Sokmenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 230)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tamaus  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 233)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 39.;Ptolema, daughter of Heras in conjunction with Tanouris, daughter of Isidoros (Poudes);;(left margin: drachmas 40) orchard taxes for the 12th year: apomoira drachmas 7, obol 1, chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives drachma 1, chalki 2, naubion obols 4.5, surcharges drachma 1, obols 5;;eparourion drachmas 8, obol 0.5, chalki 2, surcharges drachma 1, obols 4, chalki 2, kollybos obols 2;;geometria for the 12t year drachmas 18, chalki 2, surcharge drachma 1, obol 1, in total drachmas 19, obol 1, chalki 2;;Polydeukes, son of Heras, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapasion, drachmas 4;;Petheus, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Pasoknopaios, mother Tepheros, drachmas 4;;Leontas, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Kastorous, drachmas 12;;Harpalos, son of Apion, grandson of Harpalos, mother Valeria, drachmas 12;;Pasion, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petheus, mother Segathis, drachmas 8;;in total for the day drachmas 116, obols 14;;Pharmouthi 1:;Mysthes, son of Phaesis, grandson of Mysthes, mother Aunchis, drachmas 8;;Onnophris, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Ptolema, drachmas 8;;Petheus, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petheus, mother Segathis, drachmas 4, obols 28;;Ptollous, daughter of Mesoeris (Koulas);;(in left margin: drachmas 12, obols 20) interest on loan from Sempronius Gemellus in the 13th year;;private account in total drachmas 13, obols 3.5, chalki 2;;Ptolemais, daughter of Apollonios (Euphrosyne);;(in left margin: drachmas 12, obols 22) orchard taxes for the 12th year: apomoira drachmas 2, obols 5, tax on the produce of oil obols 2.5, chalki 2, naubion obols 2, surcharges obols 4.5;;eparourion drachma 1, obols 5.5, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5, chalki 2, in total drachmas 6, obols 3.5;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 7, obol 0.5, surcharges obols 2.5, chalki 2, in total drachmas 7, obols 3, chalki 2;;Phasis, son of Tesenouphris, grandson of Harphaesis, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Aphrodisios, son of Onnophris, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Ptolema, drachmas 8;;Pasion, son of Petsiris, grandson of Pasion, mother Thases, drachmas 8;;Phaesis, son of Pekmes alias Heuremon, mother Sambathion, drachmas 4;;Achillas, son of Ptollis, grandson of Hieranouphis, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;Patkonnis, son of Mysthes, grandson of Patkonnis, mother Taonnophris, drachmas 8;;Anchorimphis, son of Petheus the younger, grandson of Anchorimphis, mother Apollonous, drachmas 8;;Petsaraipis, son of Hatres, grandson of Imouthes, mother Soeris, drachmas 4;;Petaus, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Onnophris, son of Sisois, grandson of Petsiris, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Sokmenis, son of Sokmenis . . . (Tamaus);;(in left margin: drachmas 4, obols 17) orchard taxes for the 12th year: apomoira drachmas 2, obols 3, tax on the produce of oil obols 2, chalki 2, naubion obol 1, chalki 2, surcharges obols 3.5, chalki 2;;eparourion drachma 1, obols 4, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5, chalki 2, in total drachmas 5, obols 4, chalki 2;;in total for the day drachmas 116."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 -- CPJ 3, 492 (lines with Sambathion) Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3786&amp;viewid=4171_39R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/3/9/r/4171_39r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3786&amp;viewid=4171_39R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3786&amp;viewid=4171_39R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
