<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Cession of Land and House</title>
            <author>Gaius Iulius Gemellus</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1691</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1691</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.6.427</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;6;427</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;6;427</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12265</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12265</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 2927</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Copy of a contract in which Gaius Iulius Gemellus, a veteran, agrees to cede a half share of an olive grove and a half share of a house to a minor named Chairemon</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Cairo</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">archive of Gaius Apolinarius Niger (&amp; family)?</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 12.5 X 21 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">complete</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">33</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>see electronic version of PMich VI, 427</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0134">(After) August 27, 134 A.D. (date of the original document)</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Hadrianus, deceased Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius Iulius Gemellus, veteran</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon son of Horos, aphelix</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petsoraipis, son of Pnepheros, phrontistes of Chairemon</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Karanis</term>
               <term>(Land &amp;amp</term>
               <term>House) Ownership</term>
               <term>Personal status: aphelix (minor child, &amp;amp</term>
               <term>guardian)</term>
               <term>Citizenship--Rome.</term>
               <term>Veterans--Rome.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Copy of cession. The 18th year of the god Hadrian, the 4th intercalary day. Gaius Iulius Gemellus, a discharged soldier, about 55 years of age, with a scar in the middle of the forehead, acknowledges to Chairemon, son of Horos, a minor, through his guardian Petsoraipis, son of Pnepheros, about 62 years of age, with a scar on the right wrist, that he has ceded to him in accordance with this agreement from the present for all time the half share, which he also acquired by cession, of an olive grove of 15/32 aroura or as much as there may be, subject to the tax of one sixth, near Karanis, and in the village of Karanis an entire half share of a house and courtyard and all the appurtenances in one parcel, with the existing neighbors and boundaries, entrances and exits, conduits and drains of the entire property, and all other rights. For these the party of the first part, Gaius Iulius Gemellus, has received from Petsoraipis to the account of Chairemon, a minor, for the olive grove 100 drachmai and for the half of the buildings 100 drachmai, the total amount being 200 drachmai, and he will not bring action concerning these in any way, and he, Iulius Gemellus, and his heirs will guarantee to Chairemon and his heirs the ceded property described above with every guarantee from all public dues and every tax up to the past 17th year and including the 17th year of Hadrian Caesar the lord, and from private encumbrances and every claim for all time. Whenever he wishes, Chairemon shall register the ceded property by means of a copy of this contract without requiring the presence of the party of the first part. If he (Gemellus) violates the agreement in any way, let him pay as penalty 100 drachmai and to the public treasury the like amount.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Pearl OM-Youtie HC, PMich VI, 427, 1944</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:6:427</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1691&amp;viewid=1">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
