<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3298</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3298</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer paying the poll-tax is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>2 papyri ; col. 159-160: 35.5 x 29.6 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 159: damaged on the right by a break (papyrus cut off left of col. 159 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 159: 25 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 159 (l. 2849-2873)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Petheus and Taelekis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 203)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tapetesouchos daughter of Korakion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 237)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Serapous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon son of Heron and Didyme grandson of Orsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis son of Heras and Isidora grandson of Orsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis son of Phanomgeus and Tepheros grandson of Pakysis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Perigenes and Tanais grandson of Akousilaos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion (son of Thaisas), doulos of Syros alias Ptolemaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Melanas son of Melanas and Taeuemeros (Taeuhemeros) grandson of Pakysis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras son of Aphrodisios and Isidora grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Esouris and Tapetheus grandson of Harpagathes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchophis son of Mysthes and Tanais grandson of Anchophis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Menandros and Soeris grandson of Anchophis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Teos son of Mysthes and Tanais grandson of Anchophis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 242)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus son of Petheus and Tamystha grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Pasoxis and Heras grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Syros son of Onnophris and Tkollainis grandson of Maron (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 231)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mystharion son of Ischyrion and Tapetheus grandson of Euemeros (Euhemeros) (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 188)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor son of Onnophris and Tkollainis grandson of Maron (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion son of Aphrodisios and Tapetaus grandson of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus son of Phanomgeus and Taptosiris grandson of Phanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon son of Phanomgeus and Tbelles grandson of Phanomgeus and Taptosiris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Karanis (Extinct city)--Defenses.</term>
               <term>Slaves--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Real property tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Women--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Guards troops--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 159;;(Mesore 16, continued);;Petheus, son of Petheus and Taelekis, grandson of Petheus, for the guards: 1 drachme; (and) for the guard towers: 3 drachmai. Total [4] drachmai;Tapetesouchos, daughter of Korakion - (through) Serapous - for garden land of year 13: for apomoira, 5 drachmai; for olive (transportation), 4 obols 2 chalkoi; for naubion, 3 obols; for supplements, 1 drachme 1 1/2 obols; for eparourion, 6 drachmai 4 obols; for supplements, 3 1/2 obols; for kollybos, 1 1/2 obols. Total: 14 drachmai 5 [1/2] obols [2 chalkoi]. (In left margin: 16 drachmai 26 obols.);Chairemon, son of Heron and Didyme, grandson of Orsenouphis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Phaesis, son of Heras and Isidora, grandson of Orsenouphis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Pakysis, son of Phanomgeus and Tepheros, grandson of Pakysis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Sarapion, son of Perigenes and Tanais, grandson of Akousilaos, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Sarapion, slave of Syros also called Ptolemaios, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Melanas, son of Melanas and Taeuemeros, grandson of Pakysis: 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Heras, son of Aphrodisios and Isidora, grandson of Petheus, for ch(--): 12 drachmai;Petheus, son of Esouris and Tapetheus, grandson of Harpagathes, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Anchophis, son of Mysthes and Tanais, grandson of Anchophis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Horos, son of Menandros and Soeris, grandson of Anchophis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai 28 obols;Teos, son of Mysthes and Tanais, grandson of Anchophis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Phanomgeus, son of Petheus and Tamystha, grandson of Satabous, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Ptolemaios, son of Pasoxis and Heras, grandson of Satabous, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Syros, son of Onnophris and Tkollainis, grandson of Maron: 16 drachmai;Mystharion, son of Ischyrion and Tapetheus, grandson of Euemeros, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Kastor, son of Onnophris and Tkollainis, grandson of Maron: 16 drachmai;Horion, son of Aphrodisios and Tapetaus, grandson of Onnophris, for ch(--): [4] drachmai;Phanomgeus, son of Phanomgeus and Taptosiris, grandson of Phanomgeus, [for ch(--): 4 drachmai];Chairemon, his son, his mother being Tbelles, [for ch(--): 4 drachmai]</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 159 (l. 2849-2873), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3298&amp;viewid=4172_39RO.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/9/r/o/4172_39ro.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3298&amp;viewid=4172_39RO.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3298&amp;viewid=4172_39RO.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
