<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>letter</title>
            <author>Herakleides (?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2023</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2023</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.6.9025</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;6;9025</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;6;9025</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">27270</idno>
            <idno type="TM">27270</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 3630</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>The writer, in an abrupt style, refers to a variety of things - his delay in loading camels, lentils and their current local cost, grain and fish. He informs Horion, whom he addresses in a slightly superior tone, that he is sending one basket containing jujubes, pomegranates, and gourds, and another with fresh dates, some old wine secured with difficulty, and a quantity of bones. After expressing the customary greetings, he reverts to business details - his failure to receive the cotton chiton he wanted, his readiness to have one woven for Horion provided materials and measurements are sent, grain being being sent to Psobthis, and the dispatch of dates, pomegranates, and a letter through Phatres, who acts as a go-between.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 18.5 x 10.5 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This papyrus, of a medium-brown color and of good quality, is complete, but damaged in many places as a result of having been folded five times perpendicularly. The left side, though split along the second fold, presents no difficulty; the major loss occurs along the fourth and fifth folds, on the right, where there are several fairly large holes.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-34</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Decipherment has not been easy owing to the numerous small perforations, to abrasion, and to the varying shape of some letters, particularly epsilon, eta, ny, pi, and ypsilon as they appear in differing ligatures. Where these letters are not completely preserved, restoration is correspondingly difficult. The writing is on the recto in a rather small, practiced, upright cursive hand of the second century.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0100" notAfter="0199">IInd century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Oxyrhynchite nome, Middle Egypt, province of Egypt (?)</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides (?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Soueros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Helen</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thaesion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">. . . nos, the son of Appian</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phatres, the son of Chairas</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Oxyrhynchite nome, Middle Egypt, province of Egypt (?)</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Psobthis.</term>
               <term>Egypt--Oxyrhynchite Nome--Commerce.</term>
               <term>Commercial correspondence--Egypt--Oxyrhynchite Nome;.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Herakleides (?) to his dearest Horion, greeting. All who send letters send them concerning the camels. I detained the men who accompany the camels. For it was after we had loaded the camels with bones that the letter was brought to me. [This was a good thing] for I was able to buy . . . at the price of one hundred twelve drachmas the metretes. [And it proved timely, too,] for strangers have come looking for olive oil. When you were sending us lentils, you should have sent grain also, since you know that we have none to furnish. If you do not wish to send it now, it can be obtained [here] at the price of a stater for one and one-half metra. If you send an advance now, send five five artabas of wheat. Lentils are being sold at the rate of two metra for the stater. I received through Phatres one hundred ninety-six drachmas and four artabas of lentils and fourteen . . . at an obol each and . . . at the rate of two obols each, and the fish. Receive from Soueros a basket in which there are one metron of jujubes, thirty pomegranates, and fifteen gourds. Tell me at what price for the artaba you wish me to buy succulent olives. For they were all asking for grain and lentils by way of advance in order that they might make preparation. Receive from the same messenger a basket in which there are two metra of fresh dates and the six metretes two choes of old wine - it is only with much trouble that I find any - and twelve artabas of bones.  Greet Helen, Thaesion and her children, and Ptolemas. Farewell. Let (?) . . .nos, the son of Appian, come (?) at once. I have not found the cotton chiton as I should have liked. If you want to have one woven for you here, send warp thread and the measurements. Take thought about the grain which is being sent to Psobthis and the grain of Chairas. Do not neglect any one of all these things. Receive from Phatres, the son of Chairas, a basket in which there are three metra of dates and fifty pomegranates and a letter. See that you do not neglect it."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Winter JG-Youtie HC, AJP 65, 251-5, 1944 -- SB VI 9025</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:6:9025</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2023&amp;viewid=3630R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/3/0/R/3630R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2023&amp;viewid=3630R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2023&amp;viewid=3630R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
