<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3647</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3647</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.224</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 30 x 32.6 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at all sides except at the top where it has been torn off. Some damage has occurred with some lacunas stretching verticallly from the bottom. One kollesis in the middle between the two columns of writing. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-40</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 13 (ll. 469-509)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Anoubas, son of Horos, grandson of Anoubas, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p.151)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Valerios, fatherless, mother Valeria (see P.Mich. IV/2, p.195)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aunes, son of Aunes, grandson of Hermas, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p.157)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis, son of Heras, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Isidora (see P.Mich. IV/2, p.244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Limnaios, son of Onnophris, grandson of Satabous, mother Ptolema (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 185)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Souchas, grandson of Heras, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p.169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Petheus, grandson of Teos, mother Taonnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p.171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Kanis, grandson of Petheus, mother Tkollainis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p.202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Sambas, mother Taeumeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p.224)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon, son of Horos, grandson of Onnophris, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p.247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Leonides, grandson of Papeis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Perigenes, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Tanais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Menandros, grandson of Anchophis, mother Soeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Satabous, mother Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Petsiris, mother Heros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Germanos, slave Longinus Isidoros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 160)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Phaesis, grandson of Petheus, mother Tanais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Aunes, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Tauris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Ptolemais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Onnophris, mother Tkollainis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petalos, son of Petaus, grandson of Petaus, mother Soeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos, son of Hatres, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Erieus the older, son of Horos, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Euthyches, slave of Sarapias (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 165)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Vettis, son of Petheus, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Taseus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 195)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Sambas, grandson of Sabinus, mother Aphrodous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pamonneouis, son of Anchoryphis, grandson of Pamonnesis, mother Didymarion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Agathos Daimon, grandson Petheus, mother Stynchis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Polydeukes, son of Heras, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapasion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 214)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Pasoknopaios, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Heras, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Hieranouphis, grandson of Demas, mother Ptolema (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>" [(Column) 13]:;Anoubas, son of Horos, grandson of Anoubas, mother Tepheros, drachmas 4;;Valerios, fatherless, mother Valeria, drachmas 8;;Aunes, son of Aunes, grandson of Hermas, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4, obols 28;;Phaesis, son of Heras, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Isidora, drachmas 4;;Limnaios, son of Onnophris, grandson of Satabous, mother Ptolema, drachmas 8;;Heras, son of Souchas, grandson of Heras, mother Tapetheus, obols 28;;Heron, son of Petheus, grandson of Teos, mother Taonnophris, drachmas 4, obols 28;;Petheus, son of Kanis, grandson of Petheus, mother Tkollainis, drachmas 20;;Sambas, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Sambas, mother Taeumeros, drachmas 4, obols 28;;Chairemon, son of Horos, grandson of Onnophris, mother Segathis, drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, son of Leonides, grandson of Papeis, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4, obols 8;;12th year the same ?, copper drachmas;in total for the day drachmas 144, obols 21, of which 12th year, obols 20;;(Tybi) 15 likewise:;Sarapion, son of Perigenes, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Tanais, drachmas 8;;Horos, son of Menandros, grandson of Anchophis, mother Soeris, drachmas 4, obols 27;;Ptolemaios, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Satabous, mother Heras, drachmas 4;;Onnophris, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Petsiris, mother Heros, drachmas 4;;Germanos, slave Longinus Isidoros, drachmas 4, obols 28;;Ptolemaios, son of Phaesis, grandson of Petheus, mother Tanais, drachmas 12;;Onnophris, son of Aunes, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thaisas, drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Tauris, drachmas 8;;in total for the day, drachmas 56, obols 26;;(Tybi) 16 likewise:;Herakleides, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Ptolemais, drachmas 4;;Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Onnophris, mother Tkollainis, drachmas 4;;Petalos, son of Petaus, grandson of Petaus, mother Soeris, drachmas 12;;Petesouchos, son of Hatres, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 12, obols 20;;Erieus the older, son of Horos, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8;;Euthyches, slave of Sarapias, drachmas 4;;Vettis, son of Petheus, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Taseus, drachmas 4, obols 28;;12th year the same, ? copper drachmas: ;Ptolemaios, son of Sambas, grandson of Sabinus, mother Aphrodous, drachmas 4;;Pamonneouis, son of Anchoryphis, grandson of Pamonnesis, mother Didymarion, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Agathos Daimon, grandson Petheus, mother Stynchis, drachmas 8, obols 28;;Polydeukes, son of Heras, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapasion, drachmas 8;;Petheus, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Pasoknopaios, mother Tepheros, drachmas 4;;(in left margin: copper drachmas)Ptolemaios, son of Heras, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, son of Hieranouphis, grandson of Demas, mother Ptolema, copper drachmas 4, obols 28;;in total for the day, drachmas 100, obols 8, of which 12th year, drachmas 8 [obols] 19 and in deposit drachmas 8."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3647&amp;viewid=4171_13R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3647&amp;viewid=4171_13R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3647&amp;viewid=4171_13R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
