<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Loan with Right of Habitation</title>
            <author>Taoris, Didyme and Soueris, the three daughters of Petsiris</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1292</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1292</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12299</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12299</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;12;635</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 100</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract by which three sisters agree to furnish lodging to Maron, son of Hermas, instead of paying interest on a debt of 200 drachmai</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto + Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Horos and Tapekysis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 23.3 x 21 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Broken off and abraded on the right side; slightly damaged along the folds</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto - 26;;Verso - 1</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto + Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0071">April 13, 71 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Bacchias, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Vespasian, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Taoris daughter of Petsiris (Petosiris), Persine</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didyme daughter of Petsiris (Petosiris), wife of Herakleides, Persine</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Soueris daughter of Petsiris (Petosiris), wife of Onnophris, Persine</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides son of Chairemon, husband and legal guardian of Didyme, and legal guardian of Taoris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Onnophris, husband and legal guardian of Soueris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron son of Hermas (see also P.Mich. X, 583)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Eubis (Eubios) son of Isidoros</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Bacchias, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Bacchias, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome; he legomene Borroanon laura</term>
               <term>Contracts--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Home ownership--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Interest--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Loans--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Iranians--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Guardian and ward650: 0:Iranians--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Recto);;Copy. The third year of the Emperor Caesar Vespasianus Augustus, the 18th of the month of Pharmouthi, in Bacchias in the division of Herakleides of the Arsinoite nome.;Taoris, about fifty years old . . ., and Didyme, about forty-five years old, with a scar on her forehead on the right, and Soueris, about . . . years old . . ., who are, all three of them, daughters of Petsiris, Persian women, and mutual sureties for recovery, and for whom the guardians are: for Taoris and Didyme the husband of Didyme, Herakleides, the son of Chairemon, about . . . years old, with a scar on his left . . .; for Soueris her own husband Onnophris, the son of Onnophris, about . . . years old, with a scar . . ., acknowledge to Maron, son of Hermas, about 41 years old, with a scar in the middle of his forehead below the hair, that they have received from him a loan of two hundred silver drachmai in coined money forthwith from hand to hand out of the house, and that instead of the interest thereon, the parties of the first part have agreed that Maron, his representatives, and whomever he wishes shall reside for five years from the aforesaid time in the property which belongs to the parties of the first part themselves, in the aforesaid village of Bacchias, viz., a ninth share of a house and courtyard with all the appurtenances in the so-called street of Borroanon; of which a third share belongs to the same Maron.;Accordingly let the parties of the first part and their representatives guarantee the provisions of this contract of habitation to Maron and his representatives with full guarantee both for the duration of the loan established by the contract and for as long as additional lodging is necessary. And they will deliver the designated ninth share of the house and courtyard unencumbered, unpledged, not offered as collateral, and free from all debts, both public and private, and they will see that no one hinders Maron or his representatives from living in this property, lodging others therein, collecting the rents, and using all the appurtenances of the house and courtyard in common.;And at the expiration of the period let the parties of the first part repay the two hundred silver drachmai to Maron, and until they repay they agree that Maron shall reside as stated above. And if it appears that Maron has undergone expense in repairing or also in building or for any other purpose in the aforesaid ninth share of the house and courtyard, it is necessary that the parties of the first part repay Maron himself without any delay or subterfuge.;Signatory: for Didyme and Taoris Herakleides, their aforesaid guardian and husband of Didyme; for Soueris and her guardian and husband Eubios, son of Isidoros, about 25 years old, with a scar in the middle of his nose.;;(Verso);;Copy of the contract of habitation, (made) by Taoris and others to Maron.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Browne GM, BASP 7, 13-16, 1970 -- SB XII 10779 Browne GM, PMich XII, 635, 1975 -- The line on the Verso was omitted in both editions; it shows that the name of the first sister is Taoris, not Tauris. (PH)</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1292&amp;viewid=100R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/0/0/R/100R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1292&amp;viewid=100R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1292&amp;viewid=100R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/0/0/V/100V.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1292&amp;viewid=100V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1292&amp;viewid=100V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
