<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>list of aromata and honey</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1906</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1906</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.14.12074</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;14;12074</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;14;12074</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">65756</idno>
            <idno type="TM">65756</idno>
            <idno type="dclp">65756</idno>
            <idno type="dclp-hybrid">tm;;65756</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 3243</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>The papyrus contains a list of aromata and honey with seven items. These items were all used for medical purposes in antiquity and most likely this is the intended use for the items listed on this particular list. (TC)</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Zenon-archive (?)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 8.5 x 22 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">A light-brown papyrus regularly cut at all sides. After the list was written on the sheet, it was folded vertically toward the center - twice from left to right and twice from right to left; five long panels of equal size were formed. Some time after the papyrus had been folded, a notch two centimeter in length was cut along the right-hand fold, about one centimeter from the top of the papyrus. In view of the haste with which the papyrus was folded so soon after the writing, it seems highly likely that the whole process was intended from the beginning. Yet the purpose of such a procedure is not easy to determine. Perhaps a tie was put around the narrow formed by the cut-out. By means of such a tie the folded list could be suspended from some other object, possibly a hook; the list could not be read, however, when the papyrus was folded and suspended in such a way.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-9</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The list is of seven items is written on the upper half of the papyrus sheet: the top margin is four centimeters; the blank space at the bottom is eleven centimeters; at left is a normal two centimeter margin. The individual letters were carefully formed and each item were in the list occupies a single line. The hand can probably be dated to the first half of the third century B.C. Characteristic is the formation of the my, produced by two more or less vertical lines and a shallow curve which joins them; the ny (especially in lines 5-6), where the cross stroke moves toward the horizontal and the final stroke extends upward and almost reaches the height of a kappa; the tau, which is shaped like backward gamma; the ypsilon, which is similar in form to the tau, but whose cross stroke is slightly curved; and the omega, which is a raised and wavy stroke. The alpha is a capital letter, extremely regular in form, and the examples here resemble those in the earliest papyri.;The document was folded before the ink was dry and traces of offsets of letters appear in the margin at lines 1,4, and most conspicuously at line 8.;A small mark (line 1) appears in the second panel of the recto, just to the right of the hole produced by the notch; the purpose of the mark was apparently to show the scribe the probable position of the notch which was to be made and to remind him to start his first line well below that point.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="-0299" notAfter="-0250">(early) to middle third century B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Philadelphia, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt (?)</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Philadelphia, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt (?)</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>-</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>-</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Hanson AE, TAPA 103, 161-6, 1972, Photo -- SB XIV 12074</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:14:12074</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1906&amp;viewid=3243R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/4/3/r/3243r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1906&amp;viewid=3243R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1906&amp;viewid=3243R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
