<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>medical text</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1448</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1448</idno>
            <idno type="dclp">63839</idno>
            <idno type="TM">63839</idno>
            <idno type="dclp-hybrid">p.lond.lit;;170</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1469</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>This papyrus preserves a single column from a roll which contained a medical treatise. The subject of our fragmentary column is the nourishment to be given to patients who are afflicted  with constipation.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 6 x 13.6 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">A strip of papyrus has broken off along the right side, carrying with it 5-9 letters from each of the first 14 lines, but the losses are not insurmountable. Beyond line 14, however, the situation is desperate. The loss of papyrus is so extensive that we have mo attempt at restoration of the lines.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-24</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The taxt has the usual generous format of well written books produced by professional scribes. There is an upper margin of 2.3 cm., while of the left margin only 1 cm. remains at lines 5-7. The lines are well-spaced and the medium-sized letters are upright, somewhat squarish, and belong to the "formal mixed" category, cf. Turner, Greek Manuscripts, p. 26. The letters alpha and delta are angular, both of them extending backwards so that they frequently look alike; sigma is always narrow, as likewise epsilon, except for its elongated tongue; pi, tau and ypsilon extend below the line; omega has a regularly rounded bottom. The hand is reminiscent of O. Montevecchi, La Papirologia, Tav. 66, but is perhaps even closer to that  of C. H. Roberts, Greek Literary Hands, 15c and 17b, but without their leftward slant. 15c, the Michigan Dioscorides papyrus, is securely dated to the 2nd half of the 2nd century A.D. 17b, the Hellenica Oxyrhynchia, has likewise been assigned to the 2nd half of the 2nd century A.D. While Tav. 66, the famous London Bacchylides papyrus, of which the date has undergone several revisions, is now firmly assigned to the late 2nd  century A.D.P. Mich. inv. 1469 has no accents or breathings. Punctuation is effected with high points (lines 5, 9, 15, 22) and paragraphoi (beneath lines 5 and 15).</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0150" notAfter="0199">(late) IInd century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>-</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">sub-literature</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>" . . . to take the small portion of food, to drink all the previously mentioned liquids, and to drink in addition a little new wine, diluted until somewhat watery. To those who have a persistent constipation hard to clear up, much more than the quantities prescribed are given; but to those who suffere from weakness, less. And a moderate diet is prescribed when the bowels have become more relaxed. The risk of injury to the eyes have been previously mentioned.  . . ."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC-Youtie LC, Scritti Onore Montevecchi, 431-5, 1981 -- SB XVI 12529 Andorlini I, Yale Class Stud 28, 49, 1985</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:16:12529</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1448&amp;viewid=1469R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/6/9/r/1469r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1448&amp;viewid=1469R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1448&amp;viewid=1469R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
