<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of Sacred Land </title>
            <author>Cheos, son of Harmiysis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1353</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1353</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11569</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11569</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.kron;;48dupl</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1270</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract by which Cheos, son of Harmiysis, sells to Mieus, son of Phomsais, three arourai of sacred land; this copy was intended for incorporation in the records of the grapheion (as shown by l. 1), and bears a brief docket on the verso.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto + Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">Duplicate of P.Mich. V, 260 = P.Kron. 48 (inv. 640). - Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 14 x 29 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">ink rubbed from the surface of the papyrus at places at the top and bottom</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto - 48;;Verso - 2</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto + Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0035">December 26, 35 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Tiberius, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Cheos son of Harmiysis and Thaesis (see P.Kron., p. xx)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mieus son of Phomsais = Pomsais (see also P.Mich. V, 238, l. 103)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis son of Horouanchious = Anchious (see also P.Mich. II, p. 224</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">V, p. 389)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marcus Iulius Hyllos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thaesis daughter of Psosneus, mother of Cheos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles (alias Orseus?) son of Herodes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ischyrion son of Patron</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orseus (= Herakles alias Orseus son of Herodes?)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome; kyte (koite?) legomene</term>
               <term>Administration</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Land Ownership</term>
               <term>Land Status</term>
               <term>Notary</term>
               <term>Illegitimacy--Egypt</term>
               <term>Sale</term>
               <term>Taxation (Land)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Recto);;The twenty-second year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, Peritios 30, Choiak 30, in Tebtynis in the division of Polemon of the Arsinoite nome. Cheos, son of Harmiysis, about twenty-five years old, with a scar on his left thumb, acknowledges to Mieus, son of Phomsais, about forty years old, with a scar on his right shin, that he has sold to him, Mieus, the sacred land that belongs to him, Cheos, by inheritance from his father, three arourai, or as many more as there may be. The neighbors are on the south the allotment of Orsenouphis, son of Horouanchious, on the north the allotment of Marcus Iulius Hyllos, on the west the so-called quarters, on the east the allotment formerly belonging to Psosneus, son of Tapesouris. Cheos acknowledges that he has received from Mieus the whole price agreed upon in full, from hand to hand, out of the house, and that he and his representatives will guarantee to Mieus ad his representatives the provisions of the sale with every guarantee, from all public debts and all imposts and the naubion tax and the artab tax and the arithmetikon, and surtaxes and all other charges levied for former times up to the past twenty-first year and for the past twenty-first year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, and from private encumbrances aand every claim forever. Cheos's mother, Thaesis, daughter of Psosneus, about forty years old, with a scar on her right knee, consents to the sale and agrees not to proceed against it nor to bring any claim against it. The signatory of the acknowledging parties is Herakles, son of Herodes, about fifty years old, with a scar on his right wrist; of the other, Ischyrion, son of Patron, about twenty-five years old, with a scar in the middle of his forehead beneath the hair.;(2nd hand) I, Cheos, son of Harmiysis, acknowledge that I have sold to Mieus, son of Phomsais, the sacred land belonging to me by inheritance from my father, three arourai or as many as there may be, and all the appurtenances in Tebtynis; the neighbors being on the south the allotment of Orsenouphis, son of Anchious, on the north the allotment of Hyllos, on the west the quarters, on the east the allotment formerly belonging to Psosneus, son of Tapesouris. And I have received the price in full and guarantee the sale from all public debts and from the artab tax and naubion tax, and from every impost for former times up to the past twenty-first year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus and for the past twenty-first year. My mother, Thaesis, daughter of Psosneus, consents as aforesaid. . . . Orseus wrote for them because they are illiterate.;(3rd hand) Mieus, son of Phomsais. The sale was made to me as aforesaid. Ischyrion, son of Patron, wrote for him because he is illiterate.;;(Verso);;Agreement (of sale) of 3 arourai of sacred land, (made) by Mieus to Cheos (sic).</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 261, 1944 -- Verso, l. 1, has only Mieuto(s), not Mieut(os) Phomsais as given in the ed.pr. (PH)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:261</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1353&amp;viewid=1270R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1353&amp;viewid=1270R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1353&amp;viewid=1270R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1353&amp;viewid=1270V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1353&amp;viewid=1270V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
