<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3325</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3325</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 29 is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 29-30: 34.5 x 29.5 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 29: nearly complete (papyrus cut off left of col. 28 when housed in glass); damaged near a kollesis</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 29: 59 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 29 (l. 397-456)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus son of Pnepheros and Thaesis grandson of Phanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras son of Horos alias Karanos and Tamystha grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabous son of Petheus and Tapetaus grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 226)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Akoution son of Heron and Tauris grandson of Akousilaos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 150)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion son of Petsiris and Thases grandson of Pasion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron son of Petheus neoteros and Apollonous grandson of Anchorimphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinus son of Pasoknopaios and Tapetheus grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides son of Abykis and Herais grandson of Abykis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Menches and Thasis grandson of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras son of Petsiris and Isidora grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos son of Petesouchos and Tasoucharion grandson of Petesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymion son of Petheus presbyteros and Tasoucharion grandson of Didymion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 161)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios son of Onnophris and Ptolema grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 157)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dioskoros son of Petheus and Taorsenouphis grandson of Kollouthos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis son of Ptolemaios and Soeris grandson of Orsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 194)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Leonides and Thermouthis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anoubas son of Horos and Tepheros grandson of Anoubas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 151)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Valerius son of Valeria, apator (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 195)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus son of Petheus and Tapasion grandson of Petaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon son of Heron and Didyme grandson of Orsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon son of Pasoxis and Tanephremis grandson of Pasoxis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas son of Ptolemaios and Taeuemeros grandson of Sambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 224)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasoknopais (Pasoknopaios) son of Phasis and Tanomgeus grandson of Esouris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 199)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psenesis son of Petesouchos and Heras grandson of Psenesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Perigenes and Tanaisgrandson of Akousilaos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios son of Ptolemaios and Tapetesouchos grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Perigenes son of Zoilos and Sambathion grandson of Ptolemaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Petheus and Taphasis grandson of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 203)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Illegitimacy--Egypt</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 29;;On the 17th (of Phamenoth), similarly:;Phanomgeus, son of Pnepheros and Thaesis, grandson of Phanomgeus: 8 drachmai;    column 5;Heras, son of Horos also called Karanos and Tamystha, grandson of Petheus: 20 drachmai;    column 22;Satabous, son of Petheus and Tapetaus, grandson of Satabous: 4 drachmai;    column 1;Akoution, son of Heron and Tauris, grandson of Akousilaos, for the guard towers: 8 drachmai;    column 1;Pasion, son of Petsiris and Thases, grandson of Pasion: 8 drachmai;    column 5;Maron, son of Petheus the younger and Apollonous, grandson of Anchorimphis: 8 drachmai;    column 8;Sabinus, son of Pasoknopaios and Tapetheus, grandson of Horos: 4 drachmai;    column 9;Herakleides, son of Abykis and Herais, grandson of Abykis: 8 drachmai;    column 9;Onnophris, son of Menches and Thasis, grandson of Onnophris: 4 drachmai;    column 10;Heras, son of Petsiris and Isidora, grandson of Heras: 4 drachmai 20 obols;    column 18;Petesouchos, son of Petesouchos and Tasoucharion, grandson of Petesouchos: 16 drachmai;    column 23;Didymion, son of Petheus the elder and Tasoucharion, grandson of Didymion: 4 drachmai;    column 25;Aphrodisios, son of Onnophris and Ptolema, grandson of Pnepheros: 8 drachmai;    column 4;Dioskoros, son of Petheus and Taorsenouphis, grandson of Kollouthos: 8 drachmai;    column 27;Orsenouphis, son of Ptolemaios and Soeris, grandson of Orsenouphis: 4 drachmai;    column 28;Ptolemaios, son of Leonides and Thermouthis, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai;    column 28;Anoubas, son of Horos and Tepheros, grandson of Anoubas: 4 drachmai;    column 29;Valerius, of unknown father, his mother being Valeria: 28 obols;    column 29;Petaus, son of Petheus and Tapasion, grandson of Petaus: 4 drachmai 28 obols;    column 34;Chairemon, son of Heron and Didyme, grandson of Orsenouphis: 8 drachmai;    column 35;Chairemon, son of Pasoxis and Tanephremis, grandson of Pasoxis: 4 drachmai;    column 40;Sambas, son of Ptolemaios and Taeuemeros, grandson of Sambas: 8 drachmai;    column 41;Pasoknopais, son of Phasis and Tanomgeus, grandson of Esouris: 4 drachmai;    column 42;Total for the day: 160 drachmai 18 obols.;;On the 18th, similarly:;Psenesis, son of Petesouchos and Heras, grandson of Psenesis: 16 drachmai;    column 102;Sarapion, son of Perigenes and Tanais, grandson of Akousilaos: 4 drachmai;    column 45;Aphrodisios, son of Ptolemaios and Tapetesouchos, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai;    column 45;Perigenes, son of Zoilos and Sambathion, grandson of Ptolemaios: 4 drachmai;    column 46;Petheus, son of Petheus and Taphasis, grandson of Onnophris: 8 drachmai;    column 48</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 29 (l. 397-456), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3325&amp;viewid=4172R5.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/R/5/4172R5.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3325&amp;viewid=4172R5.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3325&amp;viewid=4172R5.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
