<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Division of Property</title>
            <author>Haryotes the elder, Kronion, and Haryotes the younger, also called Arabarches, sons of Herodion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1347</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1347</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.323</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12134</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12134</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;323/324/325qrpl</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1264</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract for the division among three brothers, Haryotes the elder, Kronion, and Haryotes the younger, of four slaves inherited from their father, Herodion; the services of one of these is however reserved, in accordance with the terms of Herodion's will, for the mother Taorseus, for as long as she lives</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Duplicate of P.Mich. V, 324 (inv. 1273) and P.S.I. VIII, 903; P.Mich. V, 325 (inv. 675) is an additional copy of two of the subscriptions. - Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 18.6 x 28 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">complete</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">37</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>2nd hand: see also P.Mich. V, 339</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0047">February 23, 47 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Claudius, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heryotes presbyteros son of Herodion and Taorseus (see also P.Mich. V, 339)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kronion son of Herodion and Taorseus (see also P.Mich. II, 123, verso, col. VIII, l. 8?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Haryotes alias Arabarches son of Herodion and Taorseus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thermoutharion, doule</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambous, doule</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraklas, doulos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraklous, chole, doule</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Taorseus daughter of Haryotes, widow of Herodion</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome</term>
               <term>Family</term>
               <term>Health</term>
               <term>Inheritance</term>
               <term>Slave</term>
               <term>Woman</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>The seventh year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, the twenty-ninth of the month Xandikos, the twenty-ninth of Mecheir, in Tebtynis in the division of Polemon of the Arsinoite nome. Haryotes, about thirty-five years old, with a scar below his left jaw, and Kronion, about thirty years old, with a scar on his left forearm, and Haryotes the younger, also called Arabarches, about twenty-seven years old, with a scar above his left eyebrow, the three sons of Herodion, acknowledge that they have divided among themselves by mutual agrement, by a division at the present time, from the present day forever, the four slaves that belong to them by inheritance from their father, Thermoutharion and Sambous and Heraklas and Heraklous, who is lame; and that Haryotes the elder has received as his share Sambous with the slave offspring that shall come from her, and Kronion has received as his share the aforesaid Heraklas, and Haryotes the younger, also called Arabarches, has received as his share the aforesaid slaves, Thermoutharion and the lame Heraklous, with the slave offspring that shall come from them; and they agree that the service of the slave Thermoutharion to the mother of the contracting parties, Taorseus, daughter of Haryotes, which was assigned to her by their father, for as long as she shall live, shall continue. Each of the contracting parties, therefore, and his heirs and assigns shall own and possess the shares they have received from the present day forever indisputably, and no one of the contracting parties shall proceed against what the others have received in any way. If any of the contracting parties violates any of the aforesaid provisions, the one who does not abide by the contract shall pay the one who does abide by it double the amount of the damages and expenses and a fine of fifteen hundred silver drachmai, and a like amount to the treasury. Nonetheless, in addition to the terms of the contract remaining valid, it shall be just as they have of their own free will agreed about everything. The signatures of the three contracting parties are in their own hands. The contract shall be valid everywhere.;(2nd hand) I, Haryotes, son of Herodion, have joined in making a division at the present time, and have received as my share the aforesaid slave, Sambous, and I will do everything as aforesaid.;(3rd hand) I, Kronion, son of Herodion, have joined in making a division at the present time, and have received as my share the aforesaid slave, Heraklas, and I will do everything as aforesaid.;(4th hand) I, Haryotes the younger, also called Arabarches, son of Herodion, have joined in making a division at the present time, and have received as my share the two aforesaid slaves, Thermoutharion and Heraklous, who is lame, and I will do everything as aforesaid.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 323, 1944 -- L. 36: this copy has hekasten poeso, instead of hekasta poeso. (PH)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:323</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1347&amp;viewid=1264R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/6/4/R/1264R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1347&amp;viewid=1264R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1347&amp;viewid=1264R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
