<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>loan of money</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1603</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1603</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.16.13030</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;16;13030</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;16;13030</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">16347</idno>
            <idno type="TM">16347</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 256</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>The text is a chirographic homologia confirming a loan of money.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 17.1 x 18.4 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown and very smooth papyrus was folded three times vertically and probably four times horizontally. Two of the horizontal fold panels (= 4 cm.) are lost on the left from lines 3-11, and three panels (= 6 cm.) are lost from lines 1-2 and 12-17. But, except in lines 1, 3, and 17, where the names of the borrowerand the lender will have stood, the text is easily restorable from known examples of loan agreements of the same period.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-16</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The hand of the body of the contract is medium-sized and semi-cursive, with letters 3 mm. high. The writing is in the main flourished and quite expensive, and the scribe has a fondness for long, decorative horizontal strokes. There is often crowding toward the right edge of the papyrus, thus indicating that this edge was the original limit of the piece. The hypograph (2nd hd.) is written in a smaller hand, with letters 2 mm. in height, regularly spaced, and rather square. The left margin is lost, while at the right, the writing runs almost to the edge of the papyrus. Line 1 is certainly the first line of the document, although the upper margin is lost. At the bottom, the blank space varies from 6.8 cm. to 7.4 cm., since the last line of the text (the hypograph, line 17) slants upward. Interlineation averages 3 mm., and approximately 1 cm. separates the body of the agreement from the hypograph.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0205">June/July, 205 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Alabastrine, Hermopolite nome, Middle Egypt, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Imperator Caesar Lucius Septimius Severus Pius Pertinax Arabicus Adiabenicus Parthicus Maximus, emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marcus Aurelius Antoninus Pius Augusti, emperor</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Alabastrine, Hermopolite nome, Middle Egypt, province of Egypt (?)</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Alabastrine,;Hermopolite nome</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"NN . . . from the village of Alabastrine of the Hermopolite nome, priest of the first-rank temples of Apollo and Isis, to NN, eques and signifier of the turma of Heraclides of the Ala Mauretana, greetings.;I acknowledge that I have received from you as a loan in cash the full sum of 116 drachmas in imperial silver coinage, at interest of 1 drachma per mina a month, which I bind myself to repay to you within 4 months from Epeiph of the current thirteenth year without delay. If I do not make repayment, when the time for repayment begins, I agree to be laible to seizure until such time as I repay both the principal with a 50% surcharge and the simple interest, and interest at the same rate for the period beyond the term of the loan. You have the right of execution against both me and all my property, as if there were a judgement. Let this chirograph, written in one copy and subscribed by me, be valid, as if registered in the public archives. The thirteenth year of the Imperatores Caesares Lucius Septimius Severus Pius Pertinax Arabicus Adiabenicus Parthicus Maximus and Marcus Aurelius Antoninus Pius Augusti, Epeiph.;(2nd hd.) I, NN, acknowledge that I have received 116 drachmas in full, as stated above."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Priest NE, ZPE 51, 65-70, 1983, Pl IV -- SB XVI 13030</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:16:13030</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1603&amp;viewid=256R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/5/6/r/256r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1603&amp;viewid=256R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1603&amp;viewid=256R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
