<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3848</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3848</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 36.9 x 30.7 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at the right and the left. Kollesis in center and in the right side. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-38</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 81 (ll. 3219-3257)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Apollonios, grandson of Harpagathes, mother Thermouthis  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion, son of Petheus, grandson of Sambathion, mother Tathautis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Petalos, grandson of Petaus, mother Taeuhemeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon, son of Chairemon, grandson of Sambas, mother Sokratiaine (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Leonides, son of Phanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 184)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petalos, son of Kapparis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Philous, daughter of Teberis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 246)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion, son of Sambas, grandson of Phaesis, mother Aphrodite (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymos, son of Satabous, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ninis, son of Asklas, grandson of Ninis, mother Tabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymos, son of Heron, grandson of Heras, mother Tasiaipis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 161)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Agathos Daimon, grandson of Petheus, mother Stiynchis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Horion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Turbon, son of Titinsambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 243)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Sambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides, son of Leonides (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Lupus, son of Horos, grandson of Menches, mother Tapapeis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herieus, son of Sambas, grandson of Peteesis, mother Tapapeis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Sambathion, mother Taseus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Herieus, mother Anthia (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor alias Sabeinos, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Satabous, mother Melidous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 182)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois, son of Naaraus the younger, grandson of Theabennis, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 223)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarouanitis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 226)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 81:;Epeiph 20:;Sarapion, son of Apollonios, grandson of Harpagathes, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;Pasion, son of Petheus, grandson of Sambathion, mother Tathautis, drachmas 4 copper drachmas 4;;Petaus, son of Petalos, grandson of Petaus, mother Taeuhemeros, drachmas 8;;Chairemon, son of Chairemon, grandson of Sambas, mother Sokratiaine, drachmas 8 copper drachmas 4;;Leonides, son of Phanomgeus (Petalos, son of Kapparis);;(in left margin: drachmas 16 obols 8) orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira drachmas 3 obols 2, tax on the produce of olives obols 3, naubion obols 2, surcharges obols 5;;eparourion drachmas 2 obol 1.5, surcharges obol 1 chalki 2, kollybos obol 0.5 chalki 2, he paid Pharmouthi 28, in total drachmas 7 obols 3.5;;geometria of year 12 drachmas 8 obols 2, surcharges obols 3 chalki 2, in total drachmas 8 obols 5 chalki 2;;and Philous, daughter of Teberis;;orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira drachma 1 obol 1.5, tax on the produce of olives obol 1 chalki 2, naubion obol 0.5 chalki 2, surcharges obols 2;;eparourion drachma 1 obols 4, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5, in total drachmas 3 obols 5;;geometria of year 12 drachmas 3 obol 0.5 chalki 2, surcharges obol 1 chalki 2, in total drachmas 3 obols 2;;Pnepheros, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tapetheus, copper drachmas 4 obols 28;;Pasion, son of Sambas, grandson of Phaesis, mother Aphrodite, drachmas 20 obols 20 copper drachma 1 obols 8;;Didymos, son of Satabous, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tanomgeus, copper drachmas 4 obols 28;;Ninis, son of Asklas, grandson of Ninis, mother Tabous, drachmas 4;;Didymos, son of Heron, grandson of Heras, mother Tasiaipis, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Agathos Daimon, grandson of Petheus, mother Stiynchis, obols 28;;(in left margin: drachmas 52 obols 14) Phanomgeus, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Horion (Turbon, son of Titinsambas);;orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira drachmas 13 obol 0.5 chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives drachma 1 obols 5 chalki 2, naubion drachma 1 obols 2, surcharges drachmas 3 obols 1.5 chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 8 obols 4.5, surcharges obols 5 chalki 2, kollybos obols 3, in total drachmas 29 obols 4.5;;Sarapion, son of Sambas;;orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira drachmas 5, tax on the produce of olives obols 4 chalki 2, naubion obols 3, surcharges drachma 1 obol 1.5;;eparourion drachmas 3 obols 2, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2, kollybos obol 1 chalki 2, in total drachmas 11 obol 1.5 chalki 2;;and to Herakleides, son of Leonides;;orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira drachmas 5, tax on the produce of olives obols 4 chalki 2, naubion obols 3, surcharges drachma 1  obol 1.5;;eparourion drachmas 3 obols 2, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2, kollybos obol 1 chalki 2;;Lupus, son of Horos, grandson of Menches, mother Tapapeis, drachmas 8;;Herieus, son of Sambas, grandson of Peteesis, mother Tapapeis, drachmas 4;;Maron, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Sambathion, mother Taseus, drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Herieus, mother Anthia, copper drachmas 4;;Kastor alias Sabeinos, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Satabous, mother Melidous, drachmas 4;;Sisois, son of Naaraus the younger, grandson of Theabennis, mother Thaisas, copper drachma obols 28;;(in left margin: drachmas 8 obols 8) orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira drachma 1 obols 4, tax on the produce of olives obol 1.5, naubion obol 1, surcharges obols 2.5;;eparourion drachma 1 obol 0.5 chalki 2, surcharges obol 0.5 chalki 2, kollybos obol 0.5, in total drachmas 3 obols 5;;geometria of year 12 drachmas 4 obol 1, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 4 obols 2.5 chalki 2.";Sambas, son of Petheus (Sarouanitis);;(in left margin: drachmas 8 obols 8) orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira drachma 1 obols 4, tax on the produce of olives obol 1.5, naubion obol 1, surcharges obols 2.5;;eparourion drachma 1 obol 0.5 chalki 2, surcharges obol 0.5 chalki 2, kollybos obol 0.5, in total drachmas 3 obols 5;;geometria of year 12 drachmas 4 obol 1, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 4 obols 2.5 chalki 2."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 -- CPJ 3, 492 (lines with Sambathion) Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3848&amp;viewid=4171_81R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/8/1/r/4171_81r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3848&amp;viewid=4171_81R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3848&amp;viewid=4171_81R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
