<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3643</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3643</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.224</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 31.3 x 32.5 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Regularly cut at the left side and at the right side. Top and bottom somewhat torn. No kollesis visible. On the back, in the lower left corner, a small rectangular piece of papyrus has been pasted on, presumably for fortification. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-43</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 9 (ll. 315-358)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. In the left margin, beginning between lines 333-334, there is an oblique stroke going downwards towards the left edge of the papyrus. (TC) More such oblique strokes are found in the left margin of lines 353 and 354; their purpose is somewhat unclear. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchophis, son of Anchophis, grandson of Petheus, mother Taorsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petaus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion, son of Kanis, grandson of Anchophis, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron, son of Satabous, grandson of Maron, mother Tkonnos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menches, brother, with the same mother (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis, son of Pekmes alias Euremon, mother Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes, son of Patkonnis, grandson of Harobros, mother Ptolema (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Tapsais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petoraipis, son of Hatres, grandson of Imouthes, mother Soeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides, son of Abychis, grandson of Abychis, mother Herais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Lucius Longinus Gemellus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 185)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Stiynchis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harsiesis, son of Peteus, grandson of Harsiesis, mother Thatres (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Heron, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Eserempis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Leonides, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 184)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Petheus, grandson of Petaus, mother Tapasion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Karanos, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Imouthes, mother Tapetsiris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis, son of Heras, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Isidora (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon, son of Heron, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Didyme (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Achillas, brother with the same mother, (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis, son of Phasis, grandson of Esouris, mother Tanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Komon, fatherless, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 183)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchophis, son of Petheus, grandson of Anchophis, mother Aphrodous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Menandros, grandson of Anchophis, mother Soeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Ekysis, grandson of Menadros, mother Herais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Tbelles (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Onnophris, grandson of Onnophris, mother Sopas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Leontas, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Kastorous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 184)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpalos, son of Apion, grandson of Harpalos, mother Valeria (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Peteesis, grandson of Apollonios, mother Tanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 223)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apion, son of Ammonios, grandson of Apion, mother Apollonous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 152)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Akousilaos, grandson of Pasoknopaios, mother Thatres (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"[(Column) 9]:;Anchophis, son of Anchophis, grandson of Petheus, mother Taorsenouphis, drachmas 8;;Petesouchos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petaus, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8;;in total for the day, drachmas 160, obols 9, of which in the12th year drachmas 12, obols 20;;(Hadrianeios) 28 likewise:;Horos the younger, son of Hatres, grandson of Horos, mother Teraus, drachmas 4;;Onnophris, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Horion, son of Kanis, grandson of Anchophis, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 8;;Maron, son of Satabous, grandson of Maron, mother Tkonnos, drachmas 4;;Menches, brother, with the same mother, drachmas 4;;Phaesis, son of Pekmes alias Euremon, mother Sambathion, drachmas 8;;Mysthes, son of Patkonnis, grandson of Harobros, mother Ptolema, drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Tapsais, drachmas 8;;Petoraipis, son of Hatres, grandson of Imouthes, mother Soeris, drachmas 4;;Herakleides, son of Abychis, grandson of Abychis, mother Herais, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Naaraus, grandson of Horion, mother Taorsenouphis, drachmas 4;;Lucius Longinus Gemellus, for the third (of the revenue) of the bath establishment including extra charges, drachmas 28;;Petesouchos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Stiynchis, drachmas 8;;Harsiesis, son of Peteus, grandson of Harsiesis, mother Thatres, drachmas 4;;(in left margin): thus until the account for Mecheir.;Petheus, son of Heron, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Eserempis, drachmas 4, obols 27;;Leonides, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Heras, drachmas 4;;Petaus, son of Petheus, grandson of Petaus, mother Tapasion, drachmas 4;;Karanos, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Imouthes, mother Tapetsiris, drachmas 4;;Phaesis, son of Heras, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Isidora, drachmas 4;;Chairemon, son of Heron, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Didyme, drachmas 4;;Achillas, brother with the same mother, drachmas 4;;Pakysis, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tepheros, drachmas 4;;Pakysis, son of Phasis, grandson of Esouris, mother Tanomgeus, drachmas 8;;in total for the day, drachmas 144, obols 26, of which a third is for the bath-tax drachmas 28;;(Hadrianeios) 29 likewise:;Komon, fatherless, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 8;;Anchophis, son of Petheus, grandson of Anchophis, mother Aphrodous, drachmas 8;;Horos, son of Menandros, grandson of Anchophis, mother Soeris, obols 28;;Heron, son of Ekysis, grandson of Menadros, mother Herais, drachmas 12, obols 28;;Chairemon, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Tbelles, drachmas 4;;Heras, son of Onnophris, grandson of Onnophris, mother Sopas, drachmas 4;;in total for the day, drachmas 40, obols 26.;(Hadrianeios) 30 likewise:;(uncertain abbreviation in the left margin), Leontas, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Kastorous, drachmas 24;;(uncertain abbreviation in the left margin, Harpalos, son of Apion, grandson of Harpalos, mother Valeria, drachmas 8;;Sambas, son of Peteesis, grandson of Apollonios, mother Tanomgeus, drachmas 4, obols 28;;Apion, son of Ammonios, grandson of Apion, mother Apollonous, drachmas 20;;12th year, Pnepheros, son of Akousilaos, grandson of Pasoknopaios, mother Thatres, drachmas 6,;water-guard from the village of Magdola."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3643&amp;viewid=4171_9R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3643&amp;viewid=4171_9R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3643&amp;viewid=4171_9R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
