<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>loan of money with interest in kind</title>
            <author>Aurelius Ammonios</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2142</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2142</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.14.12088</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;14;12088</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;14;12088</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">18184</idno>
            <idno type="TM">18184</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 406</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>The text contains an acknowledgement from Aurelius Ammonios, resident of Oxyrhynchos, to Flavius Nilus, who is attached to the staff of the praeses of the Augustamnica, that he has received a loan of 50 talents on Phamenoth 9 to be repaid in Pauni, hence a short-term loan to enable Ammonios to carry on until the harvest season.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 10.4 x 25 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This medium-brown papyrus is preserved in almost its original dimensions and has suffered serious damage only on the left side, where a large, roughly triangular piece has been torn away, taking with it the beginnings of lines 10-17.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-35</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The text is written in three different hands, all with a thin pointed pen and black ink. All three hands are cursives, but the second and the third hands, obviously written much faster and with less care than the first, both have a significant rightward slant. (TC) The text is well placed on the sheet, with an upper margin of 1.3 cm. and a left margin of 1.5-2 cm. On the right side the lines run most frequently to the edge of the sheet, and below the text is a space of 3 cm.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0346">March 5, 346 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Oxyrhynchos, Oxyrhynchite nome, Middle Egypt, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Flavius Amantius, consul</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Flavius Albinus, consul</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Flavius Nilus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Ammonios, son of Ammonios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurrelius Satornilus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Oxyrhynchos, Oxyrhynchite nome, Middle Egypt, province of Egypt (?)</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Augustamnica,;Oxyrhynchos.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"The year after the consulship of Flavius Amantius and Flavius Albinus, clarissimi.;To Flavius Nilus, who is attached to the office of the praeses of the Augustamnica, Aurelius Ammonios, son of Ammonios, from the illustrious and most illustrious city of the Oxyrhynchites, greetings. I acknowledge that I have received from you as a loan from hand to hand out of your house the sum of fifty silver talents in imperial coinage; and in place of interest I will provide you daily and without interruption for the service of your household one and a half . . . of edible vegetables. And the fifty silver talents of the principal sum I will necessarily repay to you in the month Pauni of the present year 40, 22, 13 without any delay or argument; otherwise, I will pay to you for the period beyond the term of the loan the interest mutually agreed. You shall have the right of execution both against me and against all my property. This chirograph written in a single copy is valid, and in regard to the formal question, I have so declared. The aforesaid consulship, Phamenoth 9.;(2nd hd.) I, Aurelius Ammonios, have received as a loan the fifty talents of silver, and I will make repayment including also the daily service as aforesaid. And in response to the formal question, I have so declared. I, Aurelius Satornilos, have written for him since he says that he is illiterate.;(3rd. hd.) Validated by me, Chairremon."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, ZPE 23, 139-42, 1976 -- SB XIV 12088 Youtie HC, Scriptiunculae I, 383-386, 1981</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:14:12088</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2142&amp;viewid=406R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/0/6/R/406R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2142&amp;viewid=406R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2142&amp;viewid=406R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
