<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3299</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3299</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 16 is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 15-16: 37.8 x 30 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 16 complete (papyrus cut to the right of col. 16 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 16: 55 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 16 (l. 61-115)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Esouris son of Kames and Thaesis, grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Paoueites son of Petheus and Tapetheus, grandson of Phasis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Petheus and Thaisas, grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon son of Horos and Segathis, grandson of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios son of Ptolemaios and Tapetesouchos, grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Perigenes son of Zoilos and Sambathion, grandson of Ptolemaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion son of Petheus and Komonis, grandson of Esouris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Petheus and Ptolema, grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Komon, apator, son of Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 183)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Thaisas, doulos of Syros alias Ptolemaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Patron son of Sokmenis and Taonnophris, grandson of Sokmenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 200)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis son of Pasoxis and Thaesis, grandson of Polyndikos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Menandros and Soeris, grandson of Anchophis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Panesneus son of Ischyras and Thaesis, grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles son of Mysthes and Charis, grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nikephoros, doulos of Longinus Isidoros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Petheus and Thaisas, grandson of Petesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron son of Ptolemaios and Heras, grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Apollonios and Thermouthis, grandson of Harpagathes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Phanomgeus and Taptosiris, grandson of Phanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus (son of Phanomgeus and Taptosiris, grandson of Phanomgeus) (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon son of Phanomgeus and Tbelles, grandson of Phanomgeus and Taptosiris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion son of Petheus and Tathautis, grandson of Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Kames and Thaesis, grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Besis and Heras, grandson of Thoteus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Illegitimacy--Egypt</term>
               <term>Slaves--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 16;;(Mecheir 14, continued);Esouris, son of Kames and Thaesis, grandson of Heras: 12 drachmai;    column 41;Paoueites, son of Petheus and Tapetheus, grandson of Phasis: 4 drachmai;    column 41;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus and Thaisas, grandson of Heras: 4 drachmai;    column  42;Chairemon, son of Horos and Segathis, grandson of Onnophris: 8 drachmai;    column 42;Aphrodisios, son of Ptolemaios and Tapetesouchos, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai;    column 45;Perigenes, son of Zoilos and Sambathion, grandson of Ptolemaios: 4 drachmai;    column 46;Total for the day: 264 drachmai 2 obols.;;On the 15th, similarly:;Horion, son of Petheus and Komonis, grandson of Esouris: 12 drachmai;    column 18;Onnophris, son of Petheus and Ptolema, grandson of Petheus: 20 drachmai;    column 13;Komon, of unknown father, son of Tasoucharion: 16 drachmai;    column 47;Sarapion, slave of Syros also called Ptolemaios, the offspring of Thaisas: 12 drachmai;    column 50;Patron, son of Sokmenis and Taonnophris, grandson of Sokmenis: 8 drachmai;    column 50;Phaesis, son of Pasoxis and Thaesis, grandson of Polyndikos: 16 drachmai;    column 51;Horos, son of Menandros and Soeris, grandson of Anchophis: 16 drachmai 28 obols;    column 51;Panesneus, son of Ischyras and Thaesis, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai;    column 54;Herakles, son of Mysthes and Charis, grandson of Petheus: 12 drachmai;    column 54;Nikephoros, slave of Longinus Isidoros: 4  drachmai;    column 57;Pnepheros, son of Petheus and Thaisas, grandson of Petesouchos: 4 drachmai;    column 59;Heron, son of Ptolemaios and Heras, grandson of Pnepheros: 8 drachmai;    column 59;Sarapion, son of Apollonios and Thermouthis, grandson of Harpagathes: 4 drachmai 28 obols;    column 61;Ptolemaios, son of Phanomgeus and Taptosiris, grandson of Phanomgeus: 8 drachmai;    column 62;Phanomgeus, his brother, (born) of the same mother: 8 drachmai;    column 62;Chairemon, his son, (born) of Tbelles: 8 drachmai;    column 62;Pasion, son of Petheus and Tathautis, grandson of Sambathion: 8 drachmai;    column 62;Sarapion, son of Kames and Thaesis, grandson of Heras: 8 drachmai;    column 63;Pnepheros, son of Besis and Heras, grandson of Thoteus: 8 drachmai 28 obols;    column 64;Petsiris, son of Petesouchos and Apia, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai;    column 67</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 16 (l. 61-115), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3299&amp;viewid=4172R1.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/R/1/4172R1.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3299&amp;viewid=4172R1.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3299&amp;viewid=4172R1.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
