<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Contract of Loan and Lease</title>
            <author>Hermas, son of Ptolemaios</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1314</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1314</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.3.188</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;3;188</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;3;188</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11991</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11991</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 108</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract by which Hermas, son of Ptolemaios, agrees to furnish lodging to Tapekysis, daughter of Horos, instead of paying interest on a debt of 300 drachmai</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank, except for a patch bearing some traces of red ink</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Horos and Tapekysis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 20 x 22 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Broken off on the left side; abraded on the right side</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">27</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The 1st hand is a somewhat elegant, upright cursive reminiscent of that of the writer of P.Mich. III, 195, 197, and 198 although slightly less florid [see also P.Mich. III, 189]; the 2nd employs very crude uncials; the 3rd is an irregular cursive which appears again in the second subscription to P.Mich. III, 196; and the docket at the bottom was written by the secretary who made the corresponding notation in P.Mich. III, 189 and 195. (Boak)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0120">August 18, 120 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Bacchias, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Hadrianus, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tapekysis daughter of Horos granddaughter of Katoites, wife of Horos (see P.Mich. III, p. 180</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">XI, p. 15 &amp; 102)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Katoites son of Menches (&amp; unnamed metochoi) (see P.Mich. X, p. 20)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Katoites grandson of Belles (see P.Mich. X, p. 20</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">XI, p. 15)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonios son of Dioskoros</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Bacchias, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Bacchias, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome</term>
               <term>Debtor and creditor--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Home ownership--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Interest--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Husband and wife--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Rent--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Housing--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Guardian and ward--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>650: Drachma.</term>
               <term>Scars--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Family--Egypt--Bacchais (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Suretyship and guaranty--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Receipts (Acknowledgments)--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Contracts--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Building--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Dwellings--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Notaries--Egypt--Bacchias (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>The fourth [year] of the Emperor Caesar Trajan Hadrian Augustus, the twenty-[fourth] of the month Kaisareios, Mesore 24, in Bacchias of the division of Herakleides of the Arsinoite [nome].;Hermas, son of Ptolemaios, the son of Ammonios, about eighty-five years old, with a scar [in the middle of his forehead], acknowledges to Tapekysis, daughter of Horos, the son of Katoites, about forty-five years old with a scar on her upper lip [to the left], acting under the guardianship of her husband Horos, son of Horos, about fifty years old with a scar on his left eyebrow, that he, the party of the first part, [has received from her] a sum of [three hundred] drachmai of coined silver of Augustan issues in cash from hand to hand out of the house, and that instead of the interest thereon the party of the first part has agreed that she and her heirs and whomever she may wish shall reside, for so long as the party of the first part owes [the aforesaid] money, in the dwelling that belongs to him, the party of the first part, in the aforesaid village, [of which the neighbors] are, as the parties have dictated in mutual agreement; on the south [building sites] belonging to Katoites, son of Menches, and his associates and for a certain part a portion of a common entrance and exit; on the north a royal road; on the west building sites belonging to the aforesaid Katoites and his associates; on the east a courtyard of Horos, son of Katoites, the son of Belles, and his brothers; and that the party of the first part and his heirs guarantee the conditions of [this] contract of occupation to Tapekysis and her heirs with [every] guarantee, and let the party of the first part see that no one prevents Tapekysis or her heirs from [occupying the premises] and lodging others therein and collecting the rents and using [all] the appurtenances without hindrance. And if it shall appear that Tapekysis has undergone expense for repair or construction, [and]  the party of the first part, Hermas, [wishes] to pay back the aforesaid money, let him repay it along with the aforesaid money, the responsability resting upon her Tapekysis.;Signatory for Tapekysis [and her] guardian, Ammonios, son of Dioskoros, about 45 years old with a scar on his forehead to the right below the hair.;(2nd hand) I, [Hermas], son of Ptolemaios, acknowledge that I have received from Tapekysis the three hundred [drachmai] in silver in cash and in place of the interest I shall agree that she shall [live in] the aforesaid house for so long as I may owe it, [and . . .], and I shall guarantee (it) with every guarantee and shall deliver it free from [. . .], and (whenever I shall repay the money), if it shall appear that she has undergone any expense, I shall repay it as stated above.;(3rd hand) I, [Tapekysis], daughter of Horos, acting under the guardianship of my husband Horos, have received the agreement as aforesaid. I, Ammonios, son of Dioskoros, wrote for them as they are illiterate.;(4th hand) Recorded through the grapheion at Bacchias.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich III, 188, 1936 -- BL III, 110 (l. 16-18; 22-23); BL V, 68 (l. 6); BL VI, 80-81 (l. 3, 4, 16, 20)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:3:188</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1314&amp;viewid=108.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/1/0/8/108.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1314&amp;viewid=108.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1314&amp;viewid=108.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
