<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Loan of Money</title>
            <author>Theokles, son of Euboulides; Aristokles, son of Herakleides</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1512</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1512</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">2888</idno>
            <idno type="TM">2888</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;3;190</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1717</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract according to which Theokles, son of Euboulides, lends to Aristokles, son of Herakleides, the sum of 3 talents 780 drachmai for 13 months at 24 per cent interest, Megisto, the wife of aristokles being named as surety for her husband; the agreement concludes with the signalments of the contracting parties and surety. A note in the right margin seems to indicate that (after some time?) the affair had devolved to the sons of the contracting parties, only Megisto being still alive.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 25.8 x 30.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Damaged mainly in the lower part and along the folds</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Main text - 34;;Note in right margin - 8</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Main document: a large, clear hand; note in the right margin: very cursive (MacGregor - Schuman)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="-0172">July 6, 172 B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Philadelphia, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemy (VI Philometor) Epiphanes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kleopatra (II Philometor) Epiphaneia</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollodoros son of Zenon, hiereus (of the deified Alexander and earlier Ptolemies)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kleainete daughter of Komanos, athlophoros (of the deified Berenike Euergetis)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapias daughter of Apollonios, kanephoros (of the deified Arsinoe Philadelphos)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Eirene daughter of Ptolemaios, hiereia (of the deified Arsinoe Philopator)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Theokles son of Euboulides, Makedon tes epigones, father of Euboulides (see also P.Freib. III, 34)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aristokles son of Herakleides, Korinthios tes epigones, husband and guardian of Megisto, father of Herakleides</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Megisto daughter of Nikostratos, Persine, wife of Aristokles</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ktesikles(?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Euboulides son of Theokles, heptarouros(?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides son of Aristokles, Korinthios</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Probably Philadelphia, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Philadelpheia (Philadelphia), Arsinoite nome; Makedon (tes epigones); Korinthios (tes epigones); Persine</term>
               <term>Debtor and creditor--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Ptolemaic dynasty, 305-30 B.C.</term>
               <term>Ethnic groups--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Suretyship and guaranty--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinxt xity)</term>
               <term>Husband and wife--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Guardian and ward--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Egypt--Kings and rulers--Religious aspects.</term>
               <term>Priests--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Alexander. the Great, 356-323.</term>
               <term>Women--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Contracts--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Drachma.</term>
               <term>Interst--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Justice, Administration of--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Physiognomy--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Main text);;In the reign of Ptolemy, son of Ptolemy and Cleopatra, the gods Epiphaneis, the ninth year; Apollodoros, son of Zenon, being the priest of Alexander, the gods Soteres, the gods Adelphoi, the gods Euergetai, the gods Philopatores, the gods Epiphaneis, and the gods Philometores; the athlophoros of Berenike Euergetis being Kleainete, daughter of Apollonios; the priestess of Arsinoe Philopator being Eirene, daughter of Ptolemaios; Apellaios 5, Pauni 5, in Philadelphia of the Arsinoite nome.;Theokles, son of Euboulides, Macedonian of the epigone, has lent to Aristokles, son of Herakleides, Corinthian of the epigone, 3 talents 780 drachmai of bronze money produced to view, for 13 months from the above date, with interest at 2 drachmai the mina per month. Aristokles shall repay to Theokles the aforestated loan, namely 3 talents 780 drachmai in bronze money, plus the interest accruing thereon, in the month of Apellaios, or in the Egyptian calendar, Pauni, in the tenth year. If he does not repay it, he shall pay as penalty the loan plus fifty per cent and simple interest, and Aristokles &lt;read: Theokles&gt; shall have the right of execution upon Aristokles or his surety, whichever of them he may choose, or upon both, as if by court decision. The surety of Aristokles for the payment in full of the above-mentioned loan of 3 talents 780 drachmai is Megisto, daughter of Nikostratos, a Persian woman, acting with her guardian, her husband, the aforementioned Aristokles. The agreements shall be valid wherever it may be produced.;;Theokles, about . . . years of age with a scar in the middle of the forehead, long-faced, with a scar on the lower lip to the right.;Aristokles, about . . . years of age with a scar in the middle of the forehead, round-faced, somewhat dim-sighted.;Megisto, about 23 years of age, of medium height, fair complexion, and eyes of rather light color.;;;(Note in the right margin);;(2nd hand) Euboulides, son of Theokles, owner of 7 arourai (?), of the village of Philadelphia . . . debt(?) from Herakleides, son of Aristokles, Corinthian of the epigone . . ., and his security, Megisto, daughter of Nikostratos, a Persian woman, of Philadelphia: 2 talents 780 drachmai.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Schuman VB-MacGregor MF, PMich III, 190, 1936 -- BL III, 110 (l. 25; 36-37; 39-40; 42); BL V, 68 (l. 35-42); BL VII, 109 (l. 42)</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1512&amp;viewid=1717R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/1/7/r/1717r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1512&amp;viewid=1717R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1512&amp;viewid=1717R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
