<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Petition to an Epistrategos</title>
            <author>Gellius Serenus, Gemellus (alias) Horion and others</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1687</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1687</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14456</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14456</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;14;11478</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 2920</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Petition to the epistrategos Antonius Colonianus, made by the body of the landowners and public cultivators of Kerkesoucha, who complain that they can't fulfil their obligations of work on a wattled weir, because of the katasporeis, who neglected to furnish the material for it.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Gaius Apolinarius Niger (&amp; family)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 17.5 X 14 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">probably complete, but the bottom of the sheet has been torn off; some rubbing in the center of the sheet</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">26</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>upright official hand; writing along the fibres</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0210" notAfter="0211">210/211 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Kerkesoucha, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Antonianus Colonianus, epistrategos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gellius Serenus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gemellus (alias) Horion (son of Gaius Apollinarius Niger</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">= Gaius Gemellus Horigenes) (see P. Mich. VI, 422 introd</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) former prefects of Egypt</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) katasporeis tes Argaitidos phiales of the 19th year</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Kerkesoucha; Argaitis phiale; Kormos (phryganikon emblema)</term>
               <term>Irrigation canals and flumes-- Egypt-- Kerkesoucha Orous (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Agriculture--Taxation-- Egypt-- Kerkesoucha Orous (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Nile River-- Egypt-- Kerkesoucha Orous (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Corvee--Egypt-- Kerkesoucha Orous (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>To Antonius Colonianus, the most noble epistrategos, from Gellius Serenus and Gemellus Horion and the rest of the landowners and public cultivators of the village of Kerkesoucha.;First of all, most excellent of governors, those who serve as prefect from time to time, devoting forethought to the land, issue written orders concerning the accomplishment of the labor of maintenance on the dikes and canals. And although we were as always most zealously prepared to perform fully the labors that pertain to the land, the supervisors of sowing for the Argaitis bowl in the present 19th year, for some unknown reason, or through simple negligence, did not produce the wood and materials which are annually provided by them for the reconstruction of the wattled weir, in the vicinity of the same village, called the "Log", nor did they in any way provide for maintenance, (2nd hand) 'as if (without the least?) suspicion of the fact that canals make the difference (between success and failure)'. (1st hand) Since the land runs the risk of going dry on this account and inflicting injury  on the most sacred treasury in the matter of the dues paid for these (arourai), which come to not a few myriads (of artabai), at a time when the most sacred Nile has shown himself most favorable to us for a good issue, we request, if it seems best to your beneficient genius, that you order with your (characteristic) vigor that the work be done, &lt;so that&gt; we may be able blamelessly to maximise the imminent sowing - may it be for good ! - and nothing be lost to the most sacred treasury.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, ASAE 29, 54-58, 1929 -- SB IV 7361 Youtie HC, ZPE 15, 149-152, 1974, Pl. V -- SB XIV 11478</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1687&amp;viewid=2920R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/0/R/2920R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1687&amp;viewid=2920R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1687&amp;viewid=2920R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
