<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3832</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3832</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 35.2 x 29.6 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at the right and the left. Kollesis at the right. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-36</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 67 (ll. 2696-2732)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Teos, son of Petheus, grandson of Teos, mother Taonnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 242)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Sambas, mother Taeuhemeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 224)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Melanas, grandson of Petheus, mother Tamystha (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Perigenes, son of Zoilos, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petsiris, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Petsiris, mother Heros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 211)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor, son of Marres, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nikephoros, slave of Longinus Isidoros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Besis, grandson of Thoteus, mother Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Besis, son of Petheus, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 159)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Euhemeros, son of Neilos, grandson of Euhemeros, mother Taeuhemeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Neilos, his son, mother Sambous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 190)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Keras, son of Nekpheraus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 182)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thaoues (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 174)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kames, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Tkonnos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Pasoknopaios, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kanis, son of Anchophis, grandson of Marres, mother Taorsoraipis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinos, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Horos, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Onnophris, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetsookis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Satabous, grandson of Horos, mother Theonis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 220)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis, son of Panesneus, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dionysios, fatherless, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasoxis, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Panther, mother Taseus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 199)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Panesneus, son of Ischyras, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ischyras, his son, mother Tamystha (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 179)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 67:;Teos, son of Petheus, grandson of Teos, mother Taonnophris, drachmas 32;;Sambas, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Sambas, mother Taeuhemeros, copper tetradrachmas 4;;Heras, son of Melanas, grandson of Petheus, mother Tamystha, copper tetradrachmas 4;;Aphrodisios, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetesouchos, drachmas 4;;Perigenes, son of Zoilos, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Sambathion, drachmas 4;;Petsiris, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Petsiris, mother Heros, drachmas 4;;Kastor, son of Marres, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8;;Nikephoros, slave of Longinus Isidoros, drachmas 4;;Heron, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Heras, drachmas 4;;in total for the day drchmas 108 obols 24;;(Pachon) 25:;Pnepheros, son of Besis, grandson of Thoteus, mother Heras, drachmas 4;;Besis, son of Petheus, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;Euhemeros, son of Neilos, grandson of Euhemeros, mother Taeuhemeros, drachmas 4 obols 27;;Neilos, his son, mother Sambous, drachmas 4 obols 27;;Keras, son of Nekpheraus (Thaoues);;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 5 obol 1, tax on the produce of olives obols 4.5, naubion obols 3 chalki 2, surcharges drachma 1 obols 2 chalki 2;;(in left margin: drachmas 12 obols 3) eparourion drachmas 3 obols 2.5 chalki 2, surcharges obols 2, kollybos obol 1.5, in total drachmas 11 obols 5 chalki 2;;Pnepheros, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Kames, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Tkonnos, drachmas 4;;Petheus, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Pasoknopaios, mother Tepheros, drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 140 obols 28;;(Pachon) 26 likewise:;Kanis, son of Anchophis, grandson of Marres, mother Taorsoraipis, drachmas 4;;Sabinos, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Horos, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Petheus, son of Onnophris, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetsookis, copper tetradrachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Satabous, grandson of Horos, mother Theonis, drachmas 4;;Pakysis, son of Panesneus, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Dionysios, fatherless, mother Tepheros, drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 28.;(Pachon) 27 likewise:;Pasoxis, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Panther, mother Taseus, drachmas 4;;Panesneus, son of Ischyras, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Ischyras, his son, mother Tamystha, obols 28."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 -- CPJ 3, 492 (lines with Sambathion) Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3832&amp;viewid=4171_67R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3832&amp;viewid=4171_67R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3832&amp;viewid=4171_67R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
