<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Collection of Abstracts of Contracts (Eiromenon)</title>
            <author>Unknown scribe of the grapheion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3181</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3181</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.241</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;241</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;241</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12082</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12082</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 948</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>First sheet of a day by day register of abstracts of the contracts recorded at the record-office (grapheion) of Tebtynis during the beginning of the 3rd year of the Emperor Tiberius. - Abstract 1 records a sale of a house in Tebtynis; abstract 2, a loan of 168 drachmai between the same parties; abstract 3, a contract for service in a pottery; abstract 4, another loan, of 100 drachmai</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Verso; Recto is P.Mich. V, 346</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 14.2 x 29 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">worn at the folds and at the top and bottom, and somewhat fragile</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Verso - 45</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>A small upright cursive, with peculiarities in the formation of certain letters and combinations of letters; checks have been made in the margin below the opening words of each entry</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0016">August-September 16 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Tiberius, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tatithinxis, daughter of Kronides (&amp; unnamed son)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pateinis tritos, son of Tagonsis and Taorseus, husband of Tenaus, Perses tes epigones</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tenaus, daughter of Orseus and Araisis, wife of Pateinis tritos, Persine</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Lysimachos son of Lysimachos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Diodoros son of Psenobastis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harmiysis son of Harmiysis, relative &amp; guardian of Tatithinxis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Patynis son of Aunes, father of Aunes, Perses tes epigones</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aunes son of Patynis grandson of Aunes, Perses tes epigones</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Patron son of Heron grandson of Gaias</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambathion son of Sambathion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Lakianis son of Lakianis alias Skanapeus, Perses tes epigones</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris; Perses (tes epigones); Persine</term>
               <term>Administration</term>
               <term>Ethnicity</term>
               <term>House Ownership</term>
               <term>Industry</term>
               <term>Loan</term>
               <term>Notary</term>
               <term>Paramone (obligation to remain at someone's service)</term>
               <term>Iranians--Egypt</term>
               <term>Profession</term>
               <term>Salary</term>
               <term>Sale</term>
               <term>Servility</term>
               <term>Taxation (persons)</term>
               <term>Topography (Tebtynis)</term>
               <term>Woman (&amp;amp</term>
               <term>guardian)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>The 3rd year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, [the . .] of the month of Sebastos.;(1) Sale and renunciation of a house and all its appurtenances in Tebtyni in the division of Polemon, of which the measurements are: south to north 8 1/2 cubits, west to east 13 cubits; its neighbors: on the south, an open court of the buyer Tatithinxis and her son, on the north and west a common entrance and exit, on the east a royal road. And he receives the whole price agreed upon, in full, and will guarantee (the sale) with every guarantee for all time. Which (contract) Pateinis the third, son of Tagonsis, his mother being Taorseus, about 25 years old, with a scar on the flat of his right foot, makes with Tatithinxis, daughter of Kronides, about 37 years old, with a conspicuous right eye. Also the wife of Pateinis, Tenaus, daughter of Orseus, her mother being Araisis, about 24 years old, with a scar on the middle of her nose, approves the aforesaid sale and will not prosecute for all time.;Signatories: for the parties of the first part Lysimachos, son of Lysimachos, about 22 years old, with a scar on the left side of his face; and for Tatithinxis Diodoros, son of Psenobastis, about 27 years old, with a scar on the first finger of his left hand.;(2) The same Tatithinxis, daughter of Kronides, about 37 years old, with a conspicuous right eye, 'acting with, as guardian, her relative Harmiysis, son of Harmiysis, about 40 years old, with a scar on his left wrist', has loaned to the same Pateinis the third, son of Tagonsis, a Persian of the epigone, about 25 years old, with a scar on the flat of his right foot, and his wife Tenaus, daughter of Orseus, a Persian woman, about 24 years old, with a scar on the middle of her nose, with, as guardian, her aforesaid husband, both of them mutual sureties for recovery, one-hundred and sixty-eight drachmai in coined silver as a capital sum, at a monthly interest of one drachme on the mina up to the repayment in Mesore of the presend 3rd year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus. The same signatories.;(3) Patynis, son of Aunes, about 60 years old, with a scar on the right side of his face, and his son Aunes, about 20 years old, with a scar in the middle of his face, both of them Persians of the epigone, mutual securities, acknowledge to Patron, son of Heron, the son of Gaias, about 26 years old, with a scar on his left cheek, that they have received from him 40 drachmai of coined silver, and that, in consideration thereof and of the monthly pay which Aunes shall receive, for the month of Sebastos and for Phaophi together 22 drachmai amd from the month Neos Sebastos up to Mesore 22 of the 3rd year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus 10 silver drachmai per month, [[the poll tax for Aunes]] Aunes will present himself to remain with Patron from the aforesaid time until Mesore 22 of the same year, to knead clay in the pottery of Patron and to do all the things assigned to him without absenting himself during the day, 'and for whatever day he may be absent . . .', the poll tax for Aunes and necessities and clothing being a charge on the parties of the first part, and after the term the parties of the first part will be released from service.;Signatory for the parties of the first part: Lysimachos, son of Lysimachos, 22 years old, with a scar on the left side of his face.;(4) Sambathion, son of Sambathion, about 46 years old, with a scar on his right shin, has loaned to Lakianis, son of Lakianis, surnamed Skapaneus, a Persian of the epigone, about . . years old, with a scar on his left knee, a capital sum of 100 drachmai of coined silver at the interest of one drachme on the mina per month until repayment is made in Mecheir of the 3rd year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus.;Signatory for the party of the second part: Lysimachos, son of Lysimachos, [22 years old, with a scar on the left side of his face].</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich V, 241, 1944 Tcherikover VA - Fuks A, CPJ II, 413 (= l. 39-45 only), 1960</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:241</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3181&amp;viewid=948V.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/4/8/V/948V.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3181&amp;viewid=948V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3181&amp;viewid=948V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
