<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3843</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3843</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 33.3 x 30.1 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at the right and the left. Kollesis at left and right sides. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-37</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 78 (ll. 3098-3135)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Nestosiris, grandson of Petheus, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpagathes, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Harpagathes, mother Tasiaipis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sempronia Longinia (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 228)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Julius Maximus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 178 and 159)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maximion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus, son of Tesenouphis, grandson of Harphaesis, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Tapsais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchorymphis, son of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides, son of Abykis, grandson of Abykis, mother Herais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tamarres, daughter of Apynchis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 233)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tamarron (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 233)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpagathes, son of Satabous, grandson of Anchophis, mother Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Karanos, fatherless, mother Prodous, undertaker (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Papeis, fatherless, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis, son of Heron, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Zoidous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 193)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Petheus, grandson of Kollouthos, mother Taorsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Valerios, fatherless, mother Valeria (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 195)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Karanos, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Imouthes, mother Tapetsiris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Patron, son of Sokmenis, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Taonnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 200)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasoxis, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Panther, mother Taseus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 199)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Anchophis, grandson of Herakles, mother Teseuris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion, son of Aphrodisios, grandson of Onnophris, mother Tapetaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, his brother with the same mother (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 78:;naubion of katoikoi of year 13 obols 3.5, surcharges obol 0.5, kollybos chalki 2;;Petheus, son of Nestosiris, grandson of Petheus, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 32 obols 13.;(Pauni) 21 likewise:;Harpagathes, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Harpagathes, mother Tasiaipis, drachmas 12 obols 28;;Sempronia Longinia through the agency of Julius Maximus (Maximion);;orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira drachmas 43 obols 5.5, tax on the produce of olives drachmas 6 obol 1.5, naubion drachmas 4 obols 2.5, surcharges drachmas 10 obols 5.5 chalki 2;;(in left margin: drachmas 216 obols 27) eparourion drachmas 29 obols 2, surcharges drachmas 2 obols 2.5, kollybos drachma 1 obols 4, in total drachmas 98 obols 5.5 chalki 2;;geometria of year 12 drachmas 109 obols 4.5 chalki 2, surcharges drachmas 6 obols 5.5, in total drachmas 116 obols 4 chalki 2;;naubion of katoikoi of year 13 drachmas 2 obols 3.5, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2, kollybos obol 0.5, in total drachmas 2 obols 5.5 chalki 2;;in total for the day drachmas 232 obols 26.;Epeiph 5:;Phanomgeus, son of Tesenouphis, grandson of Harphaesis, mother Thaesis, copper drachmas 4;;Phanomgeus, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Tapsais, copper drachma 1 obols 28;;Anchorymphis, son of Petheus;;(in left margin: drachmas 20 obols 14) camel tax of year 13 drachmas 20, surcharges drachma 1 obol 1.5, in total drachmas 21 obol 1.5;;Herakleides, son of Abykis, grandson of Abykis, mother Herais, copper drachmas 4;;Tamarres, daughter of Apynchis (Tamaron);;orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira obols 5, tax on the produce of olives obol 1 chalki 2, naubion obol 1, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2;;(in left margin: drachmas 4 obols 10) eparourion obols 3.5, surcharges obol 0.5, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachmas 2 obol 1 chalki 2;;geometria of year 12 drachmas 2 obol 0.5, surcharges obol 0.5, in total drachmas 2 obol 1.5;;Harpagathes, son of Satabous, grandson of Anchophis, mother Sambathion, copper drachma 1 obols 28;;Karanos, fatherless, mother Prodous, undertaker, copper drachmas 4 obols 28;;Papeis, fatherless, mother Thaesis, copper drachmas 8;;Leonides, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Heras, drachmas 4;;Orsenouphis, son of Heron, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Zoidous, copper drachmas 4;;Heron, son of Petheus, grandson of Kollouthos, mother Taorsenouphis, copper drachma 1 (that of the priests) drachmas 4;;Valerios, fatherless, mother Valeria, obols 28;;Karanos, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Imouthes, mother Tapetsiris, drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 76 obols 20.;(Epeiph) 6 likewise:;Patron, son of Sokmenis, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Taonnophris, drachmas 4;;Pasoxis, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Panther, mother Taseus, drachmas 4;;Horos, son of Anchophis, grandson of Herakles, mother Teseuris, copper drachmas 4;;Horion, son of Aphrodisios, grandson of Onnophris, mother Tapetaus, copper drachmas 4 (that of the priests) drachmas 4;;Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Heras, drachmas 8;;Heron, his brother with the same mother, drachmas 4."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 -- CPJ 3, 492 (lines with Sambathion) Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3843&amp;viewid=4171_78R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/7/8/r/4171_78r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3843&amp;viewid=4171_78R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3843&amp;viewid=4171_78R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
