<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3782</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3782</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso contains the tax-payments of six persons</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 37 x 30.1 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at both sides. Kolleais in right side. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-38</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 35 (ll. 1504-1542)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Chairemon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Onnophris, grandson of Thebennis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Heron, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Eserempis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Diodoros, son of Hatres (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mystharion, son of Diodoros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 188)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tepheros, daugter of Sokmenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 241)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tkames, daughter of Mates (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 242)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Nestosiris, grandson of Petheus, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis, son of Heron, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Zoidous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 193)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Soeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 194)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles, son of Sokrates, grandson of Phasis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles, son of Petaus, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Tanesneus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Sisois, grandson of Satabous, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Souches, grandson of Heras, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Apollonios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 200)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 166)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis, son of Phasis, grandson of Esouris, mother Tanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Melanas, grandson of Petheus, mother Tamystha (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion, son of Mysthes, grandson of Pasoxis, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraklous, daughter of Hatres (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Sambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Thaisas, slave of Syros alias Ptolemaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptollas, son of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 221)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptollas, son of Abel (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 221)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 35.;Ptolem(), son of Chairemon;;(in left margin: to Sarap()) for the epitimion paricheirographontes drachmas 100, surcharges drachmas 6, obol 1.5, in total drachmas 106, obols 1.5;;Heron, son of Onnophris, grandson of Thebennis, mother Tapetheus, obols 28;;Petheus, son of Heron, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Eserempis, drachmas 8;;Diodoros, son of Hatres, father of Mystharion, son of Diodoros;;(in left margin: drachmas 12, obols 15)geometria for the 12th year drachmas 12, obols 5.5, surcharges obols 5.5, in total drachmas 13, obols 4.5;;Tepheros, daugter of Sokmenis (Tkames, daughter of Mates);;(in left margin: drachmas 88, obols 5) orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 17, obols 4.5, tax on olive produce drachmas 2, obols 3.5, naubiondrachma 1, obols 4.5, chalki 2, surcharges drachmas 4, obols 2.5, chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 11, obols 5, chalki 2, surcharges drachma 1, kollybos obols 4, in total drachmas 40, obol 0.5, chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 44, obols 2, chalki 2, surcharges drachmas 2, obols 5, in total drachmas 47, obol 1, chalki 2;;naubion of the katoikoi for the 13th year, obol 1, surcharges chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total obol 1, chalki 2;;Petheus, son of Nestosiris, grandson of Petheus, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;Heron, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 4;;Orsenouphis, son of Heron, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Zoidous, drachmas 4;;Orsenouphis, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Soeris, drachmas 4;;Herakles, son of Sokrates, grandson of Phasis, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Herakles, son of Petaus, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Segathis, drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Tanesneus, drachmas 4;;Petaus, son of Sisois, grandson of Satabous, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;Heras, son of Souches, grandson of Heras, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Petheus, son of Apollonios through the agency of Herais (daughter of the admirable);;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachma 1, obols 2.5, tax on olive produce obol 1, chalki 2, naubion obol 1, surcharges obols 2.5;;(in left margin: drachmas 8, obols 4)eparourion drachma 1, obols 4, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5, chalki 2, in total drachmas 5, obols 4, chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 6, obol 1.5, surcharge obols 2.5, in total drachmas 6, obols 4;;Pakysis, son of Phasis, grandson of Esouris, mother Tanomgeus, drachmas 4;;Heras, son of Melanas, grandson of Petheus, mother Tamystha, drachmas 8;;Horion, son of Mysthes, grandson of Pasoxis, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 8;;in total for the day drachmas 264, obols 15;;(Phamenoth) 28 likewise:;Heraklous, daughter of Hatres through the agency of (Ptolemaios, son of Sambas);Ptolemaios, priest                                                                              (weaver);;(in left margin: drachmas 21, obols 9) orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 2, obols 3, tax on produce from olives obols 2, chalki 2, naubion obol 1.5, surcharge obols 3.5, chalki 2;;eparourion drachma 1, obol 4, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5, chalki 2, in total drachmas 5, obols 4, chalki 2, drachmas 5, obols 4, chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 6, obol 1.5, surcharges obols 2.5, in total drachmas 6, obols 4;;Petheus, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 8;;Sarapion, son of Thaisas, slave of Syros alias Ptolemaios, drachmas 8;;Ptollas, son of Horos (Ptollas, son of Abel);;(in left margin: drachmas 8, obols 28) orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 5, tax on the produce of olives obols 4, chalki 2, naubion obols 3, surcharges drachma 1, obol 1.5;;eparourion drachmas 3, obols 2, surcharges obol 1.5, kollybos obol 1, chalki 2, in total drachmas 11, obol 1.5, chalki 2."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 -- BL III, 113 (on l. 1504); BL IX, 159 (on l. 1524) Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3782&amp;viewid=4171_35R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/3/5/r/4171_35r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3782&amp;viewid=4171_35R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3782&amp;viewid=4171_35R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
