<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3333</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3333</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 40 is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 39-40: 34.3 x 29.8 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 40: complete (papyrus cut off right of col. 40 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 40: 51 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 40 (l. 845-895)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion son of Komon and Taseus alias Isarion grandson of Esouris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor, doulos of Taseus alias Isarion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis son of Heron and Zoidous grandson of Orsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 193)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anoubas son of Horos and Tepheros grandson of Anoubas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 151)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonis (Ammonios) son of Pasoknopaios and Thatres grandson of Limnaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 151)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Ptolemaios and Thaesis grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles son of Petaus and Segathis grandson of Orsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Petaus and Segathis grandson of Orsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 203)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Karanos son of Orsenouphis and Tapetsiris grandson of Imouthes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes son of Petheus and Tasoucharion grandson of Mysthes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petermouthis son of Kastor and Taonnophris &lt;read: Tasoucharion?&gt; grandson of Heraklas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Teos son of Petheus and Taonnophris grandson of Teos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 242)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon son of Pasoxis and Tanephremis grandson of Pasoxis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Esouris son of Kames and Thaesis grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Paoueites son of Petheus and Tapetheus grandson of Phasis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios son of Ptolemaios and Tapetesouchos grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis son of Pasoxis and Thaesis grandson of Polyndikos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron son of Ekysis and Herais grandson of Menandros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpagathes son of Ptolemaios and Tasiaipis grandson of Harpagathes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ischyras son of Panesneus and Tamystha grandson of Ischyras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 179)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Pasoxis and Heras grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron son of Horos and Taarpagathes (Taharpagathes) grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Slaves--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 40;;(Pharmouthi 1, continued);Pasion, son of Komon and Taseus also called Isarion, grandson of Esouris: 24 drachmai;    column 19;Horion, his son, (born of) Tauris: 24 drachmai;    column 19;Kastor, slave of Taseus also called Isarion: 24 drachmai;    column 20;Orsenouphis, son of Heron and Zoidous, grandson of Orsenouphis: 28 obols;    column 23;Anoubas, son of Horos and Tepheros, grandson of Anoubas: 28 obols;    column 29;Ammonis, son of Pasoknopaios and Thatres, grandson of Limnaios: 12 drachmai;    column 29;Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios and Thaesis, grandson of Pnepheros: 16 drachmai;    column 19;Herakles, son of Petaus and Segathis, grandson of Orsenouphis: 8 drachmai;    column 31;Petheus, his brother, (born) of the same (mother): 4 drachmai;    column 31;Karanos, son of Orsenouphis and Tapetsiris, grandson of Imouthes: 28 obols;    column 35;Mysthes, son of Petheus and Tasoucharion, grandson of Mysthes: 4 drachmai;    column 36;Petermouthis, son of Kastor and Taonnophris, grandson of Heraklas: 4 drachmai;    column 40;Teos, son of Petheus and Taonnophris, grandson of Teos: 4 drachmai 27 obols;    column 39;Chairemon, son of Pasoxis and Tanephremis, grandson of Pasoxis: 4 drachmai;    column 40;Esouris, son of Kames and Thaesis, grandson of Heras: 4 drachmai;    column 41;Paoueites, son of Petheus and Tapetheus, grandson of Phasis: 4 drachmai;    column 41;Total for the day: 200 drachmai 23 obols.;;On the 2nd, similarly:;Aphrodisios, son of Ptolemaios and Tapetesouchos, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai;    column 45;Heron, son of Sisois and Didymarion, grandson of Petesouchos: 4 drachmai;    column 46;Phaesis, son of Pasoxis and Thaesis, grandson of Polyndikos: 8 drachmai;    column 51;Heron, son of Ekysis and Herais, grandson of Menandros: 4 drachmai;    column 51;Harpagathes, son of Ptolemaios and Tasiaipis, grandson of Harpagathes: 4 drachmai 28 obols;    column 52;Ischyras, son of Panesneus and Tamystha, grandson of Ischyras: 8 drachmai;    column 54;Ptolemaios, son of Pasoxis and Heras, grandson of Satabous: 4 drachmai;    column 54;Heron, son of Horos and Taarpagathes, grandson of Petheus: 24 drachmai;    column 53</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 40 (l. 845-895), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3333&amp;viewid=4172_9RO.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/9/r/o/4172_9ro.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3333&amp;viewid=4172_9RO.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3333&amp;viewid=4172_9RO.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
