<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lease of Public Land</title>
            <author>Horos, son of Harmiysis; Orsenouphis, son of Horouanchious; Harmais, son of Petesouchos; Stotouetis, son of Kollouthos; Aunes, son of Tephorsos; and Onnophris, son of Kollouthos, all 6 being presbyteroi demosion georgon; and Harmiysis, son of Orseus, grammateus georgon</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2843</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2843</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.313</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;313</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;313</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12123</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12123</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 646</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Lease of pasture land by Herakleides, son of Didymos, from the six elders and the secretary of the public cultivators in Tebtynis (compare P.Mich. II, 121, recto, col. IV, abstract 12). The body of the contract was not finished</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 15 x 22 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">broken off at the bottom; the surface of the papyrus has been badly worn, and much of the writing is very faint</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">28</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0037">December 5, 37 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Harmiysis grandson of Harpares, presbyteros of the demosioi georgoi of Tebtynis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis son of Horouanchious, presbyteros of the demosioi georgoi of Tebtynis (see also P.Mich. II, p. 224</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">V, p. 389)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harmaeis (Harmais) son of Petesouchos, presbyteros of the demosioi georgoi of Tebtynis (see also P.Mich. V, 297?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Stotouetis (Stotoetis) son of Kollouthos, presbyteros of the demosioi georgoi of Tebtynis (see also P.Mich. V, 314?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aunes son of Tephorsos (Tephersos), presbyteros of the demosioi georgoi of Tebtynis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Kollouthos, presbyteros of the demosioi georgoi of Tebtynis (see also P.Mich. II, 121, recto, col. IV, abstract 2?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harmiysis son of Orseus, grammateus of the demosioi georgoi of Tebtynis (see also P.Mich. II, 121, recto, col. IV, abstract 12)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides son of Didymos, Perses tes epigones (see also P.Mich. V, 236</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">262?)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome; Perses; drymos theou legomenos; Kanabis legomenon</term>
               <term>Agriculture</term>
               <term>Animals</term>
               <term>Ethnicity</term>
               <term>Guild</term>
               <term>Land Ownership</term>
               <term>Lease</term>
               <term>Iranians--Egypt</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>The second year of Gaius Caesar Augustus Germanicus, Peritios 9, Choiak 9, in Tebtynis of the division of Polemon in the Arsinoite nome. Horos, son of Harmiysis, son of Harpares, about 68 years old, with a scar on his right forearm, and Orsenouphis, son of Horouanchious, about 58 years old, with a scar on his right calf, and Harmaeis, son of Petesouchos, about 55 years old, with a scar on his left calf, and Stotouetis, son of Kollouthos, with a scar on the little finger of his left hand, and Aunes, son of Tephorsos, about 33 years old, with a scar on the left side of his forehead, and Onnophris, son of Kollouthos, about 35 years old, with a scar on his right knee, the six being elders of the public cultivators of the same village, and Harmiysis, son of Orseus, secretary of the cultivators, about 55 years old, with a scar on his right forearm, the seven have leased to Herakleides, son of Didymos, a Persian of the epigone, about 50 years old, with a scar on the middle of his nose, the half share of the so-called marsh of the god, the part on the east near the said village of Tebtynis, of the reed bed and arum and lotus root, and of the dry pastures of the so-called Kanabis, for two years from the present second year of Gaius Caesar Augustus Germanicus; the arum and whatever there is for fodder for pigs; the rent of all the land being sixty drachmai of minted silver coin a year . . .;;;(2nd hand) We, Horos, son of Harmiysis, son of Harpares, and Orsenouphis, son of Horouanchious, and Harmaeis, son of Petesouchos, and Stotouetis, son of Kollouthos, and Aunes, son of Tephorsos, and Onnophris, son of Kollouthos, the six elders of the public cultivators, and Harmiysis, secretary of the cultivators, the seven belonging to the same cultivators, acknowledge that we have leased to Herakleides, son of Didymos, the half share of the so-called marsh of the god, the eastern part, near the village of Tebtynis, of the reed bed and arum and lotus root, and of the dry pastures of the so-called Kanabis, for two years from the present [- - -]</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 313, 1944</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:313</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2843&amp;viewid=646R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/4/6/R/646R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2843&amp;viewid=646R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2843&amp;viewid=646R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
