<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>loan on mortgage</title>
            <author>Marcus Aurelius Euhemerus</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1604</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1604</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.14.11705</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;14;11705</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;14;11705</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14507</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14507</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 257</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>This text is a copy, written in one hand throughout, of a loan on mortgage followed by an application for communication of the certified copy and the official order to the record office of the Arsinoite nome along with two endorsements and the signature of the scribe. The whole document was presumably part of a petition. Only the latter part of the loan has survived. A loan is made by Gaius Valerius Severus to Markus Julius Casianus on the collateral of a house and grinding machine belonging to Julius Casianus in the village of Philadelphia. The amount of the loan and the rate of interest are lost, but the specifications of duties, rights, and guarantees are preserved.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; traces from another document</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 17.2 x 16.1 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This medium-brown papyrus is badly torn where it had been folded and where it decayed on the outside. It appears in seven vertical strips, of which the first four are completely detachable. These strips were patched together by means of other papyrus on the verso by the dealer, who joined the fragments wrongly.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-27</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The hand of the scribe, Marcus Aurelius Euhemerus, is very practiced, with ligatures throughout; but the generally squeezed effect of the writing is broken irregularly by very large letters, making it very difficult to estimate how many letters are missing in the lacunas.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0213">213 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Philadelphia, Herakleides division, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Arion Sarapion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Julius Casianus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius Valerius Serenus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Caesar Marcus Aurelius Severus Antoninus Parthicus Maximus Britannicus Maximus Pius Augustus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marcus Claudius Theodorus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Harpocration</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Philadelphia, Herakleides division, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt (?)</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Philadelphia, Herakleides meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</term>
               <term>Debtor and creditor--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Home ownership--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>650 0:Grain--Machinery--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Mortgages--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Land titles--Registration and transfer--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>". . . on the security of a small house belonging to him in the village of Philadelphia in the division of Heraklides of the Arsinoite nome along with a machine for grinding grain, of which the adjacent areas are as they designated by mutual agreement, on the south and west a vacant lot, on the north the property of Arion Sarapion, on the east a public road. Julius Casianus must repay the principal to Valerius Serenus on the above date and the interest monthly without fail and the same interest for the time beyond payment. Moreover, he will deliver the mortgaged small house clear and without encumbrance and not pledged in security for another loan, and no agent of his may take action against it in any way before the appointed time of repayment. If he does not act justly in accordance with the terms, the party entering the into possession of the mortgaged property will have the right to (assume assume ownership of?) it and to manage and dispose of it as he chooses, the guarantee resting upon Julius Casianus perpetually. And if, unfortunately, any accident or reduction or anything else at all happens to the mortgaged property or any part of it, neither the loan nor the interest will in any way be the responsibility of Valerius, who will still have the right of execution against all the property of the debtor because the loan is guaranteed against risks. And that all this has been done fairly, Gaius Valerius Serenus has asked in good faith and Marcus Julius Casianus has consented in good faith. The 22nd year of the Emperor Caesar Marcus Aurelius Severus Antoninus Parthicus Maximus Britannicus Maximus Pius Augustus, Phaophi 2.;And since I desire this to be communicated to the keepers of the property registers of the Arsinoite nome, I request that when the certified copy of the agreement is presented and the official order, both subscribed, you will write to them so that they will be properly informed. The 22nd year of the lord Emperor Aurelius Severus Antoninus Augustus, Phaophi.;I, Marcus Claudius Theodorus, have signed it, and a copy of the . . . on the margin is appended. The 22nd year of Aurelius Severus Antoninus Caesar, Phaophi.;I, Aurelius Harpokration, have signed it. I, Marcus Aurelius Euhemerus and however I am called, wrote it.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Gignac FT, BASP 13, 93-7, 1976 -- SB XIV 11705 -- BL X, 210 (bibliography)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:14:11705</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1604&amp;viewid=257R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/5/7/R/257R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1604&amp;viewid=257R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1604&amp;viewid=257R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
