<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3855</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3855</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 38.2 x 29.8 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Regularly cut at the top. Kollesis left center. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-42</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 88 (ll. 3495-3537)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Eutas, son of Sambas, grandson of Petheus, mother Ammonous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hatres, son of Apollonios, grandson of Heraklas, mother Taorsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 156)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Harphaesis, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tapontos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Petaus, grandson of Petheus, mother Isis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, his brother with the same mother (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor, son of Sisois, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 182)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Besis, grandson of Thoteus, mother Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Naaraus the older, grandson of Thebennis, mother Tamarres (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Sambas, grandson of Onnophris, mother Eserempis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Pakysis, grandson of Petheus, mother Tamaron (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Sokmenis, grandson of Sambas, mother Tkollainis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 224)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dios, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 160)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Esouris, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Aunes, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Onnophris, grandson of Maron, mother Tkollainis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Charidemos, son of Petoraipis, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis, son of Kaladytes, grandson of Heras, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 195)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos, son of Heraklas, grandson of Heraklas, mother Stiynchis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastresis, slave of Thaisareion alias Nebsosis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 190)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor, son of Achillas, grandson of Kastor, mother Aphrodous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor the younger, his brother of the same mother (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Kastor, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 182)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor alias Ptolemaios, his brother with the same mother (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 182)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius Sempronius Serenus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 160)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabeinos, son of Valens (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaia Valeria (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 159)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Saturnilus, brother of Pankras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 227)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Primogenes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 215)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marcus Anthestius Capitolinus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didyme, daughter of Herakleides (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 161)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>-</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 88:;Eutas, son of Sambas, grandson of Petheus, mother Ammonous, drachmas 20;;Hatres, son of Apollonios, grandson of Heraklas, mother Taorsenouphis, copper drachmas 8;;Pnepheros, son of Harphaesis, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tapontos, drachmas 12;;Petaus, son of Petaus, grandson of Petheus, mother Isis, drachmas 16;;Pnepheros, his brother with the same mother, drachmas 8;;Kastor, son of Sisois, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaisas, drachmas 4;;Pnepheros, son of Besis, grandson of Thoteus, mother Heras, drachmas 8 copper drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Naaraus the older, grandson of Thebennis, mother Tamarres, drachmas 4 obols 28;;Onnophris, son of Sambas, grandson of Onnophris, mother Eserempis, too old to pay poll tax, guard taxes drachmas 8 obols 8;;Petheus, son of Pakysis, grandson of Petheus, mother Tamaron, drachmas 4 copper drachmas 4;;Sambas, son of Sokmenis, grandson of Sambas, mother Tkollainis, drachmas 4;;Dios, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 12;;Ptolemaios, son of Esouris, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4 copper drachmas 4;;Onnophris, son of Aunes, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thaisas, drachmas 20 obols 24;;Sarapion, son of Onnophris, grandson of Maron, mother Tkollainis, drachmas 20;;Charidemos, son of Petoraipis, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Pakysis, son of Kaladytes, grandson of Heras, mother Segathis, copper drachmas 8;;in total for the day drachmas 364 obols 23.;Mesore 1:;Petesouchos, son of Heraklas, grandson of Heraklas, mother Stiynchis, drachmas 8;;Kastresis, slave of Thaisareion alias Nebsosis, copper drachmas 4;;Kastor, son of Achillas, grandson of Kastor, mother Aphrodous, drachmas 12;;Kastor the younger, his brother of the same mother, drachmas 12;;Kastor, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Kastor, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 12;;Kastor alias Ptolemaios, his brother with the same mother, drachmas 12;;Gaius Sempronius Serenus (Sabeinos, son of Valens);;(in left margin: drachmas 108) orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira drachmas 14 obol 1, tax on the produce of olives drachmas 2, naubion drachma 1 obols 2.5, surcharges drachmas 3 obol 0.5 chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 9 obols 2.5 chalki 2, surcharges obols 4.5 chalki 2, kollybos obols 3 chalki 2, in total drachmas 31 obols 5.5;;geometria of year 12 drachmas 70 obols 5, surcharges drachmas 4 obols 3, in total drachmas 75 obols 2;;Gaia Valeria (Saturnilus, brother of Pankras);;orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira drachmas 2 obols 3, tax on the produce of olives obols 2 chalki 2, naubion obol 1.5, surcharges obols 3.5 chalki 2;;(in left margin: drachmas 16 obols 28) eparourion drachma 1 obols 4, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5 chalki 2;;and land of the kleronomos Primogenes;;orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira obols 4 chalki 2, naubion obol 0.5 chalki 2, surcharges obol 1 chalki 2;;eparourion obols 3, surcharges obol 0.5, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachma 1 obols 4;;geometria of year 12 drachmas 8 obols 3, surcharges obols 3 chalki 2, in total drachmas 9 chalki 2;;and to Marcus Anthestius Capitolinus;;naubion of katoikoi of year 13 drachma 1, surcharges obol 0.5 chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachma 1 obol1;;and to Didyme, daughter of Herakleides;;likewise naubion of katoikoi of year 13 obols 2, surcharges chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total obols 2.5."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 -- BL III, 113 (on l. 8 a.o); BL III, 113 (on l. 3516) Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3855&amp;viewid=4171_88R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3855&amp;viewid=4171_88R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3855&amp;viewid=4171_88R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
