<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>homily</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1329</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1329</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1191</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>The text is clearly a homily. The part that remains begins with a simple list of various evil deeds perpetrated by characters in the Old Testament. Some of these are obscured by mutilations of the text and some by strange spelling of proper names, but for the most part they are easily recognizable. Because of his wickedness, the homilist continues, the devil has gained the upper hand and seks to snare the unwary. But help is at hand through Jesus Christ, who has sown the good seed and multiplied the number of those who believe in him. He has poured upon us the water of baptism and we have received his body and blood. The sins of the world have been pardoned through the gifts of God.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Recto; Written across the fibers; scribe rotated papyrus 90 degrees to accommodate the format of the text.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is Blank</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="cop">Coptic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 17.5 x 33.1 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The upper part of this almost yellow papyrus is broken off, but an ornamental line at the bottom below the text would seem to indicate that the end is complete. There is a break across the papyrus after line 49, but there is no loss of text. There is no margin on the right side or at the bottom of the sheet, and there is a somewhat irregular margin of about 1.5 cm. on the left. It is impossible to estimate the original size of the papyrus, but it is obvious that it is from a roll and not from a codex.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-59</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Fifty-nine lines are preserved, apparently written by two hands. The first hand (lines 1-46) is heavy, crude, with irregularly formed and badly spaced letters and uneven lines. The second part (lines 46-59) gives the effect of a more practiced hand, although it, too, is irregular and the forms of the letters approximate those of the first. The alteration in appearance could be due to the finer pen with which this part is written rather than to a change in scribe. Some of the grosser defects in the writing can be attributed to the poorly finished surface of the papyrus. For a parallel, cf. P. Mich. inv. 3564, a piece of papyrus that had also been used for Greek accounts of the Arab period. A date in the seventh century, or even tlater, might therefore be suggested for this text.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0600" notAfter="0799">VIIth/VIIIth century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="cop">Coptic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>-</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">literary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>". . . are adulterers. The elders are false witnesses. Their mouths are murderers. The elders utter false words. The two calves of gold are on high places of Bethel. The serpent of bronze is in Nesthan. The pillar of Baal is in Samaria . . . deals in the evil eye in the valley of the sons of Hinnom. The calf of gold is in Horeb. Israel plays the harlot in the land of Moab. Cain kills, being disobedient. The watchmen commit violence. Ham derides the nakedness of his father. The men of Shinar build the tower. Chedorlaomar makes war. The Philistines oppress strangers. Esau is angry. Dan is zealous. The wife of the Egyptian is importunate. Pharaoh is merciless. Adonijah is overweening. Saul rends the mantle of the prophet. Absalom hates his father. Hadar the Edomite is an adversary. Ahab is a robber. Jezebel pursues the prophet. Manasseh pours out the blood of the just. Nebuchadnezzar kindles a furnace of fire and those who hope in the Lord are thrown into it. The presidents bring accusations against Daniel. Elihu speaks shameless words. On account of these things the world is troubled, the devil is vain, the dragnet is spread out, the net is cast, the hooks are thrown, a pit is dug, a snare is prepared at the time of my safety. All these things being so, my beloved brethren, let us not go forth in a great concourse of words. For, indeed, the Scripture is wont to say "Godliness in a sufficiency." And he also saith in the Apostle "Five words are better than ten thousand." Who is it who hath sowed, who hath become greater than Jesus Christ? But I am wont to take a witness for myself whether our Lord hath sowed or not. Come, Matthew, Jesus shall tell us. He said to his apostles "He who soweth the good seed in the son of man", in order that he may know that he is the one who himself sows his own. In what way are they greater than he, his own whom he has sown after the twelve. They will seek the holy spirit who hath brought them to the land to come. He hath given gifts to those who believe in him, as Paul hath said "He hath given gifts to men." The Scripture saith "All good cometh from him." Jeremiah also himself saith "Dig up thorns and plant the pure wheat." In all these things he teacheth everyone about our Lord, that he is the one who hath rooted out sin from the world. He hath planted the seed of life in . . . and the nations have believed, bringing forth fruit until they become a hundred, some sixty, some others thirty, that ye may know that his own have become greater than he. The one who lays up for himself when he is in need, this thing it is that we know, If a man strives to lay up goods and they are not left to him, what shall it profit him? This is the very way of the devil, who hath cursed all mankind through the first sin. Our Lord, our Saviour, hath cursed all mankind through the first sin. Our Lord, our Saviour, hath come with speed. He hath snatched us from his serpents (?). He hath cast upon us the water of baptism. But he hath purified us. We have received of his body and his blood. God hath been reconciled to his likeness. The sins of all the world have been pardoned through the gifts of God.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, Studies Aziz Suryal Atiya, 226-39, 1972 -- l. 17: pdidomeos; l. 18: iesabel; l. 20; l. 26; l. 39: TMETCNOOC; l. 40: NAOITH; l. 41: NETPISTEOYE; l. 49: NT[A]YPISTEOYE</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1329&amp;viewid=1191R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/9/1/r/1191r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1329&amp;viewid=1191R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1329&amp;viewid=1191R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
