<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Donatio mortis causa</title>
            <author>Soueris, daughter of Onnophris and Soueris, granddaughter of Labesis + Orseus, son of Tryphon</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1389</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1389</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.8.9642.3</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14280</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14280</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;8;9642_3</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1335</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Soueris, daughter of Onnophris, granddaughter of Labesis, mother Soueris, acting with her husband, Orseus, son of Tryphon, as her guardian, divides her property equally between her two sons, Onnophris and Tephersais. The property consists of a house inherited from her father, a share of another house and court that has been purchased, and household goods and clothing. The sons have the responsibility of providing a fitting funeral for their mother. To her daughter, Thermouthis, Soueris has left the sum of sixty drachmas, perhaps in addition to dowry already received. This is probably to be a charge on the estate after the mother's death. All the other terms of the agreement has been lost.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 28 x 9.2 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Fourteen complete lines and a few traces of letters from a fifteenth line remain from the top of this document. The full width of the papyrus and the upper margin is intact.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-14</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick and regular cursive. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0125">125 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtunis, Polemon division, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt (?)</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Imperator Caesar Trajanus Hadrianus Augustus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Soueris, daughter of Onnophris, granddaughter of Labesis, mother Soueris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orseus, son of Tryphon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tephersais</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thermouthis</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtunis, Polemon division, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt (?)</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Tebtunis, Polemon division, Arsinoite nome</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"The tenth year of Imperator Caesar Trajanus Hadrianus Augustus, Phaophi the twentieth, in Tebtunis in the division of Polemon of the Arsinoite nome. Soueris, daughter of Onnophris, son of Labesis, her mother being Soueris, from the aforesaid village of Tebtunis, about fifty-two years old, with a scar on her right shin, with her guardian, her husband, Orseus, son of Tryphon, about sixty-two years old, with a scar on the little finger of his left hand, acknowledges that she, the contracting party, Soueris, has ceded after her death to the children born of her to her aforesaid husband Orseus, to the three of them, Onnophris and Tephersais and Thermouthis, to the two Onnophris and Tephersais, half to each to be held in common and equally, and if either of them does not survive, to his children, the house that belongs to the said Soueris by inheritance from her father and the share of eleven-eighteenths of another house and court that belongs to her by purchase and all the appurtenances of all the property in the aforesaid village of Tebtunis, and all the household goods that shall be left by her and the utensils and furniture and clothing and sums owed to her, or other things of any kind whatsoever; and to Thermouthis she has bequeathed sixty drachmas of silver. The funeral rites and laying out of their mother shall devolve upon the two, Onnophris and Tephersais, together and equally, as shall seem best to them . . . "</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, TAPA 88, 140-1, 1957 -- SB VIII 9642.3 -- BL VII, 213 on line 3</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:8:9642.3</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1389&amp;viewid=1335R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/3/5/r/1335r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1389&amp;viewid=1335R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1389&amp;viewid=1335R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
