<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of a House</title>
            <author>Orseus, Pakebkis, Papnebtynis and Mieus, all sons of Harmiysis; Herodes, son of Herodes; and Psenkebkis, son of Psonsneus</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2907</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2907</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.269</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12105</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12105</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;269/270/271qrpl</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 665</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Subscriptions to a contract by which six men, including four brothers, sell to a certain Psonsneus the half share of a house and court which they own in common; four months earlier, the same persons and property were probably involved in a division of property, recorded in P.Mich. II, 121, verso, col. I, l. 7, as a contract between Orseus and others and Psosneus</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Duplicate: P.S.I. VIII, 907 (with the descriptions of the parties); P.Mich. V, 270 (inv. 715; 1st subscription only); 271 (inv. 718; 1st subscription only). - Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 29.5 x 27 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">badly frayed at the bottom; damaged along some folds</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1 + 25 (or 26)</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0042">August 28, 42 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Claudius, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orseus son of Harmiysis and Tausiris, husband of Tamieus (see also P.Mich. II, 121, verso, col. I, l. 7</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">and perhaps P.Mich. V, 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psonsneus = Psonneuos (Psosneus) (see also P.Mich. II, 121, verso, col. I, l. 7)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tamieuos (Tamieus) daughter of Patynis, wife of Orseus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herodes son of Herodes and Taarmiysis, husband of Tamares</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Opis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tamares daughter of Aunes, wife of Herodes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Melantas son of Kronion (see also P.Mich. V, 318)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakebkis son of Harmiysis and Tausiris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Papnebtynis son of Harmiysis and Tausiris, husband of Thenmieus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orseus son of Labaeis (Labais) (former owner)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles son of Orsenouphis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) sons of Hatreponsis &lt;or: of Hatres, son of Honsis?&gt;</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orseus son of Prious (former owner)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Eutychos son of Eutychos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Haratytis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thenmieus daughter of Mieus, wife of Papnebtynis</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Tebtynis</term>
               <term>Family</term>
               <term>House Ownership</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Sale</term>
               <term>Topography (Tebtynis)</term>
               <term>Woman</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[Year] 2 of Claudius, 5th intercalary day of the month Kaisareios.;;;I, Orseus, son of Harmiysis, my mother being Tausiris, have joined in selling the share that belongs to me of the half share of an old fallen house, inherited from my father, and of the court and all appurtenances held in common and undivided by me and the purchaser Psonsneus and others, in Tebtynis, and I have joined in receiving the entire price in full, immediately, from hand to hand, out of the house, and in guaranteeing the sale with every guarantee as aforesaid. My wife Tamieus, daughter of Patynis, gives her consent to the sale and agrees that she will not proceed against it forever or bring any charges, and that no one else shall in her behalf as aforesaid. I, Orseus, wrote for my wife because she is illiterate.;(2nd hand) I, Herodes, son of Herodes, my mother being  Taarmiysis, have joined in selling the share that belongs to me of the half share of an old fallen house, inherited from my father, and of the court and all appurtenances held in common and undivided by me and the purchaser Psonsneus and others, in Tebtynis, formerly called the property of Opis, and I have joined in receiving the entire price in full, immediately, from hand to hand, out of the house, and in guaranteeing the sale with every guarantee. And my wife Tamares, daughter of Aunes, consents to this sale and agrees that she will not proceed against it forever or bring any claim, and that no one else shall in her behalf as aforesaid. Melantas, son of Kronion, wrote for them because they are illiterate.;(3rd hand) We, Pakebkis and Papnebtynis, both sons of Harmiysis, our mother being Tausiris, have joined in selling the shares that belong to us of the half share of an old fallen house, inherited from our father, and of the court and all the appurtenances held in common and undivided together with you, the purchaser, and others, in Tebtynis, formerly called the property of Opis; the neighbors of the entire house and court being on the south the house formerly belonging to Orseus, son of Labaeis, and now belonging to Herakles, son of Orsenouphis, and in part the house and court of the sons of Hatreponsis(?); on the north the house formerly belonging to Orseus, son of Prious, and now belonging to Eutychos, son of Eutychos, and in part the vacant lots of Haratytis and others now belonging to Eutychos the elder, son of Eutychos; on the west and east the royal roads. And we have joined in receiving from Psonsneus the entire price agreed upon, in full, immediately, from hand to hand, out of the hosue, and in guaranteeing the sale with every guarantee from public and private debts and every claim forever. The wife of Papnebtynis, Thenmieus, daughter of Mieus, consents to the sale and agrees not to proceed against it forever . . . [- - -].;;(Traces of 4 or 5 more lines).</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 269, 1944</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:269</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2907&amp;viewid=665R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/6/5/R/665R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2907&amp;viewid=665R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2907&amp;viewid=665R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
