<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3838</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3838</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 32.5 x 30.4 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at the right and the left. Kollesis left and right sides. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-36</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 73 (ll. 2893-2929)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis, son of Heron, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Zoidous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 193)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Sokmenis, grandson of Pausis, mother Tkames (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 220)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles, son of Sokrates, grandson of Phasis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Valerius, fatherless, mother Valeria (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 195)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammon, son of Apion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 150)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apion, son of Ammon (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 152)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Leonides, son of Apion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 184)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis, son of Heras, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Isidora (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois, son of Limnaios, grandson of Satabous, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Petheus, grandson of Teos, mother Taonnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phasis, son of Amphiomis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 246)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pemes, son of Atai (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchophis, son of Petheus, grandson of Anchophis, mother Aphrodous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Imouthes, son of Keras, grandson of Menadros, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 177)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Phaesis, grandson of Petheus, mother Tanais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor, his son, mother Tapasion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 182)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Apollonios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Petheus, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion, son of Aphrodisios, grandson of Onnophris, mother Tapetaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Kames, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sentis alias Theagenes, son of Petheus, grandson of Theagenes, mother Tauris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 228)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Onnophris, grandson of Harendotes, mother Isidora (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Onnophris, grandson of Onnophris, mother Sopas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Valeria, daughter of Isias (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 194)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Valeria, daughter of Herais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 194)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Esouris, son of Samels (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Athenion, son of Horos, grandson of Pakysis, mother Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 150)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Patsontis district; see also electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 73:;Orsenouphis, son of Heron, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Zoidous, obols 28;;Ptolemaios, son of Sokmenis, grandson of Pausis, mother Tkames, drachmas 8;;Herakles, son of Sokrates, grandson of Phasis, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Valerius, fatherless, mother Valeria, drachmas 4, obols 27;;Ammon, son of Apion (Apion, son of Ammon);;(in left margin: drachmas 16 obols 14) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 5, tax on the produce of olives obols 4 chalki 2, naubion obols 3, surcharges drachma 1 obol 1.5;;eparourion drachmas 3 obols 2, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2, kollybos obol 1 chalki 2, in total drachmas 11 obol 1.5 chalki 2;;and to Leonides, son of Apion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 184);;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachma 1 chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives obol 1.5, naubion obol 0.5 chalki 2, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2;;eparourion obols 4.5, surcharges obol 0.5, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachmas 2 obols 3.5;;naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year drachma 1 obols 2.5, surcharges obol 1, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachma 1 obols 3.5;;tax on land plots in release likewise obols 4, surcharges obol 1, kollybos chalki 2, in total obols 5 chalki 2;;in total for the day drachmas 124 obols 7.;(Pauni) 5 likewise:;Phaesis, son of Heras, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Isidora, drachmas 4;;Sisois, son of Limnaios, grandson of Satabous, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4 obols 28;;Heron, son of Petheus, grandson of Teos, mother Taonnophris, drachmas 4;;Phasis, son of Amphiomis (Pemes, son of Atai);;(in left margin: drachmas 4 obols 12) geometria for the 12th year drachmas 5, surcharges obols 2, in total drachmas 5 obols 2;;Anchophis, son of Petheus, grandson of Anchophis, mother Aphrodous, copper tetradrachmas 4;;Imouthes, son of Keras, grandson of Menadros, mother Tepheros, copper tetradrachma;;Ptolemaios, son of Phaesis, grandson of Petheus, mother Tanais, drachmas 8;;Kastor, his son, mother Tapasion, drachmas 8;;in total for the day drachmas 48 obols 11.;(Pauni) 6 likewise:;Ptolemaios, son of Apollonios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 8;;Pnepheros, son of Petheus, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Thaisas, copper tetradrachma;;Horion, son of Aphrodisios, grandson of Onnophris, mother Tapetaus, drachmas 4;;Sarapion, son of Kames, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Sentis alias Theagenes, son of Petheus, grandson of Theagenes, mother Tauris, drachmas 12;;Horos, son of Onnophris, grandson of Harendotes, mother Isidora, drachmas 4;;Heras, son of Onnophris, grandson of Onnophris, mother Sopas, drachmas 4;;Valeria, daughter of Isias through the agency of Valeria, daughter of Herais (Esouris, son of Samels);;(in left margin: drachmas 36, obols 16) apomoira drachmas 15, tax on the produce of olives drachmas 2 obol 0.5 chalki 2, naubion drachma 1 obols 3, surcharges drachmas 3 obols 4.5;;eparourion drachmas 10, surcharges obols 4.5 chalki 2, kollybos obols 3.5, in total drachmas 33 obols 4.5;;Athenion, son of Horos, grandson of Pakysis, mother Heras, drachmas 4."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3838&amp;viewid=4171_73R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3838&amp;viewid=4171_73R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3838&amp;viewid=4171_73R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
