<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3789</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3789</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.1.224</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso contains two lines with amounts paid in tax; the name of  the individuals who paid these amounts are not preserved</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 30.2 x 30 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at all sides except the bottom. Kollesis in the right middle. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-35</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 42 (ll. 1764-1799)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC) Space free for three lines is blank at the bottom of this column.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Satabous, mother Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptollis, son of Orsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 221)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, worker on irrigation machines (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mystharion, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Euhemeros, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 188)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Thakialis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Akousilaos, grandson of Pasoknopaios, mother Thatres (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Papeis, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phasis, son of Pakysis, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tanebkenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 246)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Besis, son of Petheus, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 159)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Petaus, grandson of Petheus, mother Isis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor, son of Kastor, grandson of Apollonios, mother Heraklous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois, slave of Tasoucharion, son of Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Phasis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 204)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tip (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 242)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonios, son of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 153)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois, son of Hekemon (?) (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Pasoknopaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Kiales, muleteer (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 183)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Artemis, son of Mysthes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 156)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois, son of Ptillos, grandson of Pathabes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 42.;Ptolemaios, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Satabous, mother Heras, drachmas 4;;Ptollis, son of Orsenouphis (Heras, worker on irrigation machines);;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 2 obols 5, tax on the produce of olives obols 2.5 chalki 2, naubion obol 1.5 chalki 2;;eparourion drachma 1 obols 5.5, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 6 obols 3;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 7 chalki 2, surcharges obols 2.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 7 obols 3;;naubion of the katoikoi for the 13th year obols 4, surcharges obol 0.5, kollybos chalki 2, in total obols 4.5 chalki 2;;Mystharion, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Euhemeros, mother Tapetheus, obols 28;;Pnepheros, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Thakialis, drachmas 8;;Pnepheros, son of Akousilaos, grandson of Pasoknopaios, mother Thatres, drachmas 8;;Papeis, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Heras, obols 28;;Phasis, son of Pakysis, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tanebkenis, drachmas 8;;Besis, son of Petheus, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;Pnepheros, son of Petaus, grandson of Petheus, mother Isis, drachmas 8;;Kastor, son of Kastor, grandson of Apollonios, mother Heraklous, drachmas 16;;Sisois, slave of Tasoucharion, son of Thaisas, drachmas 16;;Petheus, son of Phasis (Tip);;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 2 obols 4, tax on the produce of olives obols 2.5, naubion obol 1.5 chalki 2, surcharges obols 4 chalki 2;;(in left margin: drachmas 12 obols 15) eparourion drachma 1 obols 4.5 chalki 2, surcharges obol 1 chalki 2, kollybos obol 0.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 6 obol1 chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 6 obols 4, surcharges obols 2.5, in total drachmas 7 obol 0.5;;in total for the day drachmas 240 obols 19, of which to Sarap() drachmas 76 obols 19.;(Pharmouthi) 4 likewise:;Apollonios, son of Horos (Sisois, son of Hekemon):;(in left margin: drachmas 16 obols 21) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 5, tax on the produce of olives obols 4 chalki 2, naubion obols 3, surcharges drachma 1 obol 1.5;;eparourion drachmas 3 obols 2, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2, kollybos obol 1 chalki 2, in total drachmas 11 obol 1.5 chalki 2;;other orchard taxes for the 12th year drachmas 2 obols 5, tax on the produce of olives obols 2.5, naubion obols 2, surcharges obols 4.5;;eparourion drachma 1 obols 5.5, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 6 obols 3 chalki 2;;Petheus, son of Pasoknopaios through the agency of Heras (Kiales, muleteer);;(in left margin: drachmas 12 obols 26) orchard taxes for the 12th year drachmas 3 obol 0.5 chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives obols 2.5 chalki 2, naubion obols 2, surcharges obols 5;;eparourion drachmas 2 obol 0.5, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 7 obol 0.5 chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 7 obol 1, surcharges obols 2.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 7 obols 3.5 chalki 2;;Artemis, son of Mysthes (son of Sisois, son of Ptillos, grandson of Pathabes;;(in the left margin: drachmas 16 obols 25) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 3 obols 4.5, tax on the produce of olives obols 3 chalki 2, naubion obols 2.5, surcharges drachma 1;;eparourion drachmas 2 obols 3, surcharges obol 1 chalki 2, kollybos obol 1, in total drachmas 8 obols 3.5;;geometria of the 12th year drachmas 9 obols 2 chalki 2, surcharges obols 3.5, in total drachmas 9 obols 5.5 chalki 2."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3789&amp;viewid=4171_42R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3789&amp;viewid=4171_42R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3789&amp;viewid=4171_42R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
