<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3644</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3644</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.224</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 31.3 x 32.5 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Regularly cut at the left side and at the right side. Top and bottom somewhat torn. No kollesis visible. On the back, in the lower left corner, a small rectangular piece of papyrus has been pasted on, presumably for fortification. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-42</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 10 (ll. 359-401)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Some additions are made in the left margin. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos, son of Heraklas, grandson of Heraklas, mother Stiynchis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Petheus, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Taseus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabeinos, son of Petheus, grandson of Heraklas, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Polis, son of Petheus, grandson of Keras, mother Herais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herieus the older, son of Horos, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Eutyches, slave of Sarapias (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 165)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Herieus, grandson of Petaus, mother Tlemenesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Harmiysis, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Sambas, grandson of Sabeinus, mother Aphrodous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hatres, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Heraklas, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 157)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Horos, grandson of Horos, mother of Taharmothes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Harpekysis, grandson of Satabous, mother Tasokonopis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonios, son of Ischyrion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 153)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Eutas, son of Koukallos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 152)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpagathes, son of Satabous, grandson of Anchophis, mother Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Euhemeros, son of Euhemeros, grandson of Keras, mother Tauris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinus, son of Petheus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Herakleia (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus, son of Tesenouphis, grandson of Harphaesis, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 246)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Achillas, son of Ptollis, grandson of Hieronouphis, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Esouris, son of Petheus, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Ptolemas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Menches, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thaseis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchophis, son of Horos, grandson of Anchophis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Ptolema (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon, fatherless, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Soeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 194)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Leonides, grandson of Petheus, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anoubas, son of Horos, grandson of Anoubas, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 151)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion, son of Sisouchos, grandson of Sisouchos, mother Apollonous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Sisois, grandson of Satabous, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Horos, mother Eseremphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Pasoxis, mother Tanephremis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petheus, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Horos, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 223)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"[Column 10];Petesouchos, son of Heraklas, grandson of Heraklas, mother Stiynchis, drachmas 4;;Petaus, son of Petheus, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Taseus, drachmas 4;;Sabeinos, son of Petheus, grandson of Heraklas, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 8;;Polis, son of Petheus, grandson of Keras, mother Herais, drachmas 8;;Herieus the older, son of Horos, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Eutyches, slave of Sarapias, drachmas 4;;Petaus, son of Herieus, grandson of Petaus, mother Tlemenesis, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Harmiysis, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Sambas, grandson of Sabeinus, mother Aphrodous, drachmas 4;;Hatres, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Heraklas, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Horos, son of Horos, grandson of Horos, mother of Taharmothes, drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, son of Harpekysis, grandson of Satabous, mother Tasokonopis, drachmas 12;;Apollonios, son of Ischyrion through Eutas alias Kou-;kallos;;The account tax [of land] of katoikoi of Karanis in 12th year:;drachmas 16, obols 1/2, added charges drachma 1, 2 chalkoi. In total drachmas 17, 1/2 obol and 2 chalkoi;;(left margin: drachmas 16, obols ]19 (?)) naubion for the katoikoi of the 12th year, 3 obols, added charges 1/2 obol, drachmas 1 and 2 chalkoi;;in total for the day, drachmas 168, obols 10, of which the poll tax for the 12th year drachmas 4, obols 16;;and account tax, naubion for the 12th year, drachmas 18, 4 obols;;Harpagathes, son of Satabous, grandson of Anchophis, mother Sambathion, drachmas 4;;Euhemeros, son of Euhemeros, grandson of Keras, mother Tauris, drachmas 24;;Sabinus, son of Petheus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Herakleia, drachmas 4;;Phanomgeus, son of Tesenouphis, grandson of Harphaesis, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Achillas, son of Ptollis, grandson of Hieronouphis, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;Esouris, son of Petheus, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Ptolemas, drachmas 4;;Onnophris, son of Menches, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thaseis, drachmas 8;;Anchophis, son of Horos, grandson of Anchophis, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 8;;Onnophris, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Ptolema, drachmas 8;;12th year, Petheus, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetheus, copper drachmas 8;;Chairemon, fatherless, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 20;;Orsenouphis, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Soeris, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Leonides, grandson of Petheus, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;Anoubas, son of Horos, grandson of Anoubas, mother Tepheros, drachmas 4;;Horion, son of Sisouchos, grandson of Sisouchos, mother Apollonous, drachmas 8;;Petaus, son of Sisois, grandson of Satabous, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Horos, mother Eseremphis, drachmas 8;;Chairemon, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Pasoxis, mother Tanephremis, obols 28;;in total for the day, drachmas 128, obols 27,of which for the 12th year;;[Tybi] 8 likewise:;Pasion, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petheus, mother Segathis, drachmas 8, drachmas 28;;Sambas, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Horos, mother Tapetheus, obols 28;;in total for the day, drachmas 12, obols 27."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3644&amp;viewid=4171_10R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3644&amp;viewid=4171_10R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3644&amp;viewid=4171_10R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
