<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3824</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3824</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 36.7 x 29.8 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at the left and at the right. Kollesis left of center. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-35</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 60 (ll. 2427-2462)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Helene, daughter of Hieranouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptollas, son of Touamabis  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 221)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Agathopous, slave of Taseus alias Isarion  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 148)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Neilos, son of Lupus, grandson of Horos, mother Ammonarion  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 190)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles, son of Petheus, grandson of Onnophris, mother Taseus  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Phaesis, mother Tapasion  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 182)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Hatres  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Deios, son of Panpis  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 160)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Petheus  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon, son of Pateis  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Komon, son of Onnophris, grandson of Satabous, mother Ptolema  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion his brother with the same mother  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Achillas, grandson of Onnophris, mother Didymarion  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Onnopris  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psas  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius Julius Saturnilus  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 159)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Neilos, physician  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 190)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sopatra, daughter of Maron  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 232)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 60:;(Pachon) 4 likewise:;Helene, daughter of Hieranouphis (Ptollas, son of Touamabis);;(in left margin: drachmas 12 obols 12) geometria for the 12th year drachmas 12 obols 3, surcharges obols 4.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 13 obol 1.5 chalki 2;;Agathopous, slave of Taseus alias Isarion, drachmas 12;;Neilos, son of Lupus, grandson of Horos, mother Ammonarion, drachmas 12;;Herakles, son of Petheus, grandson of Onnophris, mother Taseus, drachmas 4 copper drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 44 obols 12.;(Pachon) 11 likewise:;Kastor, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Phaesis, mother Tapasion, drachmas 20;;Petheus, son of Hatres (Deios, son of Panpis);;(in left margin: drachmas 8 obols 2) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 3 obols 2.5, tax on the produce of olives obols 3, naubion obols 2, surcharges obols 5 chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 2 obol 1.5 chalki 2, surcharges obol 1 chalki 2, kollybos obl 0.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 7 obols 4.5;;Onnophris, son of Petheus  (Chairemon, son of Pateis);;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 10 obols 5, tax on the produce of olives drachma 1 obols 3.5, naubion drachma 1 obol 0.5, surcharge drachmas 2 obols 4.5;;(in left margin: drachmas 52 obols 16) eparourion drachmas 7 obol 1.5, surcharges obols 4, kollybos obols 2.5, in total drachmas 24 obols 3.5;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 27 obol 0.5, surcharges drachma 1 obols 4 chalki 2, in total drachmas 28 obols 4.5 chalki 2;;Komon, son of Onnophris, grandson of Satabous, mother Ptolema, drachmas 32;;Pasion his brother with the same mother , drachmas 32;;Heron, son of Achillas, grandson of Onnophris, mother Didymarion, drachmas 8;;Horos, son of Onnopris  (Psas);;(in left margin: drachmas 12 obols 8) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 2 obols 2 chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives obols 2.5 chalki 2, naubion obol 1.5, surcharges obols 3.5 chalki 2;;eparourion drachma 1 obols 4, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 5 obols 4;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 5 obols 5 chalki 2, surcharges obols 2 chalki 2, in total drachmas 6 obol 1.5;;naubion of the katoikoi for the 13th year chalki 2, surcharges chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, obols 0.5 chalki 2;;in total for the day drachmas 164 obols 26;;(Pachon) 12 likewise:;Gaius Julius Saturnilus through the agency of Sarapion  (Neilos, physician);;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 30 obol 1.5 chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives drachmas 5 obol 1.5 chalki 2, naubion drachmas 5 obol 0.5, surcharges drachmas 7 obols 4.5;;eparourion drachmas 23 obols 3, surcharges drachma 1 obols 5.5 chalki 2, kollybos drachma 1 obol 1 chalki 2;;(in left margin: drachmas 100) naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year drachma 1 obol 1.5, surcharges obol 0.5 chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachma 1 obols 2.5;;on land plots in release likewise obols 3.5, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total obols 5.5;;grammateia obols 2, surcharges chalki 2, in total obols obols 2 chalki 2;;Sopatra, daughter of Maron;;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 10, tax on the produce of olives drachma 1 obols 2.5, naubion drachma 1, surcharges drachmas 2 obols 3;;eparourion drachmas 6 obols 4, surcharges obols 3.5, kollybos obols 2 chalki 2, in total drachmas 22 obols 3 chalki 2."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3824&amp;viewid=4171_60R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/6/0/r/4171_60r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3824&amp;viewid=4171_60R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3824&amp;viewid=4171_60R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
