<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Mandates</title>
            <author>Hermas (?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2206</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2206</idno>
            <idno type="dclp">59984</idno>
            <idno type="TM">59984</idno>
            <idno type="dclp-hybrid">p.mich;2.2;130</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 44</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Mandates of Hermas II,6 - III,1 (l.1); III,2.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Under inv. no 44 there are two papyri, one inv. no 44 and the present one 44-H. The letter "H" was given at the time of edition but the purpose is not denoted</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Verso; Recto is unpublished</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 8.7 x 12.1 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The papyrus is of fairly good quality, originally well smoothed, at least on the recto side, thin, and of light color. The piece has been torn and badly crumpled, and the surface of the verso has been injured in several places.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">23 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: h;Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Irregular upright semicursive hand. Eta is of the h-shape, with a rather tall first stroke. The horizontal forms a sharp angle with the last stroke, which descends from it in a ponounced curve and then turns up towards the right. A similar curve is used in the last stroke of pi. Upsilon branches widely, and does not extend below the line; in one instance it is quite small and its stem curves up sharply to the right. Omicron is of medium size, with the breadth exceeding the height. Sigma is nearly closed, and the top is usually flat; in two places the flat top is prolonged to fill out unused space. In one case (l. 6) sigma is a narrow downward facing curve like an inverted U. A single sign, a short horizontal stroke, seems to serve several purposes. In l. 3 it does duty as an acute accent, in l. 4 as a smooth breathing or perhaps a grave accent, and in the other five places where it occurs it is the rough breathing. A similar vague use of a horizontal stroke is to be found in the Berlin cursive papyrus of Genesis. In l. 7 and 2 a point on the base line is apparently used to separate concrrent vowels. It might be regarded as a minor punctuation in the first instance, but in the second no pause is possible. The original height of the column is somewhat doubtful (c. 28 lines?) There is nothing to indicate the original length of the manuscript.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0175" notAfter="0199">(Third quarter of the) IInd century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Arsinoite Nome, province of Egypt (?)</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Arsinoite Nome, province of Egypt (?)</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>-</term>
               <term>Hermas,;d 2nd cent.-- Mandates.</term>
               <term>Christian literature, Early.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literature; Christian</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>So he who gives is innocent, for as he received from the Lord a service to perform, he has sincerely performed it, without distinguishing to hom to give or not to give.So this service, sincerely performed, becomes glorious in the sight of God. So he who renders it sincerely will live to God. So keep this command, as I have told you, so that your repentance and that of your family may be found sincere, and your heart clean and stainless. Mand. III. And again he said to me.;III,2. - - - ] For they received from him a spirit free from deceit. If they give this back a lying one, they have defiled the Lord's command and become defrauders of him.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Carlini A, Par. Pass. 208,1983, 29-37 Bonner C, HThR 20, 105-16, 1927, Pl I,II Bonner C, Shepherd of Hermas; PMich 130, 129-36, 1934</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2206&amp;viewid=44-H.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2206&amp;viewid=44-H.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2206&amp;viewid=44-H.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
