<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3706</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3706</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 29.3 x 32.3 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at left and right. Kollesis down the middle of the sheet. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-48</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 29 (ll. 1228-1276)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. Only a little free margin at the left. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Onnophris, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetsooukis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabous, son of Dioskoros, grandson of Satabous, mother Tahorion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 226)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Naaraus, grandson of Horion, mother Taorsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Agathopous, slave of Taseus alias Isarion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis, son of Panesneus, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron, son of Maron, grandson of Petoraipis, mother Herois (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Diodoros, fatherless, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchophis, son of Kanis, grandson of Anchophis, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonis, son of Ammonios, grandson of Ammonios, mother Tninis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 151)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Ptollis, grandson of Herakles, mother Thases (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 204)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Tanesneus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Sisois, grandson of Satabous, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Souchas, grandson of Heras, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apynchis, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 154)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon, son of Horos, grandson of Onnophris, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son, mother Stotoetis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Heras, grandson of Petheus, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Melanas, son of Pakysis, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tanebkenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Polyndikos, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Petsiris, mother Heros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion, son of Aphrodisios, grandson of Onnophris, mother Tapetaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Kames, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Abykis, son of Demas, grandson of Abykis, mother Taonnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 148)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Onnophris, grandson of Onnophris, mother Sopas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Charidemos, son of Petoraipis, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Euhemeros, son of Neilos, grandson of Euhemeros, mother Taeuhemeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Petheus, grandson of Teos, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabeinos, son of Apynchis, grandson of Sambas, mother Thatres (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Sambas, grandson of Sabeinos, mother Aphrodous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Petermouthis, grandson of Apynchis, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus, son of Tesenouphis, grandson of Harphaesis, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Longinos Archonian previously known as Herais, son of Theogidon (Neilos) (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 184)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Taorsenouphis, daughter of Papeis through Soeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 235)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) [29]:;Petheus, son of Onnophris, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetsooukis, drachmas 8;;Satabous, son of Dioskoros, grandson of Satabous, mother Tahorion, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Naaraus, grandson of Horion, mother Taorsenouphis, drachmas 4;;Agathopous, slave of Taseus alias Isarion, obols 28;;Pakysis, son of Panesneus, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Maron, son of Maron, grandson of Petoraipis, mother Herois, drachmas 8;;Diodoros, fatherless, mother Thaisas, obols 28;;Heron, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 4;;Anchophis, son of Kanis, grandson of Anchophis, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;Ammonis, son of Ammonios, grandson of Ammonios, mother Tninis, drachmas 8;;Petheus, son of Ptollis, grandson of Herakles, mother Thases, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Tanesneus, drachmas 4;;Petaus, son of Sisois, grandson of Satabous, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 8;;Heras, son of Souchas, grandson of Heras, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 8;;Apynchis, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 4;;Chairemon, son of Horos, grandson of Onnophris, mother Segathis, drachmas 4;;Horos, son, mother Stotoetis, drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 96, obols 27;;(Phamenoth) 17 likewise:;12th year Heras, son of Heras, grandson of Petheus, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 16 copper drachmas 16;;Melanas, son of Pakysis, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tanebkenis, drachmas 8;;Phaesis, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Polyndikos, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Onnophris, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Petsiris, mother Heros, drachmas 4;;Horion, son of Aphrodisios, grandson of Onnophris, mother Tapetaus, drachmas 4;;Sarapion, son of Kames, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8;;Abykis, son of Demas, grandson of Abykis, mother Taonnophris, drachmas 4;;Heras, son of Onnophris, grandson of Onnophris, mother Sopas, drachmas 4;;Charidemos, son of Petoraipis, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Euhemeros, son of Neilos, grandson of Euhemeros, mother Taeuhemeros, drachmas 4, obols 27;;in total for the day drachmas 76, obols 27;;(Phamenoth) 18 likewise:;Pnepheros, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tapetheus, obols 28;;Onnophris, son of Petheus, grandson of Teos, mother Segathis, drachmas 4;;Sabeinos, son of Apynchis, grandson of Sambas, mother Thatres, drachmas 12;;Ptolemaios, son of Sambas, grandson of Sabeinos, mother Aphrodous, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Petermouthis, grandson of Apynchis, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4 obols 28;;in total for the day drachmas 28, obols 27;;(Phamenoth) 19 likewise:;Phanomgeus, son of Tesenouphis, grandson of Harphaesis, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Longinos Archonian previously known as Herais, son of Theogidon (Neilos);orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 6, 2 1/2 obols, oil-production drachmas 1, naubion obols5;;added charges drachma 1, obols 3 1/2 and 2 khalkoi, eparourion drachmas 4, 2 obols, added charges obols 2 khalkoi 2, kollybos1 1/2 obol, in total drachmas 16, 5 obols;;geometria for year 12 drachmas 16, 2 khalkoi, added charges drachma 1, 2 khalkoi, in total drachmas 17, 1/2 obol;;Taorsenouphis, daughter of Papeis through Soeros;;orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 2, 3 obols, tax on olive produce 2 obols 2 chalki, naubion 1 1/2 obol, added charges 3 1/2 obols 2 chalki;;eparourion drachma 1, 4 obols added charges 1 obol kollybos 1/2 obol 2 chalki, in total drachmas 5, 4 obols 2 chalki;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 6, 1 1/2 obol added charges 2 1/2 obols, in total drachmas 6, 4 obols;;[naubion of katoikoi for 13th year 4 obols added charges 1/2 obol, kollybos 2 chalki]."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 -- CPJ 3, 492 (lines with Sambathion) Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3706&amp;viewid=4171_29R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/9/r/4171_29r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3706&amp;viewid=4171_29R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3706&amp;viewid=4171_29R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
