<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Census declaration by house owners</title>
            <author>Philippiatote; Ploution; Isidora</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1245</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1245</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.20.14303</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;20;14303</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;20;14303</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14858</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14858</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Corn. Inv. II 16</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Official copies of census returns of several house owners for the house to house census taken every 14 years. these were part of a roll which had at least four columns, presumably more.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">In ed. princ. the ends of col. I and the beginning of col. IV are not transcribed and published. Edition of them in SB XX 14303</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 22 x 49.8 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The papyrus is well preserved only at the bottom. All the other sides are broken off. Some damage at the bottom margin does not effect the text itself. Many holes to the right bottom area.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">col. II, 23 lines; col. III, 25 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The hand is the same throughout. Many abbreviations and ligatures.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0117" notAfter="0147">117-118, 131-132, 146-147 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Arsinoiton polis, metropolis of the Arsinoite nome, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Eudymos, strategos of the Arsinoite nome, Herakleidou meris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hermaios, also called Dryton, royal secretary of the Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides and Eubulos, secretaries of the metropolis of the Arsinoite nome</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herodes, amphodarch of the quarter of the Hiera Pyle ("Sacred Gate"), of the metropolis of the Arsinoite nome</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron laographos of the quarter of the Hiera Pyle ("Sacred Gate"), of the metropolis of the Arsinoite nome</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Philippiaine, daughter of Zoilos, granddaughter of Apollonios, wife of Ploution</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ploution, son of Komon, catoecus of the 6475, husband of Philippiaine</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Komon, father of Ploution</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Zoilos, father of Philippiaine, son of Apollonios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonios, father of Zoilos, grandfather of Philippiaine</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hadrianus Caesar, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Zois, daughter of Herakleides, granddaughter of Sokrates I, mother of Sokrates II</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides, father of Zois, son of Sokrates I</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sokrates I, father of Herakleides, grandfather of Zois</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sokrates II, son of Dioskoros and Zois, grandson of Herakleides, brother of Aphrodous I and II</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodous I, daughter of Dioskoros and Zois, granddaughter of Herakleides, sister of Aphrodous II and Sokrates II</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodous II, daughter of Dioskoros and Zois, granddaughter of Herakleides, sister of Aphrodous I and Sokrates II, wife of her brother Sokrates II</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dioskoros, son of Sokrates II and Aphrodous II, brother of Onesimos, Asklas, Zoidous, Herais</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onesimos, son of Sokrates II and Aphrodous II, brother of Dioskoros, Asklas, Zoidous, Herais</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Asklas, son of Sokrates II and Aphrodous II, brother of Onesimos, Dioskoros, Zoidous, Herais</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Zoidous, daughter of Sokrates II and Aphrodous II, sister of Onesimos, Dioskoros, Asklas, Herais</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herais, daughter of Sokrates II and Aphrodous II, brother of Onesimos, Dioskoros, Zoidous, Zoidous</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Isarous, sister of Sokrates I, who lives with Sokrates,, aunt of Sokrates II, Aphrodous I and II</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Protarchos, strategos of the Arsinoite nome, Herakleidou meris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hermaios, royal secretary of the Herakleidou meris of the Arsinoite nome</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron, secretatry of the metropolis of the Arsinoite nome</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didas, collector of Moeris amphodon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, amphodarch</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dios laographos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Antoninos also called Hermaios, appointed official</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ploution, son of Komon and Ptollarous, grandson of Heron and Apollonios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Komon, father of Ploution, husband of Ptollarous, son of Heron</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptollarous, also called Ptolema, daughter of Apollonios, wife of Komon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, father of Heron, grandfather of Ploution</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonios, father of Ptollarous</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maximos also called Nearchos, strategos of the Arsinoite nome, Herakleidou meris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides, royal secretatry of the Arsinoite nome, Herakleidou meris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinos, secretary of the metropolis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Antoninos, secretary of the metropolis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Isidora I, daughter of Heron third and Isidora II, granddaughter of Heron and Askepiades I, wife of Asklepiades II</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, father of Isidora I, husband of Isidora II, son of Heron</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, father of Heron third, grandfather of Isidora I</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Isidora II, daughter of Asklepiades I, wife of Heron third, mother of Isidora II</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Asklepiades II, son of Asklepiades III, husband of Isidora I</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Asklepiades III, father of Askepiades II</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Arsinoite nome;;Herakleidou meris;;Hiera Pyle, amphodon;;Moeris, amphodon;;Apollonios Parembole, amphodon;;Apollonios Hierakeios, amphodon</term>
               <term>Government publications--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Census--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Egypt -- ArsinoȽ (Fayyïum : Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Cities and towns--Officials and employees--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Census districts--Egypt.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>col. I [fragmentary];col. ii;To Eudymos, strategos of the Arsinoite nome, Herakleidou meris, and to Hermaios, also called Dryton, royal secretatry of the same division, and to Herakleidou and Eubulos, secretaries of the metropolis and to Herakleides, chief, and his fellow collectors of money-taxes of the metropolis, and to Herodes, amphodarch of the quarter of the Hiera Pyle ("Sacred Gate"), and to Maron laographos of the same quarter:;From Philippiaina, daughter of Zoilos, son of Apollonios, enrolled in the house census on another memorandum in the qurater Moeris with her legal representative, her husband Ploution son of Komon, catoecus of the 6475. I ownin the same quarter Moeris a fourth part of a fourth share of a house and two-thirds of a second (house) in which I declare the following persons for the house to house census of the past second year of Hadrian Caesar our lord in the quarter of the Hiera Pyle in which also they were returned in the house to house census of the seventh year of the divine Traianus. They are, including those in the second house, Zois, daughter of Herakleides, son of Sokrates, aged 53: her son Sokrates son of Dioskoros who has passed his examination, aged 32, without distinguishing mark; a daughter Aphrodous, aged 13; another daughter Aphrodous, married to her brother Sokrates mentioned above, aged 28; and the elderly paternal aunt of the foregoing who lives with Sokrates, Isarous, aged 70. Therefore I give in (the declaration) to the appointed strategos and to all the others. Year 3 of Hadrianus Caesar our Lord, Phamenoth 22.;To Protarchos, strategos of the Arsinoite nome, Herakleidou meris, Hermaios royal secretary of the same division, Maron secretatry of the metropolis, Didas collector of Moeris, Ptolemaios amphodarch, Dios laographos, and Antoninos also called Hermaios , appointed official, from Ploution son of Komon son of Heron, his mother being Ptollarous, also called Ptolema, daughter of Apollonios, catoecus of the 6475, enrolled in Moeris quarter.;col. iii;...on another memorandum:;There belongs to me in the quarter of Apollonios Parembole a ... share of a house in which I declare the following residents for the house census of the past 16th year of Hadrianus Caesar our lord, in the quarter of ...;Sokrates son of Dioskoros, of the selected class, aged 46, without distinguishing mark, and his ... wife who is registered as his wife and sister born of the same mother, Aphrodous, aged 42, both registered for the 2nd year in the Hiera Pyle; and their children, Dioskroros enrolled in the birth register, aged 12; and Onesimos enrolled in the birth register, aged 10; and Asklas, enrolled in the birth register, aged 8; and a daughter Zoidous, aged 6; and Herais, aged 2. therefore I hand in the memorandum to the srategos appointed and to all the other officials. Year 17 of Hadrianus Caesar our lord, Epeiph 28.;To Maximos also called Nearchos, strategos, Herakleides, royal secretatry of the Arsinoite nome, Herakleides meris, and Sabinos and Antoninos, secretaries of the metropolis:;From Isidora daughter of Heron third, son of Heron, her mother being Isidora daughter of Asklepiades, declared and registered through another memorandum in the quarter of Apollonios Hierakeios with her legal quardian, Asklepiades, son of Asklepiades. There belongs to me in the quarter Moeris a fourth share of a house and courtyard in which I hereby declare as residents for the house to house census of the past 9th year of Antoninus Caesar our lord (in the quarter) in which also they were enrolled in the census of the 16th year of Hadrianus ... ;col. IV;[fragmentary]</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Westermann WL - Kraemer CJ, PCorn, 16, 1926 Bagnall RS, BASP 28, 18-27, 1991 -- SB XX 14303 -- BL IX, 227; BL XI, 229 (l. 23)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:20:14303</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1245&amp;viewid=C2_16R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1245&amp;viewid=C2_16R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1245&amp;viewid=C2_16R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
