<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3324</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3324</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 28 is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 27-28: 37.7 x 29.6 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 28: nearly complete (papyrus cut off right of col. 28 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 28: 49 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 28 (l. 348-396)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron son of Ekysis and Herais grandson of Menandros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Pasoxis and Heras grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Anchophis and Teseuris grandson of Herakles (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nikephoros, doulos of Longinus Isidoros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasoxis son of Pasoxis and Taseus grandson of Panther (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 199)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Abykis son of Demas and Taonnophris grandson of Abykis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 148)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus son of Esouris and Tkollauthis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Euemeros son of Neilos and Taeuemeros grandson of Euemeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Neilos son of Euemeros and Sambous grandson of Neilos and Taeuemeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 190)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Castrensis, doulos of Thaisarion alias Nebsosis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herieus neoteros son of Horos and Thaesis grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apitas son of Kastor and Petronia grandson of Apitas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 152)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Polis son of Petheus and Herais grandson of Keras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinus son of Petheus and Herakleia grandson of Phanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herieus prebyteros son of Horos and Thaesis grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ninis son of Asklas and Tabous grandson of Ninis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Sambas and Aphrodous grandson of Sabinus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Anchorimphis and Achillis grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Orsenouphis and Anthia grandson of Herieus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Petheus and Eserempis grandson of Aunes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion son of Lupus and Ammonarion grandson of Horion (Horos) (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Heras and Tasoucharion grandson of Ptolemaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Slaves--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 28;;(Phamenoth 14, continued);Heron, son of Ekysis and Herais, grandson of Menandros: 8 drachmai;    column 51;Ptolemaios, son of Pasoxis and Heras, grandson of Satabous: 4 drachmai;    column 54;Horos, son of Anchophis and Teseuris, grandson of Herakles: 4 drachmai;    column 55;Nikephoros, slave of Longinus Isidoros: 4 drachmai 28 obols;    column 57;Pasoxis, son of Pasoxis and Taseus, grandson of Panther: 4 drachmai 28 obols;    column 53;Abykis, son of Demas and Taonnophris, grandson of Abykis: 8 drachmai;    column 65;Petaus, son of Esouris and Tkollauthis, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai;    column 71;Euemeros, son of Neilos and Taeuemeros, grandson of Euemeros: 12 drachmai 10 obols;    column 75;Neilos, his son, (born) of Sambous: 8 drachmai;    column 75;Total for the day: 112 drachmai 7 obols.;;On the 15th, similarly:;Castrensis, slave of Thaisarion also called Nebsosis: 8 drachmai;    column 76;Herieus the younger, son of Horos and Thaesis, grandson of Pnepheros: 4 drachmai;    column 80;Apitas, son of Kastor and Petronia, grandson of Apitas: 4 drachmai;    column 88;Polis, son of Petheus and Herais, grandson of Keras: 8 drachmai;    column 85;Sabinus, son of Petheus and Herakleia, grandson of Phanomgeus: 4 drachmai;    column 20;Herieus the elder, son of Horos and Thaesis, grandson of Pnepheros: 4 drachmai;    column 87;Ninis, son of Asklas and Tabous, grandson of Ninis: 4 drachmai;    column 88;Ptolemaios, son of Sambas and Aphrodous, grandson of Sabinus: 8 drachmai;    column 95;Horos, son of Anchorimphis and Achillis, grandson of Horos: 4 drachmai;    column 98;Ptolemaios, son of Orsenouphis and Anthia, grandson of Herieus: 4 drachmai;    column 99;Polydeukes, son of Heras and Tapasion, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai;    column 100;Horos, son of Petheus and Eserempis, grandson of Aunes: 8 drachmai;    column 104;Horion, son of Lupus and Ammonarion, grandson of Horion: 20 drachmai;    column 91;Ptolemaios, son of Heras and Tasoucharion, grandson of Ptolemaios: 8 drachmai;    column 96;Total for the day: 92 drachmai</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 28 (l. 347-396), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3324&amp;viewid=4172R4.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/R/4/4172R4.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3324&amp;viewid=4172R4.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3324&amp;viewid=4172R4.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
