<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3305</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3305</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12000</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12000</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;225</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 17 is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 17-18: 34.8 x 30 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 17 nearly complete (papyrus cut to the left of col. 17 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 17: 59 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 17 (l. 116-174)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas son of Sokmenis and Tkollainis grandson of Sambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 224)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herieus neoteros son of Horos and Thaesis grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Pnepheros and Tapetheus grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymos son of Satabous and Tanomgeus grandson of Pakysis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ninis son of Asklas and Tabous grandson of Ninis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ouetis (Vettius) son of Petheus and Taseus grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 195)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dioskoros son of Aiaus and Thases grandson of Orsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion son of Petheus and Zoidous grandson of Kames (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabous son of Petheus and Tapetaus grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 226)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios son of Petheus and Taseus grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron son of Pekmeis alias Heuremon and Taseus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Phanomgeus and Tapsais grandson of Phanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petoraipis (Petsoraipis) son of Hatres and Soeris grandson of Imouthes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Petaus and Thaesis grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Sokmenis and Thaesis grandson of Sokmenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 204)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis son of Heron and Zoidous grandson of Orsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 193)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonis (Ammonios) son of Ammonios and Tninis grandson of Ammonios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 151)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron son of Petheus and Taorsenouphis grandson of Kollouthos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles son of Sokrates and Tapetheus grandson of Phasis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles son of Petaus and Segathis grandson of Orsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus alias Karanos, son of Sokmenis and Tasokmenis grandson of Sokmenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 204)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Herakles and Didyme grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus son of Petheus and Tapasion grandson of Petaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Komon son of Pnepheros and Tkollathis (Tkollauthis) grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 183)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Teos son of Petheus and Taonnophris grandson of Teos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 242)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasoknopais son of Phaseis and Tanomgeus grandson of Esouris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 199)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 17;;(Mecheir 15, continued);Sambas, son of Sokmenis and Tkollainis, grandson of Sambas: 4 drachmai;    column 69;Herieus the younger, son of Horos and Thaesis, grandson of Pnepheros: 8 drachmai;    column 80;Pnepheros, son of Pnepheros and Tapetheus, grandson of Pnepheros: 8 drachmai;    column 82;Didymos, son of Satabous and Tanomgeus, grandson of Pakysis: 4 drachmai 28 obols;    column 84;Ninis, son of Asklas and Tabous, grandson of Ninis: 4 drachmai;    column 88;Ouetis, son of Petheus and Taseus, grandson of Pnepheros: 16 drachmai;    column 88;Dioskoros, son of Aiaus and Thases, grandson of Orsenouphis: 8 drachmai;    column 95;Pasion, son of Petheus and Zoidous, grandson of Kames: 24 drachmai 28 obols;    column 51;Total for the day: 288 drachmai 24 obols;;On the 16th, similarly:;Satabous, son of Petheus and Tapetaus, grandson of Satabous: 4 drachmai;    column 1;Horos the younger, son of Hatres and Teraus, grandson of Horos: 4 drachmai;    column 2;Aphrodisios, son of Petheus and Taseus, grandson of Pnepheros: 8 drachmai;    column 3;Heron, son of Pekmeis also called Heuremon and Taseus: 12 drachmai 28 obols;    column 6;Ptolemaios, son of Phanomgeus and Tapsais, grandson of Phanomgeus: 16 drachmai;    column 8;Petoraipis, son of Hatres and Soeris, grandson of Imouthes: 4 drachmai;    column 9;Pnepheros, son of Petaus and Thaesis, grandson of Pnepheros: 12 drachmai 28 obols;    column 11;Petheus, son of Sokmenis and Thaesis, grandson of Sokmenis: 8 drachmai;    column 17;Orsenouphis, son of Heron and Zoidous, grandson of Orsenouphis: 8 drachmai;    column 23;Ammonis, son of Ammonios and Tninis, grandson of Ammonios: 8 drachmai;    column 26;Heron, son of Petheus and Taorsenouphis, grandson of Kollouthos: 4 drachmai;    column 27;Herakles, son of Sokrates and Tapetheus, grandson of Phasis: 8 drachmai;    column 29;Herakles, son of Petaus and Segathis, grandson of Orsenouphis: 8 drachmai;    column 31;Petheus also called Karanos, son of Sokmenis and Tasokmenis, grandson of Sokmenis: 8 drachmai;    column 32;Petheus, son of Herakles and Didyme, grandson of Petheus: 12 drachmai;    column 45;Total for the day: 128 drachmai 26 obols;;On the 17th, similarly:;Petaus, son of Petheus and Tapasion, grandson of Petaus: 12 drachmai 27 obols;    column 34;Komon, son of Pnepheros and Tkollathis, grandson of Satabous: 12 drachmai 26 obols;    column 37;Teos, son of Petheus and Taonnophris, grandson of Teos: 4 drachmai 19 obols;    column 39;Pasoknopais, son of Phasis and Tanomgeus, grandson of Esouris: 4 drachmai;    column 42</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 17 (l. 116-174), 1936 -- L. 147: read 28 obols, instead of 27 obols. (PH)</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3305&amp;viewid=4172R2.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/R/2/4172R2.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3305&amp;viewid=4172R2.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3305&amp;viewid=4172R2.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
