<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Property Settlement after Marriage</title>
            <author>Haryotes, son of Lysimachos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1354</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1354</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.340</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;340</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;340</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12149 12150</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12149 12150</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1271</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Rough drafts of two contracts, prepared at the grapheion according to the wishes of the parties; the ages and signalments of the various parties are left blank, and the subscriptions are in the hand of a clerk. The first contract (recto, col. I-II) is an acknowledgment by Haryotes that he has received from father-in-law Didymos a gift (prosdosis and prosphora) 20 drachmai and 5 arourai of a catoecic allotment, in addition to the dowry given to him four years earlier, presumably at the time of the marriage with Didymos's daughter, Herakleia; in case of divorce Haryotes agrees to restore to Didymos or to Herakleia both the dowry and the additional gift.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto, col. I-II; see also Recto, col. III, and Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 40 x 28 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">broken off on the left side</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto, col. I - 44;;col. II - 35</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: First text (recto, col. I-II)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Recto: medium-sized cursive, resembling that of P.Mich. V, 244 and almost certainly penned by the writer of P.Mich. V, 226; Verso: a sloping cursive different from the hand on the recto (Boak)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0045" notAfter="0046">45-46 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Rhodous daughter of Herakleides, wife of Didymos (see PMich. V, p. 332)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Claudius, Emperor</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Ibion Eikosipentarouron, Polemonos meris; Aigyptios; Hellenikos; Perses</term>
               <term>Dowry--Egypt--Tebtynis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Ethnicity</term>
               <term>Ibion Eikosipentarouron</term>
               <term>Land Ownership</term>
               <term>Marriage</term>
               <term>Iranians--Egypt</term>
               <term>Slave</term>
               <term>Woman (&amp;amp</term>
               <term>guardian)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Haryotes, son of Lysimachos, about       years old, with a scar                                , acknowledges to the father of his wife Herakleia, who has been and is still living with him, Didymos, son of Maron, about       years old, with a scar                                , the aforesaid Herakleia, about       years old, with a scar                                , together with her aforesaid father Didymos as guardian, being present and approving all the conditions set forth through this contract, that he has received from him [[as a gift in accordance with this...]] in accordance with this contract as an addition to the dowry 'for the benefit of the aforesaid Herakleia' twenty drachmai in silver, from hand to hand, out of the house, and as a gift without evaluation the five arourai, more or less [[according to the existing...]], of a catoecic allotment belnging to Didymos near Ibion Eikosipentarouron in the division of Polemon, of which the adjacent properties have beens et forth in the contracts concerning them, and which formerly belonged to the aforesaid Haryotes, apart from the dowry in gold and silver which the same Didymos, with his wife Rhodous, daughter of Herakleides and mother of Herakleia, has given him for the benefit of the same Herakleia and apart from a supplementary gift of allotments and slaves belonging to him according to two other contracts [[one being an Egyptian alimentary...]] completed through the same grapheion in the 3rd year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Germanicus Imperator in such and such a month, of which one is an Egyptian alimentary contract, while the other is Greek. [[and the gift of the aforesaid allotment has been made from the harvests of the present 6th year]] And these shall remain valid together with all the provisions therein prescribed, and the gift of the aforesaid allotment has been made from the harvests of the present 6th year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Germanicus Imperator, [[all public charges for the allotment being on [[Haryotes]] Didymos from past timesup to the 5th year and for the 5th year also]].;Accordingly let Haryotes and Herakleia live together with one another just as formerly, 'in contentment', 'as there has been born to them a female child whose name                  '; but if trouble should develop between them and they should separate from one another, either Haryotes divorcing Herakleia or Herakleia leaving of her own accord, let the allotment of five arourai given as aforesaid become at once the property of Didymos, but if he should not survive, of his daughter Herakleia; and let Haryotes give back to Didymos, but if he should not survive, to the same Herakleia the dowry specified in former contracts and other gifs and parapherna and also the twenty drachmai also specified in this deed of gift, immediately in case of divorce, but in case of voluntary separation within sixty days after they have been demanded. And if he shall not restore them as has been written, he shall repay them immediately and half as much again; the right of execution resting with Didymos or, if he should not survive, with his daughter Herakleia against the party of the first part, Haryotes, [[and against...]] just as against a Persian of the epigone, and against all his possessions as if in accordance with a judgment.;Subscription of Haryotes:;I, Haryotes, son of Haryotes (sic), acknowledge that I have received as a supplementary gift the twenty drachmai in silver and as a grant the aforesaid allotment, and I concur as aforesaid.;Subscription of Didymos:;I, Didymos, son of Maron, [[have given]] with the consent of my daughter Herakleia acting under my guardianship, have given a supplementary gift of twenty silver drachmai to Haryotes for the sake of Herakleia, and as a grant the aforesaid allotment of the five arourai, and we concur as aforesaid. I, Didymos, have written for my daughter also as she is illiterate.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Edgerton WF-Husselman EM, PMich V, 340, recto, col. I-II, 1944</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:340</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1354&amp;viewid=1271R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/7/1/R/1271R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1354&amp;viewid=1271R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1354&amp;viewid=1271R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
