<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A treatise on rhetoric and style</title>
            <author>Unknwon</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3954</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3954</idno>
            <idno type="dclp">66741</idno>
            <idno type="TM">66741</idno>
            <idno type="dclp-hybrid">p.bingen;;9</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich. inv. 3800</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>One column of a text discussing features of style and composition followed by the left edge of another column. The fragmentary Greek of col. I, 2-4 includes mention of rhythm. Col. I, 4-7 seems to discuss how "onoma &lt;to te&gt;tupemenon" (a problematic term) possesses forcefulness, conciseness, and meaning. In col. I, 7-9 a sequence which seems to begin as an explanatory relative clause referring to things that are "commonplace with respect to discourse", may have suffered some textual corruption. Col. I, 9-14, apparently a single sentence, discusses how "metaphor, in addition to being contrary to custom and to "sullogismos", in which "epilexeis" especially take delight, is...". Here the text once again becomes lacunose, but it seems that the discussion of metaphor now relates the figure in some manner, probably by way of contrast, to the "ordinary things". The fragmentary state of col. II obscures most of the sense for us there, but metaphor is probably mentioned in col. II, 2-3. That metaphor was dealt with quite extensively in this section of the treatise, with perhaps a direct continuation of the discussion from column I, is suggested as well by a probable Homeric quotation illustrating metaphorical usage in col. I, 8.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is described</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 11.5 x 7.7 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Medium-brown scrap, incomplete at both top and bottom.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. I, 15 lines; col. II, 12 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The verso of the papyrus was used for another, more informally written prose text of which there survive the right edge of one column and the final five lines of another -the latter followed by a blank area which should indicate that this is the final column. The subject matter of this verso text includes a possible discussion of geography or itinerary and a mention of prophets and, perhaps, orders of priests. Although not a deluxe quality, the hand and the overall execution of the recto text show considerable skill as well as concern for presenting a pleasing visual appearance. Lettrs are separately formed in a professional book hand into which cursive forms intrude only occasionally. The line filler in col. I, 7 is part of the writer's strategy for keeping the right edge of the column even, although he does not always attain this goal. There are no accents, breathings, or punctuation. the standard rules for syllabification at line end appear to have been broken in col. I, 14. Of three possible iota-adscripts, the scribe wrote one while executing the original text, but he or someone with similar to slightly lighter ink added the other two supralinearl. The changing of epsilon to omicron in col. II, 8 by means of a diagonal cancellation stroke and supralinear addition may be due to the same source, as is perhaps the marginal diagonal mark at col. II, 2.;Despite these outward signs of formal care lavished on the book, flaws are apparent even in the short strech of text preserved. In col. I, 5-6 the writer appears to have inverted the first two vowels of a participial phrase and to have spelled "deinon" as "denon". Moreover, although we can follow the topics being discussed in col. I in a general way, on at least one occasion the syntax is diificult to construe. thw writer or someone before him may have introduced confusion into what the format and surviving contents would lead us to assume to have been a formal treatise.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0100" notAfter="0199">IInd century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Oxyrhynchus (?), Middle Egypr, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>-</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Literary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Renner T, PBingen, 43-46, no 9, 2000, Pl. 5 (recto) -- Morelli, CE 77, 2002, 314, l. 4 "prosh" (already in app. c rit. and note ad loc.)</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3954&amp;viewid=3800R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/0/0/R/3800R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3954&amp;viewid=3800R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3954&amp;viewid=3800R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
