<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Official Letter</title>
            <author>Aurelius Ammonios alias Apollonios, strategos of the Oxyrhynchite nome</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1298</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1298</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.16.12994</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;16;12994</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;16;12994</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">16338</idno>
            <idno type="TM">16338</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1016</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Official letter sent on July 19, 241 A.D., by the strategos of the Oxyrhynchite nome to the keepers of the property registers of the same nome, notifying them that Aurelius Theon, son of Diogenes, has been granted exemption from liturgic service for being the father of five children; the letter is followed by a copy of the petition (l. 10-32) addressed by Aurelius Theon to the strategos, which itself includes copy of an earlier petition (with the same object) by Aurelius Theon to the prefect (l. 14-24) and of the agreement given by the said prefect in May 239 A.D. (l. 25-26). The last line (l. 33) probably certified that the privilege was duly recorded in the property registers on July 20, 241 A.D.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>2 papyri ; 28 x 23.8 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Broken off at the top and on the left side; a few holes on the left upper portion and on the lower right hand part</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">33</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The writing is characteriwed by firm strokes (McCarren)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0019" notAfter="0241">July 19 A.D. 20, 241 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Oxyrhynchus, Oxyrhynchite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Ammonios alias Apollonios, strategos of the Oxyrhynchite nome</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Theon son of Diogenes and Soeris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Lucretius Annianus, prefect of Egypt</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gordianus, Emperor (&amp; consul)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Chairemon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(M. Acilius) Aviola, consul</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) [komogrammateus] of Mermertha</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) bibliophylakes enkteseon of the Oxyrhynchite nome</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pausanias son of Aurelius Theon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonios son of Aurelius Theon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aneiketos (Aniketos) son of Aurelius Theon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Agathos Daimon son of Aurelius Theon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Herakles son of Heraklammon</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>probably Oxyrhynchus, Oxyrhynchite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Oxyrhynchon polis (Oxyrhynchus), Oxyrhynchite nome; Mermertha</term>
               <term>Tax exemption--Egypt--Bahnasïa.</term>
               <term>Service, Compulsory non-military--Egypt--Bahnasïa.</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Bahnasïa.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Traces of 4 lines);;[Aurelius Ammonios], also known as Apollonios, [strategos of the Oxyrhynchite, to the keepers of the property registers], greetings: [. . .] I send to you, my dear friends, [the copy of the petition which Aurelius Theon submitted to me] enclosing another (petition), addressed by him to Lucretius Annianus, the ex-prefect, [along with the copy of the] subscription, for your information. I pray that you may be in good health, my dear friends. [In the 4th year] of the Imperator Caesar Marcus Antonius Gordian Pius Felix Augustus, Epeiph 25.;    [To Aurelius] Ammonios also known as Apollonios, strategos of the Oxyrhynchite, [from Aurelius] Theon, son of Diogenes, his mother being Soeris, from the city of Oxyrhynchus. The following is a copy of the petition which I submitted to the most eminent ex-prefect, Lucretius Annianus, [extracts] of the imperial ordinances having been inserted therein, and of the decision which I received from him:;        To [Lucretius] Annianus, most illustrious prefect, from Aurelius Theon, son of Diogenes, his mother being Soeris, from the city [of Oxyrhynchus]. The imperial ordinances are clear, most illustrious prefect, and plainly [it is ordained] that one who has become father of five children, be released from the burden of liturgical offices, as he himself undertakes such a [burdening] public service as raising so many [children] with his care and expenses. I myself, although being of small means as to my resources, have not shrunk from the rearing of [my children] who now also have become known through public documents. I ask that the orders issued by the [imperial edicts] be safeguarded also for me. Therefore, I present the petitions in order that, my lord, in accordance with [your - - -] reverence for the laws you, by (your) subscription, direct the strategos of the nome, [- - -] lawlessness, that is, that I may not be burdened by any [liturgy] in accordance with the orders issued in the case of many others, so that I may be relieved. Farewell. I, [Aurelius Theon, sent] (the petition) for submission. I, Aurelius Chairemon, wrote for him since he is illiterate.;        [The - - - day before] the Kalends of June, in the consulship of our lord Gordian Augustus and Aviola. [The strategos] will see to it that everything is done in accordance with the orders issued regarding such matters.  volume [ ], sheet 265(?).;    [This completes the petition] and the subscription. I have thus appended the names of my children, which also appear in the [registers of the public] records, and I request that you send (copy of this) to the [village secretary] of Mermertha where I have performed my public duties, [in order that he may know] I am not under the obligation of public duties, but also to the keepers of the property registers, (so that) they [make] the appropriate registration. The list is: Pausanias, Apollonios, Aniketos, Agathos Daimon, [- - -. Year . .] of the Imperator Caesar Marcus Antonius Gordian Pius Felix Augustus, [- - -. I, Aurelius Theon, have submitted (this petition)]. I, Aurelius Herakles, son of Heraklammon, wrote for him since he is illiterate.;[I, Aurelius - - -, assistant, have conveyed it.] Year 4, Epeiph 26.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - McCarren VP-Hagedorn D;   Rep Ser. - ZPE 49;   1982;   pg. 76-78 -- BL X, 217 (l. 26); J.D. Thomas, ZPE 160 (2007), 205-210 (l. 26) -- SB XVI 12994 McCarren VP, Diss, 2, 1975 McCarren VP, PMich XIV, 675, 1, Pl. I-V -- BL IX, 295 (bibliography)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB:16:12994</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1298&amp;viewid=1016R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/1/6/R/1016R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1298&amp;viewid=1016R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1298&amp;viewid=1016R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
