<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3697</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3697</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 25.7 x 32.8 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at left and right. Kollesis near the left edge. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-44</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 24 (ll. 998-1042)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Sambas, grandson of Sabeinos, mother Aphrodous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Herieus, mother Anthia (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor alias Sabeinos, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Satabous, mother Melitous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 182)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes, son of Naaraus, grandson of Petheus, mother Taorsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis, son of Kastor, grandson of Pakysis, mother Teseuris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 195)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios, son of Onnophris, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Ptolema (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 157)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Pekmeis alias Heuremon, mother Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Tapsais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabeinos, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Horos, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Stiynchis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, his brother, with the same mother (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis, son of Heras, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Isidora (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, slave of Syros alias Ptolemaios, son of Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Demas, son of Satabous, grandson of Horos, mother Theonis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 160)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Aphrodisios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Didymarion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nikephoros, slave of Longinus Isidoros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpagathes, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Harpagathes, mother Tasiaipis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Satabous, mother Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Esouris, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptollas, son of Satabous, grandson of Ptollas, mother Tapontos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 221)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraklas, fatherless, mother Taonnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron alias Heraklas, son of Karanos, grandson of Heraklas, mother Artemis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion, son of Sambas, grandson of Phaesis, mother Aphrodite (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Doras, grandson of Apollonios, mother Tauris, (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petheus, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kephalon, son of Isidoros, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 183)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menches, son of Satabous, grandson of Maron, mother Tkonnos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Achillas, son of Ptollis, grandson of Hieranouphis, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Theon, son of Theon, grandson of Petheus, mother Zoidous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 177)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psenesis, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Komonis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 24:;Ptolemaios, son of Sambas, grandson of Sabeinos, mother Aphrodous, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Herieus, mother Anthia, drachmas 4;;Kastor alias Sabeinos, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Satabous, mother Melitous, drachmas 4;;Mysthes, son of Naaraus, grandson of Petheus, mother Taorsenouphis, drachmas 4;;Pakysis, son of Kastor, grandson of Pakysis, mother Teseuris, drachmas 16;;in total for the day drachmas 64;;(Mecheir) 27 likewise:;Aphrodisios, son of Onnophris, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Ptolema, drachmas 24;;Heron, son of Pekmeis alias Heuremon, mother Sambathion, drachmas 4;;Phanomgeus, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Tapsais, obols 28;;Sabeinos, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Horos, mother Tapetheus, obols 28;;Petaus, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8;;Petesouchos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Stiynchis, drachmas 8;;Petaus, his brother, with the same mother, drachmas 12;;Phaesis, son of Heras, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Isidora, drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 68, obols 27;;(Mecheir) 28 likewise:;Sarapion, slave of Syros alias Ptolemaios, son of Thaisas, drachmas 20, obols 28;;Onnophris, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Aphrodisios, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetesouchos, obols 28;;Demas, son of Satabous, grandson of Horos, mother Theonis, drachmas 12;;Pnepheros, son of Aphrodisios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Didymarion, drachmas 4;;Nikephoros, slave of Longinus Isidoros, drachmas 12;;for the12th year Harpagathes, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Harpagathes, mother Tasiaipis, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Satabous, mother Heras, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Esouris, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 68, obols 27 of which for the 12th year drachmas 4;;(Mecheir) 29 likewise:;Ptollas, son of Satabous, grandson of Ptollas, mother Tapontos, drachmas 4, obols 28;;Heraklas, fatherless, mother Taonnophris, drachmas 8;;Heron alias Heraklas, son of Karanos, grandson of Heraklas, mother Artemis, drachmas 24;;Pasion, son of Sambas, grandson of Phaesis, mother Aphrodite, drachmas 12, obols 8;;for the 12th year the same, ? copper drachmas ;;Ptolemaios, son of Doras, grandson of Apollonios, mother Tauris , drachmas 8, obols 28;;in total for the day drachmas 64, obols 27 of which for the 12th year obols 20;;(Mecheir) 30 likewise:;Pasion, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petheus, mother Segathis, drachmas 4;;Kephalon, son of Isidoros, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 16;;Menches, son of Satabous, grandson of Maron, mother Tkonnos, drachmas 4;;Achillas, son of Ptollis, grandson of Hieranouphis, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;Theon, son of Theon, grandson of Petheus, mother Zoidous, drachmas 4;;Psenesis, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Komonis, drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 36;;Phamenoth."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 -- CPJ 3, 492 (lines with Sambathion) Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3697&amp;viewid=4171_21R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3697&amp;viewid=4171_21R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3697&amp;viewid=4171_21R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
