<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of Part of a House</title>
            <author>Didymos &amp; his 4 brothers, sons of Herakleides (the younger)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1360</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1360</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.276</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;276</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;276</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12114</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12114</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1275</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract by which five sons of Herakleides (the younger) sell to Tamaron, daughter of Herakleides, a seventh share of half of a house, which share was first inherited by a sixth brother, Lysimachos, who had died childless</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 28.3 x 29.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">slightly damaged along some folds</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">41</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>4th hand: unskilled hand of a slow-writer</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0047">August 28, 47 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Tamaron daughter of Herakleides (see P.Mich. V, p. 332)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Asklas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor son of Lysimachos (&amp; unnamed brothers) (see also P.Mich. V, 232?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Claudius, Emperor</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Euergetis (Arsinoiton polis), Arsinoite nome; Tameion (amphodon) kaine legomene</term>
               <term>Family--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Home ownership--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Inheritance and succession--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Deeds--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Sales--Egypt.</term>
               <term>ArsinoȽ (Fayyïum : Extinct city)--Surveys.</term>
               <term>Women--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Notaries--Egypt.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>We, Didymos and Herodes and Herakleides and Maron and Herakleides, also called Louris, all five sons of Herakleides, acknowledge that we have sold to Tamaron, daughter of Herakleides, from the present day, forever, the seventh share of the half of a house and yard and all the appurtenances, held in common and undivided by us and by Didymos, the brother of our dead father Herakleides, in the metropolis, Euergetis, of the Arsinoite nome, near the Treasuries quarter, that is called New, the share sold being that which belonged to Lysimachos, our brother by the same father and mother, who died childless and intestate. The neighbors of the whole house and yard are on the south the so-called old house and yard of Didymos, son of Maron, on the north the royal road, on the west the house of Asklas, on the east the house of Kastor, son of Lysimachos, and his brothers. And we have received from Tamaron the whole price agreed upon, in full, at once, from hand to hand, out of the house, and we guarantee the sale on mutual security wit every guarantee from both public and private liabilities and from every claim forever. We shall also present ourselves, recording for you, Tamaron, the sale of the aforesaid seventh part of the aforesaid house and yard of the aforesaid Lysimachos, through a six-witness document of the record-office in the metropolis, whenever you order it, no one receiving anything at all on account of our having received the price from you previously as aforesaid. If we do not do this, or if we do not abide by these conditions, we will pay you the price which we received from you, increased by one half and with the interest, and a fine of one thousand drachmai, and the same amount to the treasury; Tamaron, nevertheless, incurring no loss in the matter of the guarantee devolving upon us for the things we sold her before according to the contracts which we made with her. This chirograph shall be valid wherever produced and for everyone who produces it. The seventh year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, the fifth intercalary day of the month Kaisareios.;(2nd hand) I, Herodes, son of Herakleides, acknowledge that I have joined in selling the aforesaid seventh share of the aforesaid house and courtyard in the metropolis, and in receiving the price and guaranteeing the sale with every guarantee. And also I shall submit myself whenever you order it, confirming the sale through the &lt;record office&gt; in the metropolis without any subterfuge or evasion. If I do not do it, I shall join in paying the aforesaid fine, Tamaron suffering no loss with respect to the other guarantee incumbent upon me and the aforesaid for what we have previously sold. This chirograph shall be valid wherever produced and for everyone who produces it. The seventh year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, the fifth intercalary day of the month Kaisareios.;(3rd hand) I, Herakleides, son of Herakleides, acknowledge that I have joined in selling the aforesaid seventh share of the half share of the aforesaid house and courtyard in the metropolis, and in receiving the price and guaranteeing the sale with every guarantee. And also I will submit myself, whenever you order it, recording the sale for you, together with the aforesaid persons, through whatever archives in the metropolis you wish, and receiving nothing at all, and I will submit my wife, Arsinoe, daughter of Didymos, to give her consent, also receiving nothing at all. If I do not do this, I will pay the aforesaid fine. This chirograph shall be valid everywhere produced and for anyone producing it, Tamaron receiving no loss with respect to the guarantee devolving upon me for what we sold her previously in accordance with the contract we made with her. The seventh year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, the fifth intercalary day of the month Kaisareios.;(4th hand) I, Maron, son of Herakleides, acknowledge that I have joined in selling the aforesaid seventh share of the half share of the aforesaid house and court in the metropolis, and in receiving the price and guaranteeing the sale with every guarantee. And in addition I will submit myself whenever you shall order me, recording the sale for you, together with the aforesaid persons, through whatever archives in the metropolis you wish, receiving nothing at all, and I will submit my wife, Arsinoe, daughter of Didymos (sic), to give her consent, likewise receiving nothing at all. If I do not do this, I will pay the aforesaid fine. This chirograph shall be valid everywhere produced and for anyone producing it, Tamaron receiving no loss with respect to the guarantee devolving upon me for what we sold her previously in accordance with the contract we made with her. The seventh year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, the fifth intercalary day of the month Kaisareios.;(5th hand) I, Herakleides, also called Louris, son of Herakleides, acknowledge that I have joined in selling the aforesaid seventh share of the half share of the aforesaid house and court in the metropolis, and in receiving the price and guaranteeing the sale with every guarantee. And I will also submit myself, whenever you order it, recording the sale together with the aforesaid persons, through whatever archives in the metropolis you wish, receiving nothing at all as aforesaid.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 276, 1944 -- L. 11: read tei touton (for ti touton), instead of pe&amp;lt;r&amp;gt;i touton. (PH)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:276</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1360&amp;viewid=1275R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/7/5/R/1275R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1360&amp;viewid=1275R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1360&amp;viewid=1275R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
