<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Cession of Catoecic Land</title>
            <author>Mysthas, son of Akousilaos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1351</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1351</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.273</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12109</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12109</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;273dupl</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1268</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Subscriptions to a contract by which Mysthas, son of Akousilaos, cedes to Maximus, son of Diodoros also called Papontos, a catoecic allotment of six arourai, with one quarter of an aroura of the impost of the village (epibole komes)</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Duplicate of P.S.I. VIII, 906. - Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 39.5 x 28.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Nearly complete</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1 + 12 + 1</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>2nd hand: slow-writer</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0046">May 22, 46 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthas son of Akousilaos, Makedon ton katoikon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maximus son of Diodoros alias Papontos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psenosiris son of Phamounis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonios son of Ammonios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heronas, koureus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron son of Heraklios (Herakleios)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Claudius, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron son of Chresimos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonios son of Lysimachos</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>koile  legomene Phregme (Phremei)</term>
               <term>Cession</term>
               <term>Ethnicity</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Irrigation</term>
               <term>Land Ownership</term>
               <term>Land Status</term>
               <term>Profession</term>
               <term>Taxation (Land)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(4th hand) Official copy. Month Germanikeios, Pachon 27.;;;;(1st hand) I, Mysthas, son of Akousilaos, a Macedonian of the catoeci, acknowledge that I have ceded to Maximus, son of Diodoros also called Papontos, to Maximus himself and to his heirs and assigns for transfer from the present day forever, six arourai of the catoecic allotment that belongs to me by inheritance from my father, and one quarter of an aroura of the village impost in addition, all of them, as many as there may be, in one parcel, in the so-called valley of Phremei; of which the neighbors are on the south the estates belonging to the treasury, with an irrigation canal between; on the north the allotment of Psenosiris, son of Phamounis; on the west the allotment of Ammonios, son of Ammonios, and in part that of Heronas the barber, with an irrigation canal between, by which the allotment is watered; on the east the allotment of Heron, son of Herakles, with an irrigation canal between, into which the allotment is drained. And I shall draw up the customary documents for the transfer and cession to Maximus through the office of catoecic records. And I have received from Maximus all the established sum of money for the cession immediately, from hand to hand, out of the house, and I guarantee the conditions of this cession with every guarantee from public debts and all assessments and from the naubion tax and the artab tax and the arithmetikon and the price of the land and fines and all other demands made from past times up to the present sixth year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, and from private debts and every claim forever, and I shall do everything as aforesaid. Maron, son of Chresimos, wrote for him because he writes too slowly. (2nd hand) I, Mysthas, son of Akousilaos, have ceded and received the sum of money and given the guaranteem and I ordered him to write as aforesaid. (3rd hand) I, Maximus, son of Diodoros also called Papontos. The cession was made to me as aforesaid. Apollonios, son of Lysimachos, &lt;wrote for him&gt; because he is illiterate.;;(4th hand) Mysthas, about [. .] years old, with a scar on his left forearm. Maximus, about 25 years old, with a scar on both his eyebrows. Maron, son of Chresimos, about 30 years old, with a scar on his right forearm. The signatory Apollonios, about 25 years old, with a scar on his left wrist.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 273, 1944</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:273</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1351&amp;viewid=1268R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/6/8/R/1268R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1351&amp;viewid=1268R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1351&amp;viewid=1268R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
