<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Agnitio bonorum possessionis</title>
            <author>Aurelius Thonis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3896</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3896</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.thomas.20</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0258;;20</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.thomas;;20</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">78797</idno>
            <idno type="TM">78797</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich. inv. 1946</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>The first column of text is a latin petition submitted in September 269 by Aurelius Thonis, of Oxyrhynchus, to the prefect of Egypt, concerning an inheritance from his deceased sister, Aurelia Saraheus. The petitioner acts not only in his name, but also on behalf of his two half-brothers, Aurelius Thonis (II) and Aurelius Theoninos alias Petronius, perhaps because these are still minors or are absent. Their sister died childness and intestate, and Aurelius Thonis requests that the three of them be allowed to come into possession of her property. The document contains no description of the property and is silent on how Saraheus came to possess it; she may have inherited it from her parents or from a husband deceased before her even as a result of a divorce. The latin petition is followed by a subscription in Greek, not written by Aurelius Thonis himself, as he was illiterate, but by Aurelius Dioskoros.  The petition was certainly submitted in two copies to the prefect, who must have added his signature of approval to one of them which was then retained as a record in his office. On the copy which has survived to us, a member of his staff copied his subscription, with a reference to the location of the original in the prefect's records and return it to Aurelius Thonis. The latter, then, had the Latin text (and its Greek subscription!) translated into Greek on a second sheet, which was glued to the first one.  The presence of another subscription in the name of Aurelius Thonis shows that he took one more step, that of requesting that the local authorities have the property transferred as approved by the prefect and originally registered in his name.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso some traces of stray ink</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc" otherLangs="la">Greek; Latin</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 15.5 x 14.3 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">On the left, some twenty to thirty letters of the first column are missing. The upper left part of the right column (II) is broken off.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. I: 11 lines; col. II: 29 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>It is made of two sheets of papyrus, each of different size and quailty, glued together. This unsusual feature may be explained by the different stages of composition of the text.  The left piece of papyrus is darker and wider.The latin petition is written in a fast chancery hand. The Greek subscription presents similarities with the flow and shape of the Latin, but due to the change of the alphabet, it is uncertain whether both parts were written by the same man.  The hand that wrote the translation is small cursive. another subscription (in the name of Aurelius Thonis) is written by a less experienced hand)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0269" notAfter="0270">269-270 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Oxyrhynchos, Oxyrhynchite nome, Middle Egypt, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelio(/u)s Thoni(u)s, son of Thonis and Thais</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thoni(u)s, father of Aurelios Thonis, Thonis, Theoninos and Saraheus, husband of Thais</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thais, mother of Aurelios Thonis, wife of Thonis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelio(/u)s Thoni(u)s, brother of Aur. Thonis and Aur. Saraheus, son of Thonis and Hieraciaina</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelio(/u)s Theonino(/u)s, alias Petronas (/Petronius), brother of Aur. Thonis and Saraheus, son of Thonis and Hieraciaina</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelia Saraheus, sister of Aurl. Thonis, Thonis and Theoninos, daughter of Thonis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Claudius Caesar Augustus, consul</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Paternus, consul</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelios Diskoros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelios Kopres</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Oxyrhynchus / Oxyrhynchos</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Col. I (latin) (m.1) [To X, most illustrius] prefect of Egypt, [from Aurelius Thonius, son of Thonius(?)], his mother being Thais, from [the illustrious] Oxyrhynchus. [I beg you], my lord, to grant to me and my [kindred] brothers, [Aurelii Thonius and Theo]ninus, alias Petronas, from the same, [aforesaid father, their mother being Hieraciaina], possession of the property of Aurelia Saraheus, [our kindred sister], who died childless and intestate, [in accordance with the part of the edict in which] it is promised to be given [to the lawful heirs]. Dated [in the consulship of Claudius and Paternus;(Greek) (m.2) I, Aurelios Thonis, ask for myself and my kindred] brothers the possession of the property of our sister [Saraheus, as aforesaid. I, Aurelius Dioskoros], wrote for him because he does not know  letters.;[(latin) In accordance with the edict; I have read it] (Greek) (m. 3) Column 48, volume 1.;Col. II (Greek) (m.4) [To X. most illustrious prefect of Egypt from Aurelius Thonis, son of Thonius(?), his mother being Thais, from the illustrious] city of  Oxyrhynchus. I beg you, my lord, to grant to me and my kindred brothers, Aurelii Thonis and Theoninos, alias Petronius, from the same and aforesaid father, their mother being Hieraciaina, possession of the property of Aurelia Saraheus, our kindred sister, who died childless and intestate, in accordance with the part of the edict in which it is promised to the lawful heirs. Dated in the consulship of Claudius Caesar Augustus and ofPaternus;(m.5) I, Aurelios Thonis,son of Thonis(?), have presented (this petition).  I, Aurelius Kopres, wrote for him because he does not know  letters. Year 3, [month, date].</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Gagos T - Heilporn P, PThomas, 175-185, no 20, 2001, Plate 16</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Thomas:20</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3896&amp;viewid=1946R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/4/6/r/1946r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3896&amp;viewid=1946R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3896&amp;viewid=1946R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3896&amp;viewid=1946V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3896&amp;viewid=1946V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
