<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3273</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3273</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer paying the poll-tax is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 129 is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 129-130: 33.2 x 29.2 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 129: nearly complete (papyrus cut off left of col. 129 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 129: 41 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 129 (l. 2151-2191)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois son of Naaraus deuteros and Thaisas grandson of Theabenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus son of Tesenouphis and Thaesis grandson of Phanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron son of Satabous and Tkonnos grandson of Maron (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kanis son of Anchophis and Tauorsoraipis grandson of Mares (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Patkonnis son of Mysthes and Taonnophris grandson of Patkonnis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 200)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides son of Abykis and Herais grandson of Abykis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Menches and Thaseis grandson of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Sisois and Thaesis grandson of Petsiris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Sokmenis and Thaesis grandson of Sokmenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 204)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor son of Petheus and Herakleia grandson of Phanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hatres son of Diodoros apator and of Aphrodous</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Agathopous, doulos of Thermoutharion alias Tpaietis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 148)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dioskoros son of Petheus and Taorsenouphis grandson of Kollouthos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dionysios son of Tepheros, apator (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Valerius son of Valeria, apator (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 195)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonios son of Pasoknopaios and Thatres grandson of Limnaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 151)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus alias Karanos son of Sokmenis and Tasokmenis grandson of Tasokmenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 204)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus son of Sisois and Thermouthis grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Chairemon and Stotoetis grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Illegitimacy--Egypt</term>
               <term>Guards troops--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Slaves--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 129;;On the 26th (of Pauni):;Sisois, son of Naaraus the second and Thaisas, grandson of Theabenis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;    column 101;Phanomgeus, son of Tesenouphis and Thaesis, grandson of Phanomgeus, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;    column 3;Maron, son of Satabous and Tkonnos, grandson of Maron, for ch(--): 8 drachmai;    column 5;Kanis, son of Anchophis and Tauorsoraipis, grandson of Mares, for (the contribution for) the guards: 28 obols;    column 4;Patkonnis, son of Mysthes and Taonnophris, grandson of Patkonnis: 4 drachmai;    column 7;Herakleides, son of Abykis and Herais, grandson of Abykis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;    column 9;Onnophris, son of Menches and Thaseis, grandson of Onnophris: 4 drachmai;    column 10;Onnophris, son of Sisois and Thaesis, grandson of Petsiris, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;    column 12;Petheus, son of Sokmenis and Thaesis, grandson of Sokmenis: 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(--): 4 drachmai;    column 17;Kastor, son of Petheus and Herakleia, grandson of Phanomgeus, for ch(--): 8 drachmai;    column 21;Hatres, son of Diodoros who is of unknown father, and of Aphrodous: 8 drachmai;    column 21;Agathopous, slave of Thermoutharion also called Tpaietis, for ch(--): 28 obols;    column 21;Dioskoros, son of Petheus and Taorsenouphis, grandson of Kollouthos, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;    column 27;Dionysis, of unknown father, his mother being Tepheros, for ch(--): 28 obols;    column 28;Valerius, of unknown father, his mother being Valeria: 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(--): 28 obols;    column 29;Ammonis, son of Pasoknopaios and Thatres, grandson of Limnaios, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;    column 29;Petheus also called Karanos, son of Sokmenis and Tasokmenis, grandson of Tasokmenis, for ch(--): 8 drachmai;    column 32;Petaus, son of Sisois and Thermouthis, grandson of Satabous, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;    column 34;Ptolemaios, son of Chairemon and Stotoetis, grandson of Horos: 4 drachmai;    column 42;Total for the day: 96 drachmai 25 obols.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 129 (l. 2151-2191), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3273&amp;viewid=4172_26RO.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/6/r/o/4172_26ro.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3273&amp;viewid=4172_26RO.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3273&amp;viewid=4172_26RO.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
