<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Encomium of Demosthenes (?)</title>
            <author>Unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1291</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1291</idno>
            <idno type="dclp">63548</idno>
            <idno type="TM">63548</idno>
            <idno type="dclp-hybrid">tm;;63548</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 10</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>7 papyri ; ab: 8 x 20. 3cm; cd: 16.1 x 10.9; f: 3.2 x 8.1 ; gh: 5.4 x 6.4; e: 5.7 x 9; j 3.1 x 4.4 ; i: 3.2 x 4.1 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The papyrus is of good quality, but it is badly preserved, being full of breaks and worm holes. Fr. e is discolored to a dark umber shade. Some breaks and worm holes along the course of the ancient foldings.  The fragments were rearranged between glass according to the sequence proposed by Gallo, Frammenti biografici, no.5, p.163-184, 1975, and so here different than pl.VII-VIII there. Also the Fragment E (of ed. princ.) was named Fragment F (ef. ed. princ.) and Fragment F as Fragment E, folllowing Gallo's edition.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">fr. ab: col. I, 24 lines, col. II, 24 lines; fr. cd: col. I, 7 lines; col. II, 7 lines;  fr. e: col. I, 8 lines; fr. f: col. I, 13 lines; fr. j: col. I, 5 lines; fr. i: col. I, 4 lines.</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The lower margin is c. 6.6 cm. The columns are straight and narrow, averaging 4.5 cm in width and containing eleven letters to a line. A space of less than 2 cm separates the columns. ;The handwriting is uncial with a marked contrast between the breadth of the angular (, gamma, eta, kappa, mu, nu pi, tau) and the smallness of the round letters (theta, omicron, sigma). Epsilon combines the smallness of the round letter with the breadth of the others by prolonging the rather high cross-bar to the right. There is a tendency toward compression at the ends of lines, while in seven instances the space-filler is used to bring the line out even with the rest. The upright strokes have a marked slope of about 12 degrees to the right from the vertical, while the round letters tend to the oval type. The hand is regular but not mechanical, letters like vu varying considerably in breadth even when considerations of space do not enter in.  In details, iota, rho, tau upsilon all reach below the line. Mu has a very shallow saddle, being at times nearly instiguishable from pi. Both omicron and omega are placed high in the line, the former being of the two-stroke type with the second stroke also sometimes curving to the right, the latter having always the flat bottom. The three stroke theta is interesting. Ypsilon is shallow and curves to the left. Xi is found complete once only and consists of two parallel lines with the middle stroke disconnecetd from the top but joined to the bottom. Ligatures of ai and ei are in two or three cases found at the ends of lines. Iota adscript is written (four times as it is expected, once in correction). Two ypsilons are dotted. No accents and breathings. In one case a double dot over iota. The paragraphos appears once added by a later hand. Some apostrophes, possibly intented as quotation marks, on the left hand margin of fr. cd.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0100" notAfter="0199">IInd century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Literary; oratory</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Blake WE, TAPA 57, 275-9, 1926 I.Gallo, Frammenti biografici I, no.5, p.163-184, 1975, pl.VII-VIII</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1291&amp;viewid=10R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/1/0/r/10r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1291&amp;viewid=10R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1291&amp;viewid=10R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
