<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of Part of a House</title>
            <author>Tasouchos, daughter of Sekonopis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2780</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2780</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.249</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;249</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;249</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">15166</idno>
            <idno type="TM">15166</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 625</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Demotic contract for the sale of a third of a house and courtyard, made by Tasouchos, daughter of Sekonopis, to Patynis, son of Harapis; the subscriptions are in Greek, as well as the date which was added at the top of the papyrus</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc" otherLangs="egy-Egyd">Greek; Demotic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 41.5 x 27.6 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">broken off on the left side; damaged along some folds</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Demotic - 2 columns of 9 lines each;;Greek - 1 + 6</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>First Greek hand in a very small cursive hand, with many peculiarities of spelling</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0018">August 28, 18 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Tiberius, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tasouchos daughter of Sekonopis and Soueris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Patynis son of Harapis and Tapetesouchos, mdkn &amp; b3k (. . . &amp; servant) of Souchos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Horos (&amp; unnamed brothers)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nechoutes = Nektonnephis son of Sekonopis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Papontos son of Petesouchos (and of Tasouchos?)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyd">Demotic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Talei, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome; canal of Moeris</term>
               <term>House ownership</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Priest</term>
               <term>Religion</term>
               <term>Sale</term>
               <term>Talei (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Woman</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Greek) [Year] 4 of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, 5th intercalary day of Mesore. Official copy.;;(Demotic, 1st col.) Year 4 of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, 5th month of summer, the (days of) illumination, day 5. The woman Tasouchos, daughter of Sekonopis, her mother being Soueris, has said to the . . . and servant of Souchos, Patynis, (son of) Harapis, his mother being Tapetesouchos, "You have caused my heart to be satisfied (with the) silver (of the) price of &lt;my&gt; one-third share which makes one share in three shares of &lt;my&gt; mother's part of a house, together with her part of (the) courtyard, its excess of measure (or) its deficiency of measure, every . . ., which is (in) the Souchos town of Talei, (in) the division of Polemon, on the side of the canal of Moeris, (in the) Arsinoite nome. The boundaries (of) the part of a house in which this one-third share is located: south, the royal road; north, the places of Horos, (son of) Horos, and his brothers; west, (the) house of Nechoutes, son of Sekonopis; east, (the) house of Aklas, son of . . ., - - - this one-third share. No man (in the) world, nor I likewise, shall be able to exercise authority over it except you, from this date on. He that shall come to you &lt;on account of it&gt;, I will cause &lt;him&gt; to be far from you in respect of it, of necessity, without delay, and I will cause [it] to be clear for you from every writing, &lt;every&gt; document.;;(Demotic, 2nd col.) Year 4 of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, 5th month of summer, [the (days of) illumination, day 5. The woman] Tasouchos, daughter of Sekonopis, her mother being Soueris, [has said] to the . . . and servant of Souchos, Patynis, [(son of) Harapis], his mother being Tapetesouchos, "I am far from you in respect of this one-third share which makes [one] share [in three shares of] this part of a house of my mother (in the) Souchos town of Talei, [in the division of Polemon], on the south side of the canal of Moeris, (in the) [Arsinoite] nome. The boundaries: south, (the) royal road; north, (the) places of Horos, [son of Horos, and his brothers;] west, the house of &lt;Nechoutes, son of&gt; Sekonopis; east, &lt;the house of&gt; Aklas, [son of - - -]. - - - -. I have received (the) silver of [its] price [from your hand, my heart is] satisfied therewith. No man in the world shall be able to exercise authority [over it, except you, from this date on].;;(Greek subscriptions) (1st hand) I, Tasouchos, daughter of Sekonopis, my mother being Soueris, acknowledge that I have sold, according to the Egyptian contracts, to Patynis, son of Harapis, his mother being Tapetesouchos, the third part, that belongs to me by inheritance from my mother, of a house and court common and undivided and all the appurtenances in Talei in the division of Polemon. The neighbors of the whole part of my maternal inheritance are: on the south the royal road, on the north the lots of Horos, son of Horos, and his brothers, on the west the house of Nektonnephis, son of Sekonopis, on the east the . . . of Akousilaos, son of . . . . And I have received in full the whole price agreed upon, and I guarantee the sale with every guarantee forever, and I shall do everything else as aforesaid. Papontos, son of Petesouchos, . . ., wrote for her because she is illiterate.;(2nd hand) Patynis, son of Harapis. The sale of the inherited third share of the house and court has been made to me, and I have paid the price as aforesaid. Eutychos(?), son of Eutychos, wrote for him because he is illiterate.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Edgerton WF-Husselman EM, PMich V, 249, 1944, Pl. II</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:249</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2780&amp;viewid=625R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/5/R/625R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2780&amp;viewid=625R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2780&amp;viewid=625R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
