<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3858</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3858</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 31.6 x 30.6 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Regularly cut at the top, at the left and at the right. Kollesis just to the right of center. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-38</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 91 (ll. 3615 - 3653)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Tapondos, daughter of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 238)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Hatres (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion, son of Heraklas, fatherless, mother Demarous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Demas, son of Satabous, grandson of Horos, mother Theonis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 160)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Karanos, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Imouthes, mother Tapetsiris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon, son of Heron, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Didyme (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis, son of Heras, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Isidora (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes, son of Petheus, grandson of Mysthes, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Limnaios, son of Onnophris, grandson of Satabous, mother Ptolema (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 185)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion alias Sokrates, son of Achillas, grandson of Hatres, mother Tamaron (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Souchas, grandson of Heras, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Achillas, grandson of Onnophris, mother Didymarion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Leonides, grandson of Papeis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Esouris, son of Kames, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Sambas, mother Taeuhemeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 224)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Sisois, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Didymarion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171/2)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras alias Aphrodisios, son of Heras, grandson of Petheus, mother Apollonarion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Melanas, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 188)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Apollonios, grandson of Harpagathes, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Taptosiris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Kames, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor, son of Sisois, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 182)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Athenion, son of Pyrrhos, grandson of Athenion, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 150)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>70th cleruchy;;Patsontis dioikesis</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 86:;The 29th of the same (month);;Karanos, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Imouthes, mother Tapetsiris, drachmas 4;;Limnaios, son of Onnophris, grandson of Satabous, mother Ptolema, copper drachmas 4;;Mysthes the younger, son of Dioskoros, grandson of Mysthes, mother Tepheros, drachmas 20;;Ptolemaios, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Horos, mother Eserempis, drachmas 20;;Ptolemais, daughter of Apollonios (Ischyras, chief of police);;orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira drachmas 17 obols 3, tax on the produce of olives drachmas 2 obols 2.5 chalki 2, naubion drachma 1 chalki 3.5, surcharges drachmas 4 obols 2.5;;(in left margin: drachmas 40) eparourion drachmas 11 obols 3, surcharges drachma 1, kollybos obols 3, in total drachmas 39 obols 2.5 chalki 2;;Paoueites, son of Petheus, grandson of Phasis, mother Tapetheus, copper drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Thaisas, copper drachmas 4;;Petheus, son of Onnophris (wife of Petenas ?);;orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira drachmas 2 obols 2 chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives obols 2.5 chalki 2, naubion obol 1.5, surcharges obols 4;;(in left margin: drachmas 36 obols 16) eparourion drachma 1 obols 4, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 5 obols 4 chalki 2;;geometria of year 12 drachmas 5 obols 5 chalki 2, surcharges obols 2 chalki 2, in total drachmas 6 obol 1.5;;and to Akousarion, son of Euhemeros through the agency of Tapetheus, daughter of Euhemeros;;orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira drachmas 5, tax on the produce of olives obols 4 chalki 2, naubion obols 3, surcharges drachma 1 obol 1.5;;eparourion drachmas 3 obols 2, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2, kollybos obol 1.5, in total drachmas 11 obol 1.5 chalki 2;;geometria of year 12 drachmas 12 obols 3, surcharges obols 4.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 13 obol 1.5 chalki 2;;Chairemon, son of Horos, grandson of Onnophris, mother Segathis, drachmas 4 copper drachmas 4;;Petaus, son of Petheus, grandson of Petaus, mother Tapasion, obols 28;;Aphrodisios, son of Anchophis, grandson of Petheus, mother Melanous, drachmas 4 copper drachmas 4;;Phanomgeus, son of Petheus, grandson of Satabous, mother Tamystha, copper drachmas 4;;Heron, son of Horos, grandson of Petheus, mother Taharpagathes, drachmas 12;;Panesneus, son of Ischyras, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaesis, copper drachmas 8;;Sarapion, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Sarapion, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4 obols 20 copper drachmas 4 obols 8;;Petheus, son of Kanis, grandson of Petheus, mother Tkollainis, drachmas 8;;Petheus, son of Kanis, cultivator in the 70th cleruchy;;orchard taxes of year 12 in the dioikesis of Patsontisapomoira drachma 1 obol 1.5, naubion obol 0.5 chalki 2, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2;;(in left margin: drachmas 12 obols 28) eparourion obols 5, surcharges obol 0.5, kollybos obol 0.5, in total drachmas 2 obols 4;;geometria of year 12 drachmas 3 obol 0.5 chalki 2, surcharges obol 1 chalki 2, in total drachmas 3 obols 2;;rent of year 12 drachmas 8, surcharges obols 3, in total drachmas 8 obols 3;;Lucius Antonius Pomp()anus (Marinus, son of Kelaulis);;(in left margin: drachmas 64, 10 obols) orchard taxes of year 12 drachmas 4 obol 0.5, tax on the produce of olives obols 3.5 chalki 2, naubion obols 2.5, surcharges drachma 1 chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 2 obols 4 chalki 2, surcharges obol 1.5, kollybos obol 1, in total drachmas 9 obol 1.5 chalki 2;;geometria of year 12 drachmas 7, surcharges obols 3, in total drachmas 7 obols 3;;and Marcus Sempronius Clemens through the agency of Marinus;;orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira drachmas 8 obols 4.5, tax on the produce of olives drachma 1 obol 1.5, naubion obols 5.5, surcharges drachmas 2 obol 1 chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 5 obols 5, surcharges obols 3, kollybos obols 2, in total drachmas 19 obols 4.5 chalki 2;;geometria of year 12 drachmas 21 obols 5 chalki 2, surcharges drachma 1 obols 2.5, in total drachmas 23 obol 1.5 chalki 2;;naubion of katoikoi of year 13 drachmas 2 chalki 2, surcharges obol 1 chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachmas 2 obol 1.5 chalki 2."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 -- CPJ 3, 492 (lines with Sambathion); BL III, 113 (on l. 8 a.o); BL III, 113 (on l. 416, 420, 427, 519, 1084, 1312, 1441, 1504, 1944, 2275, 2970, 3370, 3516, 4013, 4267a, 4356, 4549, 5225, 5497, 5672, 5912, 6049, 6057, 6062, 6104, 6131, 6164, 6244, 6258, 6271, 6308, 6316, 6413, 6418, 6424); BL VII, 109 (bibliography); BL VII, 109 (on l. 2652); BL VIII, 212 (on l. 3380); BL VIII, 212 (on l. 6274, 6422); BL IX, 159 (on l. 1524); BL X, 124 (on l. 2253, 4115, 5321, 5882); BL XI, 131 (on l. 1765-1799, 5268, 6007, 6315). Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3858&amp;viewid=4171_85R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/8/5/r/4171_85r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3858&amp;viewid=4171_85R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3858&amp;viewid=4171_85R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
