<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Private Letter</title>
            <author>Claudius Terentianus</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2451</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2451</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.8.476</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;8;476</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;8;476</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">27089</idno>
            <idno type="TM">27089</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 5397</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Letter from Claudius Terentianus to his father(?) Claudius Tiberianus, seeking to win his father's consent for bringing a woman into his household</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Cairo</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto + Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">archive of Claudius Tiberianus</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 24 X 22 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">damaged mainly along the folds on the left side</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto - 30 + 1 in left margin;Verso - 3</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto + Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>See electronic version of PMich VIII, 476</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0100" notAfter="0199">(Early) IInd century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>unknown place (in or near Alexandria?), province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Achillas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) stratiotes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Iulius</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymos, nomikos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Longinus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Cursilla</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Epitynchanon</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>a Caesareum; Arsinoite nome</term>
               <term>Army</term>
               <term>Concubinage (&amp;amp</term>
               <term>marriage)</term>
               <term>Family</term>
               <term>Feeding</term>
               <term>Religion</term>
               <term>Citizenship--Rome.</term>
               <term>Personal status: slavery(?)</term>
               <term>Woman</term>
               <term>Soldiers--Rome.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Claudius Terentianus to Claudius Tiberianus, his lord and father, very many greetings. Before all else I pray for your health and success, which are my wish. I myself am in good health and make obeisance for you daily in the presence of our lord Sarapis and the gods who share his temple. I want you to know, father, that I have received a basket (kalathion) from Achillas. Likewise, another basket was given to me by the soldier, in which I found two large loaves of bread and dates, and from the father of Iulius a small basket (sphyridallion) and my small baskets (talaria) and a sword-sheath. He sent me word about a woman; with my consent he was buying(?) one for me. As far back as two years ago I would have taken a woman into my house, but I did not permit myself nor do I permit myself to take anyone without your approval, and you will not hear otherwise from me on this subject. If perchance the woman whom I decide to bring down is one able to be the more kindly disposed toward you for my sake(?) and to take more thought for you than for me, the outcome is that I do you a favor rather than that you blame me. On this account, lacking your approval, until today no woman has come into my house. You are aware, for another thing, that I have relieved you of your difficulties; [and if(?)] you remain steadfast in refusal the rest of your life, I shall do without my woman. If not, the woman whom you approve is the one whom I also want. I wrote you this letter at night, having found an opportunity, but I was not able to send it. Please write me a reply about your well-being and about the letter. Salute all those in the Caesareum, each by name. Salute Didymos, the notary, together with his entire household. You will tell Longinus that I hope to go upcountry again. For one thing I thank the gods, that I gave you more than the eight drachmai. If I had not, the same thing would have happened. And if you go up to the Arsinoite nome, go to Cursilla and get the five logs of timber and bring them when you come as well as anything else that you are able to bring down to us for the winter. Epitynchanon salutes you. Salute all your friends, each by name.;;(Verso) Deliver to Claudius Tiberianus . . . from Claudius Terentianus, his son, a soldier of the legion.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Winter JG-Youtie HC, PMich VIII, 476, 1951, Pl. VI -- BL IV, 55 (on origin); BL VII, 111 (on line 10; bibliography); BL VIII, 215 (bibliography); BL IX, 161 (bibliography) White J.L., Light from Ancient Letters, 110, 1986</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:8:476</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2451&amp;viewid=1">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
