<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of a Vacant Lot</title>
            <author>Mersis alias Pyrrhos, son of Labesis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2942</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2942</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.308</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;308</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;308</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">25200</idno>
            <idno type="TM">25200</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 680</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Demotic contract, with Greek subscription, for the sale of a vacant lot by Mersis, also called Pyrrhos, son of Labesis, to Eutychos the elder, son of Eutychos.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Egyd">Demotic and Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 40.9 x 28.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">deeply frayed at both top and bottom, so that the upper part of the demotic text is gone, and only scattered letters can be read in the last two and one-half lines of the Greek subscription</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">11 + 8</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0001" notAfter="0099">Ist century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Mersis alias Pyrrhos son of Labesis, husband of Herais</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herodes son of Herodes alias Isidoros (see also P.Mich. V, 243)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marepsemis son of Marepsemis alias Chresimos(?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herais daughter of Orsenouphis and Arete(?), wife of Mersis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kronion son of Shp3(?), p3 ss knbt ("the document scribe") of Tebtynis</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Egyd">Demotic and Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Tebtoinis (Tebtynis)</term>
               <term>Land Ownership</term>
               <term>Notary</term>
               <term>Religion</term>
               <term>Sale</term>
               <term>Topography (Tebtynis)</term>
               <term>Woman</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Demotic) [- - - with] its excess of measure (or) its deficiency of measure. The boundaries of this courtyard [in] which this room [and these] storehouses [- - -] who is called Isidoros, and the places of Neferpsachn who is written above: north, the temple of Thoth 'and - - -'; west, the royal road; east, my share; &lt;no man in the world, nor&gt; I likewise, &lt; shall be able to&gt; exercise authority over it, except you, from this date on. He that shall come to you on account of it, I will &lt;cause&gt; him to be far &lt;from you&gt; in respect of it, of necessity without delay, divine cubit, without anything. No man (in the) world shall be able to come to you on account of it. If we withdraw ourselves from you so as not to, we will give so much refined silver (and) so much other refined silver (for) the burnt offerings (and) the libations of the king, may he live forever! Written by Herais his wife, daughter of Orsenouphis, his (sic) mother being Arete(?), the wife of Mersis, saying, "I am present (and) I write, my heart is satisfied therewith. Take(?) this courtyard and the room and this storehouse. He that shall come unto you on account of it, bearing my share, I will cause him to be far from you, of necessity, without delay." Written by Kronion, son of . . ., the document scribe of Tebtynis. Written by Marepsemis, (son of) Marepsemis, who is called Chresimos. Written.;;(Greek) I, Mersis, also called Pyrrhos, son of Labesis, acknowledge that I have sold to Eutychos the elder, son of Eutychos, the vacant lot that belongs to me, in which there are a building and storehouses and all the appurtenances, in Tebtynis; the measurements of all of which are from south to north, seven cubits, from west to east, twenty-six and one-half cubits, to the extent of the total measurements in cubits, as many as there may be. The neighbors are on the south the court of Herodes, son of Herodes also called Isidoros, and in part the lots of the purchaser Eutychos, on the north the Hermaion, temple of the great god,a nd in part an open space of the same temple, on the west the royal road, and on the east the lots of Mersis himself. And I have received the entire price agreed upon for them, in full, from hand to hand, out of the house, and I guarantee the sale with every guarantee from public and private debts and every impost as aforesaid. Marepsemis, son of Marepsemis, wrote for him because he is illiterate. The wife of Mersis, Herais, daughter of Orsenouphis, her mother being Arete(?), consents to the sale, and agrees that she will not proceed against it forever, or bring any claim, and that no one else shall do so in her behalf forever as aforesaid . . . [- - -]</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 308, 1944</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:308</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2942&amp;viewid=680R_1.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/1/680R_1.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2942&amp;viewid=680R_1.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2942&amp;viewid=680R_1.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/2/680R_2.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2942&amp;viewid=680R_2.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2942&amp;viewid=680R_2.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
