<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3306</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3306</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 18 is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 17-18: 34.8 x 30 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 18: complete (papyrus cut to the right of col. 18 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 18: 54 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 18 (l. 175-228)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas son of Ptolemaios and Taeuemeros grandson of Sambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 224)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Chairemon and Stotoetis grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras son of Melanas and Tamystha grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus son of Petheus and Tamystha grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Pasoknopaios and Heros grandson of Petsiris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Papeis son of Ptolemaios and Heras grandson of Pnepheros, brother of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros (son of Ptolemaios and Heras grandson of Pnepheros), brother of Papeis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apitas son of Chairemon and Tasoucharion grandson of Apitas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 152)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides son of Petheus and Ptolemais grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos son of Heraklas and Stiynchis grandson of Heraklas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor son of Ptolemaios and Tasoucharion grandson of Kastor (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 182)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Didymos and Tauris grandson of Maron (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos son of Hatres and Tapetheus grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Polis son of Petheus and Herais grandson of Keras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Petheus and Segathis grandson of Teos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herieus presbyteros son of Horos and Thaesis grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor son of Achillas and Aphrodous grandson of Kastor (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus son of Herieus and Tremennesis (Tlemenesis) grandson of Petaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Agathos Daimon and Stiynchis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Petaus and Tauris grandson of Petaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois son of Naaraus deuteros and Thaisas grandson of Petaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Artemas son of Heron and Thaesis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hatres son of Apollonios and Taorsenouphis grandson of Heraklas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 156)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 18;;Sambas, son of Ptolemaios and Taeuemeros, grandson of Sambas: 20 drachmai;    column 41;Horos, son of Chairemon and Stotoetis, grandson of Horos: 8 drachmai;    column 42;Heras, son of Melanas and Tamystha, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai;    column 42;Phanomgeus, son of Petheus and Tamystha, grandson of Satabous: 28 obols;    column 53;Onnophris, son of Pasoknopaios and Heros, grandson of Petsiris: 16 drachmai;    column 55;Papeis, son of Ptolemaios and Heras, grandson of Pnepheros: 20 drachmai;    column 59;Pnepheros, his brother, (born) of the same mother: 4 drachmai 28 obols;    column 59;Apitas, son of Chairemon and Tasoucharion, grandson of Apitas: 20 drachmai;    column 65;Total for the day: 140 drachmai 12 obols.;;On the 18th, similarly:;Herakleides, son of Petheus and Ptolemais, grandson of Heras: 4 drachmai;    column 76;Petesouchos, son of Heraklas and Stiynchis, grandson of Heraklas: 8 drachmai 8 obols;    column 78;Kastor, son of Ptolemaios and Tasoucharion, grandson of Kastor: 8 drachmai;    column 78;Petheus, son of Didymos and Tauris, grandson of Maron: 4 drachmai;    column 80;Petesouchos, son of Hatres and Tapetheus, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai;    column 82;Polis, son of Petheus and Herais, grandson of Keras: 4 drachmai;    column 85;Onnophris, son of Petheus and Segathis, grandson of Teos: 4 drachmai;    column 85;Herieus the elder, son of Horos and Thaesis, grandson of Pnepheros: 8 drachmai;    column 87;Kastor, son of Achillas and Aphrodous, grandson of Kastor: 8 drachmai;    column 90;Petaus, son of Herieus and Tremennesis, grandson of Petaus: 4 drachmai;    column 89;Ptolemaios, son of Agathos Daimon and Stiynchis, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai;    column 91;Polydeukes, son of Heras and Tapasion, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai;    column 100;Horos, son of Petaus and Tauris, grandson of Petaus: 4 drachmai;    column 101;Sisois, son of Naaraus the second and Thaisas, grandson of Petaus: 28 obols;    column 101;Hatres, son of Phanomgeus and Tapetheus, grandson of Heraklas: 4 drachmai;    column 103;Artemas, son of Heron and Thaesis, grandson of Petheus: 20 drachmai;    column 96;Hatres, son of APollonios and Taorsenouphis, grandson of Heraklas: 16 drachmai;    column 64;Total for the day: 120 drachmai 7 obols.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 18 (l. 175-228), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3306&amp;viewid=4172R2.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/R/2/4172R2.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3306&amp;viewid=4172R2.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3306&amp;viewid=4172R2.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
