<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>marriage agreement and donatio mortis causa</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1854</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1854</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.16.12334</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;16;12334</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;16;12334</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">26722</idno>
            <idno type="TM">26722</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 3172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>This text has two parts. The first (lines 1-8) is the end of a Greek marriage agreement, referred to as syngraphe. The surviving part of the marriage contract contains arrangements for the repayment of dowry in case of divorce and a provision ensuring that one party may retain control over property acquired after the date of the present agreement. Although the majority of such contracts were arranged by the husband and wife themselves, the parties in this settlement are both women. Apollonous, who undertakes the agreement (line 5), is responsible for returning the dowry in case of divorce (lines 1-4) and is liable to prosecution in event of default (lines 5-6). She operates on behalf of the husband in the marriage, and is presumably his mother. The second party is not clearly identified in the remaining fragment, but appears to be Tamarres (see lines 822n). The identity of the spouses whose marriage is  at issue is also a matter of conjunction. They are evidently Kronous, a beneficiary of Tamarres (lines 11-20) and therefore probably her daughter, and Gaius Julius Isidoros: the names of these two are linked once in the marriage agreement (line 6), and one or both of them also appear in the division of property in contexts that make it practically certain that they are man and wife (lines 11, 20).;Lines 8-22 contain Tamarres' distribution of property. Her dispositions consist of at least three parcels of land (including one of 16 arouras: lines 12, 17, 18; also 19?) and a slave  (lines 14-15), and provide for a payment to the household of Kronous. The text concludes with provisions for the alimentary support of the donor (line 21), and the name and the beginning of the signalments of the hypographeus. In the lost second column would have been the subjectively phrased subscriptions of Apollonous and Tamarres and the signatures of the hypographeus and the witnesses, if any.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso contains traces of ink but no writing</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 12.8 x 18.5 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The surviving portion of the papyru, which is medium brown, was folded vertically in four sections. The writing is well preserved except at the folds.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1 - 23</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The script is small and informal but clear with a slight rightward slant. There are some cursive forms (b, e, k, p) and some ligatures, but in general the letters are written distinctly and with a certain flair; decorative hooks and clubbing are added to most vertical strokes. For similar hand cp. P. Mich. IV 224 and 225, pl. 2 and 3 (Karanis, A.D. 172/173 and 173/174); P. Gr. Berol. pl. 26b (Upper Egypt, A.D. 185); P. Berol. inv. 21880, ZPE 9 (1972) 251 - 255, pl. 7b (Arsinoe, A.D. 189). At the top an unknown amount is missing, and at the left as much as half the original length of the line may be lost. At the right the papyrus breaks off at the end of the line of writing, and at the bottom a margin of 4.8 cm. is preserved.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0150" notAfter="0199">(late) IInd century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Philadelphia, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonous</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tamarres</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kronous, mother of Tamarres</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius Julius Isidoros</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Philadelphia, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt (?)</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>-</term>
               <term>Mothers--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Land tenure--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Slavery--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Antenuptial contracts--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Dowry--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Divorce settlements--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Property--Egypt--Philadelphia (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[Text too fragmentary for translation].</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>McNamee K, BASP 19, 149-57, 1982 -- SB XVI 12334 (and XVIII, p. 481) -- BL IX, p. 281 (l. 16)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:16:12334</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1854&amp;viewid=3172R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/7/2/r/3172r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1854&amp;viewid=3172R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1854&amp;viewid=3172R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
