<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Cancellation of a loan contract</title>
            <author>Heraclius, son of Heracles</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1256</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1256</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.corn.6</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0097;;6</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.corn;;6</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10607</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10607</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Corn. Inv. I 125</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Cancelled contract of loan</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; on Verso a short description of the text on recto</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 18.3 x 26.1 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Light brown papyrus regularly cut off, except in bottom right corner and lower left side, where a significant part of the papyrus is lost. The loss of text, however, is insignificant and the missing may be easily restored. A few other minor abrasions scattered around on the document, although these are too small to be serious. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto: 1 - 31; verso 1-2</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>When the note was paid the contract was cancelled by drawing a series of heavy strokes, in the form of the letter X, over the entire face of the loan. The upper two series of these cross strokes are large, the first row covering ll. 1-5, the second row ll. 5-10. The remaining six rows of cross strokes are, roughly, half the size of the upper rows. The body of the document is written in an irregular hand, varying from a carefully formed uncial to a somewhat smaller cursive. The second hand, that of the lender, Heraclius, is semi-cursive and slovenly. Dionysius, the borrower (third hand), writes in heavy crude uncials. The clerk who countersigned the document for the office of the nomographus (fourth hand) writes in uncials with few ligatures, rather finely, with self-conscious effort.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0017">17 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Oxyrhyncha, Polemon meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraclius</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heracles</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dionysius</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tiberius Caesar Augustus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Polemon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraclius</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heracles</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dionysius</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thasos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psoiphis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hermias</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Oxyrhyncha, Polemon meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt (?)</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Oxyrhyncha, Polemon meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</term>
               <term>Loans--Egypt--Oxyrhnchos.</term>
               <term>Suretyship and guaranty--Egypt--Oxyrhnchos.</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Oxyrhnchos.</term>
               <term>Debt cancellation--Egypt--Oxyrhnchos.</term>
               <term>Women--Egypt--Oxyrhnchos.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Docket) "Heraclius, aged 35, wart on the middle of his nose.;In the third year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus on the 10th of the month Xanthikos, Mecheir 10th, in Oxyrhyncha of the division of Polemon of the Arsinoite nome, Heraclius son of Heracles, aged thirty-five, wart on the middle of his nose, loaned to Dionysius, son of Maron, Persian of the Epigone, aged forty-two, scar on the right wrist, together with his wife, Thasos, daughter of Psoiphis, of the classification "Persian", aged forty, scar on the right eyebrow, acting with her guardian, her husband Dionysius  mentioned above, they being sureties one for the other for repayment, the capital sum of 480 drachmas in coined silver. This money he has received from him forthwith from hand to hand out of the house, at interest of one drachma three obols on the mina for each month. This loan, the 480 drachmas of coined money in silver, the borrowers shall pay back to Heraclius in the month Tybi of the coming fourth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus. If they do not repay it, they shall forfeit the loan increased by one-half, and the interest itself, and Heraclius shall have the right of execution upon the borrowers and all their belongings.";(2nd hand) "And I, Heraclius, son of Heracles, have loaned the 480 drachmas of silver agreed upon, according to all the foregoing conditions.";(3rd hand) "He, Dionysius, son of Maron, Persian of the Epigone, and my wife Thasos, daughter of Psoiphis, of the classification "Persian", with her guardian, namely, me, her husband Dionysius mentioned above, being sureties one for the other for repayment, have the loan from Heraclius son of Heracles, administrator of the affairs of Heraclius, son of Heracles, son of Herodes, to wit, the capital sum of 480 drachmas on the mina for each month. This money we will pay back in the month Tybi of the coming fourth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus as agreed.;I, the above-mentioned Dionysius, have written also on behalf of my wife, Thasos, who cannot write, and I am registered as her guardian. I am forty-two years old, scar on my right wrist.";(4th hand) "Year 3 of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, Mecheir the 10th, through Hermias, nome scribe of Oxyrhychaaa;Verso: "Loan of 480 drachmas silver by Heraclius to Dionysius and his wife."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Westermann WL - Kraemer CJ, PCorn, 6, 1926 -- BL II.2, 46 on lines 6, 9, 14, 15; BL VIII, 89</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Corn.:6</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1256&amp;viewid=C2_5R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/_/5/r/c2_5r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1256&amp;viewid=C2_5R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1256&amp;viewid=C2_5R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/_/5/v/c2_5v.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1256&amp;viewid=C2_5V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1256&amp;viewid=C2_5V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
