<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Dioscorides, Materia Medica 2.76.2 and 76.7-18</title>
            <author>Dioscorides</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1738</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1738</idno>
            <idno type="dclp">59697</idno>
            <idno type="TM">59697</idno>
            <idno type="dclp-hybrid">tm;;59697</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 3</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Materia Medica 2.76.2 and 76.7-18</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Marganne, inventaire 116; LDAB 801; MP[3]346;plate in Roberts, GLH 15c;</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto + Verso</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; a: 13.8 x 32.7 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">There are parts of three columns. Of the first only a few letters remain in a projection at the upper left-hand side. We have by far the greater part of the second column, is spite of several bad cracks and the loss of several small pieces. A large part of the bottom of this column, at the right, has been split off, and the piece cannot now be replaced accurately because of the warping of the parts with which it was originally connected. Of the third column about one-half is left; the rest was lost by a longitudinal split.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. I, 23 lines; col. II, 89 lines; col. III, 87 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto +Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The columns of writing are 28.2 to 28.5 cm by 7 cm. The columns are of a length quite uncommon in literary texts; there are 89 lines in the second column, 87 in the third. The average number of letters in a line is from 27 to 29, but the scribe allows himself considerable freedom, sometimes writing as many as 34, especially where he encroaches upon the margin, sometimes as few as 24.  The margins are genrous with 3.8 cm lft blank at top and 3.1 cm at bottom; intercolumnar space is usually 1.5 cm, although this diminishes to ca. 1.1 cm whenever there is ekthesis, usually in the line following a paragraphus plus on-line blank space. The text has neither accents nor breathings. Numerals are usually represented by letters, which in most cases have the horizontal stroke above them; but sometimes the stroke is no longer perceptible, if it was there at all. "mn", with a mark like a breve abone it, stands for "mnas". In two cases the case endings of the perfect participle passive have been abbreviated (Col. 2, 78 and col. 2, 82). There are no punctuations except the indications of paragraphs. A pause is indicated by a space of three to five letters, and under the first one or two letters of the line in xhich the space occurs, a short horizontal stroke (paragraphus) was drawn, and is still to be seen except in one of the nine places. This is the normal method in the earlier papyri. In addition, the line under that in which the pause occurs is projected one letter-space into the left-hand margin. Thompson (Paleography, 59) describes the latter device as coming into use later than the paragraphus and superseding it; but the two are found together. Divisions were probably made by this method in col. 2 also, at 51 and 63, and in 63 the space may be seen; but the loss of the left margin with a few letters has obscured the paragraph indication. In col. 2 at lines 17 and 20 we have what appear to be major divisions of the matter; the paragraphus is longer and has a wedge, or diple, added to its head.  In these two instances the division appears to give evidence of a textual relation between the papyrus and a mediaeval manuscript. At the end of several lines of col. 2 there is found a peculiar little check which may be designed to fill unoccupied space, but has no other discernible use (line fillers). The text is written in a good, small, sloping book-hand. Turner's formal mixed style. Alpha is usually made in two parts, the loop being a long sharp angle; but it sometimes made with a rounded slighly open loop continued, without lifting the pen, into the down stroke. The horizontal stroke of theta usually crosses the right-hand side of the ellipse. The stroke between the two uprights of mu is only very slightly dipped. Mu and nu are broad, sigma and epsilon are narrow. Omicron is small. Omega is generally an unbroken curve like the lower part of a circleor ellipse. But in several cases it is made in two parts -one stroke down and then to right, and another down and slightly feftward, meeting or passing beyond the first. ;With about ten possible occurances, iota adscript is entirely lacking in verb inflection. In the dative case it is found 13 times and omitted 16 times. Confusion among the vowels and diphthngs is relatively  infrequent for so long a fragment, though cases do occur -"ei" for "i" thre times, "i" for "ei" once, "h" for "ei" twice, "ai" for "e" once. The "n" is regularly written (five times) in "sunzeson". Nu movable occurs once at the end of a sentece, once before a vowel, once before a consonant, and is omitted twice before vowels. Numerals are mostly alphabetic, usually marked by an overstroke. Only minimal corrections have been made to the text as preserved (col. 2, 25)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0150" notAfter="0193">(second half  of the) IInd century A.D. and before192/193 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Literary; medical</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Bonner C, TAPA 53, 142-68, 1922, Pl III Flemming R - Hanson AE, Greek Medical Papyri I, no 2, 9-35, 2001, Plate II</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1738&amp;viewid=3R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/3/r/3r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1738&amp;viewid=3R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1738&amp;viewid=3R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
