<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3341</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3341</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).;The column numbers of cols. 53-54 seem to have been corrected. Traces of an erased marginal note on the left of l. 1233.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 54 is blank except for a short pen trial</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 53-54: 34 x 30 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 54: nearly complete (papyrus cut off right of col. 54 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 54: 63 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 54 (l. 1194-1246)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles son of Mysthes and Charis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus son of Onnophris and Tkateis grandson of Petaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon son of Phanomgeus and Tbelles grandson of Phanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Onnophris and Isidora grandson of Harendotes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sentis alias Theagenes son of Petheus and Tauris grandson of Theagenes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 228)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Besis son of Petheus and Thermouthis grandson of Akousilaos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 159)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas son of Onnophris and Thermouthis grandson of Sambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 223)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Apynchis and Tapetheus grandson of Aunes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nekpheraus son of Euemeros and Taonnophris grandson of Nekpheraus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 190)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron son of Ptolemaios and Heras grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Apollonios and Thermouthis grandson of Harpagathes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Pnepheros and Tapetheus grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Phasis and Helene grandson of Keras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymos son of Satabous and Tanomgeus grandson of Pakysis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Petheus and Segathis grandson of Teos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Didymos and Thaisas grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herieus son of Sambas and Tapapeis grandson of Peteesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois son of Karanos and Artemis grandson of Heraklas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Anchorimphis and Achillis grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Orsenouphis and Anthia grandson of Herieus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron son of Ptolemaios and Taseus grandson of Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonis son of Petronius and Ptolemais grandson of Apollonios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 153)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Horos and Taarmothes (Taharmothes) grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax exemption--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Diseases--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 54;;(Pharmouthi 19, continued);Herakles, son of Mysthes and Charis, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai;    column 54;Petaus, son of Onnophris and Tkateis, grandson of Petaus: 8 drachmai;    column 57;Chairemon, son of Phanomgeus and Tbelles, grandson of Phanomgeus: 8 drachmai;    column 62;Horos, son of Onnophris and Isidora, grandson of Harendotes: 8 drachmai;    column 63;Sentis also called Theagenes, son of Petheus and Tauris, grandson of Theagenes: 8 drachmai;    column 63;Besis, son of Petheus and Thermouthis, grandson of Akousilaos: 4 drachmai;    column 65;Sambas, son of Onnophris and Thermouthis, grandson of Sambas: 4 drachmai 28 obols;    column 68;Petsiris, son of Petesouchos and Apia, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai 28 obols;    column 67;Ptolemaios, son of Apynchis and Tapetheus, grandson of Aunes: 4 drachmai;    column 70;Nekpheraus, son of Euemeros and Taonnophris, grandson of Nekpheraus: 4 drachmai;    column 75;Total for the day: 132 drachmai 25 obols.;;On the 20th similarly:;Heron, son of Ptolemaios and Heras, grandson of Pnepheros: 4 drachmai 28 obols;    column 59;Sarapion, son of Apollonios and Thermouthis, grandson of Harpagathes: 4 drachmai;    column 61;Pnepheros, son of Pnepheros and Tapetheus, grandson of Pnepheros: 28 obols;    column 82;Sarapion, son of Phasis and Helene, grandson of Keras: 28 obols;    column 85;Didymos, son of Satabous and Tanomgeus, grandson of Pakysis: 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(--): 4 drachmai;    column 84;Onnophris, son of Petheus and Segathis, grandson of Teos: 4 drachmai;    column 85;Petheus, son of Didymos and Thaisas, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai 20 obols;    column 88;Herieus, son of Sambas and Tapapeis, grandson of Peteesis: 28 obols;    column 82;Sisois, son of Karanos and Artemis, grandson of Heraklas: 40 drachmai. (In left margin:) [[. . .]];    column 82;Horos, son of Anchorimphis and Achillis, grandson of Horos: 4 drachmai;    column 98;Ptolemaios, son of Orsenouphis and Anthia, grandson of Herieus: 4 drachmai;    column 99;Maron, son of Ptolemaios and Taseus, grandson of Sambathion: 8 drachmai;    column 101;Apollonis, son of Petronius and Ptolemais, grandson of Apollonios, diseased, for the guards: 4 drachmai;    column 105;Horos, son of Horos and Taarmothes, grandson of Horos: 8 drachmai;    column 105;Total for the day: 112 drachmai 16 obols.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 54 (l. 1194-1246), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3341&amp;viewid=54RO.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/4/r/o/54ro.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3341&amp;viewid=54RO.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3341&amp;viewid=54RO.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
