<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Release of Claims on Property</title>
            <author>Arsinoe, daughter of Herakleides</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1348</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1348</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.350</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;350</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;350</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12160</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12160</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1265</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract by which Arsinoe agrees to give up any claim to property which her parents, Herakleides and Ptolema, may leave on their death, in return for the dowry which she received from them at the time of her marriage to Lysimachos, son of Lysimachos.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso has faint traces of ink (offset?)</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 27 x 27.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">nearly complete, but rubbed on the folds</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">35</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0037">August 24, 37 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius, Emperor</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome</term>
               <term>Dowry--Egypt--Tebtynis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Family</term>
               <term>House Ownership</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Inheritance</term>
               <term>Land Ownership</term>
               <term>Marriage</term>
               <term>Woman (&amp;amp</term>
               <term>guardian)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>The first year of Gaius Caesar Augustus Germanicus, in the month Hyperberetaios, the first of the intercalary days, first intercalary day of Mesore, in Tebtynis in the division of Polemon of the Arsinoite nome. Arsinoe, daughter of Herakleides, about twenty years old, with a scar on her chin on theright, with her guardian, her own husband Lysimachos, son of Lysimachos, about twenty-eight years old, with a scar on his right eyebrow, acknowledges to her own parents, Herakleides the younger, son of Maron, about forty-six years old, with a scar on the left side of his chin, and his wife, the mother of Arsinoe, Ptolema, daughter of Herodes, about forty years old, with a scar on her right calf, with her guardian, the same Herakleides, that she resigns to them all the property which they have and which they may acquire, the allotments of land and vineyards and gardens and building sites and slaves and cattle of all kinds and furniture and household stock and all sums due them and everything which they may acquire and whatever is left by them in any way whatsoever, excepting only the women's utensils and clothin belonging to Ptolema herself, because Arsinoe is satisfied with what was given to her as a dowry by her aforesaid parents, Herakleides and Ptolema, through the marriage contracts made with her aforesaid husband, Lysimachos, son of Lysimachos. But if anyone proceeds against Herakleides or Ptolema or their male children, or brings any charge in the name of Arsinoe, Arsinoe herself shall prosecute him at her own cost and expense. If Arsinoe or others on her behalf shall commit any act of aggression in the same way against the aforesaid Herakleides and Ptolema or against their heirs, or if she shall commit any act of accusation or dispute or claim or hindrance or fraud, it shall be invalid and inadmissible for Arsinoe and for everyone who shall proceed in her behalf. And Arsinoe shall pay to the aforesaid or to the one of them against whom she has proceeded, immediately, twice the amount of the damages and expenses and a fine of a thousand drachmai of minted silver as a private debt and a like sum to the treasury, the terms agreed upon remaining valid nonetheless.;(2nd hand) I, Arsinoe, daughter of Herakleides, with my guardian, my husband Lysimachos, son of Lysimachos, acknowledge that I have released to my aforesaid parents, Herakleides the younger, son of Maron, and my mother, Ptolema, daughter of Herodes, any claim to all the property which they hold or shall acquire, including allotments of land and vineyards and gardens and building sites and slaves and cattle of all kinds and furniture and household stock and all sums due them, and whatever they shall acquire, and whatever shall be left by them in any way whatsoever, excepting only the women's utensils and garments belonging to Ptolema herself, because I am satisfied with the dowry given me by my aforesaid parents, Herakleides and Ptolema, through the marriage contracts which I have with my husband Lysimachos, son of Lysimachos. But I, Arsinoe, shall at my own cost and expense prosecute anyone who proceeds or brings any charge against Herakleides or Ptolema or their male children in the name of me, Arsinoe. And I shall do the rest as aforesaid. I, Lysimachos, wrote for my wife because she is illiterate, and I have been registered as her guardian.;(3rd and) Herakleides the younger, son of Maron, and my wife, Ptolema, daughter of Herodes, with her guardian, me, her husband, Herakleides. The release was made to us as aforesaid. I, Herakleides, wrote for my wife, who is illiterate.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 350, 1944 -- BL VII, 111 (l.16)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:350</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1348&amp;viewid=1265R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/6/5/R/1265R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1348&amp;viewid=1265R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1348&amp;viewid=1265R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/6/5/V/1265V.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1348&amp;viewid=1265V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1348&amp;viewid=1265V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
