<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Security for a debt</title>
            <author>Stephanos also called Amois, son of Apollophanes and Ptolarrous</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1262</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1262</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.oxy.3.508</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0181;3;508</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;508</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20640</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20640</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Corn. Inv. MSS. A 101. IV</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>A contract between Stephanos and Heraklas, by which the former apparently accepts liability for the repayment of two loans from Heraklas to Roufos and Diokles, but the papyrus breaks off before the details of the transaction are made clear</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 13.3 x 11.1 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The papyrus is broken off at at its upper left margin and its botton part is lost.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">26 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The letters are made separately without many ligatures . The top margin is 1.7 cm and the feft c, 2 cm. There is no right margin as trhe scribe continues the writing til the right edge of the writing area. Note that in l. 3 the space blank left before and after the digit "l" (30th of the month)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0102">23 August, 102 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Oxyrhynchos, Oxyrhynchite nome, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Emperor Caesar Nerva Traianus Augustus Germanicus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Stephanos also called Amois, son of Sosibios and Ptollarous, grandson of Apollophanes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sosibios, father of Stephanos, son of Apollophanes, husband of Ptollarous</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollophanes, father of Sosibios, grandfather of Stephanos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptollarous daughter of Chairemon, wife of Sosibios, mother of Stephanos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon, father of Ptollarous, grandfather of Stephanos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraklas (I), son of Heraklas (II) and Demetrous, grandson of Harthonis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraklas (II), father of Heraklas (I), husband of Demetrous, son of Harthonis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Demetrous, mother of Heraklas (I)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harthonis, father of Heraklas (II), grandfather of Heraklas (I)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Roufos, son of Diokles (I) and Didyme, brother of Diokles (III), grandson of Diokles (II) and Roufion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Diokles (I) , father of Roufos and Diokles (III), son of Doikles (II), husband of Didyme</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didyme, mother fo Roufos and Diokles (III), wife of Diokles (I), daughter of Roufion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Roufion, father of Didyme, grandfather of Roufos and Diokles (III)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Diokles (II), father of Diokles (I), grandfather of Roufos and Diokles (III)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Diokles (III), brother of Roufos, son of Diokles (I) and Didyme, grandson of Diokles (II) and Roufion</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Oxyrhynchos, Oxyrhynchite nome, Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Oxyrhynchon polis;Thebaid</term>
               <term>Loans--Egypt--Bahnas誰a .</term>
               <term>Contracts--Egypt--Bahnas誰a .</term>
               <term>Mortgages--Egypt--Bahnas誰a .</term>
               <term>Interest--Egypt--Bahnas誰a .</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>The fifth year of the Emperor Caesar Nerva Traianus Augustus Germanicus, the 30th of the month Kaisarios, at Oxyrhynchon polis of the Thebaid. Stephanos also called Amois, son of Sosibios son of Apollophanes, his mother being Ptollarous daughter of Chairemon, inhabitants of Oxyrhynchon polis, acknowledhes to Heraklas son of Heraklas grandson of Harthonis, his mother being Demetrous, also of Oxyrhynchon polis, in the street, that he, Stephanos, the contracting party, has become security for two loans which Heraklas lent from his own money through the record-office at the said city, the first being in the month of Mecheir of the 2nd year of Traianus Caesar the lord to Roufos son of Diokles grandson of Diokles, his mother being Didyme daughter of Roufion, for 450 silver drachmai bearing interest secured upon a mortage of the real property of Roufos stated in the loan, the second being in Tubi of the following 3rd year to Roufos' full brother Diokles for 416 more silver drachmai upon a mortage of his real prperty stated in the loan, which loans are in Heraklas' possesion, and Heraklas has the right ...</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Grenfell BP-Hunt AS, POxy III, 508, 1903</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Oxy.:3:508</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1262&amp;viewid=C0_IVR.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/I/V/r/C0_IVr.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1262&amp;viewid=C0_IVR.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1262&amp;viewid=C0_IVR.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
