<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Arrangement Regarding Payments</title>
            <author>Leontiskos, son of Leontiskos; Thymos, son of Megakles; Tesenouphis, son of Petous</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1896</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1896</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">5242</idno>
            <idno type="TM">5242</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;3;182</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 3233</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Arrangement regarding the repayment of a debt and its interests owed by Eirene to Nikandros: Eirene had farmed out to Leontiskos, Thymos, and Tesenouphis the crops of the olive, fig, and pomegranate trees in her garden located in Philadelphia; the lessees here agree to give to Nikandros the payments for the crops from this land, which Eirene had previously mortgaged to the same Nikandros; the latter will then credit these payments to the account of Eirene. Eirene's agreement to the terms of this contract is preserved in P.Mich. III, 183 (see also P.Mich. III, 200).</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Papers of Eirene, daughter of Orpheus (see S.B. Pomeroy, Women in Hell.Egypt, p. 158-160)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 17.8 x 31.8 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Some damage along the folds and on the right side</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">52</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The writing is in medium-sized square letters (Schuman)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="-0182">March 4, 182 B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Krokodeilon polis (Arsinoiton polis), Arsinoite nome, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Leontiskos son of Leontiskos, Perses tes epigones (see also P.Mich. III, 183</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">193</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thymos son of Megakles, Makedon tes epigones (see also P.Mich. III, 183</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tesenouphis son of Petous, Arsinoites (see also P.Mich. III, 183</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">193</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">200</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nikandros, Syrakosios, (hippeus), ogdoekontarouros (see also P.Mich. III, 183</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">200)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Theodoros</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Probably Philadelphia, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Krokodeilon polis (Arsinoiton polis), Arsinoite nome; Perses (tes epigones); Makedon (tes epigones); Arsinoeites (Arsinoites); Philadelpheia (Philadelphia), Herakleidou meris</term>
               <term>Soldiers--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Debtor and creditor--Egypt--ArsinoȽ (Fayyïum : Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Ethnic groups--Egypt--ArsinoȽ (Fayyïum : Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Land tenure--Egypt--ArsinoȽ (Fayyïum : Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Leases--Egypt--ArsinoȽ (Fayyïum : Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Weights and measures, Ancient.</term>
               <term>Mortgages--Egypt--ArsinoȽ (Fayyïum : Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Iranians--Egypt</term>
               <term>Farm rents--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Weights and measures, Ancient.</term>
               <term>Women--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Drachma.</term>
               <term>Philadelphia (Egypt : Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Rent--Egypt--ArsinoȽ (Fayyïum : Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Receipts (Acknowledgments)--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Interest--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Talentum (The Latin word)</term>
               <term>Farms--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Farm produce--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Crown lands--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Coinage--Egypt.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Year 23, Panemos 28, Tybi 28, in Krokodilopolis of the Arsinoite nome.;Leontiskos, son of Leontiskos, Persian of the epigone, and Thymos, son of Megakles, Macedonian of the epigone, and Tesenouphis, son of Petous, a resident of Arsinoe, agree with Nikandros, Syracusan, of the troop of Theodoros of the second hipparchy, holder of an eighty-aroura allotment, to pay to him on behalf of Eirene, daughter of Orpheus, a Macedonian woman, to be credited against the loan, with interest, of 44 talents and 4800 drachmai granted in accordance with the mortgage of a vineyard and garden belonging to her located in Philadelphia in the division of Herakleides, contracted in year 23, month of Daisios: 48 talents of bronze money (which is) the rent of the olive, fig, and pomegranate crops located in the aforesaid garden on royal and gift-land within a single boundary which Leontiskos, Thymos, and Tesenouphis have leased from Eirene for the 24th year in accordance with contracts of lease; and (they agree) that they will make payments to Nikandros or to whomsoever he orders, in Philadelphia, according to the clauses in the contracts, from Pauni of the year 23 to Thoth of year 24 2 bronze talens monthly, and in the month of Phaophi 8 bronze talents, and in Hathyr of the same year15 talents, and in Choiak of the same year the remaining 17, Nikandros or his agents providing them with receipts for each payment.;And if they do not make payments in accordance with the prescribed terms, let Leontiskos, Thymos, and Tesenouphis pay as penalty to Nikandros straightway whatever they owe one and a half times. But if they in no way break the contract, let Nikandros receive for Eirene the above-mentioned 48 bronze talents toward the loan on mortgage and the interest in accordance with what was stated above, and whatever  remainder they owe to him in connection with the mortgage. If there is any shortfall in respect of the 48 bronze talents whether through ruin, risk or failure of the crops concerned in the aforesaid leases which Eirene made with the aforesaid men, having received this from Eirene let him make a cancellation of the mortgage in the time specified therein.;And if Nikandros, having received from the aforesaid men the above-mentioned 48 bronze talents, either does not credit them to Eirene or furthermore after receiving the remainder does not cancel the mortgage, let Nikandros pay to Eirene straightway a fine of one thousand silver drachmai of the old Ptolemaic coinage and let it none the less be obligatory for Nikandros to cancel the mortgage. The agreement shall be binding everywhe re.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Schuman VB, PMich III, 182, 1936 -- BL III, 110 (l. 18); BL XI, 131 (l.18)</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1896&amp;viewid=3233.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/3/3/3233.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1896&amp;viewid=3233.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1896&amp;viewid=3233.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/3/3/r/3233r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1896&amp;viewid=3233R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1896&amp;viewid=3233R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
