<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>copy of receipt</title>
            <author>Heraklas alias Herakleon, son of Archelaos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1341</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1341</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.16.13003</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;16;13003</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;16;13003</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">16343</idno>
            <idno type="TM">16343</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1230</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contains a copy of a document that registers the payment of a penalty (prostimon) which Heraclas, son of Archelaos, had paid to the public bankers of Oxyrhynchus on April 21, 159.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">P. Mich. inv. 173a + P. Mich. inv. 175</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 16.3 x 19.5 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light brown papyrus is complete except for the loss of a large piece at the upper left hand corner. The text is also damaged by a number of small abrasions, though the text may easily be restored. This leaf appears to have been cut off on the right side, and there is a kollesis close  to the cut (approximately 0.5 cm. from the right edge) and the loss of minor papyrus fragments renders a calculation of the number of letters lost to the right uncertain, especially in the first line of the text.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-20</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The writing is rather clear and practiced, especially in the first 6 lines, in which the writing remains very regular. Then it becomes more cursive and irregular, especially in the ligatures and abbreviations, but undoubtedly the coarse pen contributes to increase the irregularity. Plenty of close parallels to this hand may be found in R. Seider, Palaeographie der griechischen Papyri, I 1, Stuttgart 1967, no. 35, Taf. 21 (1st hd.), CPR VII 3 (taf. 2), and P. Oxy. XLIV 3172 (as far as the more cursive part of the document is concerned).;There remains a margin of approximately 2 cm. at the top, at the bottom, and at the left side. To the right</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0178">September 2, 178 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Oxyrhynchite nome, Middle Egypt, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraclas aliasHerakleon, son of Archelaos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Amoonios, son of Sarap[. . . .]</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrianus Antoninus Augustus Pius , emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apion, son of Herodes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sogenes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hierakion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Imperator Caesar Marcus Aurelius Antoninus, emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Imperator Licius Aurelius Commodus, emperor</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Oxyrhynchite nome, Middle Egypt, province of Egypt (?)</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Oxyrhynchos.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"Heraclas alias Heracleon, son of Archelaos, from . . . of the city of Oxyrhynchus, to Ammonios, son of Sarap[   ] . . . alias Zeneios, greetings. I have attached this copy of the receipt for the payment of the fine related to the 1/4 of an aroura of the property cultivated with wheat, as stated in the autograph receipts which I have issued, so that you may be informed (on the matter). It runs as follows: In year 22 of Imperator Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrianus Antoninus Augustus Pius, Pharmouthi 26. Heraklas alias Heracleon, son of Archelaos, has paid to Apion, son of Herodes, and his fellow public bankers of Oxyrhynchos, the penalty, which he owed for the admission of the treasury in the 22nd year, on a 1/4 of an aroura, next to the Upper Iseion,;of the property of Sogenes of the private land cultivated with cereal chosen for the construction . . . entered by the royal scribe: 75 drachmas with 6 drachmas, 2 obols and 3 chalkoi for prosdiagraphomena, that was 6 drachmas, 2 obols and 3 chalkoi , in total 81 drachmas, 2 obols and 3 chalkoi.;I, Hierakion, assistant, have signed for 81 drachmas, 2 obols and 3 chalkoi . ;Year 19 of Imperator Caesares Marcus Aurelius Antoninus and Lucius Aurelius Commodus, our lords Augusti, Thoth 5."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Gara A, ZPE 50, 61-6, 1983 -- SB XVI 13003 -- BL XI, 221 (l. 1-2, 12, 14, 14) Gagos T, BASP 34, 44-46, 1997, Pl. 2-3</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:16:13003</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1341&amp;viewid=1230R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/3/0/r/1230r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1341&amp;viewid=1230R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1341&amp;viewid=1230R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
