<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3713</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3713</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 33.5 x 29.3 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at left and right. Kolleais in right center of the sheet. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-37</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 34 (ll. 1465-1502)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. Left margin over 3.5 cm. and right margin over 1.5 cm. Approximately 3 cm. between the two columns. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Isidoros, son of Petalion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 179)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tamaron, daughter of Saturnilus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 233)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, the blind, son of Kiame (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thatres, daughter of Orsenouphis (grandddaughter of Sarap(), son of Imouthes) (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 175)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabous, son of Dioskoros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 226)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aunes, soldier (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 157)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Papiris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpagathes, son of Satabous, grandson of Anchophis, mother Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Theon, son of Theon, grandson of Petheus, mother Zoidous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 177)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Gaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonous, son of Pabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 151)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Syros, son of Papos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 179)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Priskos alias Pasoxis, son of Satabous, grandson of Pnepheros, mother  Thermothis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 215)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Petheus, grandson of Herakles, mother Tauris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son, mother Tamystha (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Heras, grandson of Petheus, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apion, son of Ammonios, grandson of Apion, mother Apollonous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 152)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonarion, daughter of Esouris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 150)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;;Patsontis.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 34.;naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year, obols 2, surcharges chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total obols 2.5;;Isidoros, veteran (son of Petalion);orchard taxes for the 12th year: apomoira drachmas 5, obol 1, tax on the produce of oil obols 4.5, naubion obols 3, chalki 2, surcharges drachma 1, obols 2;;(in left margin: drachmas 12, obols 2) eparourion drachmas 3 obols 2.5, surcharges obols 2, kollybos obol 1, chalki 2, in total  drachmas 11, obols 4.5;;Tamaron, daughter of Saturnilus (granddaughter of Horos, the blind, son of Kiame;(in left margin: obols 6);naubion for the holders of land in release of the 13th year, drachma 1, obols 3, surcharges, obols 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total  drachma 1, obols 5, chalki 2;;Thatres, daughter of Orsenouphis (grandddaughter of Sarap(), son of Imouthes);(in left margin: drachmas 16, obols 20)geometria for the 12th year drachmas 16, obols 2.5, chalki 2, surcharges drahma 1, chalki 2, in total drachmas 17, obols 3;;naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year obols 3, surcharges obol 0.5, kollybos  chalki 2, in total obols 3.5, chalki 2;;Satabous, son of Dioskoros, cultivator of the 4th cleruchy;;taxes on dates for the 12th year in the administrative district of Patsontis, drachmas 7, surcharges obols 3, in total drachmas 7, obols 3;;Aunes, soldier;;land taxes for the 12th year: apomoira drachmas 2, obols 3, tax on the produce of oil obols 2, chalki 2, naubion obol 1.5, surcharges obols 3.5, chalki 2, drachmas 7, obols 3;;eparourion drachmas 3 obols 2.5, surcharges obol 1.5, chalki 2, kollybos obol 0.5, chalki 2, in total  drachmas 6, obols 4;;(in left margin: drachmas 12, obols 22) geometria for the 12th year drachmas 6, obol 1.5, surcharge obols 2.5, in total drachmas 6, obols 3; ;Papiris, cultivator of the 80th cleruchy;;orchard taxes for the 12th year in the administrative district of Patsontis, apomoira drachma 1, chalki 2, naubion obol 1, surcharges obol 1.5;;eparourion obols 4, chalki 2, surcharges obols 0.5, kollybos obols 0.5, in total drachmas 2, obols 2;;date tax for the 12th year drachmas 15, surcharges drachma 1, in total drachmas 16;;Harpagathes, son of Satabous, grandson of Anchophis, mother Sambathion, drachmas 4;;Theon, son of Theon, grandson of Petheus, mother Zoidous, drachmas 4;;Onnophris, son of Gaios for the tax for the epistrategos;charged on wool-shearers for the13th year, drachmas 12, surcharges obols 5, in total drachmas 12, obols 5.;Ammonous, son of Pabous through the agency of Syros, son of Papos, a dyer;;orchard taxes for the 12th year: apomoira drachmas 5, tax on the produce of oil obols 4, chalki 2, naubion obols 3, surcharges drachma 1, obol 1.5;;eparourion drachmas 3, obols 2, surcharges obol 1.5, chalki, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachmas 11, obol 1.5, chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas obols 3, surcharges obols 4.5, chalki 2, in total drachmas 13, obol 1.5, chalki 2;;Priskos alias Pasoxis, son of Satabous, grandson of Pnepheros, mother  Thermothis, drachmas 12;;in total for the day, drachmas 192, obols 10;;(Phamenoth) 27 likewise:;Horos, son of Petheus, grandson of Herakles, mother Tauris, drachmas 16;;Heras, son, mother Tamystha, drachmas 16;;Heras, son of Heras, grandson of Petheus, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 24;;Apion, son of Ammonios, grandson of Apion, mother Apollonous, drachmas 12;;Ammonarion, daughter of Esouris, through Petheus (son of Panabos);;(in the left margin: drachmas 12, obols 21) land tax for the 12th year drachmas 6, obol 1.5, tax on the produce of olives, obols 5.5, naubion obols 4, surcharges drachma 1, obols 3.5, chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 4, obol 1, surcharges obols 2, chalki 2, kollybos obol 1.5, in total drachmas 11, obol 1.5."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 -- BL III, 113 (on l.1441) Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3713&amp;viewid=4171_34R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/3/4/r/4171_34r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3713&amp;viewid=4171_34R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3713&amp;viewid=4171_34R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
