<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3630</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3630</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.224</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 31.1 x 15.2 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at all sides. The sheet is well preserved apart from a vertical tear. 3 kolleseis. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-38</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 1 (ll. 1-39)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of each tax payer. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Ptolemas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Sambas, grandson of Sabeinos, mother Aphrodous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Anchorimphis, grandson of Horos, mother Acheillis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Erieus, mother Antheia (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois, son of Onnophris, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Sampathion, mother Taseus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisois, son of Naaraus the younger, grandson of Theabeneus, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 229)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes, son of Naraaus, grandson of Petheus, mother Taorsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Zenas, son of Phaesis, grandson of Zenas, mother Tapasion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 165)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Petheus, grandson of Aunes, mother Eseremphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron, son of Limnaios, grandson of Maron, mother Thaisas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Artemas, son of Heron, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Petermouthis, grandson of Apyngchis, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos the younger, son of Hatres, grandson of Horos, mother Teraus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus, son of Tesenouphis, grandson of Harpaesis, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Tapsais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabous, son of Dioskoros, grandson of Satabous, mother Tahorion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 226)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Naaraus, grandson of Horion, mother Taorsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harsiesis, son of Petheus, grandson of Harsiesis, mother Thatres (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Onnophris, grandson of Theabeneus, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis, son of Panesneus, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis, son of Petheus, grandson of Horion, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 194)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymion, son of Petheus the older, grandson of Didymion, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 161)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonis, son of Ammonios, grandson of Ammonios, mother Tninis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 151)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Valeris, fatherless, mother Valerias (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 194)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Sambas, mother Taeuemeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 224)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Harpagathes, grandson of Horos, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249 )</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"Hadrianius 11,  (Column) 1;Horos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Ptolemas, 16 drachmas;;Ptolemaios, son of Sambas, grandson of Sabeinos, mother Aphrodous 4 drachmas;;the same12th year, the remainder is the administrator fee;;Horos, son of Angkhoryphis, grandson of Horos, mother Acheillides, 4 bronze drachmas;;Ptolemaios, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Erieus, mother Antheia 8 drachmas;;Sisois, son of Onnophris, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Tapetheus, 16 drachmas;;12th year: Maron, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Sampathion, mother Taseus, 4 bronze drachmas, the remainder is the administrator fee;;Sisois, son of Naaraus the second, grandson of Theabeneus, mother Thaisas, 4 drachmas;;Mysthes, son of Naraaus, grandson of Petheus, mother Taorsenouphis, 12 drachmas;;Zenas, son of Phaesis, grandson of Zenas, mother Tapasion, 8 drachmas;;Horos, son of Petheus, grandson of Auneios, mother Eseremphis, 8 drachmas;;12th year Maron, son of Limnaios, grandson of Maron, mother Thasias 16 drachmas, 4 bronze drachmas;;Artemas, son of Heron, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaesis, 8 drachmas;;Ptolemaios, son of Petermouthis, grandson of Apyngchis, mother Thermouthis, 4 drachmas, 28 obols;;Horos the younger, son of Atreios, grandson of Horos, mother Teraus, 4 drachmas;;Phanomgeus, son of Tesenouphis, grandson of Harpaesis, mother Thaesis, 8 drachmas;;Ptolemaios, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Tapsais, 8 drachmas;;Satabous, son of Dioskoros, grandson of Satabous, mother Taorion, 4 drachmas;;Petaus, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis, 12 drachmas;;Ptolemaios, son of Naaraus, grandson of Horion, mother Taorsenouphis, 8 drachmas;;Harsiesis, son of Petheus, grandson of Harsiesis, mother Thatrious, 4 drachmas;;Heron, son of Onnophris, grandson of Theabeneus, mother Tapetheus, 28 obols;;Pakysis, son of Panesneus, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tapetheus, 4 drachmas;;12th year: Petheus, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetheus, 4 bronze drachmas, 28 obols;;12th year: Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis, 4 bronze drachmas;;Orsenouphis, son of Petheus, grandson of Horion, mother Tapetheus, 8 drachmas;;Petesouchos, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Tasoucharion, 8 drachmas;;Didymion, son of Petheus the elder, grandson of Didymion, mother Tasoucharion, 4 drachmas;;Ammonis, son of Ammonios, grandson of Ammonios, mother Tninis, 4 drachmas;;Valeris, fatherless, mother Valerias, 8 drachmas;;the total for the day 224 drachmas, 8 obols, of which in the12th year 40drachmas, 10 obols;;The 12 of the same (month);;Sambas, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Sambas, mother Taeuemeros, 16 drachmas;;the 12th year, Horos, son of Harpagathes, grandson of Horos, mother Thaesis ; 8 bronze drachmas,  the remainder is the administartor fee of the priests;;The same 13th year,;the same 12th year, priest Isis, daughter of Phramareios, the old;drachmas 1, 2 obols, 2 chalkoi; additional taxes - kollyboi 2 chalkoi, the total 1 drachma, 3.5 obols."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 -- BL III, 113 (line 8 and elsewhere); BL IV, 54 (line 4 and elsewhere)BL XI, 131 (bibliography) Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.:Mich.:4:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3630&amp;viewid=4171_1R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/_/1/r/4171_1r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3630&amp;viewid=4171_1R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3630&amp;viewid=4171_1R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
