<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3631</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3631</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.224</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 31.1 x 15.2 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at all sides. The sheet is well preserved apart from a vertical tear. 3 kolleseis. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-38</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 2 (ll. 40-78)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of each tax payer. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Leonides, grandson of Petheus, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Sisois, grandson of Satabous, mother Thermouthis  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos alias Karanos, son of Petheus, grandson of Herakles, mother Tauris  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, the son, mother Tamystha</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Karanos, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Imothes, mother Tapetsiris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Achillas, son of Heron, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Didyme  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes, son of Petheus, grandson of Mysthes, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Souchas, grandson of Heras, mother Tapetheus  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apynchis, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tasoucharion  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 154)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phasis, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Thaisas  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 246)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasoknopaios, son of Phasis, grandson of Esouris, mother Tanomgeus  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 199)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Thaisas  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Perigenes, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Tanaios  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Horos, mother Eserempis  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus, son of Petheus, grandson of Satabous, mother of Tamystha  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Anchophis, grandson of Herakles, mother Teseuris  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petsiris, son of Pasoknopiaos, grandson of Petsiris, mother Heros  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 211)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mystharion, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Euhemeros, mother Tapethis  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 188)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Onnophris, grandson of Petaus, mother Tkateis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Kames, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Tbellis  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Achillas, son of Phaesis, grandson of Zenas, mother Tasigonis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Athenion, son of Pyrrhos, grandson of Athenion, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 150)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Sokmenis, grandson of Sambas, mother Tkollainis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 224)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Onnophris, mother Tkollainis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinos, son of Petheus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Herakleia (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ninis, son of Askla, grandson of Ninis, mother Tabous, (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Harmiysis, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petaus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchophis, son of Anchophis, grandson of Petheus, mother Taorsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor alias Sabeinos, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Satabous, mother Melitous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 182)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Polydeukes, son of Hera, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapasion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 214)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Kelolis, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 170)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"  Column B;Ptolemaios, son of Leonides, grandson of Petheus, mother Thermouthis, 16 drahmas;;Petaus, son of Sisois, grandson of Satabous, mother Thermouthis, 8 drachmas;;Horos alias Karanos, son of Petheus, grandson of Herakles, mother Tauris, 4 bonze drachmas;;Heras, the son, mother Tamystha, 4 bronze drachmas;;Karanos, son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Imothes, mother Tapetsiris, 16 drachmas;;The same12th, the remainder is the administrator fee;;Achillas, son of Heron, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Didyme, 8 drachmas;;Mysthes, son of Petheus, grandson of Mysthes, mother Tasoucharion, 4 drachmas;;Heras, son of Souchas, grandson of Heras, mother Tapetheus, 4 drachmas;;Apynchis, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Pakysis, mother Tasoucharion, 8 drachmas;;Phasis, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Thaisas, 16 obols, guard of the aqueducts;;Pasoknopaios, son of Phasis, grandson of Esouris, mother Tanomgeus, 8 drachmas;;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Thaisas, 8 drachmas;;Sarapion, son of Perigenes, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Tanaios, 4 drachmas, 28 obols;;the same 12th year, the remainder is the administrator fee;;Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Horos, mother Eserempis, 12 drachmas;;Phanomgeus, son of Petheus, grandson of Satabous, mother of Tamystha, 4 drachmas;;Horos, son of Anchophis, grandson of Herakles, mother Teseuris, 4 drachmas;;Petsiris, son of Pasoknopiaos, grandson of Petsiris, mother Heros, 4 drachmas;;Mystharion, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Euhemeros, mother Tapethis, 8 drachmas; ;Petaus, son of Onnophris, grandson of Petaus, mother Tkateis, drachmas 8 drachmas;;Sarapion, son of Kames, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis, 28 obols;;Chairemon, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Tbellis, 8 drachmas;;Total for the day: drachmas 96, 24 obols of which the12th year drachmas drachmas 20, 23 obols; for  the priests listed below 12 obols; as payment for the 12th year, 12 obols;;The13th of the same (month);;Achillas, son of Phaesis, grandson of Zenas, mother Tasigonis, 20 drachmas;;Athenion, son of Pyrrhos, grandson of Athenion, mother Tasoucharion, 12 drachmas;;Sambas, son of Sokmenis, grandson of Sambas, mother Tkollainis, 4 drachmas;;Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Onnophris, mother Tkollainis, 8 drachmas;;Sabinos, son of Petheus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Herakleia, 4 drachmas;;Ninis, son of Askla, grandson of Ninis, mother Tabous, 8 drachmas; ;Ptolemaios, son of Harmiysis, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tasoucharion, 4 drachmas;;Petesouchos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petaus, mother Thaesis, 12 drachmas;;Anchophis, son of Anchophis, grandson of Petheus, mother Taorsenouphis, 12 drachmas;;Kastor alias Sabeinos, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Satabous, mother Melitous, 8 drachmas;;Polydeukes, son of Hera, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapasion, 8 drachmas;;Heras, son of Kelolis, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis, 8 drachmas;"</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3631&amp;viewid=4171_2R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3631&amp;viewid=4171_2R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3631&amp;viewid=4171_2R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
