<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Agreement not to Prosecute</title>
            <author>Didymos, son of Maron, and his daughter Herakleia</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1355</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1355</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.340</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;340</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;340</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12149 12150</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12149 12150</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1271</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Rough drafts of two contracts, prepared at the grapheion according to the wishes of the parties; the ages and signalments of the various parties are left blank, and the subscriptions are in the hand of a clerk. The second contract (recto, col. III) is an agreement by which Didymos and his daughter Herakleia pledge themselves not to raise any claims against Patynis, son of Apollonios, on account of a fifth share of a house and courtyard in Tebtynis which they had previously disputed and which Patynis had acquired in some way and had sold to Chrates, son of Harpaesis</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto, col. III; see also recto, col. I-II, and Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 40 x 28 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">broken off on the left side</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto, col. III - 42</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Second text (Recto, col. III)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Recto: medium-sized cursive, resembling that of P.Mich. V, 244 and almost certainly penned by the writer of P.Mich. V, 226; Verso: a sloping cursive different from the hand on the recto (Boak)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0045" notAfter="0046">45-46 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Patynis son of Apollonios (see P.Mich. II, p. 227</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chrates son of Harpaesis (see also P.Mich. II, 127)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris</term>
               <term>Covenants not to sue--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Guardian and ward--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Women--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Home ownership--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Didymos, son of Maron, about       years old, with a scar                                , and his daughter Herakleia, about       years old, with a scar                                , under the guardianship of her husband Haryotes, son of Lysimachos, about       years old, with a scar                                , make an agreement with Patynis, son of Apollonios, about       years old, with a scar                                , that, since the parties of the first part have had a dispute with Patynis over a fifth part of the 'so-called new' house and courtyard, and its 'entrance' and exit, in Tebtynis of the division of Polemon, which has been sold by Patynis in the past year [[and since consequently the parties of the first part]] in accordance with the contracts affecting property rights which he enjoyed, and since consequently the parties of the first part concur in his remaining rights, they in no wise accuse or shall accuse Patynis or Chrates, son of Harpaesis, who has purchased from him in respect to the aforesaid fifth part in any way. And if they shall prosecute or bring accusation, apart from the prosecution and accusation to be brought on behalf of any of them being invalid, he shall in addition pay to Patynis himself at once both the damages and double the expenses and as a penalty 500 drachmai in silver and an equal sum to the treasury, and nonetheless the terms agreed upon shall be valid, [[Subscription of Patynis]] without diminution of the rights of Didymos and Patynis over the part of other places in another parcel in the same village which each claims to possess.;Subscription:;We, Didymos, son of Maron, and my daughter Herakleia, acting under the guardianship of her husband Haryotes, son of Lysimachos, agree that we shall not prosecute or accuse Patynis in accordance with all the aforesaid. I, Haryotes, wrote for my wife since she is illiterate.;Subscription:;I, Didymos, son of Maron, agree not to prosecute or accuse Patynis in accordance with all the aforesaid.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Edgerton WF-Husselman EM, PMich V, 340, recto, col. III, 1944</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:340</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1355&amp;viewid=1271R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/7/1/R/1271R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1355&amp;viewid=1271R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1355&amp;viewid=1271R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
