<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Land cession</title>
            <author>Unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2095</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2095</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.18.13764</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;18;13764</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;18;13764</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14759</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14759</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 3761</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Cession of two plots of catoechic land: one of 4 arouras and one of 3 arouras.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso contains remains of two columns of 2-line entries.</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 25.2 x 20 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">A light-brown papyrus partly regularly cut off at the left and bottom. 1.5 cm. from the left edge is a kollesis.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-26</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in an upright and detached hand. Each entry on the verso is preceded by a number (65/66 and 76/77/78 are still readable) which one of the numbers of the klerouchies at Karanis. At the left is a free margin of 2 cm. and at the bottom one of 5 cm. Since l. 1 has been written by the same hand which wrote the other lines and since no personal subscription seems to have been added at the bottom, we are in all probability dealing with a copy.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0148" notAfter="0161">Between 148 A. D. - 161 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrianus Antoninus Augustus Pius, emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sochotes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapias</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptollarion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dionysios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt (?)</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>- - - division of the Arsinoite nome</term>
               <term>Administration</term>
               <term>land tenure</term>
               <term>land transfer</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary; land cession</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"- - - of  the - - - division of the Arsinoite nome. Year - - - of Imperator Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrianus Antoninus Augustus Pius on the -th of the month - - in - - of the - - - division of the Arsinoite nome. N. N., son of N. N., grandson of Sochotes, aged about 54 years - - - and N. N., sonof N. N., grandson of N. N., aged about - - years - - - both priests (?) of - -, the twice great god and of the associate gods of the fifth phyle acknowledge to Sarapias, daughter of N. N., granddaughter of N. N., aged about - - years  - - - with as guardian for transaction N. N. son of N. N., grandson of N. N., aged about 28 years with a chopped off finger, that they have ceded to her for conveyance from now on for all time three arouras of a catoechic holding formerly in the  possession of N. N., son of N. N., in the neighbourhood of the village - - in the - - division of the Arsinoite nome which belong to them and which were bought in accordance with a deed of sale drawn up through the record-office in the metropolis in Phaophi of year 12 and - - aroura(s) of land assigned to the village and four arouras of a catoechic holding in - - formerly in the possession of N. N., daughter of N. N., granddaughter of Apion but now in the possession of - -  the twice great god and all the associate gods (acquired ?) in Pharmouthi of the -th with their existing boundaries and entrances and exits and watering-places and drains and all the other rights, of which the neighbours are, as, according to the acknowledging party, the cessions encompass: of the three arouras and the assigned land: in the South - - -, in the North - - - in the middle being an irrigation canal, in the west the holding formerly of Aphrodisios, in the East the holding of Ptollarion in the middle being a watering-place and of the four arouras: in the South a canal, in the North dry land on which there are date-palms fit for being fructuated in the middle being - - -, in the West - - - field, in the East the holding of Dionysios in the middle being the canal through which the ceded arouras are irrigated - - -. Enforceable shall also be the transactions registered in the list of katalochismoi. The acknowledging party has received from Sarapias the sum fixed for the cession of the arouras ceded as above-written: Petesouchos thousand sixhundred silver drachmas and N. N. - - silver drachmas through the money-changers bank of N. N. near the colonnade of Athena; and the acknowledging party themselves, Petesouchos and N. N., and their cessionaries shall guarantee with full security for Sarapias and her cessionaries the ceded arouras in accordance with the above-described boundaries and neighbours, which they shall transfer neither encumbered, nor liable to distraint, nor mortgaged, and free of all public duties, artaba-taxes, naubia, numeration-taxes, assessments, debt-entries, fines - - -, land assigned to the village and Petesouchos (shall) also (guarantee it) free of all land assigned to the village from the former times up to the past -th year of Antoninus CAesar the lord included, as well as from private obligations and every claim whenever. Nobody shall hinder Sarapias and her cessionaries to have possession of the in total seven and - - - arouras ceded to her as above-written - - -and to gain the produce of them - - - and to use the other uses according to the custom from the beginning up till now and as is made clear by (the) public documents.The acknowledging party shall neither prosecute nor accuse nor dispute with a view to the afore-mentioned agreement. If they transgress in any way they shall pay to Sarapias as a fine the cession sum which they received from her with a surplus of 50 %, twice the amount of the damages and the expenses, and to the Treasury the same sum. Nevertheless both the afore-mentioned agreement and the transactions registered in the list of katalochismoi shall remain enforceable forever."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn PJ, Tyche 1, 180-3, 1986 -- SB XVIII, 13764 -- BL IX, 305 (l. 9); BL X, 222 (l. 5)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:18:13764</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2095&amp;viewid=3765R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2095&amp;viewid=3765R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2095&amp;viewid=3765R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2095&amp;viewid=3765V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2095&amp;viewid=3765V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
