<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter</title>
            <author>Unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.5196</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)5196</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.Inv. 436</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 20.4 x 12.3 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Dark brown papyrus with a roughened surface; it is badly damaged at the middle as a result of horizontal and vertical folds; the papyrus has lost a portion at the right side to the top as a result of another horizontal fold, and badly damaged line 3 as a result of the same fold. Broken off at the left and bottom; it preserves the right and top margins in which it is regularly cut. The preserved text is clear and readable. The fibers are frayed at the several spots. Small strip of papyrus is removed at the bottom to the left side. There is a horizontal kollesis almost at the middle</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">11</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written along the fibers in very large cursive letters with a tendency to uncial. The hand is slightly careless that there is some letters have been corrected, and the scribe dipped his pen into the inkwell to be sure getting the right form of those letters. The interlinear spaces are almost even of ca. 0.5 cm. The scribe wrote the opening of his letter by writing the letters in larger scale than the body of the text; alpha with two loops the lower one invade the interlinear space; V-shaped upsilon; iota shaped in a vertical stroke with a hook at the top; rounded big omicron. No abbreviations or other diacritical marks are attested.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0300" notAfter="0399">IVth Century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-5196&amp;viewid=1">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
