<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter to the Praefectus Annonae Alexandrinae</title>
            <author>Flavius Claudius Patricius</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2136</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2136</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.turner.45</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0214;;45</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.turner;;45</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">15703</idno>
            <idno type="TM">15703</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4022</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Notification to the exactor of the Oxyrhynchite nome from the praefectus annonae Alexandrinae that two shipments of wheat from the nome had been brought to imperial storehouses in the vicinity of Alexandria and duly entered in the records there.  According to l. 24 the original letter of which this text is a copy, although addresses to the nome exactor, was turned over to one of the epimeletai who supervised the shipment as a receipt.  Nonetheless, the present papyrus plainly did not remain in the Alexandrian office.;In addition to the docket (26-27), the back contains two short accounts which have no connection with the main text. The first is dated to a fifth indiction, presumably A.D. 376/7. As a sample, l. 3, " from Kopreus and his brothers, on account of rent 31 1/2 art., on account of arrears 7 art., interest 2 1/3 art., together 40 5/6 art". From the second account, which follows in the same hand after a blank space of 6 cm: (l. 9) "of these 13 art. were brought up to the city by Kopreus on Mesore 25".</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is described, still unpublished</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 34 x 26 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The papyrus is complete and only at the folding areas of the recto is a little mutilated. There is a  fragment of c. 5 x 3 cm (folded) blank (does it belong to the same papyrus?)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">recto: 25 lines;verso: 2 lines concerning this document</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Large letters of about 1 c. in breadth and in height.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0374">April 10, 374 A.D. (or after)</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Oxyrhynchos, Oxyrhynchite nome, Middle Egypt, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Flavius Claudius Patricius, clarissimus praefectus annonae Alexandriae</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion, son of Ptolemaios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hesychios, son of Ioulianos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gratianus, consul</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Flavius Equitius, comes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Agathos daimon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Megetios, hypodektes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Flavius Nemesion, hupodektes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Asklas, hupodektes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Arios, tabularius</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Flavius Isidoros, tabularius</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Flavius Epimachos, oikonomos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Proechios, oikonomos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dionysios, auditing (?) assistant</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Paomios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Paabeus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Flavius Ammonios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelios Sarapion</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Oxyrhynchos, Oxyrhynchite nome, Middle Egypt, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Alexandria, province of Egypt</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Copy. Flavius Claudius Patricius, clarissimus praefectus annonae Alexandriae, to the exactor of the Oxyrhynchite nome, greeting. Know that in accordance with the report which you sent to the office one thousand nine hundred and forty-three artabas of wheat for the 2nd indiction have been brought to the sacrd granaries in the vicinity of Alexandria from the nome under your administation through Horion, son of Ptolemaios and Hesychios, son of Ioulianos and their associate supervisors, through the skippers named below: on the day before the nones of April eight hundred and ninety and a half artabas, and on the fourth day before the ides of the same month one thousand and fifty-two and a half artabas, in the consulship of our lord Gratianus, eternal Augustus, for the third time and of count Fl. Equitios, vir clarissimus; and (know further that) these are being entered into the accounts with a subscription by Agathos Daimon, Megetios, Nemesion, and Asklas, receivers in the civil service (?). My devotion has been informed by a report (made) at their own risk by Arios and Isidoros, tabularii of the office, Epimachos and Proechios, oikonomoi, and Dionysios, auditing (?) assistant, of which a copy is appended, and I have ordered that these facts be written in reply to you in consideration of the payment. Farewell.;To wit: through Paomios, 890 1/2 art.; through Paabeus, 1052 1/2 art.;Fl. Isisdoros, tabularios: the stated quantity of wheat, amounting to one thousand nine hundred and forty-three artabas, is accurate as stated.;I , Fl. Nemesion, receiver, have signed the receipt for the wheat,  amounting to one thousand nine hundred and forty-three artabas exactly.;Fl. Epimachos, oikonomos: the stated quantity of wheat,  amounting to one thousand nine hundred and forty-three artabas, is accurate.;Fl. Ammonios, assistant: it is accurate,  amounting to one thousand nine hundred and forty-three artabas of wheat exactly.;(m. 2) I, Aurelios Serapion, supervisor, have received together with my associates the original receipt of which you presented this copy, as stated.;(back) ( m. 3?) Paymios 890 1/2 art. wheat and Paabeus 1052 1/2 art. wheat, skippers, for the 2nd indiction.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Shelton JC, PTurner, 45, 1981, Pl XX -- BL X 278</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Turner:45</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2136&amp;viewid=4022R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/2/r/4022r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2136&amp;viewid=4022R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2136&amp;viewid=4022R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/2/v/4022v.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2136&amp;viewid=4022V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2136&amp;viewid=4022V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
