<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Astrological Treatise</title>
            <author>Unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1290</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1290</idno>
            <idno type="dclp">63547</idno>
            <idno type="TM">63547</idno>
            <idno type="dclp-hybrid">p.mich;3;149</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Astronomical treatise, presenting  a doctrine assigning parts of the body to the tutelage of the planets and a discussion of the phases of each planet in relation to the sun - both based on a description of planetary motion. The text is the result of excerpting, without understanding, sources of very different level, and is not consistent</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>18 papyri ; Total size of fragments 1-10 (col. I-XV): ca. 140 x 23.8 cm.;Frg. 1 (col. I-II): 12.5 x 17.7 cm;;frg. 2 (col. II-III): 12.5 x 22 cm;;frg. 3 (col. III): 1.5 x 8 cm;;frg. 4 (col. III-IV): 11.2 x 22 cm;;frg. 5 (col. V) 3 x 21.2 cm;;frg. 6 (col. V-VI): 14.5 x 23.5 cm;;frg. 7 (col. VI-X): 48 x 23.5 cm;;frg. 8 (col. XI-XIII): 23.5 x 22 cm;;frg. 9 (col. XIII-XIV): 5.5 x 11.2 cm;;frg. 10 (col. XIV-XV): 8 x 20.7 cm;;frg. 11 (col. XVI-XVII): 10.8 x 17.5 cm;;frg. 12 (col. XVII) 0.8 x 9.5 [now 0.8 x 7] cm;;frg. 13 (col. XVII): 5 x 10.7 cm;;frg. 14 (col. XVIII): 8 x 22.7 cm;;frg. 15 (col. XIX): 3.3 x 5.8 cm;;frg. 16 (col. XX): 4.7 x 9 cm;;frg. 17 (col. XXI): 5.2 x 11 cm;;frg. 18 (col. XXII): 4.5 x 3 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Broken off at the left and right (some fragments also at the top and/or bottom); badly damaged at some places</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. i - 26;;Col. ii - 36;;Col. iii - 40;;Col. iv - 43;;Col. v - 45;;Col. vi - 40;;Col. vii - 40;;Col. viii - 37;;Col. ix - 39;;Col. x - 41;;Col. xi - 47;;Col. xii - 46;;Col. xiii - 42;;Col. xiv - 35;;Col. xv - 39;;Col. xvi - 35;;Col. xvii - 31;;Col. xviii - 40;;Col. xix - 11;;Col. xx - 18;;Col. xxi - 20;;Col. xxii - 6</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto; col. i-xxii</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Clear, rounded uncial, with some variations of size (Robbins, 1927)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0100" notAfter="0199">IInd century  A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Astrology, Egyptian.</term>
               <term>Astrology, Greek.</term>
               <term>Astronomy, Ancient--Egypt.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Subliterary: Astrology</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col. I);;[- - -] . . . Of the fore parts the sphere of the Sun [should be considered] first, for [Saturn and the Sun have] the smallest variation in latitude; it is, then, in size 2 1/2×, that is, 150', for the degree contains 60'; the moon's is 6×, or 360'; that of Saturn 10×, or 600'; that of Jupiter 13× 45'; next, Mercury's sphere is 21× 15' or 1275'; and the sphere of Mars is 42×, or 2520'. The sphere of Venus is the largest, exceeding the breadth of the circle of the zodiac, in which the divinity is exalted and depressed; her sphere, then, is 48× or 2880'. Such is the circuit of their orbits; and by this . . .;;(Col. II) [- - -] . . . they come to apogee and have least apparent motion. Then standing still they begin to turn back . . . to the eye seeming . . . and they seem to move (the faster?) by as much as they are seen to . . ., and with accelerated movement . . . left behind by the Sun on their downward circuit they reach their own spheres. After this they come to perigee and have their greatest apparent motion. Thus the height and the breadth of their epicycles are the cause of the anomaly in their course, for their daily motion is always the same, that of the Sun 59' 8'' 16''', of the Moon 13 whole degrees and 10', of Saturn 2', of Jupiter 5', of Mars 32', and of Venus and Mercury the same as the Sun. These latter two, however, differ from the Sun by reason of their epicycles; for though they have a daily motion that is equal to the Sun's their movement in height and in breadth is not equal to his; but when they get farther south or farther north than the Sun they seem to make retrogressions, or they are passed by the Sun and stand fixed; or they are depressed and run ahead of the Sun. At such times Venus seems to run 5' {5'} &lt;read: 35'&gt;, so as to move more swiftly than the Sun, and Mercury 3× 6', that is, 186'. Since such is their order, [one may] in accordance with the epicycles of each one of them select a portion and by those measures assign it to each, both from the forward parts of the image and from the backward parts. Of the 2880' of Venus, then, one-third is 960' . . .;;(Col. III);[- - -] . . . Next in order, of the 6 1/2× of the Moon, one-third is 2 1/6×, that is, 130'; accordingly at this one hundred thirtieth point the must mark out the Moon's portion. It will extend to the tip of the chin. The visage is the most wonderful part of the image. Thus the whole head is the tabernacle of the Sun and the Moon, but he controls the faculty of knowledge, and she that of change and of affection; and from Mercury comes the faculty of thought, but from the Sum the directive faculty; but the faculty of interpretation is attached to the portion of the Moon, tongue, mouth and speech. For this reason this section is related to each of the sectae and is not far removed from the leader, the Sun. Accordingly, as in man the face is most remarkable for its changes and the affections that occur to it, so the Moon, in the universe, is remarkable for its changes of colors and for its illuminations and emanations. The Moon alone aids the . . . accepting . . . ten times in the course of the year . . . and paying back its waxings and wanings through a period of 28 days . . . And the face is the grace . . . and the Sun . . . the changes most proper to it . . .;;(Col. IV);[- - -] . . . The epicycle of Jupiter measures 13× 45', which is 825', of which one-third is 275'. Accordingly at the two hundred seventy-fifth point we must mark off the portion of Jupiter. It includes the breast as far as the stomach and the liver, in which reside fire, the mental faculty, and the appetitive faculty because the conversion into blood of the food which is introduced into the body is performed by the liver. It is for just this reason that the faculty of command is assigned to this portion; for truly the leader takes forethought for the state as the liver does for the body. If indeed the region of the liver becomes diseased, the whole body immediately becomes jaundiced or dropsical and like a corpse, because the blood is not properly managed. Therefore such things come to mankind from Jupiter, and therefore also the omens are observed in the livers of the victims by those who perform sacrifices, and appetites for food and sexual intercourse come from the liver. For from its entrance a broad vessel reaches to the seminal regions, and thus, of the food, a part is made into blood and distributed to the veins and part is divided off into that vessel and becomes semen. For this reason the testicles are on either side. For the sake of this also . . . applied to Zeus the epither "of many offspring"; and within . . . Next in order the epicycle of Mercury measures 21× 15', or 1275'; one-third of the epicycle is 425'. Accordingly at the four hundred twenty-fifth point we must mark off the portion of Mercury . . .;;(Col. V);[- - -] . . . And next the epicycle of Mars measures 42× or 2520', one-third of which is 840'; so at the eight hundred fortieth point we must mark off the portion of Mars. t will include the hands from the wrists, the pubes, the genital organs, the thighs and knees, and will end at the shins. For this reason the principle of the seed is naturally aroused in the period of Mars, who returns to his original position every 15 years; so at that time boys show signs of manhood, their voices break and they show the outward signs of puberty according to the times which the fates may hold for them; for in some cases they will be found to bring it about in 12 years, in some in 13, in some in 14, in some in 15, and in some in 16 or a little more; for these things come about in consequence of the ascensions of the Sun. From Mars indeed come manhood and the impulse to arms, from about the fifteenth year; for this reason boys are given the Olympic crown even in the twelfth year, in the zodiacal period of Jupiter, but they do not bear arms unless the period of Mars, 15 years, has been fulfilled. Castrations, the cutting off of the genital organs, the changes of women, and abortions come from Mars; and further, both incontinence and virginity are within his province, when he is moved in a certain way - about which things I have spoken in the book on the influences of the stars. Again, the breaking of thighs, the wrenching of knees, and the bruising and wounding of the shins are from Mars.;The last epicycle, which brings to an end the forward parts of the image, is that of Venus, measuring 48× or 2880', and one-third of this is 960'. The portion of Venus is from the shins to the toe nails . . .;;(Col. VI);[- - -] . . . the 840' are also slavish . . . below this we must assign 50' to the Sun as his portion. It will reach to the neck, which portion we assigned to the Sun as leader and master; then are assigned . . . fostered by the Sun somewhat in this manner; for these affections are from above. But at 130' we must mark off the portion of the Moon; and it will include the calves; and somehow, whenever we see a noteworthy face, we go around and straightway see the calf of the leg, since naturally the portion of the Moon which is akin to it leads us all to this. Afflictions, fractures, and amputations of the legs come about through the Moon's influence. Then to 200' is the portion of Saturn, the back of the knees and extremities of the hams of ever wearied men. Then to 275' is the portion of Jupiter; the hams; hence beloved boys and those who are well adapted for the practice are led to these courses through the influence of Jupiter; Ganymede serves to express this in mythology for those whose courses are natural.. And at 425' we must mark off the portion of Mercury; it will include the buttocks to the hip-joints and a little higher. This region also aids the belly and is impure. Accordingly when people have a base disease and suffer unnaturally, if it be against their will and consent, then it will be found that in the genitures of these men Venus is injured in these daemonic degrees of Mercury; but if it is by their own devices the star of Mercury will be found injured in these same degrees. The rest belongs to Mars as far as the middle of the neck; for the neck is divided; at that point the 840' ends. For the whole head belongs to the Sun and the Moon, but of the neck the forward part belongs to Saturn and the back to Mars; for this reason . . . bear on their backs.;;(Col. VII);[- - -] . . . as far as the last degree of Aries increasing . . . if it be found . . . from the first degree of Leo. Count the degrees until you come to the degree of the star and take one-third of the number, and if it is less than 16, the star is in dominant degrees, but if more than what they are up to Capricornus and away from Taurus. So must you do: if the star os fpimd om these quadrants between the first degree and the remainder of the quadrant up to the last degree, you must observe and take one-third of it and similarly observe whether the discovered number is more or less than 16. So that what I say may be easier and readier to understand, thus shall it be known: from 1× of Leo to 18× of Virgo there are fulfilled three times 16, of the fore parts, and from 1× [of Aquarius] to 18× [of Pisces] similarly; and again, from 12× [of Gemini] to 30× of Cancer, and from 12×  [of Sagittarius] to 30× of Capricorn. The degrees of the forward parts are 48 altogether. And from 18× of Virgo [to 30× of Libra and from 18× of Pisces to 30× of Aries is 42×; and from 1× of Taurus to 12× of Gemini, as well as from 1×óof Scorpio to 12× of Sagittarius, is 42×]. And they all belong to the external degrees and hinder parts.;And these are likewise the true and natural termini of the seven gods, the peculiar possessions of each several one of them. For example, [from 1× of Leo and Aquarius to 2 1/2× is the terminus of the Sun, and from] 2 1/2× of Leo and Aquarius to 6 1/2× is the terminus of the Moon; from 6 1/2× to 10×, of Saturn; from 10× to 13× 45' of Jupiter; from 13× 45' to 24× 15' of Mercury; from 24× 15' of Leo to 12× of Virgo, and from 24× 15' of Aquarius to 12× [of Pisces], of Mars; and from 12× of Virgo [and of Pisces] to 18× of Virgo and of Pisces belongs to Venus. These are dominant [degrees]. Again, from 12× of Gemini and 12× of Sagittarius to 14 1/2× of Gemini and 14 1/2× of Sagittarius belongs to the Sun; these termini are dominant degrees up to 18× of the two signs; to 22× of the two signs is the property of Saturn . . .;;(Col. VIII);[- - -] . . . and from 18× of Virgo and Pisces to 20 1/2× of both signs is the terminus of the Sun, daemonic; from 20 1/2× of both signs to 24 1/2× is the Moon's terminus; from 241 /2× of both signs to 28× is the terminus of Saturn; [from 28×] of both to 1× 45' of Libra and Aries to [14× 15' of Libra and Aries is the terminus of Mercury; and from 14× 15' of both signs to 30× of Libra and] Aries is the terminus of MArs, daemonic. Again, from 1× of Scorpio and of Taurus to 12× of Sagittarius [and of Gemini] is the terminus of Mars. Thus let these termini be marked out.;There are two sects, of night and day, of the Sun and [of the Moon], and the Sun rules the day and the Moon runs the night. Saturn and Jupiter are the bodyguards of the Sun, Mars and Venus of the Moon; Mercury belongs to the Moon by night and to the Sun by day. Whenever, then, it is needful to test a star so must you test it. In diurnal genitures . . . let the [diurnal] star be found within the 16×, [and the nocturnal] outside of them; and in nocturnal genitures, let the nocturnal stars be found within and the diurnal outside of the 16×; for the reverse is evil. And preferably let the lords of the houses of the luminaries and the masters of the centers and the lords of the loci be found upon the numbers; for greater happiness results; and preferably let the sects be performing their own proper acts; for the exchange of properties between the sects is fatal.;There are seven significant signs, the horoscope, the fourth from it, the fifth, the seventh, the ninth, the tenth, and the eleventh. Let, therefore, the stars that form the geniture be ruling their houses in the significant signs, and so let them be found, for this is best. Andf let the diurnal stars be at the diurnal centers not only in terms of signs, but also of degrees, or let them be moving toward the centers, and let the nocturnal stars be retreating. But in the nocturnal genitures, let the nocturnal stars;;(Col. IX);be at the nocturnal centers in terms of signs and degrees . . . their advance is hostile . . . if at night, the Moon. And by day let the Sun abide in a masculine sign, by  night, the Moon. By day let Saturn be at the horoscope or zenith, standing in some relation to the geniture; by night similarly Mars; for the reverse is bad, particularly if they are not sympathetic to the geniture.;The centers are called horoscope, zenith, occident, nadir. The second from the horoscope is Hope; the third Friends and Goddess; the fourth Foundation, Base, Resource; the fifth Good Fortune; the sixth Daemonie; the seventh Sign of Death; the eighth Inactive; the Ninth Defection and Region of Strange Land; the tenth Accomplishment; the eleventh Good Daemon; [the twelfth Evil Daemon]. Now according to Asclepius the subjects of the inquiry are thus arranged; from the horoscope questions of length of life are to be sought; from the second in the upward direction, livelihood; from the third, brothers; from the fourth, parents; from the fifth, children; from the sixth, injury or suffering; from the seventh, wife; from the eighth, fortune and death that puts a bound to all, according to the lords of these houses. We, however, seek from the horoscope length of life and peculiarities of soul, from the Sun father, patrimony, leaders, and the senses; from the Moon mother, maternal endowment, and body; from Saturn the confirmation of every written instrument, evil or good, and benefit from inheritances from elders and from the death of outsiders, and crops from the earth; from Jupiter offices, preisthoods, knowledge, children, wealth; from Mars, brothers, and arts of violence carried out by means of fire and iron. Injury comes from Mars, Saturn and the horoscope; by  day . . . from Saturn to Mars . . .;;(Col. X);[- - -] . . . [we inquire about] death from the descending sign, and call it the Theme of Death; and in all the book on planetary effects . . . But now we must speak of the phases of the stars or about the Sun's rising and setting . . . And the motion of the planets thus brings about in the case of Mercury and Venus the occasions of their being left behind or running ahead, and in the case of the three remaining planets their stations and retrogressions. Now when the Sun runs 15× away from the stars, the stars rise and exercise especial power upon genitures. Mars is an excessively evil influence at rising until he has escaped from the hostile fire of the Sun. Mercury again overtakes the Sun only after having been left 22× behind him; for as he descends his sphere he comes closer to the earth; but when Venus has been left 48× behind and has stood still, she descends her own proper sphere and overtakes the Sun. Thereafter, being the more depressed, they again precede him by the same distance, and when they have been elevated on their spheres they have their evening stations. Then they are again overtaken by him and within the 15× their concealments take place. The stars are in concord with their effects . . .;;(Col. XI);[- - -] . . . when they stand still they are powerful in their proper effects. But the three stars rising in opposition to the Sun move, preceding the Sun and removed from him by 15×; they come to a standstill when they are 120× away from him and are powerful in their influences; when they are 180× away and are in opposition to him they make their western evening rising and still retreat; then they turn backward in their course and are unfavorable to their own effects; then for the second time they stand still; and at the first [of their station] their significance is good, but at the end evil. Now they await the Sun, and stand still when the sun is 120× distant from them. Then they are concealed and are divergent from their effects. But Mars besides has two other phases, the ninety-day anomalies, when he is in the sextile aspect to the Sun; and in the first he is strongly maleficent and makes evil those who have their nativities at the time; but in the second [he makes] them daring, bold, evildoers and robbers caught in the act; then coming toward him the Sun is in the sexitle aspect to him.;These are called their configurations and phases. There are four configurations of the Sun, two equinoxes in the eighth degree of Aries and of Libra, and two solstices, the summer, in the eighth degree of Cancer, and the winter in the eighth degree of Capricorn. Of the Moon there are preeminently four configurations: conjunction, when it is unseen(?); first half-moon, when it is seven days old; full moon, when it is fourteen; second half-moon when it is twenty-one. The Moon looses the bonds of longitude and latitude in seven-day periods, but the Sun at the solstitial and equinoctial degrees.;The signs, because of the obliquity of the circle, do not ascend in equal periods, but vary in seven different regions or climes. For in the Ethiopic clime Aries ascends in twenty-two periods and Libra in thirty-eight, in which the amount to be added is 2 2/3; in the Syrian clime Aries ascends in twenty-one and Libra in thirty-nine periods, and the amount to be added or subtracted is 3. In the Rhodian clime [Aries ascends] in twenty and Libra in forty periods, and the amount added or subtracted is 3 1/3; in the clime of Asia and Ionia Aries ascends in nineteen and Libra in forty-one, wherein the amount added or subtracted is 3 2/3; in the clime of Argos;;(Col. XII);Aries ascends in eighteeen [and Libra in forty-two, and the amount] added [is 4]; in the clime of Rome and Italy and maritime Gaul Aries ascends [in seventeen and] Libra in forty-three, and the amount added or subtracted is 4 1/3; in . . ., Germany and [Britain] Aries ascends [in sixteen] and Libra in forty-four, and the amount added or subtracted is 4 2/3. Now in every clime Cancer and Capricornus ascend in thirty periods; fifteen periods equal one equinoctial hour, and the period is of primary importance with reference to life.;For the rest, of the signs of the zodiac some hear one another, some see one another, and some perceive one another. Those that hear one another are the ones beginning with the equinoctial signs which are equally distant from them, and their degrees hear each other's degrees and the signs the signs. For since day does not see night because it is diametrically opposite to it, equal night hears equal day. Whenever night is completed in equal hours with the day, the signs also hear one another in periods of time; for the day in Taurus is thirteen hours, when the Sun passes through Pisces or Taurus. Gemini and Aquarius hear each other; for when the Sun is in Gemini the day is fourteen hours and when he is in Aquarius the night is  fourteen hours. Cancer and Capricornus also are to one another in the relation of hearing, but they are prevented by the Earth intervening between them. Leo and Sagittarius hear one another, and similarly Virgo and Scorpio, but Libra and Aries do not. Equal day looks upon, but does not hear, equal day; so the ten signs beginning with the tropical signs and equally distant on either side look upon one another; as, for instance, Leo and Gemini; for when the Sun is in Leo and similarly when he is in Gemini the day is fourteen hours and the night ten. Similarly Taurus and Virgo look upon one another, then Libra and Aries, then Scorpio and Pisces, then Sagittarius and Aquarius; Capricornus and Cancer, however, have the seeing relation one to another but are thrust apart because of the Earth intervening between them; and no other sign rises where Capricorn rises or where Cancer rises. Thus without seeing each other they rise from these places with no sign looking upon them. For this reason these signs alone cast shadows outside, while the Sun is passing through the signs that look upon one another. Wherefore admittedly day looks upon day. But these signs which perceive one another are the dwelling places of the stars, as Cancer and Leo, Virgo ;;(Col. XIII);[and Gemini, Taurus and Libra, Scorpio and Aries, Pisces and Sagittarius, Capricornus and Aquarius - - -] . . . and the double-bodied, Gemini, Virgo, [Sagittarius, and Pisces . . .] the tropical signs . . . the double-bodied belong to Mercury and Jupiter . . . [- - -] . . . they are called "solid" because of the "solid" signs each one is set aside for a single element . . . [- - -] . . . they are called eccentricities because the earth is the central point of the universe, and is the midmost of the seven planets. Still other ethereal constellations revolve in their own circles. The Sun is in apogee in Gemini; Venus is in perigee in Pisces and in apogee in Virgo; Jupiter is in apogee in Cancer and in perigee in Capricorn . . .;;(Col. XIV-XV: too fragmentary to be translated);;(Col. XVI);[- - -] . . . Hippocrates testified; for he called the Sun Daemon and the Moon Fortune. Leo is a male sign and Cancer female; and to the five gods that move together nature has assigned houses in pairs, a male and a female. For the Sun holds dominion by day, and the Moon by night, and these both by day and by night serve the two kings; and the signs inhabited by them are the vitals of the universe. To Mercury was given the first section, that beneath Leo and Cancer, in which are Virgo and Gemini, female and male. To Venus the zone beneath this, in which are Libra and Taurus, male and female. To Mars the zone beneath this, in which are Scorpio and Aries, female and male. To Jupiter the zone beneath this, in which are Sagittarius and Pisces, male and female. To Saturn the zone over all, Capricornus and Aquarius, female and male. Thus also from these regions they stand guard over the Moon and the Sun. In these signs the stars have their own powers and are vigorous. And nature assigned them thrones and prisons; their thrones the signs upon which they are exalted and have royal power and prisons wherein they are depressed and oppose their own powers. The [throne of the Sun] is at 19× of Aries, [his prison in Libra. The Moon's throne] us 3× of Taurus, [her prison 3× of Scorpio]. Saturn's [throne is 21× of Libra, his prison in Aries. The throne of Jupiter is 15×] of Cancer, his prison 15× [of Capricornus]. The throne of Mars [is 28× of Capricornus and his prison 28] of Cancer. [The throne of] Venus [is 27× of Pisces,] her prison [27× of Virgo].;;(Col. XVII);[- - -] . . . and in Libra, Aquarius and Gemini . . . In Taurus, Virgo, and Capricornus the Moon, Venus and Mercury rejoice, and in part Mars, but he does not take part in the governorship because the trianle belongs to similar gods as masters. In Scorpio, Pisces, and Cancer Mars and Venus rejoice, and the Moon shares the triangle as well, but does not take part in the governorship by day. This is the order of the houses and exaltations. . . . [Hermes] observed the stars, among the signs of the zodiac, in the degrees from the first of Leo to the thirtieth of Libra increasing, from 1× of Aquarius to 30× of Aries moving . . . in elevation and latitude, and from 1× of Scorpio to 30× of Capricornus and from 1× of Taurus to 30× of Cancer diminishing, and from equal diminishing quadrants he observed the motion of the universal heavenly bodies becoming . . . He observed that the 360× hold significance for the universe; wherefore the universe is itself imperishable . . . For it moves . . . and equal increment and subtraction . . .;;(Col. XVIII);[- - -] . . . they rejoice in the signs before their own exaltations, and affording complete effects . . . perfect; but they are afflicted in the signs following their own exaltations. For the stars depart from their own exaltations and begin to be depressed; they do not rejoice when they are in opposition tro one another unless they exchange houses. The planets of opposite sects are more harmful when in opposition. The maleficent planets are most prone to injure in the quartile aspect and in opposition, but are harmless in trine. The beneficient planets in trine are most beneficial, in the quartile aspect or in opposition less effective. The triangles that come about when the Sun is in trine with respect to the Moon are sure in their effects but the quartile aspect and opposition are not. . . . [- - -] . . . in the quartile aspect or in opposition to the Moon when it is becoming full signifies insecurity, great and bloody dangers; and in quartile aspect to the waning Moon . . . is especially significant of insecurity and danger . . .;;(Col. XIX-XXII: too fragmentary to be translated)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Robbins FE, CP 22, 1-45, 1927 Robbins FE, PMich III, 149, 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1290&amp;viewid=1I-IV.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/-/i/v/1i-iv.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1290&amp;viewid=1I-IV.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1290&amp;viewid=1I-IV.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/v/i/i/1v-vii.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1290&amp;viewid=1V-VII.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1290&amp;viewid=1V-VII.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/i/-/x/1viii-x.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1290&amp;viewid=1VIII-X.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1290&amp;viewid=1VIII-X.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/-/x/v/1xi-xv.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1290&amp;viewid=1XI-XV.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1290&amp;viewid=1XI-XV.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/x/i/x/1xix.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1290&amp;viewid=1XIX.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1290&amp;viewid=1XIX.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/-/x/7/1xvi-x7.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1290&amp;viewid=1XVI-X7.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1290&amp;viewid=1XVI-X7.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1290&amp;viewid=1XVII.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1290&amp;viewid=1XVII.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/i/i/i/1xviii.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1290&amp;viewid=1XVIII.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1290&amp;viewid=1XVIII.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
