<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3334</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3334</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 41 is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 41-42: 27.1 x 29.5 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 41: complete (papyrus cut off left of col. 41 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 41: 53 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 41 (l. 896-948)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Mystharion son of Ischyrion and Tapetheus grandson of Euemeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 188)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Ptolemaios and Taoueiteis grandson of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mystharion son of Petheus and Thaesis grandson of Esouris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 188)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor son of Mares (Marres) and Soeris grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nikephoros doulos of Longinus Isidoros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Pasoxis and Thakiaris (Thakialis) grandson of Petesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas son of Sokmenis and Tkollainis grandson of Sambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 224)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Esouris and Thaesis grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes son of Phaesis and Aynchis grandson of Mysthes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor son of Ptolemaios and Tapasion grandson of Phaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 182)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis son of Pasoxis and Tabetsiris (Tapetsiris) grandson of Phaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kames son of Pnepheros and Tapetheus grandson of Ptollion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides son of Petheus and Ptolemais grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus son of Petalos and Taeuemeros grandson of Petaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos son of Heraklas and Stiynchis grandson of Heraklas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus son of Petheus and Taseus grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Didymos and Tauris grandson of Maron (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Ptolemaios and Thermouthis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 204)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sokmenis son of Apynchis and Thatres grandson of Sambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 230)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Harpallos (Harpalos) and Tapetheus grandson of Sarapion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Polis son of Petheus and Herais grandson of Keras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herieus presbyteros son of Horos and Thaesis grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ninis son of Asklas and Tabous grandson of Ninis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Didymos and Thaisas grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Eutyches, doulos of Sarapias (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 165)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Slaves--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 41;;(Pharmouthi 2, continued);Mystharion, son of Ischyrion and Tapetheus, grandson of Euemeros: 12 drachmai;    column 56;Onnophris, son of Ptolemaios and Taoueiteis, grandson of Onnophris: 12 drachmai;    column 100;Mystharion, son of Petheus and Thaesis, grandson of Esouris: 8 drachmai;    column 56;Kastor, son of Mares and Soeris, grandson of Heras: 4 drachmai 28 obols;    column 56;Nikephoros, slave of Longinus Isidoros: 8 drachmai;    column 57;Pnepheros, son of Pasoxis and Thakiaris, grandson of Petesouchos: 4 drachmai;    column 59;Sambas, son of Sokmenis and Tkollainis, grandson of Sambas: 4 drachmai;    column 69;Ptolemaios, son of Esouris and Thaesis, grandson of Heras: 4 drachmai;    column 69;Total for the day: 120 drachmai 27 obols.;;On the 3rd, similarly:;Mysthes, son of Phaesis and Aynchis, grandson of Mysthes: 12 drachmai;    column 4;Kastor, son of Ptolemaios and Tapasion, grandson of Phaesis: 8 drachmai;    column 58;Phaesis, son of Pasoxis and Tabetsiris, grandson of Phaesis: 4 drachmai;    column 58;Kames, son of Pnepheros and Tapetheus, grandson of Ptollion: 20 drachmai;    column 41;Herakleides, son of Petheus and Ptolemais, grandson of Heras: 4 drachmai;    column 76;Petaus, son of Petalos and Taeuemeros, grandson of Petaus: 8 drachmai;    column 77;Petesouchos, son of Heraklas and Stiynchis, grandson of Heraklas: 28 obols;    column 78;Petaus, son of Petheus and Taseus, grandson of Pnepheros: 4 drachmai;    column 80;Petheus, son of Didymos and Tauris, grandson of Maron: 8 drachmai;    column 80;Petheus, son of Ptolemaios and Thermouthis, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai;    column 82;Sokmenis, son of Apynchis and Thatres, grandson of Sambas: 16 drachmai;    column 94;Sarapion, son of Harpallos and Tapetheus, grandson of Sarapion: 4 drachmai;    column 85;Polis, son of Petheus and Herais, grandson of Keras: 4 drachmai;    column 85;Herieus the elder, son of Horos and Thaesis, grandson of Pnepheros: 4 drachmai;    column 87;Ninis, son of Asklas and Tabous, grandson of Ninis: 28 obols;    column 88;Petheus, son of Didymos and Thaisas, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai;    column 88;Eutyches, slave of Sarapias: 4 drachmai;    column 88</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 41 (l. 896-948), 1936, pl. III</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3334&amp;viewid=4172_10RO.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/0/r/o/4172_10ro.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3334&amp;viewid=4172_10RO.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3334&amp;viewid=4172_10RO.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
