<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Literary Parody</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3034</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3034</idno>
            <idno type="dclp">65665</idno>
            <idno type="TM">65665</idno>
            <idno type="dclp-hybrid">tm;;65665</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 6946</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>The recto contains a portion of a mock-epic poem about the conflict between mice and a weasel. The two adversaries are an anonymous weasel and the mouse-hero named Trixos. The verso contains a list of persons and payments grouped under villages of the Themistes meris of the Arsinoite nome.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Discussed by V.N. Jarko, Vestnik Drevnej Istorii 173, 1985, 2.52-66</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso contains a list of persons</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>10 papyri ; Fr. 1: 30.8 x 26.5 cm; and 9 smaller fragmnets, which measure: fr. a 1 x 2 cm; fr. b 3.5 x 1.8 cm; fr. c 2 x 2.4 cm; fr. d 3.2 x 2.2 cm; fr. e 10.5 x 5 cm; fr. f 10.5 x5.5 cm; fr. g 3 x 1 cm; fr. h 2 x 1 cm; fr. i 2 x 1 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Light-brown papyrus which is badly mutilated. There is a kollesis 12 cm. measured from the left edge of l. 6.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-81</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a regular bookhand of second to first century B.C. (cp. P. Koeln III 126 [pl. I in Collect. Papyr. in Honour of H. C.Youtie I], Apollodoros, I B.C. and P. Laur. III 56, epos [?], I B.C. - I A.D.). As the papyrus is a palimpsest, irregular remnants of the old writings impede the decipherment of the present writing. Parts of the upper (4.8 cm.) and lower (3.8 cm.) margins are extant, leaving 22.2 cm. for the height of the written column; its width is approx. 13.5 cm. The intercolumnium of coll. i and ii varies between 0.8 and 1.7 cm.; on fr. a (if correctly placed) 1 cm. of of the intercolumnium preceding col. i is extant. Col. i contains 31 lines (including l. 9 which was added later by the same scribe). Col. ii has 29 lines; this number appears as a stichometric subtotal on the lower left margin of the column. In front of line 40 of col. ii a stichometric delta (= 400. see note ad loc.) indicates col. i began with line 361; accordingly, about 12 columns of the beginning of the roll or, at least, of the present poem are lost. Fr. e, line 3, might be either line 100 (stichometric A) or 1100 (see note ad loc.). fr. f, line 4, is marked as line 900. Consequently, our col. ii may have been followed by some 17 or 24 columns, bringing the total to more than 31 or 38 columns respectively. A horizontal stroke between lines 41 and 42 is either a paragraphos marking the end of the section or a pointer indicating the line to which stichometric delta originally belonged (i. e. line 41, before line 9 was inserted in col. i; see note to lines 41-42). The line-beginnings of col. ii swerve increasingly to the left (Maas' Law), and meter requires that the same be assumed for col. i. My indications of missing letters at the beginning of col. i takes this fact into account; however, the precise number of missing letters here remains uncertain. No punctuation, breathings, accents, apostrophes, tremata, or other diacritical signs are used. Corrections appear in lines 7, 9, 25, 40 (stichometric sign); 7 alocho and 56 podesin remained uncorrected; iota adscript is omitted in 12 demoand in 59 ede. Certain letters and combinations of letters  are equivocal without recognition of the context; for example, alphas, lambdas, ai's and nys look almost identical.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="-0099" notAfter="-0001">Ist century B.C.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Themistes meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Themistes meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt (?)</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>-</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">literary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>-</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Schibli HS, ZPE 53, 1-25, 1983, Pl. I-IV</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3034&amp;viewid=6946R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/4/6/r/6946r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3034&amp;viewid=6946R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3034&amp;viewid=6946R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
