<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3351</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3351</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer paying the poll-tax is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 64 is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 63-64: 40.9 x 29.8 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 64: complete; cols. 65-101 were cut off and are missing.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 64: 46 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 64 (l. 1690-1735)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Eutas (Eudas) son of Sambas and Ammonous grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron son of Satabous and Tkonnos grandson of Maron (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus son of Pnepheros and Thaesis grandson of Phanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinus son of Pasoknopaios and Tapetheus grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabous son of Dioskoros and Taorion grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 226)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Satabous and Theonis grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 220)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras son of Petsiris and Isidora grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Pasoknopaios and Tapetheus grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Diodoros son of Thaisas, apator (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor, doulos of Aphrodous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Leouas son of Petheus and Tapapeis grandson of Sokmenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 184)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Longinus alias Gemellus son of Taphois, apator (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 185)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hermation, doulos of Isidoros alias Longinus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anoubas son of Horos and Tepheros grandson of Aboubas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 151)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus son of Petheus and Tapasion grandson of Petaus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Komon son of Pnepheros and Tkollaus (Tkollauthis) grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 183)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Polyndion (Polydion) son of Kopaneus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 215)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kopaneus son of Polyndion (Polydion) and Politta grandson of Kopaneus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 184)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Apollonios and Thermouthis grandson of Harpagathes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Illegitimacy--Egypt</term>
               <term>Slaves--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Real property tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 64;;Year 14, Pachon 8:;Eutas, son of Sambas and Ammonous, grandson of Petheus: 12 drachmai;    column 62;Maron, son of Satabous and Tkonnos, grandson of Maron: 4 drachmai;    column 5;Phanomgeus, son of Pnepheros and Thaesis, grandson of Phanomgeus: 4 drachmai;    column 5;Sabinus, son of Pasoknopaios and Tapetheus, grandson of Horos: 4 drachmai;    column 9;Satabous, son of Dioskoros and Taorion, grandson of Satabous: 4 drachmai;    column 9;Ptolemaios, son of Satabous and Theonis, grandson of Horos: 28 obols;    column 10;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus and Tauris, grandson of Sokmenis: 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(--), 27 obols;    column 12;Heras, son of Petsiris and Isidora, grandson of Heras: 4 drachmai;    column 18;Petheus, son of Pasoknopaios and Tapetheus, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai 28 obols;    column 19;Diodoros, of unknown father, his mother being Thaisas: 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(--), 4 drachmai;    column 21;Kastor, slave of Aphrodous: 8 drachmai;    column 21;Leouas, son of Petheus and Tapapeis, grandson of Sokmenis: 4 drachmai;    column 24;Longinus also called Gemellus, of unknown father, his mother being Taphois: 8 drachmai;    column 27;Hermation, slave of Isidoros also called Longinus: 4 drachmai 28 obols;    column 27;Anoubas, son of Horos and Tepheros, grandson of Aboubas: 4 drachmai;    column 29;Petaus, son of Petheus and Tapasion, grandson of Petaus: 4 drachmai 27 obols;    column 34;Komon, son of Pnepheros and Tkollaus, grandson of Satabous: 8 drachmai;    column 37;Total for the day: 104 drachmai 22 obols.;;On the 9th, similarly:;Polyndion, son of Kopaneus, for garden land, for year 13: for apomoira, 10 drachmai; for olive (transportation), 1 drachme 2 obols 1/2; for naubion, 1 drachme; for supplements, 2 drachmai 3 obols; for eparourion, 6 drachmai 4 obols; for supplements, 3 obols 1/2; for kollybos, 2 obols 2 chalkoi. Total: 22 drachmai 3 obols 2 chalkoi. (In left margin: 20 drachmai 23 obols.);Kopaneus, son of Polyndion and Politta, grandson of Kopaneus: 12 drachmai;    column 99;Sarapion, son of Apollonios and Thermouthis, grandson of Harpagathes: 8 drachmai;    column 61;Total for the day: 40 drachmai 23 obols.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 64 (l. 1690-1735), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3351&amp;viewid=4172_18RO.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/8/r/o/4172_18ro.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3351&amp;viewid=4172_18RO.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3351&amp;viewid=4172_18RO.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
