<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3785</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3785</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso contains two lines with amounts paid in tax; the name of  the individuals who paid these amounts are not preserved</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 34.7 x 30 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at all sides except the bottom. Kolleais in the right middle. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-36</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 38 (ll. 1618-1654)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Somas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 232)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dios, son of Teberis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 160)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Stiynchis, wife of Africanus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 231)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraklas, son of Petheus, grandson of Heraklas, mother Eserempis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor, son of Apion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apitas, son of Kothon (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 152)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Harpalos, grandson of Sarapion, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Phasis, grandson of Keras, mother Helene (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herieus the older, son of Horos, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maronis, daughter of Ptolemaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tainkimis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 233)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymos, son of Heron, grandson of Heras, mother Tasiaipis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 161)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinos, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Zoidous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor, son of Kastor (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Taakoutia (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 232)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Onnophris, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herieus, son of Sambas, grandson of Peteesis, mother Tapapeis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Demas, son of Phanomgeus(see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 160)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastresis, plaiter of wreaths (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Artemas, son of Heron, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Psenesis, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Sambas, grandson of Sabeinos, mother Aphrodous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 38.;Pnepheros, son of Pnepheros ;;(in left margin: drachmas 16, obols 25) orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 3, obols 4.5, tax on the produce of olives obols 3, chalki 2, naubion obols 2, chalki 2, surcharges obols 5.5, chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 2, obols 3, surcharges obol 1, chalki 2, in total drachmas 8, obols 3;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 9, obols 2, chalki 2, surcharges obols 3.5, chalki 2, drachmas 10;;Somas ;;Dios, son of Teberis through the agency of Stiynchis (wife of Africanus);;(in left margin: drachmas 32) orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 6, obols 2, tax on the produce of olives obols 5.5, naubion obols 4, surcharges drachma 1, obols 3.5, chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 4, obol 1.5, surcharge obols 2, chalki 2, kollybos obol 1.5, in total drachmas 14, obols 2.5;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 15, obols 5, surcharge drachma 1, in total drachmas 16, obols 5;;Heraklas, son of Petheus, grandson of Heraklas, mother Eserempis, drachmas 8;;Kastor, son of Apion (son of Apitas, son of Kothon);;(in left margin, a little below the line: drachmas 8, obols 18) orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 2, obols 3, tax on the produce of olives obols 2, chalki 2, naubion obol 1.5, surcharges obols 3.5, chalki 2;;eparourion drachma 1, obols 4, surcharges obol 1, kollybos  obol 0.5, in total drachmas 5, obols 4, chalki 2;;Sarapion, son of Harpalos, grandson of Sarapion, mother Tapetheus, obols 28;;Sarapion, son of Phasis, grandson of Keras, mother Helene, drachmas 4;;Herieus the older, son of Horos, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Maronis, daughter of Ptolemaios (of Tainkimis);;(in left margin, a little above the line: drachmas 140... ) orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 27, obols 3, tax on the produce of olives drachmas 3, obols 5, chalki 2, naubion drachmas 2, obols 4.5, surcharges drachmas 6, obols 5;;eparourion drachmas 18, obols 2, surcharge drachma 1, obols 3, chalki 2, kollybos drachma 1, obol 1, in total drachmas 62;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 68, obols 4.5, surcharges drachmas 4, obols 2, in total drachmas 73, obols 0.5;;naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year drachmas 3, obols 5, chalki 2, surcharge obols 2.5, kollybos obols 0.5, in total drachmas 4, obols 2, chalki 2;;. . . , obols 0.5;;Didymos, son of Heron, grandson of Heras, mother Tasiaipis, drachmas 4;;Sabinos, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Ptolemaios, mother Zoidous, drachmas 4;;Kastor, son of Kastor through the agency of Herais (of Taakoutia);;naubion of the katoikoi for the 13th year, drachma 1, surcharges obol 0.5, chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachma 1, obol 1;;Onnophris, son of Onnophris, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 404, obols 22;;(Phamenoth) 30 likewise:;Herieus, son of Sambas, grandson of Peteesis, mother Tapapeis, drachmas 4;;Demas, son of Phanomgeus (of Kastresis, plaiter of wreaths);;orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachma 1, tax on the produce of olives obol 1, naubion obol 0.5, chalki 2, surcharges obols 2;;(in left margin: drachmas 4, obols 14) eparourion obols 4, surcharges obol 0.5, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachmas 2, obols 2.5;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 2, obols 3, surcharges obol 1, in total drachmas 2, obols 4;;Artemas, son of Heron, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, son of Psenesis, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 16;;Ptolemaios, son of Sambas, grandson of Sabeinos, mother Aphrodous, drachmas 4."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3785&amp;viewid=4171_38R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/3/8/r/4171_38r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3785&amp;viewid=4171_38R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3785&amp;viewid=4171_38R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
