<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Division of Inherited Property </title>
            <author>Gaius Minucius Aquila and his sisters Minucia  Gemella and Minucia Thermoutharion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1684</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1684</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.9.554</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;9;554</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;9;554</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12047</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12047</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 2915</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract dividing between Minucius Aquila, on one side, and his two sisters, on the other side, the properties they inherited from their father and mother</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Date (see P. Mich. IX, p. 78): under the rule of Domitian and before the birth of Minucia Thermoutharion's daughter Valeria Diodora (see P.Mich. VI, 428; B.G.U. II, 472: born ca. 94 A.D.), as Minucia Thermoutharion is not yet married here.;The presence of the red stamp on the verso proves that this copy was authenticated by an official office (grapheion?): see P.Diog., p. 37-39.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso bears traces of a circular red stamp</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>2 papyri ; 22.5 X 11.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Recto: broken off on the left side and (slightly) at the bottom; damaged along the folds; surface badly rubbed in many places, with much of the writing almost effaced.;Verso: too little of the circular red stamp remains for the design or the inscription to be apparent.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">63</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>See electronic version of PMich IX, 554</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0081" notAfter="0094">81 - 94 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Arsinoiton polis, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Domitianus, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius Minucius Aquila</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Minucia Gemella</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Minucia Thermoutharion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius Sempronius Priscus, apolusimos apo strateias, guardian of Minucia Gemella</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Lucius Vibius Crispinus, apolusimos apo strateias, guardian of Minucia Thermoutharion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpaesis son of Limnaios, former owner</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Peteeus son of Petheus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras son of Dioskoros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tetoseiris daughter of Heras</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Ptolemais Euergetis (Arsinoiton polis), Arsinoite nome; Kerkesoucha; Psenarpsenesis; Karanis</term>
               <term>Family--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Home ownership--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Citizenship--Rome.</term>
               <term>Topographical surveying--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Women--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Veterans--Rome.</term>
               <term>Kerkesoucha Orous (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Psenarpsenïesis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Land tenure--Egypt.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[The . . . year of the] Emperor Caesar Domitian Augustus Germanicus, the 19th of the month Daisios, [19th] of Pharmouthi, [in Ptolemais] Euergetis in the Arsinoite nome. Gaius Minucius Aquila, [about . . . years old, with a scar] on his forehead, and his sisters by the same father and mother, Minucia Gemella, about [. . .] years old, [with a scar] on her right [. . .], and Minucia Thermoutharion, about twenty years old, with a scar beneath the shin of her right leg, [with their guardians, that of Minucia] Gemella being Gaius Sempronius Priscus, discharged from military service with the legion, about fifty [. . .] years old, with a scar on the top of his left foot, and that of Minucia Thermoutharion being Lucius Vibius Crispinus, discharged [from military service with the legion, about] forty-nine [years] old, with a scar on his left forearm, acknowledge to each other that they have divided among themselves in accordance with this agreement [forever] the property that belongs to them by inheritance from their father and mother. The property inherited from their father consists of six arourai [of privately held land] near Kerkesoucha, . . . and one aroura of a newly planted olive grove near Psenarpsenesis in the catoecic category, and two and a quarter arourai [of a catoecic allotment] near [Karanis] with one and one-eighth arourai of the village impost, and two houses in Karanis [with a granary and] a dovecote between. And the property inherited from the mother consists of [three arourai] of a catoecic allotment near the same village of Kerkesoucha and the half share of a house [in Karanis]. In accordance with the division which they have made with each other by mutual consent, [Gaius] Minucius Aquila has [received as the share] falling to his lot from all the property aforesaid the [six arourai] of privately owned [land near Kerkesoucha], and the one aroura of olive grove near Psenarpsenesis, and [of the two houses] in the village of Karanis the house and courtyard that lie on the west and that formerly belonged to Harpaesis, son of Limnaios, and the aforesaid granary [on the north] and the dovecote, of which the adjacent areas on the south and west are the royal roads, on the north the house of [Peteeus, son of Petheus], and on the east the other house which has been received as their share by Gemella and Thermoutharion; and [. . .] Minucia Gemella and Minucia Thermoutharion [have received] as their allotted share of [all of the aforesaid property], to be held by them in common and equally, the catoecic allotment near Karanis, consisting of two and a quarter arourai, and one and an eighth [arourai of the village impost], and the three arourai of a catoecic allotment near Kerkesoucha, and [the half share of the] house in the village of Karanis, and the other house and courtyard in the same village [on the east side with] another building site on the north, surrounded by a mud wall, called a granary, and [. . . in the] dovecote which Aquila has received, a one-story room in which there is a mill and a mortar, [the adjacent areas being on the south] a royal [road], on the north the house of the aforesaid Peteeus, son of Petheus, on the west [the house and] dovecote which [Aquila] received as his share, on the east the vacant lots of Heras, son of Dioskoros, and Tetosiris, daughter of Heras, . . .;;(15 lines, too fragmentary to be translated);;. . . let the one who does not abide by the contract pay the one who abides by it the damages and the expenses twofold, and a fine of one thousand [silver] drachmai, and an equal sum to the state treasury, while the aforesaid terms remain valid.;(2nd hand) [I, Gaius Minucius] Aquila, have reported the division and [have received] as my allotted share from the property inherited from my father and mother the six arourai of privatey held land [near] Kerkesoucha and the one aroura of olive grove near Psenarpsenesis and the house and court on the west side, in Karanis, [formerly belonging] to Harpaesis, and the granary to the north, and the [dovecote]. And I shall pay whatever public and private debts the aforesaid(?) now manifestly owes, and after one year I shall pay [to my sister] Thermoutharion the four hundred silver drachmai which I owe her, without interest, as aforesaid.;(3rd hand) We, Minucia Gemella and Minucia [Thermoutharion], each with her guardian, Gemella with me, Gaius [Sempronius Priscus], and Thermoutharion with Lucius Vibius Crispinus, [have joined in reporting] the division and have received as our share, to be held in common, the two and a quarter arourai near [Karanis] with the village impost, and the house and courtyard on the east in [Karanis], [. . .] and the granary, and the room, and the [three arourai] near Kerkesoucha, and the half share of the house as aforesaid. [I, . . .], wrote for Gemella who writes slowly and for Thermoutharion who is illiterate.;(4th hand) I, Gemella, [ordered him to write].;(5th hand) . . . Pharmouthi 19(?). Registered(?0 . . .</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich IX, 554, 1971 -- Line 15: read Limnaiou instead of Panaiou (PH)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:9:554</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1684&amp;viewid=2915R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/1/5/r/2915r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1684&amp;viewid=2915R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1684&amp;viewid=2915R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/1/5/v/2915v.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1684&amp;viewid=2915V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1684&amp;viewid=2915V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
