<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3799</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3799</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.224</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 28.8 x 29.3 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at the left and at the right. Kollesis at the left edge. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-41</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 50 (ll. 2049-2090)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. Traces of writing on the back have been washed out. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Eserempis, daughter of Chairemon (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 163)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thermouthis, daughter of Makras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 176)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos, son of Pakysis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabeinos, son of Valens (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Luppus, son of Horos, grandson of Menches, mother Tapapeis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Agathos Daimon, grandson of Petheus, mother Stiynchis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Isidoros, son of Tryphon alias Panephremis, grandson of Sambas, mother Isidora (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 179)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tamaron, daughter of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 233)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Cassianus Tiasench (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sentia Teraus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 228)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Lucius Antonius Cassianus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 185)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchophis, son of Anchophis, grandson of Petheus, mother Taorsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petaus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabous, son of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 226)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kinkiol (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 183)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabeinos, son of Apynchis, grandson of Sambas, mother Thatres (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gemella, daughter of Anthestia (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 160)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pammyrikos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 50:;Eserempis, daughter of Chairemon (Thermouthis, daughter of Makras);;orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 2 obols 3, tax on the produce of olives obols 2 chalki 2, naubion obol 1.5, surcharges obols 3.5 chalki 2;;(in left margin: drachmas 12 obols 9) eparourion drachma 1 obols 4, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obols 2.5, in total drachmas 5 obols 4 chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 6 obol 1.5, surcharges obols 2.5, in total drachmas 6 obols 4;;Petesouchos, son of Pakysis (Sabeinos, son of Valens);;orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 10 obols 3.5 chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives drachma 1 obols 3 chalki 2, naubion drachma 1 obl 0.5, surcharges drachmas 2 obols 4;;(in left margin: drachmas 52 obols 8) eparourion drachmas 7 obol 0.5, surcharges obols 3.5, kollybos obols 2.5, in total drachmas 24;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 26 obols 3.5, surcharges drachma 1 obols 4, in total drachmas 28 obol 1.5;;Luppus, son of Horos, grandson of Menches, mother Tapapeis, drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, son of Agathos Daimon, grandson of Petheus, mother Stiynchis, drachmas 4;;Isidoros, son of Tryphon alias Panephremis, grandson of Sambas, mother Isidora, drachmas 40;;Tamaron, daughter of Heras (Cassianus Tiasench);;orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 39 obols 4, tax on the produce of olives drachmas 5 obols 4, naubion drachmas 4, surcharges drachmas 10;;eparourion drachmas 26 obols 4, surcharges drachmas 2 obol 1.5, kollybos drachma 1 obols 3, in total drachmas 89 obols 4.5;;(in left margin: drachmas 296 obols 19)geometria for the 12th year drachmas 98 obols 2.5, surcharges drachmas 6 obol 1 chalki 2, in total drachmas 104 obols 3.5, chalki 2;;and Sentia Teraus;;orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 5 obols 3 chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives obols 4.5 chalki 2, naubion obols 3.5, surcharges drachma 1 obols 2.5;;eparourion drachmas 3 obols 5 chalki 2, surcharges obols 2, kollybos obol 1.5, in total drachmas 12 obols 4.5 chalki 2;;geometria drachmas 13 obols 5 chalki 2, surcharges obols 5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 14 obols 5.5;  ;Lucius Antonius Cassianus;;orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 13 obols 2 chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives drachmas 2, naubion drachma 1 obols 2.5, surcharges drachmas 3 obols 2 chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 9 obol 1, surcharges obols 4.5, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachmas 30 obols 3.5 chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 33 obols 4, surcharge drachmas 2 obol 1 chalki 2, in total drachmas 35 obols 5 chalki 2;;naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year drachmas 2 obol 1.5, surcharges obol 1.5, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachmas 2 obols 3 chalki 2;;on land in release likewise drachma 1 obols 2 chalki 2, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2, kollybos chalki 2, in total drachma 1 obols 4 chalki 2;;and for Tamarron, daughter of Heras;;naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year drachmas 2 obols 2, surcharges obol 1.5, kollybos obol 0.5, in total drachmas 2 obols 4;;in total for the day drachmas 504 obols 5;;(Pharmouthi) 10 likewise:;Anchophis, son of Anchophis, grandson of Petheus, mother Taorsenouphis, drachmas 8;;Petesouchos, son of Petheus, grandson of Petaus, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8;;Satabous, son of Onnophris (Kinkiol);;(in left margin: drachmas 4 obols 24) orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachma 1 chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives obol 1 chalki 2, naubion obol 0.5 chalki 2, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2;;eparourion obol 5, surcharges obol 0.5, kollybos obol 0.5, in total drachmas 2 obols 4;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 2 obols 3.5, surcharges obol 1.5, in total drachmas 2 obols 4.5 chalki 2;;naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year obols 3, surcharges obol 0.5, kollybos chalki 2, in total obols 3.5 chalki 2;;Sabeinos, son of Apynchis, grandson of Sambas, mother Thatres, drachmas 16;;Gemella, daughter of Anthestia (daughter of Pammyrikos);;orchard taxes for the 12th year, apomoira drachmas 17 obols 3, tax on the produce of olives drachmas 2 obols 2.5 chalki 2, naubion drachma 1 obols 4.5, surcharges drachmas 4 obols 2 chalki 2;;eparourion drachmas 11 obols 4, surcharges drachma 1, kollybos obols 4, in total drachmas 39 obols 2.5;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 43 obols 4.5, surcharges obols 4,5, in total drachmas 46 obols 3."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3799&amp;viewid=4171_50R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3799&amp;viewid=4171_50R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3799&amp;viewid=4171_50R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
