<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lease of a house</title>
            <author>Dionysia, daughter of Chairemon</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1260</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1260</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.oxy.3.502</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0181;3;502</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;502</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20636</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20636</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Corn. Inv. MSS. A 101. II</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Lease of a house and its appurtenances at Oxyrhynchos for 18 months at a rent of 200 dr. per year. The tenant is bound to deliver up the buildings in good repair at the end of the lease, and the landlord is responsible for the police-tax and brick-tax</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 25.5 x 6.7 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The papyrus is well preserved at all sides. There are nine foldings visible and the papyrus was folded from the top to the bottom</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">56 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Small letters are written by an experient hand. The top margin is 1.7 cm, the left c. 1 cm and the bottom3.3 cm. There is no right margin, as the scribe used all the scribing area til the edge of the papyrus</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0164">1 March, 164 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Oxyrhynchos, Oxyrhynchite nome, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Dionysia, daugther of Chairemon, mother of Apion, wife of Diogenes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apion, also called Dionysios, son of Diogenes and Dionysia, priest of Faustina Augusta</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Diogenes, father of Apion, wife of Dionysia</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolema, daughter of Theon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon, second cousin of Dionysia</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Theon, father of Ptolema</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ioulas, son of Didymos, by adoption son of Demetrios also called Apollonios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymos, father of Ioulas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Demetrios also called Apollonios, by adoption father of Ioulas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Emperor Caesar Marcus Aurelius Antoninus Augustus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Emperor Caesar Lucius Aurelius Varus Augustus</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Oxyrhynchos, Oxyrhynchite nome, Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Oxyrhyncon polis;Antinois;Temgenouthis quarter (Oxyrhynchos)</term>
               <term>Leases--Egypt--Bahnasïa .</term>
               <term>Housing--Egypt--Bahnasïa .</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Dionysia, daugther of Chairemon with her guardian her son Apion also called Dionysios son of Diogenes, priest of Faustina Augusta, both of Oxyrhynchon polis, has leased to Ptolema daughter of Theon, of Antinois, through Ioulas, son of Didymos, by adoption son of Demetrios also called Apollonios, of Oxyrhynchon polis, for one year and six  months dating from the first of the current month Phamenoth of the present fourth year of the lords and Emperors Antoninos and veros the house which she owns, and which previously belonged to her second cousin Chairemon, of Antinoe, at oxyrhynchos in the Temgenouthis quarter, with the court and two yards in one of which is a well, and the portico which adjoins the house and the other fixtures and the entrance and exit, at a rent for the premises leased of 200 silver drachmai a year. If the lease is guaranteed the lessee shall pay the lessor at the conclusion of each period of six months the proportion ate amount of the rent, 100 drachmai, and shall together with her assigns have the use of the premises leased to her as aforesaid for the appointed time without hindrance, and thereafter shall deliver them up free from filth and with the doors and keys received by her of all the premises, and the reel of the aforesaid well provided with a new rope, and the two existing stone presses with the water-pitchers and trough, or shall forfeit the value of anything which she fails to deliver and any arrears of rent increased by one half, and the lessor shall have the right of execution upon the lessee and upon all her property, the lessor being liable for the police-tax and brick-making tax. This lease is valid. The 4rth year of the Emperor Caesar Marcus Aurelius Antoninus Augustus and the Emperor Caesar Lucius Aurelius Varus Augustus, Phamenoth 5. I, Apion also called Dionysius, have been registered as my mother's guardian, and have leased together with the above-mentioned premises the chambers in the court. The same date.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Grenfell BP-Hunt AS, POxy III, 502, 1903</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Oxy.:3:502</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1260&amp;viewid=C0_IIR.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/I/I/r/C0_IIr.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1260&amp;viewid=C0_IIR.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1260&amp;viewid=C0_IIR.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
