<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>excerpts of the Gospel of John</title>
            <author>Gospel of John</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1997</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1997</idno>
            <idno type="dclp">107757</idno>
            <idno type="TM">107757</idno>
            <idno type="dclp-hybrid">tm;;107757</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 3521</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>This text contains a number of excerpts from the Gospel of John in the Coptic (Fayumic) language.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Copt">Coptic (Fayumic)</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support/>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Deeply discolored, with the writing faint and frequently much abraded. There are twenty-nine folios represented by fragments of greater or lesser extent. No folios are complete, most of them being broken off at the bottom. Several folios lack only from one to three lines. Since there is no Fayumic it is impossible to determine with accuracy the number of lines necessary to accomodate the missing text if it extends beyond two or three lines, although a rough estimate can be made. Single-quire manuscript, such as is common at this period.;There is one more folio, not located and not published, mounted in a separare glass at the end of the published folios. Some debris in locker 19.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The manuscript is well written in a neat uncial hand, not perfectly regular, but certainly done with care and skill, and with remarkably few errors. The letters are for the most part uniform in height, although occasionally certain letters extend below the line. The badly worn surface of the papyrus and the faded ink often make it impossible to distinguish between letters.;The orthography is in general correc with some examples of elision.;The supralineation s interesting and an attempt has been made in transcription to reproduce it as it appears in the manuscript. It is sometimes a straight line, sometimes curved, but with no apparent distinction. It almost never extends over two consonants, but it is at times placed between them, at other times is over the second letter, and even to the right of it. It is often used merely to mark the end of a word, but when so used it rarely approximates the apostrophe that is found in other early manuscripts, and is in no way distinguished from other supralinear strokes.;The diairesis is placed over the i when it follows another vowel. It is also used with initial i generally, but apparently not always, and three times it is placed over the final i. In some places it looks more like a single short stroke, but it is often so faint that this point is uncertain and it has always been transcribed as two dots. Now and then it is omitted where we should expect it, but this also may be due merely to its being effaced.;The hand is similar to P. Mich. inv. 3520, but that of 3520 is in general slightly larger. Irregularities in the size of the letters within each manuscript and the lack of the significant letters on fragments in question add uncertainty in assigning them to one or the other manuscript unless the text can be identified.;Because of the defective condition of the codex, any conclusions regarding the structure of the codex must be conjectural. As is usual with papyrus codices of this early period, the letters, while well made and pleasing in appearance, are not always uniform in size. Nor is any attempt made to make the lines even in length, and the number of letters to the line may be as low as eleven and as high as twenty-two. The margins also are not constant; on fol. 15, for example, the upper margin is 2 cm. on the recto and only 1.3 cm. on the verso. The left margin, when preserved, varies from 1.5 to 2.5 cm. The right margin is of course irregular. The number of lines to the page, when it can be determined, runs from as few as fifteen to as many as twenty. On the first nine folios, which are consecutive, there are nineteen or twenty lines to the page, while folios 15-22, also consecutive, have fifteen to eighteen lines.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0250" notAfter="0350">(late) third/(early) fourth century A. D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>unknown</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Copt">Coptic (Fayumic)</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>-</term>
               <term>Bible.-- N.T.-- John.--Coptic--Manuscripts.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">literary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>-</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, Gospel of John, 1962, 6 plates</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1997&amp;viewid=3521R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1997&amp;viewid=3521R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1997&amp;viewid=3521R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1997&amp;viewid=3521V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1997&amp;viewid=3521V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
