<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>oration</title>
            <author>Demosthenes</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3156</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3156</idno>
            <idno type="dclp">59643</idno>
            <idno type="TM">59643</idno>
            <idno type="dclp-hybrid">tm;;59643</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 918</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>This text is a parchment fragment of a codex consisting of two leaves and containg Demosthenes' Third Philippic, sections 29-34 and 61 (in part) - 68.q</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">There are five small fragments kept in a folder. There is writing on some of them, a few letters,</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto + Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>Par ; 32.5 x21 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">There are indications that the fragment in question formed part of a codex of some value. Not only the character of the text itself, but also the writing and the material used bear witness to an edition of Demosthenes that had been prepared with discrimination.The parchment is rather thin (0.13 mm.) and. at present, rather brittle, with a fine smooth surface. Broken at all sides. In excellent preservation except for some worm-holes and discoloration by water in places. The page measurement is about 16.5 x 21 cm., and this was approximately the size of the original codex.;Quires of three sheets are not unknown, but four was the more usual number and that was probably the case in this codex. If the quire consisted of four sheets, it is evident that one leaf, containing four columns, would have extended to about the beginning of section 74. Another column at least, possibly beginning a new quire, would have been necessary to account for the rest of the oration. It is also evident that sixteen columns would have sufficed to contain section 1 to the beginning of section 29. Assuming again that the quire was a quaternion, it is fair to conclude that the remaining sixteen columns were devoted to the end of another oration which preceded the Third Philippic in this codex.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-216</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto + Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The writing consists of two columns to a page; eight columns in all are therefore preserved in the manuscript. The individual columns have an average height of about 15.5 cm. and a width of about 6 cmentimeters. There are twenty-seven lines in each column and an average of sixteen letters in the individual lines.;The ink is dark brown faded to a lighter color in some places. Corrections made by a later hand are in black ink. The writing is a rather broad, upright uncial of medium size. The horizontal strokes of certain letters, especially tau and epsilon, show a tendency to end in ornamental dots. In general, the writing is somewhat larger and less precise than the fragment of Demosthenes shown in Amherst Papyri, part II, plate V, number xxiv, and is somewhat smaller and neater than the hand shown in Oxyrhynchos Papyri, vol. VIII, plate I, 1080, both of which are attributed to the fourth century A.D.;Above the center of column ii is a symbol which has not been deciphered, and above column iii is another which looks like ie, is, or a rudely formed k; both are inclosed by half-inches whose open side is toward the outer margin. They may be page numbers; if they are, a page numbered 10+ would indicate more pages in the codex than would suffice for the antecedent portion of the Third Philippics in this codex.;Faint traces are left of the lateral page rulings, as also of the horizontal ones. The latter, it would seem, appeared for every third line. The horizontal rulings seem to be confined within the lateral ones and not to extend completely across the sheet. In general, the writer followed his rulings with care.;Marks of diairesis over iota and upsilon are everywhere by the first hand, as are the marks indicating elision. Punctuation is represented by points in the high and middle position; discoloration and other causes make it difficult to determine whether or not all stops are by the first hand; most of them certainly are. Accents are not consistently employed; some are certainly in the original ink, others are not. Contraction by suspension of final nuat the end of line occurs in i 9; ii 12; iii 3; iii 4; iv 7; v 4; vi 16; vii 21; viii 13; viii 25. All save one, viii 13, occur at the end of a word. Such contraction is indicated by a stroke over the final vowel.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0300" notAfter="0399">IVth century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Panopolite nome, The Thebaid, Upper Egypt, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Panopolite nome, The Thebaid, Upper Egypt, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>-</term>
               <term>Demosthenes.-- Philippicae.--III.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Parchment</term>
               <term type="genre_form">literary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>-</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Winter JG, CP 20, 97-114, 1925</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3156&amp;viewid=918R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3156&amp;viewid=918R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3156&amp;viewid=918R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3156&amp;viewid=918V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3156&amp;viewid=918V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
