<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Receipt</title>
            <author>Pases, son of Sakaon,;Herakles, son of Sokmenis,;Peteeus, son of Pekmeis, ;Pnepheros, son of Sakaon,;Pauseiris, son of Stotoetis,;Pekmeis, son of Phanomgeus,;Petesis, son of Pekmeis,;Pekmeis, son of Alexander</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1577</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1577</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14930</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14930</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;20;15089</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 204</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Receipt of eighteen artabs of wheat equalling the rent of three arouras of grazing land</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 20.7 x 19.2 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Completely preserved on three sides; only bottom of papyrus is lost. A number of little holes in the papyrus. Ink very faint in three first lines. Upper margin 1.5 cm, left margin approximately 1.5 cm.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-30</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Experienced semicursive hands</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0050" notAfter="0051">50/51 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Kerkesoucha, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt (?)</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Pases, son of Sakaon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles, son of Sokmenis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Peteeus, son of Pekmeis,</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Sakaon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pauseiris, son of Stotoetis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pekmeis, son of Phanomgeus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesis, son of Pekmeis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pekmeis, son of Alexander</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hatres, son of Harpagathes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonios, son of Peteeus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpaesis, son of Harpaesis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Isidoros, son of Ptolemaios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hermogenes, son of Ptolemaios</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Kerkesoucha, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Kerkesoucha, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</term>
               <term>Land administration</term>
               <term>tax-collection</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"In year 11 of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator ... in Kerkesoucha in the Herakleides division in the Arsinoite nome. Pases, son of Sakaon, ca. 33 years old, with a scar on the left elbow, head of the prosodikoi georgoi of the aforesaid village, and Herakles, son of Sokmenis, ca. forty... years old, with a scar on the little finger of the left hand, and Peteeus, son of Pekmeis, ca. forty years old, with a scar on the left of the forehead, and Pnepheros, son of Sakaon, ca. forty-five years old, with a scar on the right shin, and Pauseiris, son of Stotoetis, ca. 66 years old, with a scar on the little finger on the left hand, and Pekmeis, son of Phanomgeus, ca. 35 years old, with a scar on the left of the forehead, and Petesis, son of Pekmeis, ca. 40 years old, with a scar on the left forearm, and Pekmeis, son of Alexander, ca. 50 years old, with a scar on the right eyebrow, all the nine oldest of the  prosodikoi georgoi in the same village acknowledge to Hatres, son of Harpagathes, ca. 50 years old, with a scar on the left forearm, and to Ammonios, son of Peteeus, ca. 55 years old, with a scar on the right eyebrow to have received from them 18 artabs of wheat according to the Dromos-measure, a price which equals that of grass from three arouras of land - or however much it may be - which their cattled has devoured in the course of the 11th year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Germanicus Imperator in the prosodika  fields at the same village and at the 5th road of a parcel, farmed by Harpaesis, son of Harpaesis, a deflected prosodikos georgos. Consequently neither the acknowledging party nor their successors have any debt claim against the party of Hatres or their successors as far as the grass in any form is concerned and there will be none. Signatures: for the acknowledging party: Isidoros, son of Ptolemaios, the oldest of the farmers of the same prosodos, ca. 27 years old, with a scar on the left shin; for the party of Hatres: Hermogenes, son of Ptolemaios, ca. 72 years old, with a scar on the left wrist. (2nd hand): We, Pases, son of Sakaon, head of the prosodikoi georgoi of Kerkesoucha, and Herakles, son of Sokmenis, and Peteeus, son of Pekmeis, and Pnepheros, son of Sakaon, and Pauseiris, son of Stotoetis, and Pekmeis, son of Phanomgeus, and Petesis, son of Pekmeis, and Pekmeis, son of Alexander, all nine eldest of the of the prosodikoi georgoi of the aforesaid village acknowledge to have received from Hatres, the son of Harpagathes and Ammonios, the son of Peteeus, 18 artabs of wheat according to the Dromos-measure, equalling the price of grass from three arouras of land - or however much it may be ..."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Huebner R, ZPE 84, 31-7, 1990, Taf. II -- SB XX 15089</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1577&amp;viewid=204R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/0/4/r/204r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1577&amp;viewid=204R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1577&amp;viewid=204R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
