<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lease of Land</title>
            <author>Aurelius Menas, son of Psate</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3018</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3018</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.13.666</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;13;666</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;13;666</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21378</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21378</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 6906</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract by which Aurelius Menas, son of Psate, leases from Aurelius Kollouthos, son of Christophoros, a holding where vines are grown; the lease is based partly on crop-sharing, partly on rent to be paid</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto (written across the fibres); Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Dioskoros of Aphrodito</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="cop">Greek (with part of a signature in Coptic - l. 38)</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>2 papyri ; 56 x 33.5 cm; + 1 fragment of 3.2 x 1.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">broken off and damaged at the top</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">41;;fragment - 3</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written across the fibres; 2nd and 4th hands: slow-writers</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0500" notAfter="0599">VIth century A.D. (512 or 527 A.D.[?])</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Aphrodite (Aphrodito), Antaiopolite nome, province of the Lower Thebais, Thebais, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Menas son of Psate, syntelestes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Kollouthos son of Christophoros, syntelestes (see also P.Vat.Copti Doresse 1)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anouphios (see Geographica)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Psates son of Ananias</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Georgios son of Onnophrios (Onnophris)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kollouthos, tabellion</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Aphrodite (Aphrodito), Antaiopolite nome, province of the Lower Thebais, Thebais, Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="cop">Greek (with part of a signature in Coptic - l. 38)</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Aphrodite, Antaiopolite nome; ktema kaloumenon Prmres (see also P.Lond. IV, 1419); kleros Anouphiou</term>
               <term>Agriculture</term>
               <term>Irrigation</term>
               <term>Land ownership</term>
               <term>Lease</term>
               <term>Notary</term>
               <term>Utensil</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[- - -] 9 of the fifth indiction.;(Cross) Aurelius Menas, son of Psate - - -, syntelestes, of the village of Aphrodite of the Antaiopolite nome, (Cross) to Aurelius Kollouthos, son of Christophoros, also syntelestes, of the village of Aphrodite, greetings. I acknowledge that I have willingly and of my own free choice leased from you for a period of four years, counted fro the produce of the D.V. sixth indiction, for that indiction and consequently the complete holding belonging to you of your property, of however many arourai it may be, called Prmres with two pounds and a lodge and a tower and a stable and a chaff-holder and a vineyard and an orchard and a vegetable-patch and trees and date-palms and olive-yards and mulberry-trees and citron-trees and acacias and all different trees both fruit-bearing and not fruit-bearing and the arourai all around and all the rights, both interior and exterior, according to its ancient boundaries all around situated in the western plain of the same village of Aphrodite in the kleros of Anouphios, upon condition that I hold it under my control for farming and planting by halves and perform all the work of cultivation and vine-dressing with my own beasts and at my own expense and with my own labourers and irrigate unintermittingly and without negligence and dig about and prune and support and strip the leaves off and the D.V. from it forth-coming new sweet wine and the fruits of the date-palms and of the orchard will be divided between us in half shares, myself to take one share in return for my labour, and you to take one share as your landlord's part and when I raise reeds I shall also have the smaller reeds for the use of supporting and the half of the rent of the wooden machine we shall pay out of our common fund; and I am willing to give you for the fixed rent of the arourai all around annually, whether completely flooded or (which God forbid) unflooded ten artabai of clean corn rendered as rent by my measure and one gold nomismation less one carat by the standard of the same village of Aphrodite, i.e. 10 art. of corn and 1 g.nom. less 1 car. and to deliver them to you annually, the corn at the time of the threshing and the one nomismation at the time of the public requisition as it seems good. I received from you and owe you as advance for the oxen, i.e. eight gold nomismatia each less one carat and I shall give them to you at the time of the end of the term of the current written lease, as it seems good, undisputed. The lease shall be valid and operative; and being asked the formal question I agreed on all points. (Cross). Be it also understood that I shall give you for the completion of the rent for the arourai all around as follows: if I sow phaselos during the year I shall measure to you five artabai phaselos, but if I do not sow phaselos I shall measure to you five artabai barley as it seems good and on condition that I shall return to you an iron tool of ten and a half pound at the time of leaving the same holding for what I have got in advance from you and I again agreed (Cross) and that I be allowed one date-palm annually for the account of the labourer for the care of all the date-palms. (Cross).;(2nd hand) (Cross) I, Menas, son of Psate, agree to this lease as afore said. (Cross). (3rd hand) (Cross) I, Aurelius Psate, son of Ananias, bear witnes to this lease as afore said. (4th hand) (Cross) I, Aurelius Georgios, son of Onnophrios, bear witness to this lease as afore said.;(1st hand) (Cross) Written by me, Kollouthos, D.V. tabellio. (Crosses)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn PJ, PMich XIII, 666, 1977, Pl. XXIV-XXV -- BL VII, 117 (l. 1, 9, 29, 34, 35); BL VIII, 217 (l. 3); BL IX 163 (date)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:13:666</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3018&amp;viewid=6906R_1.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/1/6906R_1.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3018&amp;viewid=6906R_1.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3018&amp;viewid=6906R_1.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/2/6906R_2.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3018&amp;viewid=6906R_2.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3018&amp;viewid=6906R_2.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
