<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Contract for Service (Paramone Contract)</title>
            <author>Pabelleous, son of Onnophris</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3095</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3095</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.10.587</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;10;587</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;10;587</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12274</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12274</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 727</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract in which Pabelleous, son of Onnophris, places his daughter, Kolleuthis, in the service of Harmiysis, son of Onnophris, for one year, in lieu of interest on a loan of 48 drachmai which Harmiysis has made to Pabelleous</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 11.1 x 25.8 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">broken off and badly frayed at the top and bottom</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">41</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>1st hand: same as in P.Mich. X, 586; 2nd hand: in an awkward, angular style (Browne)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0024" notAfter="0025">ca. 24-25 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Pabelleous (Pabelles) son of Onnophris, Perses tes epigones</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harmiysis son of Onnophris (see also P.Mich. V, 247?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kolleuthis daughter of Pabelleous</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kollouthos son of Mieus (see also P.Mich. V, 259</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">294?)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Perses</term>
               <term>Child(?)</term>
               <term>Debt</term>
               <term>Ethnicity</term>
               <term>Loan</term>
               <term>Paramone (obligation to remain at someone's service)</term>
               <term>Iranians--Egypt</term>
               <term>Servility</term>
               <term>Woman</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[- - -] Pabelleous, son of Onnophris, Persian of the epigone, about forty years old, with a scar on the left side of his forehead, [acknowledge] to Harmiysis, son of Onnophris, about twenty-six years old, with a scar on his left calf, that he has received from him forty-eight drachmai of coined silver forthwith from hand to hand out of the house, and that in place of interest upon this sum and in return for necessities and clothing, he, the party of the first part, will present his daughter, Kolleuthis, who will remain with Harmiysis and his representatives for one year from the aforesaid date, staying and accomplishing whatever is enjoined upon her, not absenting herself night or day from the house of Harmiysis without his knowledge, but following him everywhere throughout Egypt, and it shall not be permissible for Pabelleous to remove his daughter within the period, but if he does remove her, or if she herself departs of her own free will, or they in any other way violate any of the aforesaid terms, or she is convicted of stealing(?) or damaging or removing anything belonging to Harmiysis or his representatives, or does not restore in sound condition whatever she has received to guard, unless it is taken from her by force, the party of the first part shall pay forthwith to Harmiysis both the forty-eight drachmai of silver which he has received from him, as aforesaid, increased by one half and with the interest, and a fine of one hundred drachmai, and &lt;the same amount&gt; to the treasury, and the damages; and for each day on which she is disorderly . . . (he shall pay) three obols of bronze and the principal, and five times the value of the stolen object, and one and a half times the value of the object removed {and simple interest}, and if she does not return or restore it in sound condition (he shall pay) the price corresponding to the value as assessed by Harmiysis, the right of execution resting with Harmiysis against both the debtor and his property, as if in accordance with a legal judgment. And at the expiration of the period the party of the first part shall return the above-mentioned forty-eight drachmai of silver, and if he does not return them, let him pay them increased by half, and with interest, and a fine of an additional one hundred drachmai and the same amount to the treasury. Signatory of the party of the first part: Kollouthos, son of Mieus, about 20 years old, with a scar on the right wrist.;(2nd hand) I, Pabelleous, son of Onnophris, Persian of the epigone, acknowledge that I have received forty-eight drachmai of silver [- - -]</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Browne GM, PMich X, 587, 1970 -- BL VII, 114 (l. 20; 30)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:10:587</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3095&amp;viewid=727R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/7/R/727R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3095&amp;viewid=727R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3095&amp;viewid=727R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
