<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3287</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3287</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer paying the poll-tax is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 149-150: 30.7 x 30 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 149: damaged at the top and bottom (papyrus cut off left of col. 149 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 149: 26 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 149 (l. 2586-2611)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Orsenouphis and [Anthia] grandson of Herieus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron son of Ptolemaios and Taseus grandson of Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Zenas son of Phaesis and Tapasion grandson of Zenas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 165)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchophis son of Kanis and Thermouthis grandson of Anchophis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron son of Satabous and Tkonnos grandson of Maron (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabous son of Dioskoros and Taorion (Tahorion) grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 226)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros son of Petaus and Thaesis grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras son of Petsiris and Isidora grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Agathopous, doulos of Thermouthis alias Tpaietis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 148)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Nestosiris and Thermouthis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron son of Petesouchos and Tasoucharion grandson of Petesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos son of Petesouchos and Tasoucharion grandson of Petesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymos son of Pyros (Pyrrhos) and Soeris grandson of Didymos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 161)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dioskoros son of Petheus and Taorsenouphis grandson of Kollouthos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 162)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Limnais (Limnaios) son of Onnophris and Ptolema grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 185)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kames son of Pasoxis and Thaesis grandson of Polyntikos (Polyndikos) (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Teos son of Petheus and Taonnophris grandson of Teos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 242)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon son of Pasoxis and Tanephremis grandson of Pasoxis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis son of Phanomgeus and Tepheros grandson of Pakysis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas son of Ptolemaios and Taeuemeros grandson of Sambas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 224)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasoknopais (Pasoknopaios) son of Phasis and Tanomgeus grandson of Esouris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 199)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kames son of Pnepheros and Tapetheus grandson of Ptollion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Slaves--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 149;;(Epeiph 26, continued);;Ptolemaios, son of Orsenouphis and [Anthia], grandson of Herieus, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Maron, son of Ptolemaios and Taseus, grandson of Sambathion: 8 drachmai;Zenas, son of Phaesis and Tapasion, grandson of Zenas, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Total for the day: 96 drachmai 15 obols.;;On the 27th, similarly:;Anchophis, son of Kanis and Thermouthis, grandson of Anchophis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Maron, son of Satabous and Tkonnos, grandson of Maron, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Satabous, son of Dioskoros and Taorion, grandson of Satabous, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Pnepheros, son of Petaus and Thaesis, grandson of Pnepheros: 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(-): 27 obols;Heras, son of Petsiris and Isidora, grandson of Heras: 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Agathopous, slave of Thermouthis also called Tpaietis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Petheus, son of Nestosiris and Thermouthis, grandson of Petheus, for ch(--): 28 obols;Heron, son of Petesouchos and Tasoucharion, grandson of Petesouchos: 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Petesouchos, his brother, (born) of the same mother, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Didymos, son of Pyros and Soeris, grandson of Didymos: 40 drachmai;Dioskoros, son of Petheus and Taorsenouphis, grandson of Kollouthos, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Limnais, son of Onnophris and Ptolema, grandson of Satabous, for ch(--): 4 drachmai 27 obols;Kames, son of Pasoxis and Thaesis, grandson of Polyntikos: 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Teos, son of Petheus and Taonnophris, grandson of Teos: 4 drachmai 28 obols;Chairemon, son of Pasoxis and Tanephremis, grandson of Pasoxis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;Pakysis, son of Phanomgeus and Tepheros, grandson of Pakysis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai 27 obols;Sambas, son of Ptolemaios and Taeuemeros, grandson of Sambas: [- - -];Pasoknopais, son of Phasis and Tanomgeus, grandson of Esouris: [- - -];Kames, son of Pnepheros and Tapetheus, grandson of Ptollion: [- - -]</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 149 (l. 2586-2611), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3287&amp;viewid=4172_34R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3287&amp;viewid=4172_34R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3287&amp;viewid=4172_34R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
