<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of Part of a House and Courtyard</title>
            <author>Taaous, daughter of Harobroous</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3091</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3091</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.298</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">25191</idno>
            <idno type="TM">25191</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;298dupl</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 722</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Subscription to a contract by which Taaous, daughter of Harobroous, with her husband Kronion, son of Papontos, sells to Potamon, son of Onnophris, one fifth of a three-story house and courtyard, of which are excluded two storerooms which are not held in common but belong to other people; at the top of the sheet is a note which seems to indicate that the contract (or this copy of it?) is void; in the upper left-hand margin are the descriptions of the contracting parties, including the signatory of Potamon, whose signature is omitte in this copy of the subscriptions</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Duplicate of P.S.I. VIII, 913. - Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 19.3 x 28.2 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">complete, but the ink is badly rubbed along the folds</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">2  + 27 + 15</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0001" notAfter="0099">Ist century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Taaous daughter of Harobbroous, wife of Kronion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kronion son of Papontos, husband and guardian of Taaous</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Potamon son of Onnophris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Papontos son of Maron</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orseus son of Bryon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis son of Belphis (see also P.Mich. II, p. 224</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">V, p. 389)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orseus son of Orses</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Are . .</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>House</term>
               <term>House Ownership</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Sale</term>
               <term>Topography (Tebtynis?)</term>
               <term>Woman (&amp;amp</term>
               <term>guardian)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Top) (2nd hand) . . . 17.;Void.;;(Left margin) (1st hand) Taaous, about 28 years old, with a scar on the wrist of her right hand, (and) with with long straight hair. Kronion, about 30 years old, with a scar in the middle of his face. Potamon, about 56 years old, with a scar on his right forearm. Signatory: Orseus, about 30 years old, with a scar on his right temple. (2nd hand) Are . . ., 22 years old, with a scar on the bend of his left hand and above his right eyebrow . . .;;(Subscription) I, Taaous, daughter of Harobbroous, with my guardian, my husband Kronion, son of Papontos, acknowledge that I have sold to Potamon, son of Onnophris, the fifth share, belonging to me by inheritance from my father, of a three-story house and courtyard, except for one room in the house, in which there is a storeroom in the gate building, which belongs to Papontos, son of Maron, and except for the storeroom on the first floor, inside the gate building, which belongs to Orseus, son of Bryon; everything regarding the aforesaid fifth share, with the exception of these rooms, being common and undivided with respect ot the same Potamon. The neighbors of the whole house and court are on the south the house and court of the sons of Kronion, son of . . ., on the north the house and court of Orsenouphis, son of Belphis, on the west the house of the aforesaid Kronion and his partners, on the east the royal road. And I have received from Potamon the entire price agreed upon, in full, immediately, from hand to hand, out of the house, and I guarantee the sale with every guarantee from both public and private debts and every claim forever as aforesaid. Orseus, son of Orses, wrote for them because they are illiterate.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 298, 1944 -- BL III, 115 (l.5; 6)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:298</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3091&amp;viewid=722R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3091&amp;viewid=722R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3091&amp;viewid=722R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
