<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Division of Property</title>
            <author>Herakleides, Maron, Herodes, Didymos, Herakleides alias Lourios, and Herakleia, the six children of Herakleides the younger</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1367</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1367</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.326</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;326</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;326</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12137</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12137</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1282</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract for the division among five brothers and a sister of the property which they have inherited from their parents, Herakleides the younger, son of Maron, and his wife Ptolema, daughter of Herodes (named in P.Mich. V, 350) and from a sixth brother who in the interval had died intestate. The heirs receive approximately equal shares, except for the eldest who receives an extra allotment of six arourai, perhaps as a compensation for the care of his parents in their old age. The property divided amounts to a total of 107 1/2 arourai of catoecic allotments, 5 7/8 arourai of vineyards, and 18 slaves.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 64.2 x 28.7 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">slightly damaged on the right side</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. I - 51;;col. II - 14</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>small upright hand; dots above the letters indicate the deletion of a word (l.15)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0048">April 6, 48 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Claudius, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles son of Didymos, husband and guardian of Herakleia (see also P.Mich. II, 123, recto, col. VI</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">128, col. III</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">V, 240?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Agathous, (doule)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles, son of Agathous, (doulos)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Euphrosynon, daughter of Agathous, (doule)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Epaphras, (doulos)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Leontas, (doulos)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleia alias Taarmiysis, (doule)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Narkissos, son of Herakleia alias Taarmiysis, koureus, (doulos)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapas, son of Herakleia alias Taarmiysis, (doulos)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Euphrosynos, (doule)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nike, (doule)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thermouthis (also called?) Isarous, (doule)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Serapous = Sarapous, (doule)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Euphrosynos, son of Serapous, (doulos)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Helene, daughter of Herous, (doule)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herous, (doule)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thaubas, (doule)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ganymas, son of Thaubas, (doulos)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Athene, daughter of Thaubas, (doule)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Narkissos, onelates, (doulos)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas son of Akousilaos (former owner)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herodes alias Herakleides son of Lysimachos (former owner</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">see also P.Mich. V, p. 381</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kalamos (former owner)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Theophilos (former owner)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Astragalos (see Geographica)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Amenis (see Geographica)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Polle (former owner)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Teptynis = Tebtynis; Kerkesoucha Orous; Kerkesis; Herakleidou epoikion; Kerkesephis; Theogonis; kleros Astragalou legomenos; Hellenikos; kleros Ameinis (Amenios)</term>
               <term>Theogonis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Home ownership--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Inheritance and succession--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Irrigation--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Land tenure--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Land titles--Registration and transfer--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Professions--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Slaves--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Wealth--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Women--Egypt.</term>
               <term>Kerkesoucha Orous (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Guardian and ward--Egypt.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>The eighth year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, the eleventh of Pharmouthi.;Herakleides and Maron and Herodes and Didymos and Herakleides, also called Lourios, and Herakleia, the six children of Herakleides, with the guardian of Herakleia, her husband Herakles, son of Didymos, acknowledge that they have divided among themselves by mutual consent for the present, from the present day forever, the catoecic allotment that belongs to them near the village of Tebtynis, 28 1/2 arourai in two parcels; and also the 25 arourai of a catoecic allotment near Kerkesoucha Orous in one parcel; and also the 30 arourai of a catoecic allotment near Kerkesis and the farmstead of Herakleides, or as many arourai as there may be, in three parcels; and also the 6 arourai of a catoecic allotment near Kerkesephis, in one parcel; and also the 17 1/2 arourai of a catoecic allotment near Theogonis, in two parcels; and the vineyard of 3 7/8 arourai, with the vines trained upon trees, near the same village of Theogonis, in the class subject to a tax of one sixth, all inherited from our father; and, near the same village of Theogonis, a vineyard of 2 arourai, with the vines trained upon trees, inherited from our mother, in the class subject to a tax of one sixth; and also the five slaves belonging to us by inheritance from our father, their names being Agathous, and Herakles and Euphrosynon, her children, and the others Epaphras and Leontas, five persons in all; and the thirteen slaves that belong to us by inheritance from our mother, their names being Herakleia, also called Taarmiysis, and her children, Narkissos the barber and Sarapas and Euphrosynon and Nike and Thermouthis, and Serapous and her child Euphrosynos                        , and Helene, a child of Herous, who was sold before, and the remaining four slaves, whose names are Thaubas, and Ganymas and Athene, her two children, and the other Narkissos, the muleteer.;And they agree that Herakleides has received as his portion the 6 arourai, or as many as there may be, in one parcel, of a catoecic allotment formerly the property of Sambas, son of Akousilaos, near the aforesaid village of Kerkesephis the arourai having been given to him as his share previously by our father Herakleides the younger, son of Maron, on account of his being the eldest; and that the said Herakleides has also received as his portion, from the arourai near Kerkesis and the farmstead of Herakleides, 15 1/4 arourai, or as many as there may be, in three parcels, 7 arourai in the first parcel, and from the 16 3/4 arourai in the second parcel, 2 1/4 arourai which are on the east side extending from south to north, which Didymos and Herakleides, also called Lourios, shall release from the remaining 14 1/2 arourai, which they have received as their allotment, and in the third parcel the remaining 6 arourai, called those of the lesones, formerly the property of Herodes, also called Herakleides, son of Lysimachos; and that the said Herakleides has also received as his share from the aforesaid vineyards near Theogonis, a third of the vineyard of 3 7/8 arourai called that of Kalamos, in one parcel, which share Herakleides happens to have sold previously; and that the said Herakleides the elder has also received, as his share of the aforesaid slaves, three slaves, whose names are Herakles, from Agathous, and Sarapous, with any offspring which may come from her from the present time, and her son Euphrosynos.;And they agree that Maron has received and been allotted as his share of the arourai near the aforesaid village of Tebtynis, from the 28 1/2 arourai, or as many as there may be, in two parcels, 12 3/4 arourai, or as many as there may be, in two parcels, in the first parcel 7 1/2 arourai called those of Theophilos, and in the second parcel the remaining 5 1/4 arourai, extending from south to north on the east side, which are from the 21 arourai of the so-called allotment of Astragalos; and that the said Maron has also been allotted and has received as his share of the aforesaid vineyards a third of the two arourai of the Hellenikos, paying the tax of one sixth; and that the said Maron has also received and been allotted, as his share of the aforesaid slaves, four slaves, whose names are Herakleia, also called Taarmiysis, and Narkissos the muleteer, and Leontas and Ganymas.;And they agree that Herodes has also received and been allotted as his share from the arourai near the aforesaid village of Tebtynis, from the remaining 15 3/4 arourai, 5 1/4 arourai, in one parcel, which are to the west of those arourai which Maron was allotted, extending from south to north; and that Herodes has likewise received and been allotted, from the arourai near Kerkesoucha Orous, 8 1/3 arourai, extending from south to north on the east side, which are from the 25 arourai, or as many as there may be; and that the said Herodes has also been allotted and has received as his share from the vineyards near the aforesaid village of Theogonis, one third of the two arourai of the so-called Hellenikos; and that the said Herodes has also received and been allotted, as his share of the aforesaid slaves, three slaves, whose names are Epaphras and Agathous and Euphrosynon, with any offspring which shall come from her.;And they agree that Didymos has received, as his share of the remaining 15 arourai near the aforesaid village of Kerkesis, 7 1/2 arourai on the west side extending from south to north; and that the said Didymos has also received and been allotted as his share likewise, from the arourai near the aforesaid village of Theogonis, the 9 1/2 arourai of a catoecic allotment, or as many as there may be, in one parcel, the arourai being called those of the allotment of Amenis; and that the said Didymos has likewise received and been allotted, as his share of the vineyards near the village of Theogonis, a third of those two arourai of the so-called Hellenikos; and that the said Didymos has been allotted and has received as his share of the aforesaid slaves two slaves, whose names are Euphrosynos and Isarous, with the slave offspring which shall come from her from the present time.;And they agree that Herakleides, also called Lourios, has likewise received, as his share of the arourai near the aforesaid village of Kerkesis, the remaining 7 1/2 arourai on the east side extending from west to east; and that the said Herakleides, also called Lourios, has received and been allotted as his share likewise the remaining 8 arourai of a catoecic allotment near the aforesaid village of Theogonis, frmerly those of Polle; and that the said Herakleides, also called Lourios, has also received and been allotted as his share the third part of the 3 7/8 arourai of the aforesaid vineyard called that of Kalamos, which the said Herakleides, also called Lourios, happens to have sold previously; and that the said Herakleides, also called Lourios, has also received and been allotted as his share of the aforesaid slaves, three slaves, whose names are Sarapas and Thaubas and Athene, with slave offspring which may come from them.;And they agree that Herakeia has likewise received as her share, from the remaining arourai near the aforesaid village of Tebtynis, 5 &lt;1/4&gt; arourai, in one parcel, or as many as there may be, in the middle, called those of the allotment of Astragalos; and that the said Herakleia has also received as her share, from the remaining arourai near the aforesaid village of Kerkesoucha, the 8 1/3 arourai that are in the middle of the allotment extending from south to north; and that the said Herakleia has also received as her share a third of the 3 7/8 arourai of the so-called vineyard of Kalamos near the aforesaid village of Theogonis; and that the said Herakleia has also received and been allotted, from the aforesaid slaves, three slaves, whose names are Narkissos the barber and Nike and Helene, with the slave offspring which shall come from them from the present time.;And they agree that the aforesaid four, Maron and Herodes and Didymos and Herakleides, also called Lourios, have also been allotted, besides those things which they have been allotted as aforesaid, four fifths  of the share that belonged to the deceased brother of us all, Lysas, who is dead (sic), consisting of 13 7/12 arourai, 5 1/4 arourai from those near Tebtynis, and 8 1/3 arourai near Kerkesoucha Orous, which are on the west side extending from south to north,amounting to 10 13/15 arourai. And Herakleides the elder has been allotted everything from the share that has fallen to him, which is the remainder of theaforesaid arourai of Lysas, besides what the said Herakleides has previously ceded and sold to his aforesaid male brothers Maron and Herodes and Didmos and Herakleides, also called Lourios.;And they agree that in accordance with each provision and parcel of land each one shall have other things in proportion to the entire estate, both watering and draining through the aforesaid preexisting watercourses and canals and making use of the entrances and exits and drains. And they agree upon the aforesad conditions not to bring any claim or dispute or cause any hindrance or act fraudulently. And they agree that each one has received his allotments with the seed corn that is in them from the present eighth year and for the eighth year also of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator. And they agree that each of the contracting parties and their assigns and heirs shall therefore own and control the shares which have been allotted to them from the present day forever, without question, and that one shall not proceed against the share which the other has received in any manner. If any of the aforesaid contracting parties breaks the contract, the party breaking it shall pay to the party abiding by it twice the amount of the damage and expenses and as a fine 4,000 silver drachmai, and an equal amount into the treasury. And the four persons aforesaid, Maron and Herodes and Didymos and Herakleides, also called Lourios, shall not in any way incur any loss with respect to the guarantee devolving upon Herakleides the elder of his share of the aforesaid allotments and vineyards and building sites and beer shops and vacant lots and oil press and all the appurtenances which belonged to Lysas who is dead and which he, Herakleides the elder, formerly sold and ceded to them. And everything else shall be in accordance with all the stipulations designated in the contract, which are valid, all the house property and furniture and utensils being held in common and undivided, except the share which belongs to Herakleides the elder from the share of Lysas, which he sold to the four as aforesaid.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 326, 1944 -- BL VI, 82 (bibliography). - L. 23: onelaten seems tobe corrected from auleten. (PH)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:326</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1367&amp;viewid=1282R_1.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/1/1282R_1.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1367&amp;viewid=1282R_1.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1367&amp;viewid=1282R_1.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/2/1282R_2.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1367&amp;viewid=1282R_2.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1367&amp;viewid=1282R_2.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
