<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Petition to a Strategos</title>
            <author>Ptolemaios, son of Diodoros alias Dioskoros</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1650</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1650</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.11.617</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;11;617</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;11;617</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12285</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12285</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 282</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Draft of a petition sent to the strategos of the divisions of Themistos and Polemon by Ptolemaios, son of Diodoros alias Dioskoros, who complains that owing to the negligence of the shore-guard Apollonios and of the katasporeus Tyrannos the marsh which he has leased from the domain lands near Theadelphia is in danger of going dry</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Ptolemaios, son of Diodoros alias Dioskoros</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>2 papyri ; 22 x 21 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The papyrus has suffered considerably from tears and worm-holes</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">18</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0145" notAfter="0146">145/146 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Theadelphia, Themistou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">[Theon], strategos of the Themistou kai Polemonos merides</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonios, aigialophylax</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tyrannos, katasporeus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) hyperetai</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) hegemon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) epitropos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) epistrategos</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>probably Theadelphia, Themistou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Themistou meris; Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome; Theadelphia; Neilos</term>
               <term>Administration</term>
               <term>Agriculture</term>
               <term>Justice</term>
               <term>Inundation</term>
               <term>Irrigation</term>
               <term>Kharabat Ihrit  (Egypt)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>To [Theon], strategos of the Themistou and Polemonos Merides of the Arsinoite nome, from Ptolemaios, son of Diodoros also called Dioskoros, lessee of the marsh belonging to the imperial domain land in the neighborhood village of Theadelphia and of other properties. I approached the shore-guard Apollonios and the district katasporeus many times and had many confrintations with him (the shore-guard) when he was in the village, (requesting) that they supply the customary and sufficient water to the aforesaid marsh while the Nile was still at its height and before the water should go into the fields; but up to now I have been put off by them and they have refused to supply (the water), although the most sacred Nile has brought an excellent flood and ought to benefit the entire nome. The marsh therefore remains up to today in the greatest need; for the water coming from run-off was of no great quantity and was without gonos, and had received nothing of metra. As I can find no rest because of this, I request that a duplicate of this communication be delivered to the shore-guard and to Tyrannos, the katasporeus of the district, by one of the assistants of your office, in order that the marsh may be filled or they may know that if indeed any damage results from this cause they will be called to account before the most illustrious prefect and his excellency the procurator; for once the aforesaid marsh has dried down to the ground and the gonos and metrai have been reduced, damage will result not to this year's rent only, but there will result damage for the next three years, till the marsh receives gonos and metrai for growth. I retain my claims against the shore-guard concerning the . . . injunction about the marsh for the past eighth year, for trial before his excellency the epistrategos.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Shelton JC, PMich XI, 617, 1971, Pl. VI</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:11:617</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1650&amp;viewid=282R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/8/2/R/282R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1650&amp;viewid=282R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1650&amp;viewid=282R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
