<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>encomium</title>
            <author>Gregory of Nazianzus</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2495</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2495</idno>
            <idno type="dclp">107782</idno>
            <idno type="TM">107782</idno>
            <idno type="dclp-hybrid">tm;;107782</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 5567</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>The text contains the beginning of a Sahidic translation of the Panegyric of Gregory of Nazianzus on Basil of Caesarea (for the Greek original, see Migne, PG XXXVI 493ff). The Coptic translator has often had recourse to loose paraphrase instead of verbatim rendition, and he may not always have understood his model. The introductory section (R i 1-24), set off by an elaborate border, is a considerable expansion of the Greek title.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto + Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">Louvain Ms 44;</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="egy-Copt">Coptic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 20.2 x 13.3 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This text, a folio from a bicolumnar codex, is composed of two non-contiguous pieces: P. Mich. inv. 5567a preserves the upper part of the sheet; the lower part was in the Library of the University of Louvain but was destroyed in the course of World War II. A description and a photograph of the recto of the second piece was included by L. Th. Lefort in his catalogue, Les Manuscrits coptes de L'Universite de Louvain, vol. 1 (Louvain 1940) No. 44 (and Pl. X). A tiny fragment, found in the same envelope as the Michigan section, in fact belongs to the Louvain piece. The recto fits on R i 30-32; to judge from the position of the recto, the two lines of the verso occupy, respectively, the third and fourth lines from the bottom of the second column.;Because of the nature of the translation, we cannot determine precisely how many lines have been lost between the Michigan and the Louvain pieces, but the amount of missing text was not large and probably did not exceed a few lines.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-52</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: A; Recto + Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Lefort dated the writing to the eighth century; for a close parallel cf. Schubart, P. Graec. Berol. 50  (from the White Monastery; ca. 719). Probably, it should be concluded that, if not written by the same scribe, both texts came from the same scriptorium and were clearly contemporaneous.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0700" notAfter="0799">VIIIth century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Arsinoite nome?</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Apa Gregory</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Basil</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Arsinoite nome?</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="egy-Copt">Coptic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Nazianzos;;Caesarea in Cappadocia.</term>
               <term>Doctors of the church.</term>
               <term>Theology--History--Early church, ca. 30-600.</term>
               <term>Eulogies.</term>
               <term>Christian literature.</term>
               <term>Basil,;cSaint, Bishop of Caesarea,;dca. 329-379.</term>
               <term>Gregory,;cof Nazianzus, Saint--Selections--Coptic.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">literary; Christian</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(R i; Mich.) "An encomium which the holy Apa Gregory, the theologian and the bishop of Nazianzus, pronounced concerning the life of the great Basil, the bishop of Caesarea in Cappadocia, since he was his friend; he pronounced this encomium of this fellow-worker, this ... (Louv.) ... his death, on the one hand for praise of that just and great man on account of his virtues, on the other for a benefit to us as well, we who hear, and for a profit to our souls.;In the time when our blessed father, the great Basil, was with us in the body, he would set before us continually many subjects for us to speak about. For he would rejoice (R ii Mich.) over my words more than one would rejoice over his own words. And perhaps he did this in training us that he might give us his own self now as a great subject of discourse for us to ... (Louv.) For if one wishes to manifest his ability in speech, and afterwards it seems good to him to do this in looking to the measure, that is (if) he places a single single subject before himself from all the subjects, just like the painters who look to the pictures - I think that it is to this that he will direct, as it takes precedence over the others (V i; Mich.) and surpasses speech. Thus it is a great thing to speak of the honor of this man, not only for ourselves, who have made light of the honor of this man (sic), but also for the others whose life ... (V ii) Or in what shall I exalt the speech except through the honor of this man? For, as far as I am concerned, this is an obligation for me, if I can discharge it. But, as for the speech, the debt which ...."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Worrell WH, PMichCopt., 16, 1942 Browne GM, Mich Coptic Texts, 9, 1979, Pl II</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2495&amp;viewid=5567AR.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/7/a/r/5567ar.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2495&amp;viewid=5567AR.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2495&amp;viewid=5567AR.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/7/a/v/5567av.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2495&amp;viewid=5567AV.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2495&amp;viewid=5567AV.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
