<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Bid for confiscated property</title>
            <author>Ptolemais</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1578</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1578</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.turner.24</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0214;;24</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.turner;;24</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">15692</idno>
            <idno type="TM">15692</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 206</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>A bid for the purchase of confiscated property. The bid is from Ptolemais, daughter of Agenor and granddaughter of Philiscos, submitted to Aelius Aphrodisios, strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, in the name of her daughter, Claudia Areia, for 16 arouras of catoecic land put up for sale near the epoikion of Artapatou in the middle toparchy. Ptolemais offered 3200 drachmas for 16 arouras, or 200 drachmas the aroura, a price which suggests that the land was still productive. Ptolemais and her daughter Claudia Areia, whom she mentions three times by name, owned all the land adjacent to the property upon which she was bidding. The right of neighbours to buy perhaps added weight to the bid, even when the land was in the hands of the fiscus. Neither Ptolemais nor Claudia Areia can confidently be identified in the papyri published up to now, but the husband and father was presumably a Klaudius Areius.  He may have belonged to the family of Tiberius Claudius Areios who had served as strategus of the Heracleides division of the Arsinoite nome two generations earlier, 98-101</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: recto; verso is unpublished</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 18 x 24 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The papyrus is  holey and the most of theholes follow the same pattern, which means that they were made when the papyrus was still unopened. A small fragment of c. 1 x 1 cm seems not to belong to this papyrus. I can read "adou" on the side the fibers run along, and finds no position in the present text. On the other side, where the fibers run across, the papyrus fragment is blank (NL)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">15 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The text on the back of the papyrus across the fibres is a petition. The scribe cut the papyrus to fit his petition and he gave no thought to the consequences for the writing along the fibres on the other side of the papyrus.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0148" notAfter="0154">148-154 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Oxyrhynchite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Aelius Aphrodisios, strategus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemais, daughter of Agenor, granddaughter of Philiskos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Agenor, father of Ptolemais, son of Philiskos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Philiskos, father of Agenor, grandfather of Ptolemais</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Claudia Areia, daughter of Ptolemais</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hermes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Seimias</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Oxyrhynchite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Artapatou, epoikion, Middle toparchy, Oxyrhynchite nome, province of Egypt;;Seimias, kleros, Middle toparchy (?), Oxyrhynchite nome, province of Egypt</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>To Aelius Aphrodisios, strategus, from Ptolemais, daughter of Agenor and granddaughter of Philiscos, from Oxyrhynchos, mother of Claudia Areia, through the scribe Hermes. I would like to purchase for my daughter, Claudia Areia and however she styles herself, from the property offered for sale near the epoikion of Artapatou of the middle toparchy, sixteen arouras of catoecic land out of the kleros of Seimias, the neighbours on all sides being I and my daugher, Claudia Areia, for a price of 3200 drachmas. When my offer is confirmed on these terms, I shall pay the total amount in her behalf to the public bank ...; for the rest, hoever, we shall be totally without obligation, but the ownership will rest with Claudia Areia and her descendants and those acting for her.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Hanson AE, PTurner, 24, 1981</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Turner:24</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1578&amp;viewid=206R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/0/6/r/206r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1578&amp;viewid=206R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1578&amp;viewid=206R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
