<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3348</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3348</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 61 is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 61-62: 34.5 x 29.5 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 61: complete (papyrus cut off left of col. 61 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 61: 57 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 61 (l. 1551-1607)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Maron son of Ptolemaios and Taseus grandson of Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Ischyrion and Tepheros grandson of Pasoknopaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptollas son of Satabous and Tapondos (Tapontos) grandson of Ptollas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 221)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion son of Petheus and Tathautis grandson of Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabous son of Petheus and Tapetaus grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 226)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion son of Pasoxis and Segathis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes son of Phaesis and Aynchis grandson of Mysthes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion son of Kanis and Thermouthis grandson of Anchophis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis son of Pekmeis alias Heuremon and Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos son of Petheus and Tkollainis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes son of Teberis and Isidora grandson of Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides son of Abykis and Herais grandson of Abykis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Sisois and Thaesis grandson of Petsiris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harpagathes son of Satabous and Sambathion grandson of Anchophis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psenesis son of Pharmenion (Parmenion) and Tkonnos grandson of Psenesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Heron and Eserempis grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Sokmenis and Thaesis grandson of Sokmenis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 204)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Didymion son of Petheus presbyteros and Tasoucharion grandson of Didymion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 161)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis son of Ptolemaios and Soeris grandson of Orsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 194)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Valerius son of Valeria, apator (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 195)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aunes son of Aunes and Tapetheus grandson of Hermas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 157)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus son of Sisois and Thermouthis grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon son of Heron and Didyme grandson of Orsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion alias Sokrates son of Achillas and Tamaron grandson of Hatres (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apynchis son of Pnepheros and Tasoucharion grandson of Pakysis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 154)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron son of Petesouchos and Tasoucharion grandson of Petesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Esouris son of Kames and Thaesis grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Illegitimacy--Egypt</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 61;;(Pachon 4, continued);Maron, son of Ptolemaios and Taseus, grandson of Sambathion: 4 drachmai;    column 101;Petheus, son of 'Ischyrion' and Tepheros, grandson of Pasoknopaios: 8 drachmai;    column 103;Ptollas, son of Satabous and Tapondos, grandson of Ptollas: 8 drachmai;    column 97;Total for the day: 76 drachmai 28 obols.;;On the 5th, similarly:;Pasion, son of Petheus and Tathautis, grandson of Sambathion: 8 drachmai;    column 62;Satabous, son of Petheus and Tapetaus, grandson of Satabous: 4 drachmai;    column 1;Pasion, son of Pasoxis and Segathis, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai;    column 2;Mysthes, son of Phaesis and Aynchis, grandson of Mysthes: 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(---), 4 drachmai;    column 4;Horion, son of Kanis and Thermouthis, grandson of Anchophis: 8 drachmai;    column 4;Phaesis, son of Pekmeis also called Heuremon and Sambathion: 4 drachmai;    column 6;Petesouchos, son of Petheus and Tkollainis, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai;    column 7;Mysthes, son of Teberis and Isidora, grandson of Sambathion: 8 drachmai;    column 8;Herakleides, son of Abykis and Herais, grandson of Abykis: 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(---), 4 drachmai;    column 9;Onnophris, son of Sisois and Thaesis, grandson of Petsiris: 4 drachmai;    column 12;Harpagathes, son of Satabous and Sambathion, grandson of Anchophis: 4 drachmai;    column 12;Psenesis, son of Pharmenion and Tkonnos, grandson of Psenesis: 4 drachmai;    column 16;Petheus, son of Heron and Eserempis, grandson of Pnepheros: 4 drachmai;    column 17;Petheus, son of Sokmenis and Thaesis, grandson of Sokmenis: 8 drachmai;    column 17;Didymion, son of Petheus the elder and Tasoucharion, grandson of Didymion: 4 drachmai;    column 25;Orsenouphis, son of Ptolemaios and Soeris, grandson of Orsenouphis: 4 drachmai;    column 28;Valerius, of unknown father, the son of Valeria: 28 obols;    column 29;Aunes, son of Aunes and Tapetheus, grandson of Hermas: 4 drachmai;    column 32;Petaus, son of Sisois and Thermouthis, grandson of Satabous: 4 drachmai;    column 34;Chairemon, son of Heron and Didyme, grandson of Orsenouphis: 4 drachmai 28 obols;    column 35;Sarapion also called Sokrates, son of Achillas and Tamaron, grandson of Hatres: 4 drachmai;    column 38;Apynchis, son of Pnepheros and Tasoucharion, grandson of Pakysis: 4 drachmai;    column 39;Heron, son of Petesouchos and Tasoucharion, grandson of Petesouchos: 24 drachmai;    column 23;Esouris, son of Kames and Thaesis, grandson of Heras: 4 drachmai;    column 41</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 61 (l. 1551-1607), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3348&amp;viewid=4172_17RO.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/7/r/o/4172_17ro.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3348&amp;viewid=4172_17RO.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3348&amp;viewid=4172_17RO.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
