<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Copy of a Settlement of Debt and Extracts from Census Registers</title>
            <author>Unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2555</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2555</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">41728</idno>
            <idno type="TM">41728</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;22;15704</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 5806</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>The papyrus groups 4 different items: 1) a copy of the settlement of a debt, by which Gaius Sempronius Priscus alias Ammon cedes to his brother and creditor Marcus Sempronius Vestinus his ownership on a fraction of a house and on a family of 4 slaves (original of 121 A.D.); 2) an extract from the census register of 131/132 A.D., describing the household of Apronios son of Marcus and of his mother Kronous; 3) an extract from the census register of 117/118 A.D., describing the same household; 4) an extract from the census register of 131/132 A.D., describing the household of Sempronia Akousarion (sister of the Sempronii of the first copied document) and her son Gaius Sempronius Diogenes, including the family of slaves appearing in the first copied document.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Cairo</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 32.5 x 21.7 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">slightly broken off on the right lower edge</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. I - 41;Col. II - 47</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>clear and practised hand</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0138">(After) 138 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Unknown place, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius Sempronius Priscus alias Ammon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marcus Sempronius Vestinus, his brother</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hediste, slave ceded by Gaius Sempronius Priscus alias Ammon to his brother, later slave partly belonging to their sister Sempronia Akousarion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kallistos, son of Hediste, slave ceded by Gaius Sempronius Priscus alias Ammon to his brother, later slave partly belonging to their sister Sempronia Akousarion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Hediste, slave ceded by Gaius Sempronius Priscus alias Ammon to his brother, later slave partly belonging to their sister Sempronia Akousarion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Serapias, daughter of Hediste, slave ceded by Gaius Sempronius Priscus alias Ammon to his brother, later slave of their sister Sempronia Akousarion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hadrianus, former Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kronous, daughter of Maron and Pra[.]ous, granddaughter of Maron, mother of Apronios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marcus son of Apronios, hippeus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apronios, son of Marcus and of Kronous, grandson of Apronios, idiotes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonous, daughter of Heron, granddaughter of Aunes, wife of Apronios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apronios alias Pasinikos, son of Apronios and Ammonous</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kroniaina or Kronia, daughter of Apronios and Ammonous</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sempronia, daughter of Apronios and Ammonous, wife of Marcus Valerius Rufus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marcus Valerius Rufus, , hekatontarches speires (centurio cohortis), husband of Sempronia</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dioskoros, slave of Apronios son of Marcus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pantagathos, slave of Apronios son of Marcus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dioskorous, slave of Apronios son of Marcus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gaius Sempronius Diogenes, son of Sempronia Akousarion, spourios (spurius)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Flavius Titianus, prefect of Egypt</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kreskes (Crescens), slave of Sempronia Akousarion, Gaius Sempronius (Priscus alias Ammon) and Marcus Sempronius (Vestinus), later of Sempronia Akousarion alone</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sempronia Akousarion, sister of Gaius Sempronius (Priscus alias Ammon, and of Marcus Sempronius Vestinus), mother of Gaius Sempronius Diogenes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thermoutharion alias Arsinoe, daughter of Hediste, slave of Sempronia Akousarion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Onnophris, phrontistes of Marcus Sempronius Vestinus</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>amphodon Hermouthiakes (Arsinoiton polis); amphodon Boutaphiou (Arsinoiton polis); (amphodon) Phremei (Arsinoiton polis)</term>
               <term>Debtor and creditor--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Slavery--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Citizenship--Rome.</term>
               <term>Census--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Inheritance and succession--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Home ownership--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Courtyards--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax exemption--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col. I);;Copy.;Gaius Sempronius Priscus alias Ammon to his brother Marcus Sempronius Vestinus, greetings. I acknowledge to have ceded to you from all my possessions which are in the metropolis of the Arsinoite nome a tenth part of a house and a court-yeard, inherited from my father, in the quarter Hermouthiake and four slaves, named Hediste and her off-spring Kallistos and Heron and Serapias in exchange for the three thousand five hundred silver drachmai which I owe you in cash and I shall not prosecute you nor your heirs nor the slaves about anything of the things stated above nor about any matter whatsoever written or unwritten up to the present day in no way. This contract is binding. Year five of Imperator Caesar Traianus Hadrianus Augustus, Epeiph 9.;Copy from the census register incorporating descriptions of the 16th year of the divine Hadrianus, quarter Boutaphion, a 1/6 part of a house of his mother Kronous on the strength of her own memorandum. Apronios, son of Marcus, cavalryman, whose mother is Kronous, the daughter of Maron, past the age, released from the poll-tax in year 15, 61 years of age. Apronios, alias Pasinikos, son of the mother Ammonous, the daughter of Heron, scrutinized in year 15, 21 years of age. Kronous, daughter of Maron, granddaughter of Maron, whose mother is Pra.ous, herself being the mother of Apronios, 78 years of age. Ammonous, daughter of Heron, granddaughter of Aunes, his wife, 60 years of age. Kroniaina, daughter of both, 31 years of age. It had been made clear that his other daughter, Sempronia, has married Marcus Valerius Rufus, a centurion of a cohort.;;(Col. II);From the census register incorporating descriptions of the 2nd year of Hadrianus, quarter Boutaphion, a 1/6 part of a house, near (the quarter) Phremei, of his mother Kronous, daughter of Maron. Apronios, son of Marcus, deceased cavalryman, grandson of Apronios, whose mother is Kronous, a layman, enrolled in the class subject to poll-tax, 48 years of age, with a scar on the middle of his nose. Apronios, alias Pasinikos, whose mother is Ammonous, daughter of Heron, not registered, 8 years of age without distinguishing marks. Dioskoros, slave of Apronios, son of Marcus, 4 years of age without distinguishing marks. Panagathosm another slave of the same, 2 years of age without distinguishing marks. Kronous, daughter of Maron, granddaughter of Maron whose mother is Kronous &gt;read: Pra.ous&gt;, the before mentioned mother of Apronios, 64 years of age. Ammonous, daughter of Heron, granddaughter of Aunes, wife of Apronios, 36 &lt;read: 46&gt; years of age. Sempronia, daughter of both, 20 years. Kroniaina, another daughter, 17 years of age. Dioskoros, a slave of Apronios, son of Marcus, 33 years of age.;Copy from the census register incorporating descriptions of the 16th year of the divine Hadrianus, quarter Hermouthiake, 1st volume, 25th sheet, after other things, a 4/30 part of a house of his mother Sempronia. Gaius Sempronius Diogenes, bastard, whose mother is Sempronia Akousarion, scrutinized in the year 16 by the prefect Flavius Titianus. Crescens, a slave of Sempronia Akousarion, formerly of her and of Gaius Sempronius and of Marcus Sempronius, scrutinized by - - -maios, former strategos, in year 15, . . . years of age. Kallistos, a slave of the same for a 3rd part, off-spring of Hediste, above registered as belonging to the men. Heron, another off-spring of the same, slave of the same for a 3rd part, not registered, 9 years of age. Females: Sempronia Akousarion, mother of Gaius, 57 years of age. Hediste, slave of the same for a 3rd part, formerly of her deceased brother Gaius Sempronius Priscus, who has also be registered above. Serapias, off-spring of the same, slave of the same, likewise registered above. Thermoutharion, alias Arsinoe, another off-spring of the same, likewise registered above. She had made clear that from the before mentioned parts of slaves only Heron has been registered by Onnophris, son of Onnophris, bailiff of Marcus Sempronius Vestinus who was absent and who was not really a - - - of him.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn PJ, ZPE 98, 283-291, 1984</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2555&amp;viewid=1">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
