<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Division of Property</title>
            <author>Psyphis alias Harpochration, son of Serapion alias Marepkemis, and his wife Tetosiris alias Dionysia, daughter of Maron alias Marepsemis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3232</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3232</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.322</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12132</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12132</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12133</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12133</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;322a</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;322b</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 967</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Will, in the form of a contract by which Psyphis alias Harpochration, son of Serapion alias Marepkemis, and his wife Tetosiris alias Dionysia, daughter of Maron alias Marepsemis, divide their property among their sons, daughters and grandsons; these take immediate possession of the property, and, in return, they are required to provide their parents with wheat, oil and money for clothing and expenses. (See also P.Mich. V, 238, l. 151, where this contract is recorded)</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">The "chersokopai arourai" would be land which had been cleared and ploughed, but which was still unproductive.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto (see also text b: account of a beer shop)</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 80.4 x 28.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The sheet bearing text a is nearly complete; the sheet bearing text b (account of a beer shop) was attached to the left-hand side of text a, which covers the right-hand column of figures in the account</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Text a - 49</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Text a</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Small upright cursive; written under dictation (as shown by the subscription of Psyphis), a fact that may account for the somewhat ungrammatical, but colloquial, style of some of the passages. Several of the subscriptions were written by slow-writers.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0046">November 1, 46 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Claudius, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tetosiris alias Dionysia, daughter of Maron alias Marepsemis, wife of Psyphis alias Harpochration</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">add P.Mich. II, 123, recto, col. XI, l. 13?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psenkebkis son of Psenkebkis and Tamarres, grandson of Psyphis alias Harpochration and of Tetosiris alias Dionysia</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tamarres daughter of Psyphis alias Harpochration and of Tetosiris alias Dionysia, wife of Marepsemis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thaubastis daughter of Psyphis alias Harpochration and of Tetosiris alias Dionysia</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Taketon (see Geographica)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Konnas (former owner)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles neoteros son of Orsenouphis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Atesis (former owner)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ninis (former owner)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marepsemis, lesones (former owner)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tyche alias Tapaeis, paidiske doule</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thaesis daughter of Tyche alias Tapaeis, slave</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thaubas daughter of Tyche alias Tapaeis, slave</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marepsemis alias Kephalas son of Psyphis, husband and guardian of Tamarres daughter of Psyphis alias Harpochration (see also P.Mich. inv. 963)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Noumenios (see Geographica)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pabis (former owner)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thaesis daughter of Marepsemis, wife of Psyphis son of Onnophris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thermouthis (daughter of Maron alias Marepsemis), sister of Tetosiris alias Dionysia</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Marepsemis alias Kalamos son of Marepsemis and Thermouthis, nephew and guardian of Tetosiris alias Dionysia (see also P.Tebt. II, 383)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tamarres daughter of Marsisouchos, (widow of Psenkebkis son of Psyphis alias Harpochration), mother of Psenkebkis son of Psenkebkis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Dionysios son of Maron, kinsman and guardian ofThaubastis daughter of Psyphis alias Harpochration (see P.Mich. V, p. 187)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakebkis (son of Marsisouchos), brother and guardian of Tamarres daughter of Marsisouchos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Marsisouchos (see also P.Mich. II, 121, recto, col. I, abstract 2</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">V, 290 = P.S.I. VIII, 912)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome; dioryx legomene Taketonos; Isieiou hierou amphodon (Tebtynis); Noumeniou legomenos kleros; Kerkesis (Kerkeesis); Kerkesoucha Orous</term>
               <term>Agriculture</term>
               <term>Building</term>
               <term>Dowry--Egypt--Tebtynis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Family</term>
               <term>Funerary Practices</term>
               <term>House Ownership</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Inheritance</term>
               <term>Irrigation</term>
               <term>Land Ownership</term>
               <term>Land Status</term>
               <term>Marriage</term>
               <term>Priest</term>
               <term>Religion</term>
               <term>Slave</term>
               <term>Topography (Tebtynis)</term>
               <term>Woman (&amp;amp</term>
               <term>guardian)</term>
               <term>Kerkesoucha Orous (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>The seventh year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, the fifth of the month Neos Sebastos, in Tebtynis in the division of Polemon of the Arsinoite nome. Psyphis, also called Harpochration, son of Serapion also called Marepkemis, about sixty-nine years old, with a scar on his shin, acknowledges that he has made a division from the present time among the children borne to him by the wife with whom he lives without written contract, Tetosiris also called Dionysia, daughter of Maron also called Marepsemis, that is, among his son, Onnophris and Psyphis, and Psenkebkis, the son of his other son Psenkebkis, who is dead, and among the daughters born of the same Tetosiris, Tamarres and Thaubastis (as follows): ;(1) to Onnophris the sacred land that belongs to him, Psyphis, also called Harpochration, near the aforesaid village of Tebtynis, three arourai of the land of the god Soknebtynis, called chersokopai, the neighbors of which are on the south the canal, called that of Taketon, on the north the public land and in part the uncultivated land, on the west the public land, and on the east the allotment formerly that of Konnas, now belonging to Herakles the younger, son of Orsenouphis; ;(2) and also to the said Onnophris the pastophorion belonging to him, Psyphis, also called Harpochration, formerly called that of Atesis, within the inner enclosure of the temple of Kronos, the great god, in the village;;(3) and to his aforesaid sons Onnophris and Psyphis and to his grandson Psenkebkis, to the three the sacred land of the god Souchos, that belongs to him, Psyphis, also called Harpochration, near the same village of Tebtynis, it being the land from the cutting of the vineyard, one and five-sixteenths arourai, and the share that belongs to him of the storehouse and water and fishing and dyke and well and well sweeps and watchtower and all the appurtenances held in common and undivided by himself and the aforesaid Tetosiris, also called Dionysia, to each one of them one third;;(4) and to the same three, Onnophris and Psyphis and Psenkebkis, the three houses that belong to him, Psyphis, also called Harpochration, in the same village of Tebtynis, in one parcel, with the two courtyards and the entrances and exits, one the houses having two stories and called an oil press, the second having three stories and a courtyard and entrance and exit, and the third having two stories and called a hall, with a courtyard and entrance and exit;;(5) and also to the three, Onnophris and Psyphis and Psenkebkis, the old two-story house and courtyard called those of Ninis, which belong to him, Psyphis, also called Harpochration, in another parcel, on the west of the colonnade of the god Soknebtynis near the quarter of the temple of Isis, in the village,;(6) and in addition to these one and one-half shares from the five shares of the property inherited from his father, building sites and vacant lots, common and undivided;;(7) and likewise to the same three, Onnophris and Psyphis and Psenkebkis, the one and one-half shares that belong to him, Psyphis, also called Harpochration, from the five shares of the other five pastophoria, common and undivided, within the precincts of the temple of the great god Kronos in Tebtynis;;(8) and likewise to the three, Onnophris and Psyphis and Psenkebkis, the barn, formerly called that of Marepsemis, the lesones, that belongs to him, Psyphis, also called Harpochration, within the outer precinct of the same temple on the west of the colonnade that is within the gate, and in the case of all the aforesaid building sites and pastophoria, in like manner one third to each of them, Onnophris and Psyphis and Psenkebkis, with the exception of the aforesaid pastophorion, formerly called that of Atesis, which was apportioned to Onnophris alone;;(9) and to the same three, Onnophris and Psyphis and Psenkebkis, the female slave, that belongs to him, Psyphis, also called Harpochration, her name being Tyche, also called Tapaeis, and also her two female children, whose names are Thaesis and Thaubas, together with any slave offspring which shall come from them, in like manner one third to each of them, Onnophris and Psyphis and Psenkebkis;;and in the case of the aforesaid one and five-sixteenths arourai of sacred land and all the building sites and the one and one-half share of the five shares of the five pastophoria inherited from his father, and the barn and all the slaves, they are to be held in common and undivided by the three of them, in the case of all these building sites and pastophoria, of which the neighbors are set forth in the documents concerning them. Psyphis, also called Harpochration, also acknowledges that he has apportioned from the present time to his aforesaid daughters, Tamarres and Thaubastis, ;(10) to Tamarres the three arourai, or thereabouts, which Psyphis, also called Harpochration, formerly gave to her as dowry, through the alimentary contract which Tamarres made with her husband Marepsemis, son of Psyphis, the arourai being in the allotment called that of Noumenios, on the north, the neighbors of which are set forth in the alimentary contract;;(11) and to Thaubastis, also in the allotment called that of Noumenios, in another parcel on the south side, two arourai, or thereabouts, of a catoecic allotment,a nd of these also the neighbors are set forth in the documents concerning them;;(12) and also to the said Tamarres and Thaubastis the shares of the house and lots called those of Pabis, which Psyphis, also called Harpochration, gave them as dowry;;(13) and also to the aforesaid three, Onnophris and Psyphis and Psenkebkis, whatever Psyphis, also called Harpochration, shall leave in the way of utensils and furniture and household stock and sums due him and cattle of all kinds, to each likewise one third.;And the wife of the contracting party, Psyphis, also called Harpochration, the aforesaid Tetosiris, also called Dionysia, daughter of Maron, also called Marepsemis, about sixty years old, with a scar on her left forearm, also cedes from the present time the catoecic allotment of nine arourai that belongs to her near Kerkesis in the same division, in one parcel, and three arourai of vineland near the same village Kerkesis in another parcel, and one and thirteen thirty-seconds arourai of the sacred land of the god Souchos, that belongs to the said Tetosiris, also called Dionysia, near the aforesaid village of Tebtynis, in addition to the sacred land which the aforesaid Psyphis, also called Harpochration has divided as aforesaid; and likewise her share of the storehouse, and water and fishing and dyke and well and well sweep and watchtower and all the appurtenances, held in common and undivided by herself and the aforesaid Psyphis, also called Harpochration, to her aforesaid sons, Onnophris and Psyphis;;(1) to Onnophris one third of the one and thirteen thirty-seconds of sacred land near the aforesaid village of Tebtynis; and to Psyphis and Psenkebkis the remaining two thirds of the same sacred land;d;(2) and likewise to the said Psyphis three arourai from the nine arourai of the catoecic allotments near Kerkesis;;(3) and also to Psyphis one aroura from the three arourai of vineland near the said village of Kerkesis, in the second parcel;;and to her grandsons Psenkebkis, son of Psenkebkis, and Psyphis, son of Onnophris,;(4) to Psenkebkis, three arourai from the six remaining arourai of catoecic allotments near Kerkesis;;(5) and also to Psenkebkis, one aroura from the remaining two arourai of vineland in the second parcel;;(6) and to the aforesaid grandson, Psyphis, son of Onnophris, the remaining three arourai of catoecic allotments near Kerkesis, which Tetosiris, also called Dionysia, formerly gave to him through the alimentary contract which he, Psyphis, made with his wife, Thaesis,d aughter of Marepsemis;;(7) and also to the said Psyphis the remaining one aroura of vineland likewise near the said Kerkesis, the neighbors of which and of the arourai near Kerkesis and of the two and twenty-three thirty-seconds of sacred land near Tebtynis are set forth in the documents concerning them. And with regard to the property which she has divided and ceded from the present time, which she has ceded to each one as aforesaid, the aforesaid Psyphis, also called Harpochration, and Tetosiris, also called Dionysia, shall not have any power over all the aforesaid property, either to sell it or to mortgage it or alienate it or leave it to anyone else or otherwise dispose of it under any pretext, but they (the heirs) shall have control over it, and shall have the power to sell and mortgage and alienate and lease it in any manner they may desire, not requiring the presence of Psyphis, also called Harpochration, and Tetosiris, also called Dionysia, under any pretext. And the aforesaid Onnophris and Psyphis and Psenkebkis must also furnish the aforesaid Psyphis, also called Harpochration, and Tetosiris, also called Dionysia, as long as they live, two artabai of wheat and six kotylai of oil each month, and on account of expenses and clothing three hundred drachmai a year. And the three must likewise repay whatever the acknowledging parties are proved to owe either in the way of a written note or from hand to hand or by contract or in the way of public charges. And whenever the acknowledging parties shall die, the same three (sons) shall provide a funeral and laying out for both of them, suitable to their station in life, each of the three paying a third of the expense. There has been appointed as guardian of the aforesaid Tetosiris, also called Dionysia, the son of her sister Thermouthis, Marepsemis, also called Kalamos, son of Marepsemis, about forty years old, with a scar in the middle of his forehead. The aforesaid Onnophris, about 45 years old, with a scar on his right eyebrow, and Psyphis, about 33 years old, with a scar in the middle of his forehead, and Tamarres, about 42 years old, with a scar on her left forearm, and Thaubastis, about 39 years old, with a scar on the left side of her nose, and Thaesis, about 22 years old, with a scar on her left forearm, and the mother of Psenkebkis, Tamarres, daughter of Marsisouchos, about 38 years old, with a scar at the tip of her left eyebrow, with the guardian of Tamarres, her husband Marepsemis, also called Kephalas, son of Psyphis, about 45 years old, with a mole on his left eyebrow, and the guardian of Thaesis, her aforesaid husband Psyphis, about 27 years old, with a scar on the left side of his forehead beside the eyebrow,a nd the guardian of Thaubastis, Dionysios, son of Maron, about 66 years old, with a scar on his right wrist, give their consent to this agreement, to which they have agreed as it was read to them. The signatories of the aforesaid persons are for Tetosiris the aforesaid guardian appointed for her, Marepsemis, also called Kalamos, son of Marepsemis; and for Tamarres, daughter of Marsisouchos, &lt;and&gt; her brother Pakebkis, about twenty-eight years old, with a scar under the middle of his chin, the signatory Onnophris, son of Marsisouchos, about 55 years old, with a scar on the ankle bone of his right foot.;(2nd hand) I, Psyphis, also called Harpochration, son of Sarapion, also called Marepkemis, acknowledge that I have divided from the present time among my aforesaid sons and dayghters and grandson the aforesaid property that belongs to me, to each of them as aforesaid on the terms that I, Psyphis, also called Harpochration, have dictated, in accordance with which I shall not have the power to sell or mortgage or alienate or divide among others except the aforesaid, as aforesaid, to which terms I have agreed as they were read.;(2rd hand) I, Tetosiris, also called Dionysia, daughter of Maron, also called Marepsemis, with my guardian, the son of my sister Thermouthis, Marepsemis, also called Kalamos, son of Marepsemis, acknowledge that I consent to the aforesaid division. And I, Tetosiris, also called Dionysia, also acknowledge that I have ceded to my aforesaid sons and grandsons from the present time the property which I ceded to them as aforesaid, and according to the terms I shall not have any power over all this property, either to sell it or mortgage it or alienate it or leave it to others or cede it, but they shall be in control and according to the terms shall have the power from the present time to sell and mortgage and alienate and lease it in whatever manner they may desire free from interference, not requiring my presence, as my aforesaid husband, Psyphis, also called Harpochration,has ceded as aforesaid, to which I also have agreed as it was read. I, Marepsemis, wrote for Tetosiris, also called Dionysia, because she is illiterate, and I have been appointed as her guardian.;(4th hand) I, Onnophris, son of Psyphis, acknowledge that I give my consent to the aforesaid agreement, to the terms of which I have agreed as they were read, as aforesaid.;(5th hand) I, Psyphis, son of Psyphis, acknowledge that I have given my consent to the agreement, to the terms of which I have agreed as they were read, as aforesaid.;(6th hand) I, Tamarres, daughter of Psyphis, with my guardian, my husband Marepsemis, son of Psyphis, acknowledge that I have given my consent to the agreement, to the terms of which I have agreed as they were read, as aforesaid. I, Marepsemis, wrote for my wife because she is illiterate.;(7th hand) I, Thaubastis, daughter of Psyphis, with my guardian, my kinsman Dionysios, son of Maron, acknowledge that I have given my consent to this agreement, to which I have agreed as it was read, as aforesaid. I, Dionysios, wrote for her because she is illiterate.;(8th hand) I, Thaesis, daughter of Marepsemis, with my guardian, my husband Psyphis, son of Onnophris, and I also, Psyphis, acknowledge that we have given our consent to this agreement, to the terms of which we have agreed as they were read, as aforesaid. I, Psyphis, wrote for my wife because she is illiterate, and I have been appointed her guardian.;(9th hand) I, Tamarres, daughter of Marsisouchos, with my guardian, my brother Pakebkis, give my consent to the division, as aforesaid. Onnophris, son of Marsisouchos, wrote for them because they are illiterate.;(1st hand) The seventh year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, the fifth day of the month Neos Sebastos. Registered throught the record office in the village and Kerkesoucha Orous.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 322, text a, 1944 -- BL IX, 160 (l. 37).</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:322</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3232&amp;viewid=967R_1.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/1/967R_1.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3232&amp;viewid=967R_1.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3232&amp;viewid=967R_1.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/2/967R_2.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3232&amp;viewid=967R_2.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3232&amp;viewid=967R_2.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/3/967R_3.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3232&amp;viewid=967R_3.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3232&amp;viewid=967R_3.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
