<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lease of Land</title>
            <author>Phoibammon, son of Triadelphos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3019</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3019</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.13.667</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;13;667</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;13;667</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">37326</idno>
            <idno type="TM">37326</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 6907</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract by which the landowner Phoibammon, son of Triadelphos, leases a holding from the monastery of Apa Sourous in Aphrodite</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto (written across the fibres)</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Dioskoros of Aphrodito</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 61 x 31 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">broken off at the top</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">53</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written across the fibres; 7th hand uses dots to separate one wor from another (as in Latin texts)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0500" notAfter="0599">(Middle of the) VIth century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>probably Aphrodite (Aphrodito), Antaiopolite nome, province of the Lower Thebais, Thebais, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Psentouses &lt;or Psentases?&gt; (see Geographica)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tchious (see Geographica)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(monastery of) apa Sourous (see Calderini, Diz. I, 2, p. 333 etc.)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kollouchios (also Koullouchios), monazon kai proestos of the monastery of aba Sourous (see also P.Cair.Masp. III, 67342?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ioannes (John) son of Samouelios (Samuel), presbyteros kai diakonos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ioannes (John), deceased scholasticus and censitor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Victor son of Phoibammon, presbyteros of the Hagia Katholike Ekklesia of apa Mousaios (see also P.Michael. 45</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">P.Lond. V, 1661)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(Holy Catholic Church of) apa Mousaios (see Calderini, Diz. I, 2, p.339)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Daueid (David) son of Andreas, anaknostois (anagnostes) of the Hagia Katholike Ekklesia of apa Mousaios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(Holy Place of) apa Promaos (Promauos), martys (see also P.Cair.Masp. III, 67283)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Ioannes (John) son of Kyriakos (see also P.Cair.Masp. I, 67094</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">67109)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Aphrodite (Aphrodito), Antaiopolite nome, province of the Lower Thebais, Thebais, Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>ktema (...) legoumenon Psentousetos (see also P.Cair.Masp. I, 67087?); kleros Tchioutos; ktema legomenon ton bapheon; Antaiopolite nome</term>
               <term>Cadastre</term>
               <term>Land Ownership</term>
               <term>Lease</term>
               <term>Priest (Christian)</term>
               <term>Taxation (Land)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>[- - - we agree] with each other what has been written below. I, the afore-said Phoibammon, son of Triadelphos, landowner, acknowledge to the board of management of the afore-said holy monastery of Apa Sourous through the most highly favoured Kollouchios, monk and manager through you the most discreet Ioannes, son of Samouelios, presbyter and administrator, that I shall give the taxes for the below-mentioned holding of the same holy monastery, called of Psentouses, located in the western plain of the same village in the kleros of Tchious to the west of my own holding called "of the dyers" in corn and the taxes in gold, and the freight-charges and every kind of supply-levy, according to the register in the official book of Ioannes of learned memory, former scholasticus and censitor, or, if such there should be according to any other survey in the Antaipolite nome starting with the crop of the D.V. coming sacred fifteenth indiction, including it, and throughout succeeding time continually for ever. On condition that in addition to the tax-payment for the afore-mentioned holding I shall give you annually twenty artabai of clean corn rendered as rent by your measure and fifty vessels of new sweet wine, each vessel containing six xestai, while you give the vessels, i.e. 20 art. corn and 50 ves. of wine only, the corn at the time of the threshing, the wine at the time of the vintage. If any of us tries to transgress this eternal and written agreement in anything and will not abide by it the party who does not abide by it will provide to the party who does abide by it on account of penalty on the basis of the formal question being asked and agreed upon and on account of the transgression three ounces of gold which may be demanded with full power of action and after that this written agreement will be valid and operative wherever it is produced, which agreement written in two copies identical in tenor we have executed; and for all that is written above and for the claim on the afore-mentioned penalty we have submitted to each other the possessions of the afore-mentioned monastery and the possessions of the afore-mentioned Phoibammon movable, immovable and live-stock, in every class and kind as a pledge and with the force of a mortgage as though by decree of court; and concerning all that is herein written having asked each other the formal question and being asked by each other the formal question we agreed that these things were so, and so to give, do and keep, to abide for ever and to bring to an end with our own subscription and the one of the customary witnesses in order. (3 crosses).;(2nd H.) (Cross) The afore-said board of managers of the holy monastery of Apa Sourous through the most highly favoured Kollouchios, monk and manager of the same holy monastery through me, Ioannes, son of Samouelios, presbyter and administrator, the afore-mentioned I executed this agreement and I agree with all that is herein written as afore mentioned and I subscribed with my own hand by order of the afore-said manager. (2 crosses).;(3rd H.) (Cross) I, the afore-said Aurelius Phoibammon, son of Triadelphos, executed this agreement and I agree with all that is herein written as afore said and having subscribed and read it I delivered it. (Cross).;(4th H.) (Cross) I, Victor, son Phoibammon, presbyter of the Holy Catholic Church of Apa Moses, bear witness to this agreement, having heard declarations from the persons executing it (Cross) and bear witness also that I have heard from the afore-mentioned manager that he ordered the most discreet Ioannes, presbyter, to execute this agreement.;(5th H.) (Cross) I, Daueid, son of Andreas, reader of the (6th H.) same (5th H.) Holy Catholic Church bear witness to this agreement, having heard declarations from the persons executing it (Cross) and bear witness also that I heard from the afore-mentioned manager that he ordered Ioannes, the most discreet presbyter to execute this agreement.;(7th H.) (Cross) I, Ioannes, son of Promaos, reader of the Holy Place of Apa Promaos the martyr, bear witness to this agreement, having heard declarations from the persons executing it and bear witness also that I heard from the afore-mentioned manager that he ordered Ioannes, the most discreet presbyter to execute this agreement.;(8th H.) I, Aurelius Ioannes, son of Kyriakos, bear witness to this agreement, having heard declarations from the persons executing it.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn PJ, PMich XIII, 667, 1977, Pl. XXVI -- L. 4: Psentouses (or is it Psentases?) may be the name of the holding (ktema) leased to Phoibammon (as in the index of P.Mich. XIII, p. 132) rather than the name of a small monastery dependent from the bigger monastery of Apa Sourous. (PH); BL XI, 133 (For David, cf. P. Hamb. IV 265, l. 12)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:13:667</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3019&amp;viewid=6907R_1.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/1/6907R_1.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3019&amp;viewid=6907R_1.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3019&amp;viewid=6907R_1.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/2/6907R_2.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3019&amp;viewid=6907R_2.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3019&amp;viewid=6907R_2.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
