<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Accounts of Expenditures</title>
            <author>Kronion son of Apion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3230</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3230</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.2.123</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;2;123</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;2;123</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11967a 11967b 11968</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11967 11967 11968</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 966</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Recto, col. I, and Verso, col. I-XII, present accounts of expenditures made by Kronion and his colleague Eutychas, the officials of the record-office (grapheion) of Tebtynis, during the 6th year and the beginning of the 7th year of the Emperor Claudius. In view of their distribution on the papyrus and of their incompleteness, they were probably not compiled for inspection. - Verso, col. XI runs from Nov. 7 to Dec. 20, 46 A.D.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this papyrus roll, its content has been divided in the present database into several cards, one for each column.;Columns XI-XII do not immediately follow columns I-X: they are written upside down at the extreme left of the verso. However, the accounts which they contain follow the others in point of time.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Verso; Recto: register of documents prepared at the grapheion</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis; see also note</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; original size: 310 x 28 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Long roll broken at the right end, which was cut in seven pieces when housed into glass. - At the folds of the roll deep indentations have been worn from both edges toward the center of the sheet (the damage is most important in the right part of the roll). - The sheet bearing col. I of the recto and col. XI-XII of the Verso was attached to the rest after these columns had been written.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Verso, col. XI - 35</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Verso, col. XI</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>medium-sized business hand (same as in P.Mich. II, 122).</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0046">(After) December 20, 46 A.D. (Recto, col. I, A.D. Verso, col. I-XII)</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Heraklas, machairophoros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ephebos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kronion son of Soterichos (see P.Mich. II, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kronion son of Krados</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herodes son of Soterichos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apias</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) Talitai</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Eutychas zytopoios (see P.Mich. II, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron (= Heronas, nomographos?) (see P.Mich. II, p. 96)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Talites; Tristomou dromos; Tristomos; (Arsinoiton) polis</term>
               <term>Expense accounts--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Food prices--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>In Neos Sebastos:;On the 11th. For Heraklas the swordsman, who went with the other for the sake of the paper tax, as travel money: 4 drachmai 8 obols.;For beer: [. .] obols.;For breads and fishes (thrissai): 3 obols.;On the 18th. For a certain Horion who came from Ephebos with a letter:  for the price of breads and oil and a fish (thrissa) and beer: 3 obols.;On the 20th, Augustan day. Through Kronion, son of Soterichos, for the price of one papyrus (roll): 4 silver drachmai . . .;On the 22nd. Through Eutychas, for the price of turnips: 12 obols.;On the 29th. For interest on what Eutychas owes: 16 drachmai . . obols.;;On Choiak 1. For the monthly payment (diagraphe): 210 silver drachmai 6 obols.;'Expenses for this': as travel money and for beer: 8 obols.;On the 4th. For us, for beer: 1 obol.;On the 10th. For Kronion, son of Krados, for the price of one papyrus (roll): 4 drachmai 2 obols.;On the 14th.For the price of a dressed meat: 5 obols.;For Herodes, son of Soterichos, for what we borrowed of him for the payment (diagraphe) of Hathyr: 12 drachmai.;For Apias, similarly, for what we borrowed of her for the payment (diagraphe) of Hathyr: 4 drachmai.;On the 16th. Loan to Eutychas, through his wife Thermo(--), for him to give to (some people) of Talei . . .: 4 drachmai.;On the 20th. For the price of beer (bought) from Eutychas the brewer at the avenue of Tristomos: 1 5/6 artabai of wheat, (of the value) of 16 silver drachmai.;For the price of a papyrus (roll?) in the city: 2 drachmai.;On the 22nd. A loan to Eutychas, similarly, through me: 12 silver drachmai.;On the 24th. For the monthly payment (diagraphe) to Heron: 102 silver drachmai.;As travel money and for expenses: 6 obols.;;On Hathyr 23. A loan to Eutychas: 3 obols.;[- - -] in the city: 4 drachmai.;On the 28th. [- - -] 16 silver drachmai. As interest: 3 obols.;[- - -] a loan to [- - ] the thresher [- - -].</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich II, 123, Verso, col. XI, 1933</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:2:123</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3230&amp;viewid=966V1_1.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/1/_/1/966V1_1.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3230&amp;viewid=966V1_1.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3230&amp;viewid=966V1_1.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
