<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of Part of a House</title>
            <author>Aurelia Eudoxia, daughter of Georgios</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3014</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3014</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.13.662</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;13;662</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;13;662</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21375</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21375</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 6902</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Sale of a share of an old house that is in a state of decay, made by Aurelia Eudoxia to Menas, son of Christophoros</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto (written across the fibres) + Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Mich. inv. 6917a. - Archive of Dioskoros of Aphrodito.</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 130 x 33.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">quite damaged at the top, along the horizontal folds</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto - 78;;Verso - 3</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto + Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Recto written across the fibres</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0645">645 AD</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Aphrodite (Aphrodito), Antaiopolite nome, province of the Lower Thebais, Thebais, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelia Eudoxia daughter of Georgios and Routh (Ruth), wife of Aurelius Anouphios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Anouphis son of Isakios (Isaac), husband of Aurelia Eudoxia, syntelestes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Menas son of Christophoros, pragmateutes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ionathan (Jonathan), oikodomos (former owner)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Georgios, deceased father of Aurelia Eudoxia</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Menas son of Chichois, chalkoprates</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) heirs of Promauos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) heirs of Petros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Ioannes (John) son of Apollos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Ioannes son of Hermauos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Daueit (David) son of Phoibammon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Komasios son of Victor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">apa Rhasios, nomikos</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Aphrodite (Aphrodito), Antaiopolite nome, province of the Lower Thebais, Thebais, Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Aphrodite, Antaiopolite nome</term>
               <term>House Ownership</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Aphrodito (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Notary</term>
               <term>Profession</term>
               <term>Sale</term>
               <term>Topography (Aphrodito)</term>
               <term>Woman</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Traces of the so-called "Stempelschrift");;(Cross) In the name of the holy, life-giving, and consubstantial Trinity, Father, Son, and Holy Spirit, written in the month Hathyr the 3rd of the fourth indiction.;(Cross) Aurelia Eudoxia, daughter of Gergios and Ruth, with my husband Anouphis, son of Isakios, syntelestes, who [assists in this] and consents and approves of this my present sale, of the village of Aphrodite in the Antaiopolite nome to (cross) Aurelius Menas, son of the most blessed Christophoros, from the same village of Aphrodite, greetings.;I, the afore-said, Eudoxia, daughter of Georgios, with the agreement of my husband, Anouphis, the son of Isakios, syntelestes, acknowledge, having said so, by this my written security or deed of sale of my own free will and of my voluntary intent and with not to be regretted and unchangeable and unalterable reckoning with a very clear purpose and with a clear conscience and with a honest aim with straightforward intention, swearing at the same time by the Almighty God and by the victory of the imperial safety that I have sold to you, the afore-said Menas, son of the most blessed Christophoros, merchant, and have devised to you and have ceded and have given up to you from now on for all continually succeeding time for ever with the most complete rights of ownership and in good faith and with every authority and with eternal proprietary possession my complete portion that belongs to me and that has come down to me by lawful inheritance from my most blessed father, of an old, unsound house called "Jonathan, the builder" located in the northern part of the afore-mentioned village of Aphrodite in the street of the Holy Catholic Church of [- - -] being open towards the West into the public street with all its rights from basement to attic in general as I managed it at the time when my most blessed father was still alive while there has no right whatsoever been left for me in my afore-said complete portion of the afore-said old, unsound house from basement to attic as has been stated above; the boundaries of the foregoing old house on the four quarters are as follows: on the South the terrace of the house of Menas, son of Chichois, dealer in copper ware; on the East the big farm of the heirs of Promauos; on the North the house of the heirs of Petros, or whatever the boundaries may be, everywhere and on all sides, for the full and fitting price agreed and jointly approved by us with one another of two-thirds of an approved imperial gold nomismation with a deduction of two (carats for one solidus) by the balance of the same village, i.e. g. nom. 2/3 with a deduction of 2 (carats); which gold piece of the price I, the vendor, Eudoxia, daughter of Georgios, have received, having said so, with the agreement of my husband, Anouphis, son of Isakios,  from you, the purchaser, Menas, son of Christophoros, from your hand into my hands in the sight of the lawful witnesses who have written their attestations below in order, for all time from the present for ever, of full number and weight, at the time the sale was affected; with which price I am satisfied. Upon the condition that henceforth you the same purchaser, Menas, son of Christophoros possess and own and are master of my the above-descripted complete portion of the above-said unsound, old house called "Jonathan, the builder" together with every right pertaining thereto from basement to attic, according to the foregoing description, and may inhabit, manage, exploit and build it and add to it by building and lease and sublease it and transmit it to your own heirs and assigns and successors and use and enjoy it in whatever proprietary way you may please, without hindrance or let, free from opposition present or future from any of those who are heirs after me or joint-heirs, or of my relations by birth or my connections; and I shall compulsorily defend you at every moment from whoever shall take proceedings against you; and if I am negligent in the confirmation, I shall pay you three times the price together with costs and damages, in order that this deed of sale may be valid and inviolable wherever it is produced; which deed, written in one copy I have of my own free will and consent executed at the Public Registry without any violence, deceit, compulsion or fraud, without any intimidation or guile, and for your security I have given you this copy completed according to the laws with the subscription of him who subscribes for me, followed in order by those of the customary witnesses who have at my summons born witness to it; and for all that is herein written and for the guarantee of confirmation of this sale and for its freedom from encumbrances all my possessions present and future, movable, immovable and live-stock, generally and severally, in every class and kind are submitted to you as a pledge and with the force of a mortgage as though by decree of court. And being formally questioned concerning all that is herein written I agreed that the things were so, and so to give, do and keep. (Cross);(2nd hand) (Cross) I, Aurelia Eudoxia, daughter of Georgios and Ruth, with the agreement of my husband, Anouphis, son of Isakios, the afore-mentioned, have executed this deed of sale and have received the afore-said full price of two-thirds of a gold nomismation and shall confirm your possession with every confirmation against everyone, always, and I agree with all that is herein written; and I have sworn the divine oath as afore mentioned. (Cross) I, Aurelius Ioannes, son of Apollos, have written it for her on her request. (Cross);(3rd hand) I, the afore-said Aurelius Anouphis, son of Isakios, have executed this deed of sale and have received the afore-said full price of two-thirds of a gold nomismation and shall confirm your possession with every confirmation against everyone, always, and I agree with all that is herein written; and I have sworn the divine oath as afore mentioned.;(4th hand) (Cross) I, Aurelius Ioannes, son of Hermauos, bear witness to this deed of sale, having heard declarations from the person executing it and I bear witness also to the payment of the two-thirds of a gold nomismation of the price. (Cross);(5th hand) (Cross) I, Aurelius David, son of Phoibammon, bear witness to this deed of sale, having heard declarations from the persons executing it and I bear witness also to the payment of the two-thirds of a gold nomismation of the price.;(6th hand) (Cross) I, Aurelius Komasios, son of Victor, bear witness to this deed of sale, having heard declarations from the persons executing it and I bear witness also to the payment of the two-thirds of a gold nomismation of the price. (Cross);;;(7th hand) (Cross) Written by me, Apa Rasios, notary, who also executed it. (Crosses).</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Sijpesteijn PJ, PMich XIII, 662, 1977, Pl. X-XIII -- BL VII, 116-117 (date); BL VIII, 217 (l. 21; 31). - A small fragment (P.Mich. inv. 6917a) confirms the reading Christophorou on l. 6; the 3 lines of the Verso were not known by the editor and have not yet been deciphered. (PH); BL XI, 133 (l. 19); Bagnall-Worp, ZPE 148 (2004), 250-252 (dating: AD 645)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:13:662</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3014&amp;viewid=6902R_1.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/R/_/1/6902R_1.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3014&amp;viewid=6902R_1.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3014&amp;viewid=6902R_1.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/_/2/6902R2_2.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3014&amp;viewid=6902R2_2.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3014&amp;viewid=6902R2_2.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/_/1/6902R2_1.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3014&amp;viewid=6902R2_1.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3014&amp;viewid=6902R2_1.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/_/3/6902R2_3.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3014&amp;viewid=6902R2_3.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3014&amp;viewid=6902R2_3.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/V/_/1/6902V_1.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3014&amp;viewid=6902V_1.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3014&amp;viewid=6902V_1.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
