<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Guild Ordinance </title>
            <author>Kronion son of Herodes &amp; other members of his guild</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1362</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1362</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.244</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;244</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;244</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12085</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12085</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1277</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Regulations made for the 4th year of Claudius by the members of the guild of the apolysimoi (tenant farmers exempt of liturgies) of an estate of the same emperor, who serves as patron deity of the association; various provisions are given concerning the obligations of each member, as well as the penalties and fines to be eventually imposed on them</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto + Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 32 x 28.5 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">damaged along one fold at the left, and much abraded in other places</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto - 46 (lines 21-34 and 35-44 are arranged in two parallel columns);;Verso - 1</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto + Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>1st hand: a rather large upright cursive</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0043">43 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Claudius, Emperor (see also Geographica)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kronion son of Herodes, epimeletes &amp; hegoumenos, apolysimos ousias Klaudiou</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Nepheros, apolysimos ousias Klaudiou (see also P.Mich. V, 352?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psenkebkis son of Marres, apolysimos ousias Klaudiou</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Panesneus son of Harmiysis, apolysimos ousias Klaudiou (see also P.Mich. V, 248?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sigeris son of Pakebkis, apolysimos ousias Klaudiou (see also P.Mich. V, 248?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakebkis son of Sigeris, apolysimos ousias Klaudiou (see also P.Mich. V, 248?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sekonopis son of Papontos alias Diodoros, apolysimos ousias Klaudiou</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchious son of Anchious . . ., apolysimos ousias Klaudiou</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orseus (deuteros) son of Petermouthis alias Kyberomnis, apolysimos ousias Klaudiou</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Papnebtynis son of Papnebtynis, apolysimos ousias Klaudiou (see also P.Mich. II, 121, recto, col. III, abstract 3, and verso, col. II, l. 16?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kronion son of Labesis, apolysimos ousias Klaudiou (see also P.Mich. V, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Eutychos son of Eutychos . . ., apolysimos ousias Klaudiou</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos son of Protos grandson of Harmais, apolysimos ousias Klaudiou (see also P.Mich. II, 121, recto, col. III, abstract 11, and verso, col. III, l. 5)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sisoeis (Sisois) son of Eutychos, oikodomos, apolysimos ousias Klaudiou (see also P.Mich. V, 3p. 21)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Labesis son of Labesis, apolysimos ousias Klaudiou (see also P.Mich. V, 277 or 306?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harmaeis son of Harmaeis, apolysimos ousias Klaudiou</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Komon son of Anchious, apolysimos ousias Klaudiou</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orseus son of Papnebtynis, apolysimos ousias Klaudiou</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hermas son of Anchious, apolysimos ousias Klaudiou</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orseus son of Haryotes grandson(?) of Nanas, apolysimos ousias Klaudiou (see also P.Mich. V, 278</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">336?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Amaeis son of Marres, apolysimos ousias Klaudiou</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Harmiysis, apolysimos ousias Klaudiou (see also P.Mich. V, 299 or 352?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Papontos son of Papnebtynis, apolysimos ousias Klaudiou</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kronion son of Herodion (= Kronion, son of Herodes, as above?)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Tebtynis; Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome; ousia (imperial estate) of Claudius; metropolis (Arsinoiton polis)</term>
               <term>Debt--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Fasts and feasts--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Food.</term>
               <term>Funeral rites and ceremonies--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Guilds--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Professions--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Romans--Religion--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Slaves--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Taxation--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>The third year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, on the third supplementary day of the month Kaisareios, at Tebtynis in the division of Polemon of the Arsinoite nome.;Having met together, the undersigned men of Tebtynis, apolysimoi of an estate of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, voted unanimously to elect one of their number, an excellent man, Kronion, son of Herodes, to be superintendent for one year from the month Sebastos of the coming fourth year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, the same Kronion to collect the public revenues of the poll-tax of the same apolysimoi and all the expenses of the said association. If the president issues a call in the village and anyone does not attend, let him be fined two drachmai in silver for the association, except . . ., when one drachme; if outside, four drachmai; and if in the metropolis, eight drachmai. If any one of the undersigned men is held for debt up to the amount of one hundred drachmai in silver, security will be given for him for a period of sixty days by the association, but if anyone is in default and fails in any respect to pay the dues of the poll-tax or the expenses, Kronion shall have authority to seize him in the main street, or in his house, and hand over him or his slaves. It is required that the undersigned men shall pay out of the common fund to the said estate on behalf of the aforesaid Kronion the poll-tax of the said coming fourth year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator; and that they shall hold a banquet each month on the day of the god Augustus, the said Kronion furnishing drink for the toasts, and all shall obey the said president. And if a president or a father or mother or wife or child or brother or sister dies and any one of the undersigned men does not attend the funeral, let such a one be fined four drachmai for the association, and the one who is bereaved shall be feasted by the association for one day; but if anyone is in default and likewise fails in any way to satisfy any of the contributions and expenses, the said president has the right to seize him and hand him over as aforesaid.;Kronion, son of Herodes, president, about 35 years old, with a scar on his left shin.;Onnophris, son of Nepheros, about 40 years old, with a scar on his left eyebrow.;Psenkebkis, son of Marres, about 38 years old, with a scar on his forehead to the left above the eyebrow.;Panesneus, son of Harmiysis, about 30 years old, with a scar on his right eyebrow.;Sigeris, son of Pakebkis, about 29 years old, with a scar on his forehead to the left by the temple.;Pakebkis, son of Sigeris, about 35 years old, with a scar on his left thumb.;Sekonopis, son of Papontos also called Diodoros, about 32 years old, with a scar in the middle of his forehead.;Anchious, son of Anchious . . ., about 30 years old, with a scar on his right shin.;Orseus the second, son of Petermouthis also called Kyberomnis, about 33 years old, with a scar on his left thumb.;Papnebtynis, son of Papnebtynis, about 32 years old, with a scar above his right cheek.;Kronion, son of Labesis, about 30(?) years old, with a scar on his nose below the eyebrows.;Eutychos, son of Eutychos . . ., about 30 years old, with a scar on his right thumb.;Orseus, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Ph . . ., about 50 years old, with a scar on his right forearm.;Petesouchos, son of Protos, grandson of Harmaeis, about 35 years old, with a scar on his right forearm.;Sisoeis, son of Eutychos, the carpenter, about 38 years old, with a scar in the middle of his forehead.;Labesis, son of Labesis, about 35 years old, with a scar on his forehead.;Harmaeis, son of Harmaeis, about 33 years old, with a scar on his left thumb.;Komon, son of Anchious, about 37 years old, with a scar on his forehead to the right.;Orseus, son of Papnebtynis, about 30 years old, with a scar on the little finger of his left hand.;Hermas, son of Anchious, about 33 years old, with a scar on his left knee.;Orseus, son of Haryotes, grandson(?) of Nanas, about 34 years old, with a scar on the first finger of his left hand.;Amaeis, son of Marres, about 35 years old, with a scar on his left eyebrow.;Horos, son of Harmiysis, about 32 years old, with a scar on the first finger of his right hand.;Papontos, son of Papnebtynis, about 32 years old, with a scar on his left foot.;(2nd hand) I, Kronion, son of Herodes, president, have voted, as has been set forth.;(3rd hand) I, Eutychos, son of Eutychos . . ., have voted.;;(Verso);;Chirograph of Kronion, son of Herodion.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, PMich V, 244, 1944 -- BL IX, 160 (l. 10). - L. 34: read probably Har[m]a[eios] instead of Her[m]a[iou], as in P.Mich. II, 121, recto, col. III, abstract 11. (PH)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:244</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1362&amp;viewid=1277R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/7/7/R/1277R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1362&amp;viewid=1277R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1362&amp;viewid=1277R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/7/7/V/1277V.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1362&amp;viewid=1277V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1362&amp;viewid=1277V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
