<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3850</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3850</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 35 x 30.3 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at the right and the left. Kollesis at right and left. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-37</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 83 (ll. 3296-3333)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Patron, son of Sokmenis,  grandson of Sokmenis, mother Taonnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 200)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Menandros, grandson of Anchophis, mother Soeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 250)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Germanos, slave of Longinus Isidoros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 160)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus, son of Petheus, grandson of Satabous, mother Tamystha (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Anchophis, grandson of Herakles, mother Teseuris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Petsiris, mother Heros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mystharion, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 188)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Onnophris, grandson of Petaus, mother Tkateis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Kames, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Besis, son of Petheus, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 159)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabeinos, son of Sisois, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Tapais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Onnophris, grandson of Onnophris, mother Sopas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p.169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Athenion, son of Horos, grandson of Pakysis, mother Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 150)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Nekpheraus, son of Euhemeros, grandson of Nekpheraus, mother Taonnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 190)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Euhemeros, son of Neilos, grandson of Euhemeros, mother Taeuhemeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p.164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Petheus, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Taseus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos, son of Hatres, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 204)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Polis, son of Petheus, grandson of Keras, mother Herais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Eutyches, slave of Sarapias (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 165)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor, son of Achillas, grandson of Kastor, mother Aphrodous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Herieus, grandson of Petaus, mother Tremmenesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Priskos alias Pasoxis, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Satabous, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 215)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Satabous, son of Phaesis, grandson of Sarapion, mother Philoumene (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 226)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabeinos, son of Petheus, grandson of Sambas, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tapetheus, daughter of Pasoknopaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 236)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Polydeukes, son of Satornilos the wine merchant (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 236)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Euhemeros, son of Euhemeros, grandson of Keras, mother Tauris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis, son of Onnophris, grandson of Satabous, mother Soeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petheus, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 83:;Aphrodisios, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetesouchos, copper drachmas 8;;Patron, son of Sokmenis,  grandson of Sokmenis, mother Taonnophris, drachmas 4;;Horos, son of Menandros, grandson of Anchophis, mother Soeris, drachmas 4;;Germanos, slave of Longinus Isidoros, drachmas 4;;Phanomgeus, son of Petheus, grandson of Satabous, mother Tamystha, copper drachmas 4;;Horos, son of Anchophis, grandson of Herakles, mother Teseuris, copper drachmas 8;;Onnophris, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Petsiris, mother Heros, drachmas 4;;Mystharion, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4 copper drachmas 4;;Petaus, son of Onnophris, grandson of Petaus, mother Tkateis, copper drachma obols 28;;Sarapion, son of Kames, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Besis, son of Petheus, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Thermouthis, copper drachmas 4;;Sabeinos, son of Sisois, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Tapais, drachmas 8;;in total for the day drachmas 68 obols 28;;(Pauni) 23 likewise:;Heras, son of Onnophris, grandson of Onnophris, mother Sopas, copper drachmas 4;;Athenion, son of Horos, grandson of Pakysis, mother Heras, drachmas 4 obols 28;;Nekpheraus, son of Euhemeros, grandson of Nekpheraus, mother Taonnophris, copper drachmas (of priests) 4;;Euhemeros, son of Neilos, grandson of Euhemeros, mother Taeuhemeros, obols 28;;Petaus, son of Petheus, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Taseus, copper drachma (of priests) obols 28;;Petesouchos, son of Hatres, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Petheus, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Thermouthis, copper drachmas 4;;Polis, son of Petheus, grandson of Keras, mother Herais, obols 28;;Eutyches, slave of Sarapias, drachmas 4 obols 20, copper drachma obols 8;;Kastor, son of Achillas, grandson of Kastor, mother Aphrodous, drachmas 4;;Petaus, son of Herieus, grandson of Petaus, mother Tremmenesis, drachmas 4 copper drachmas 4;;Priskos alias Pasoxis, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Satabous, mother Thermouthis, copper drachmas (of priests) 4;;Satabous, son of Phaesis, grandson of Sarapion, mother Philoumene, copper drachmas 8;;Sabeinos, son of Petheus, grandson of Sambas, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8 copper drachmas 4;;Tapetheus, daughter of Pasoknopaios through the agency of Polydeukes, son of Satornilos the wine merchant;;(in left margin: drachmas 4 obols 23) orchard taxes of year 12 apomoira drachmas 2 obols 4.5, tax on the produce of olives obols 2.5 chalki 2, naubion obols 2, surcharges obols 4 chalki 2;;eparourion drachma 1 obols 5, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 6 obols 2 chalki 2;;Heras, son of Kelolis, grandson of Heras, mother Thaesis, copper drachmas 4;;Euhemeros, son of Euhemeros, grandson of Keras, mother Tauris, drachmas 4 copper drachmas 4;;Pakysis, son of Onnophris, grandson of Satabous, mother Soeris, drachmas 8;;in total for the day drachmas 108 obols 17.;(Epeiph) 24 likewise:;Pasion, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petheus, mother Segathis, drachmas 4."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3850&amp;viewid=4171_83R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3850&amp;viewid=4171_83R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3850&amp;viewid=4171_83R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
