<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3270</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3270</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer paying the poll-tax is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 126 is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 125-126: 36.6 x 29.9 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 126: complete (papyrus cut off right of col. 126 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 126: 39 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 126 (l. 2042-2080)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios son of Petheus and Stiynchis grandson of Petesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas son of Pasoknopaios and Tapetheus grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 223)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Pasoknopaios and Tapetheus grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psenesis son of Petheus and Komonis grandson of Esouris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras son of Horos alias Karanos and Tamystha grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos son of Petesouchos and Tasoucharion grandson of Petesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis son of Ptolemaios and Soeris grandson of Orsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 194)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Papeis and Thermouthis grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Achillas son of Heron and Didyme grandson of Orsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Komon son of Pnepheros and Tkollauthis grandson of Satabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 183)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon son of Pasoxis and Tanephremis grandson of Pasoxis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 247)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras son of Melanas and Tamystha grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion son of Heras the elder and Thermouthis grandson of Herakles (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion son of Petheus and Tathautis grandson of Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron son of Sabinus and Gaia grandson of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 171)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Imouthes son of Keras and Tepheros grandson of Menandros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 177)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonis (Ammonios) son of Harpagathes and Segathis grandson of Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 151)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Slaves--Taxation--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 126;;(Pauni 21, continued);Aphrodisios, son of Petheus and Stiynchis, grandson of Petesouchos: 12 drachmai; (and) for ch(--): 28 obols;    column 14;Sambas, son of Pasoknopaios and Tapetheus, grandson of Horos: 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(--): 4 drachmai;    column 86;Petheus, son of Pasoknopaios and Tapetheus, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai 28 obols;    column 19;Psenesis, son of Petheus and Komonis, grandson of Esouris, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;    column 20;Agathopous, slave of Taseus also called Isarion, the offspring of Therm(--): 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(--): 4 drachmai;    column 19;Heras, son of Horos also called Karanos and Tamystha, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai;    column 22;Petesouchos, son of Petesouchos and Tasoucharion, grandson of Petesouchos: 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(--): 4 drachmai;    column 23;Orsenouphis, son of Ptolemaios and Soeris, grandson of Orsenouphis, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;    column 28;Ptolemaios, son of Papeis and Thermouthis, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(--): 28 obols;    column 30;Achillas, son of Heron and Didyme, grandson of Orsenouphis: 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(--): 4 drachmai;    column 36;Komon, son of Pnepheros and Tkollauthis, grandson of Satabous: 4 drachmai; (and) for ch(--): 4 drachmai;    column 37;Chairemon, son of Pasoxis and Tanephremis, grandson of Pasoxis, for ch(--): 28 obols;    column 40;Heras, son of Melanas and Tamystha, grandson of Petheus, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;    column 42;Sarapion, son of Heras the elder and Thermouthis, grandson of Herakles: 4 drachmai;    column 43;Total for the day: 200 drachmai 23 obols.;;On the 22nd, similarly:;Pasion, son of Petheus and Tathautis, grandson of Sambathion, for ch(--): 12 drachmai;    column 62;Heron, son of Sabinus and Gaia, grandson of Pnepheros: 16 drachmai;    column 45;Imouthes, son of Keras and Tepheros, grandson of Menandros, for ch(--): 4 drachmai;    column 47;Ammonis, son of Harpagathes and Segathis, grandson of Heras: 16 drachmai;    column 52</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 126 (l. 2042-2080), 1936 -- BL III, 114 (l. 2051)</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3270&amp;viewid=4172_24RO.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/4/r/o/4172_24ro.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3270&amp;viewid=4172_24RO.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3270&amp;viewid=4172_24RO.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
