<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Cession of Catoecic Land</title>
            <author>Herakles, son of Chairemon</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2788</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2788</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.5.259</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;5;259</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;5;259</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12094</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12094</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 628</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract by which Herakles, son of Chairemon, also called Mieus, cedes to Chairemon, also called Onnophris, son of Horion, five arourai of catoecic land near Tebtynis; at the top of the papyrus are the brief descriptions of the parties concerned; on the verso, a brief docket</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto + Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">Archive of Kronion son of Apion, nomographos of the grapheion of Tebtynis</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 24.5 x 28.4 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">damaged at the top, bottom and right side, as well as along some folds</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Recto - 2 + 37;;Verso - 2</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto + Verso</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>1st hand: small, very cursive hand; 2nd hand: large, angular hand, with awkwardly formed letters (Husselman)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0033">April 4, 33 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Tiberius, Emperor</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles son of Chairemon alias Mieus grandson of Onnophris, Makedon ton katoikon hippeon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Chairemon alias Onnophris son of Horion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides son of Chairemon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kronides son of Haryotes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(unnamed) sons of a Chairemon</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aunes son of Aphrodisios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Akousilaos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Seras</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orseus son of Orseus, gnapheus</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kollouthos son of Mieus (see also P.Mich. V, 294(?)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">X, 587)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios neoteros son of Akousilaos (see also P.Mich. V, 246</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">354)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Tebtynis, Polemonos meris, Arsinoite nome; Makedon; ta Ammegina legomena; he Kanabis legomene</term>
               <term>Administration</term>
               <term>Agriculture</term>
               <term>Army</term>
               <term>Cession</term>
               <term>Ethnicity</term>
               <term>Literacy--Egypt--Tebtunis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Land Ownership</term>
               <term>Land Status</term>
               <term>Profession</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Recto);;[Herakles, about . . years old, with a scar on his throat on the right]. Chairemon, about 21 years old, with a scar on the [little] finger of his left [hand]. (Made on) Pharmouthi 9. Signatories: Kollouthos, about 28 years old, with a scar on his right wrist; Ptolemaios, [about 26 years old], with a scar on his left forearm.;;The nineteenth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, the ninth of the month Daisios, Pharmouthi 9, in Tebtynis in the division of Polemon of the Arsinoite nome. Herakles, son of Chairemon also called Mieus, son of Onnophris, a Macedonian of the catoecic cavalry, about . . . years old, with a scar on his throat on the right, acknowledges to Chairemon, also called Onnophris, son of Horion, about twenty-one years old, with a scar on the little finger of his left hand, that he has ceded to Onnophris, to him and to his heirs and assigns, for transfer, from the present day forever, from the catoecic allotment that belongs to him near Tebtynis, five arourai measured with the schoinion of ninety-six ells, in two parcels, which are from land that has been neglected and is not productive. The neighbors of the first parcel, which consists of three arourai in the so-called Ammegina, are on the south the allotment of Herakleides, son of Chairemon, on the east the allotment of the same Herakleides, on the north the uncultivated land, and on the west the allotment of Kronides, son of Haryotes. And the neighbors of the second parcel, which consists of the remaining two arourai in the so-called Kanabis, are on the south the allotment of the sons of Chairemon, on the north the allotment of Aunes, son of Aphrodisios, on the west the allotment of Akousilaos and Seras, on the east the allotment of Orseus, son of Orseus, the fuller. And Herakles will draw up the necessary documents for the conveyance and cession to Onnophris through the catoecic office. Herakles has also received from the purchaser the full sum established for the transfer; and Herakles himself and his assigns guarantee to Onnophris and his assigns the provisions of this cession with every guarantee from all public debts and all imposts and every tax from previous times up to the past eighteenth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus and for the eighteenth year as well, and from all private encumbrances and every claim continually forever. The signatories are, for the contracting party, Kollouthos, son of Mieus, about twenty-eight years old, with a scar on his right wrist, and for the other Ptolemaios the younger, son of Akousilaos, about 26 years old, with a scar on his right forearm.;(2nd hand) I, Herakles, son of Chairemon, also called Mieus, son of Onnophris, a Macedonian of the catoecic cavalry, acknowledge that I have ceded to Chairemon, also called Onnophris, son of Horion, to Chairemon himself and to his heirs and assigns, for transfer from the present day forever, from the catoecic allotment that belongs to me near Tebtynis, five arourai measured with the schoinion of ninety-six ells, in two parcels, which are those purchased from the unproductive land. The neighbors of the first parcel, which consists of three arourai in the so-called Ammegina, are on the south the allotment of Herakleides, son of Chairemon, on the east the allotment of the same Herakleides, on the north the uncultivated land, on the west the allotment of Kronides, son of Haryotes. The neighbors of the second parcel, which consists of the remaining two arourai in the so-called Kanabis, are on the south the allotment of the sons of Chairemon, on the north the allotment of Aunes, son of Aphrodisios, on the west the allotment of Akousilaos and Seras, on the east the allotment of Orseus, the fuller. And I shall pay the charges due for the transfer and cession through the catoecic office. I have also received from Chairemon the sum fixed upon in silver, and I shall guarantee with every guarantee from all public debts from previous times up to the past eighteenth year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, and for the eighteenth year also, and from private encumbrances and every claim forever as aforesaid. Kollouthos, son of Mieus, wrote for him as he is illiterate.;(3rd hand) Chairemon, also called Onnophris, son of Horion. The cession of the aforesaid five arourai of the catoecic allotment was made to me . . .;;(Verso);;Agreement of cession of 5 arourai.  . . .</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Husselman EM, PMich V, 259, 1944</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:5:259</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2788&amp;viewid=628R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/8/R/628R.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2788&amp;viewid=628R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2788&amp;viewid=628R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/8/V/628V.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2788&amp;viewid=628V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Verso large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-2788&amp;viewid=628V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
