<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3829</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3829</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 35.5 x 29.7 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at the right and the left. Kollesis at the right. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-40</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 65 (ll. 2614-2654)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Onnophris, mother Tkollainis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petekouis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Harmiysis, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Psenesis, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonia, daughter of Harphaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 152)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Potoslykos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 215)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes, son of Naaraus, grandson of Petheus, mother Taorsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchophis, son of Kanis, grandson of Anchophis, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Naaraus, grandson of Horion, mother Taorsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Theagenes, son of Theagenes, grandson of Ammonios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 176)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Isidoros, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 179)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Tanesneus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes, son of Petheus, grandson of Mysthes, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 189)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Polyndikos, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Germanus, slave of Longinus Isidoros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 160)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Thakialis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Lucius Julius Germanus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 185)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psensin (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Mysthes, son of Mysthes, grandson of Petsiris, mother Sambous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 188)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Phaomgeus, grandson of Phaomgeus, mother Taptosiris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tasoucharion, fatherless, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 239)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptollas, son of Abel (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 221)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Petalos, grandson of Petaus, mother Taeuhemeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tanomgeus, daughter of Pakysis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 234)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">(Maximus the bitter?)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 65:;Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Onnophris, mother Tkollainis, drachmas 4;;Onnophris, son of Onnophris (Petekouis);;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 7 obols 3, tax on the produce of olives drachma 1 obol 0.5, naubion obols 4.5, surcharges drachma 1 obols 5 chalki 2;;(in left margin: drachmas 36 obols 12)eparourion drachmas 5, surcharges obols 2.5, kollybos obol 1.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 16 obols 5.5;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 18 obols 4.5, surcharges drachma 1 obol 1 chalki 2;;Ptolemaios, son of Harmiysis, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Psenesis, grandson of Onnophris, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4 obols 20;;Apollonia, daughter of Harphaesis (he of Potoslykos);;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 2 obols 3, tax on the produce of olives obols 2 chalki 2, naubion obol 1.5, surcharges obols 3.5 chalki 2;;(in left margin: drachmas 12 obols 9) eparourion drachma 1 obols 4, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 5 obols 4 chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 6 obol 1.5, surcharges obols 2.5, in total drachmas 6 obols 4;;Mysthes, son of Naaraus, grandson of Petheus, mother Taorsenouphis, copper tetradrachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 188 obols 12;;(Pachon) 19 likewise:;Anchophis, son of Kanis, grandson of Anchophis, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Naaraus, grandson of Horion, mother Taorsenouphis, drachmas 4;;Theagenes, son of Theagenes, grandson of Ammonios, copper tetradrachmas 12;;Isidoros, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 4;;Onnophris, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis, obols 28;;Phanomgeus, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Petheus, mother Tanesneus, drachmas 4;;Mysthes, son of Petheus, grandson of Mysthes, mother Tasoucharion, obols 28;;in total for the day drachmas 40 obols 27;;(Pachon) 20 likewise:;Phaesis, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Polyndikos, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Germanus, slave of Longinus Isidoros, drachmas 8;;Pnepheros, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Thakialis, drachmas 4;;Lucius Julius Germanus (Psensin);;(in left margin: obols 8) naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year obols 4, surcharges obol 0.5, kollybos chalki 2, in total obols 4.5 chalki 2;;Mysthes, son of Mysthes, grandson of Petsiris, mother Sambous;;guard tax drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Phaomgeus, grandson of Phaomgeus, mother Taptosiris, drachmas 4;;Tasoucharion, fatherless, mother Tasoucharion (Ptollas, son of Abel);;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 22 obols 2, surcharges drachma 1 obols 2.5, in total  drachmas 23 obols 4.5;;In total for the day drachmas 48 obols 8.;(Pachon) 21 likewise:;Petaus, son of Petalos, grandson of Petaus, mother Taeuhemeros, drachmas 4;;Tanomgeus, daughter of Pakysis (Maximus, the bitter?);(drachmas 12) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 5, tax on the produce of olives obols 4 chalki 2, naubion obols 3, surcharges drachma 1 obol 1.5;;eparourion drachmas 3 obols 2, surcharges obol 1.5 chalki 2, kollybos obol 1 chalki 2, in total drachmas 11 obol 1.5 chalki 2."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 -- BL VII, 109 (on l. 2652) Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3829&amp;viewid=4171_65R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3829&amp;viewid=4171_65R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3829&amp;viewid=4171_65R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
