<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>Unknown tax-collector (Sarapion, son of Sokrates?)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3345</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3345</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4172</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording the daily collection of money taxes in the village of Karanis; the name of each tax-payer is cross-referenced with a page of another register, where taxpayers were listed geographically</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Due to the size of this tax roll (P.Mich. IV/1, 225 + IV/2, 358), its content has been divided in the present database into several cards (one for each column).</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso of col. 58 is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; cf. also P.Mich. IV/1, 224 + IV/2, 357 (inv. 4171 + 2830 + 3159 + 4910)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; col. 57-58: 33.8 x 29.1 cm; total size: ***</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">Col. 58: complete (papyrus cut off right of col. 58 when housed in glass)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">Col. 58: 50 lines</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 58 (l. 1400-1450)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0173" notAfter="0174">173-174 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakles son of Petheus and Taseus grandson of Onnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 168)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion son of Sarapion and Nilous grandson of Phaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Heron and Tasoucharion grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas son of Pasoknopaios and Tapetheus grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 223)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus son of Tesenouphis and Thaesis grandson of Harphaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris son of Pnepheros and Thaesis grandson of Phanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodisios son of Onnophris and Ptolema grandson of Pnepheros and Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 157)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pasion son of Petsiris and Thases grandson of Pasion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 198)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petsiris son of Pasion and Taonnophris grandson of Petsiris and Thases (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 211)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis son of Pekmeis alias Heuremon and Sambathion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petoraipis (Petsoraipis) son of Hatres and Soeris grandson of Imouthes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 212)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios son of Satabous and Theonis grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 220)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus son of Petheus and Stiynchis grandson of Petesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 209)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sabinus son of Petheus and Herakleia grandson of Phanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 222)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kephalon son of Isidoros and Tasoucharion grandson of Petesouchos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 183)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus son of Horos and Sambathion grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aunes son of Aunes and Tapetheus grandson of Hermas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 157)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios neoteros son of Petheus and Iulia grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras son of Melanas and Tamystha grandson of Petheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos son of Chairemon and Stotoetis grandson of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Perigenes son of Zoilos and Sambathion grandson of Ptolemaios (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pakysis son of Melanas and Taeuemeros grandson of Pakysis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 196)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Melanas son of Melanas and Taeuemeros grandson of Pakysis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 187)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Guards troops--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Poll tax--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term>Tax collection--Egypt--Karanis (Extinct city)</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Col.) 58;;(Pharmouthi 26, continued);Herakles, son of Petheus and Taseus, grandson of Onnophris: for the guards, 4 drachmai;    column 93;Pasion, son of Sarapion and Nilous, grandson of Phaesis: 12 drachmai;    column 99;Ptolemaios, son of Heron and Tasoucharion, grandson of Horos: 8 drachmai;    column 96;Sambas, son of Pasoknopaios and Tapetheus, grandson of Horos: 4 drachmai;    column 86;Total for the day: 92 drachmai 28 obols.;;On the 27th, similarly:;Phanomgeus, son of Tesenouphis and Thaesis, grandson of Harphaesis: 4 drachmai;    column 3;Onnophris, son of Pnepheros and Thaesis, grandson of Phanomgeus: 8 drachmai;    column 4;Aphrodisios, his son, (born) of Ptolema: 4 drachmai;    column 4;Pasion, son of Petsiris and Thases, grandson of Pasion: 4 drachmai;    column 5;Petsiris, his son, (born) of Taonnophris: 4 drachmai;    column 5;Phaesis, son of Pekmeis also called Heuremon and Sambathion: 4 drachmai;    column 6;Petoraipis, son of Hatres and Soeris, grandson of Imouthes: 4 drachmai;    column 9;Ptolemaios, son of Satabous and Theonis, grandson of Horos: 4 drachmai;    column 10;Petaus, son of Petheus and Stiynchis, grandson of Petesouchos: 20 drachmai;    column 14;Sabinus, son of Petheus and Herakleia, grandson of Phanomgeus: 8 drachmai;    column 20;Kephalon, son of Isidoros and Tasoucharion, grandson of Petesouchos: 8 drachmai;    column 23;Petheus, son of Horos and Sambathion, grandson of Petheus: 8 drachmai;    column 26;Aunes, son of Aunes and Tapetheus, grandson of Hermas: 4 drachmai;    column 32;Ptolemaios the younger, son of Petheus and Iulia, grandson of Petheus: 20 drachmai 27 obols;    column 34;Heras, son of Melanas and Tamystha, grandson of Petheus: 4 drachmai;    column 42;Horos, son of Chairemon and Stotoetis, grandson of Horos: 8 drachmai;    column 42;Total for the day: 120 drachmai 27 obols.;;On the 28th, similarly:;Perigenes, son of Zoilos and Sambathion, grandson of Ptolemaios: 4 drachmai;    column 46;Pakysis, son of Melanas and Taeuemeros, grandson of Pakysis: 12 drachmai;    column 50;Melanas, his brother, (born) of the same mother: 12 drachmai;    column 50</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, PMich IV/1, 225, col. 58 (l. 1400-1450), 1936</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3345&amp;viewid=4172_15RO.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/5/r/o/4172_15ro.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3345&amp;viewid=4172_15RO.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3345&amp;viewid=4172_15RO.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
