<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3695</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3695</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is blank</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 29.4 x 33 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at left and right. Kollesis near the left edge. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-53</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 22 (ll. 892-945)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides, son of Esouris, grandson of Kollouthos, mother Taonnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Ptolemais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Petalos, grandson of Petaus, mother Taeuhemeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Didymos, grandson of Maron, mother Tauris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos, son of Hatres, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Phasis, grandson of Keras, mother Helene (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Harpalos, grandson of Sarapion, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 225)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ninis, son of Asklas, grandson of Ninis, mother Tabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Agathos Demon, grandson of Petheus, mother Stiynchis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Loupos, son of Horos, grandson of Menches, mother Tapapes (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 186)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horos, son of Anchorymphis, grandson of Horos, mother Achillis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psenesis, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Psenesis, mother Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Lucius Longinus Gemellus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 185)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phasis, son of Tesenouphis, grandson of Harphaesis, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 246)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Tauris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis, son of Petheus, grandson of Horion, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 194)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Orsenouphis, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Soeris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 194)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Anchophis, son of Kanis, grandson of Anchophis, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 149)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor, son of Artemas, grandson of Heron, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonios, son of Ammonios, grandson of Ammonios, mother Tninis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 151)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Sambas, mother Taeuhemeros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 224)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kames, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Ptollion, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 180)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Nestosiris, grandson of Petheus, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ischyras, son of Panesneus, grandson of Ischyras, mother Tamystha (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 179)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Petsiris, mother Heros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Heras (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phanomgeus, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Taptosiris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 245)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, brother with the same mother (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 219)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Onnophris, grandson of Sambas, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petaus, son of Esouris, grandson of Petheus, mother Tkollauthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Onnophris, grandson of Onnophris, mother Sopas (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Doras, grandson of Apollonios, mother Tauris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 216)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Petheus, grandson of Teos, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pamonneouis, son of Anchorimphis, grandson of Pamonneouis, mother Didymarion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 197)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Pasoknopaios, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hatres, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Heraklas, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 157)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Zenas, son of Phaesis, grandson of Zenas, mother Tapasion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 165)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Heron, grandson of Horos, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petheus, mother Segathis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 203)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Esouris, son of Petheus, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Ptolema (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 164)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pnepheros, son of Petaus, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 213)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Naaraus, grandson of Horion, mother Taorsenouphis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 217)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"[(Column) 22]:;(Mecheir) 17 likewise:;Herakleides, son of Esouris, grandson of Kollouthos, mother Taonnophris, drachmas 16;;Herakleides, son of Petheus, grandson of Heras, mother Ptolemais, drachmas 4;;Pnepheros, son of Petalos, grandson of Petaus, mother Taeuhemeros, drachmas 16;;Petheus, son of Didymos, grandson of Maron, mother Tauris, drachmas 4;;Petesouchos, son of Hatres, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Sarapion, son of Phasis, grandson of Keras, mother Helene, drachmas 4;;Sarapion, son of Harpalos, grandson of Sarapion, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Ninis, son of Asklas, grandson of Ninis, mother Tabous, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Agathos Demon, grandson of Petheus, mother Stiynchis, drachmas 4;;Loupos, son of Horos, grandson of Menches, mother Tapapes, drachmas 16;;Horos, son of Anchorymphis, grandson of Horos, mother Achillis, obols 28;;Psenesis, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Psenesis, mother Heras, drachmas 8;;in total for the day drachmas 88, obols 28;;(Mecheir) 18 likewise: ;Lucius Longinus Gemellus, for a third of the bath tax for the13th year, additional charges drachmas 28;;Phasis, son of Tesenouphis, grandson of Harphaesis, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Tauris, drachmas 8;;Orsenouphis, son of Petheus, grandson of Horion, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Orsenouphis, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Orsenouphis, mother Soeris, drachmas 4;;in total for the day, drachmas 48 of which for a third of the bath of bath tax drachmas 28;;(Mecheir) 19 likewise;;Anchophis, son of Kanis, grandson of Anchophis, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;Kastor, son of Artemas, grandson of Heron, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 12;;Ammonios, son of Ammonios, grandson of Ammonios, mother Tninis, drachmas 4;;Sambas, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Sambas, mother Taeuhemeros, drachmas 8;;Kames, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Ptollion, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, son of Nestosiris, grandson of Petheus, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;Ischyras, son of Panesneus, grandson of Ischyras, mother Tamystha, drachmas 4;;Onnophris, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Petsiris, mother Heros, drachmas 4;;Pnepheros, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Heras, drachmas 8;;Phanomgeus, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Phanomgeus, mother Taptosiris, drachmas 8;;Ptolemaios, brother with the same mother, drachmas 4;;Onnophris, son of Onnophris, grandson of Sambas, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 4;;Petaus, son of Esouris, grandson of Petheus, mother Tkollauthis, drachmas 4;;Heras, son of Onnophris, grandson of Onnophris, mother Sopas, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Doras, grandson of Apollonios, mother Tauris, drachmas 4;;Pnepheros, son of Pnepheros, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Onnophris, son of Petheus, grandson of Teos, mother Segathis, drachmas 4;;Pamonneouis, son of Anchorimphis, grandson of Pamonneouis, mother Didymarion, obols 28;;Petheus, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Pasoknopaios, mother Tepheros, drachmas 4;;Hatres, son of Phanomgeus, grandson of Heraklas, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Zenas, son of Phaesis, grandson of Zenas, mother Tapasion, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Heron, grandson of Horos, mother Tasoucharion, drachmas 4, obols 28;;Petheus, son of Pasoxis, grandson of Petheus, mother Segathis, drachmas 4;;Esouris, son of Petheus, grandson of Akousilaos, mother Ptolema, drachmas 12;;Pnepheros, son of Petaus, grandson of Pnepheros, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Naaraus, grandson of Horion, mother Taorsenouphis, drachmas 4."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3695&amp;viewid=4171_22R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/2/2/r/4171_22r.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3695&amp;viewid=4171_22R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3695&amp;viewid=4171_22R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
