<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>letter</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1850</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1850</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.16.12694</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;16;12694</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;16;12694</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">30654</idno>
            <idno type="TM">30654</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 3164</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Most of the surviving portion of this letter is concerned with mundane business transactions. The writer acknowledges the receipt of 24 drachmas  by the hand of a certain Satrios. He reports that, probably upon written request, he has put in an order for a mattress and some dry goods, which are not yet ready.Their combined cost (52 drachmas ?) exceeds the amount brought by Satrios, and this is a source of concern for the writer. He promises to make up the difference from his own pocket, although he is not affluent. He mentions also that he has bought two artabas of lentils (the price is not given) and that Satrios is unwilling to take them with him. Near the end of the business portion of the letter the writer requests a cloak, to be made by his mother.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Recto; Written across the fibers; scribe rotated papyrus 90 degrees to accommodate the format of the text.</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is Blank</note>
                     <note type="related">-</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 21.5 x 12.3 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The papyrus, medium brown and fairly fine in texture, was bought by the University of Michigan in 1925. The fragment is well preserved except for a few holes which scarcely interfere with the legibility of the text. These are evenly spaced in conjunction with five horizontal creases and the top edge of the papyrus, and indicate that the sheet was originally  rolled up  from the bottom. At the top, where an undetermined amount of text has been lost, the edge is cut along one of the creases of the flattened roll. At the bottom, parallel to the writing, is a kollesis.</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-17</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>The writer left an increasingly wider left margin, varying from 0.5 to 1.4 cm. On the right, as usual in documents (see H. C. Youtie, ZPE 28, 1978, 262), he wrote all th way to the edge. His letter nearly fit the sheet, only 0.6 cm. of blank papyrus being left under the last line of text. The script, in pale black ink, is jaunty and assured. It is quickly written but contains few ligatures apart from combinations of alpha or epsilon with iota. The style is comparable to that of P. Mich. inv. 103 (ZPE 31, 1978, 170-171, 3rd cent. A.D.); and P. Amst. inv. 81 (ibid. 6, 1970, 125-128, 3rd/4th century A.D.).</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0200" notAfter="0399">IIIrd/IVth century A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>unknown</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Satrios</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Joulas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Julia</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Hephesta</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>unknown</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>-</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>". . . I come to you. I received from Satrios 24 drachmas, with you (?) writing to me about the mattress and towel and linen cloth. I have given an order for these to be made, and they are not yet finished. If they are finished soon, if I find someone trustworthy, I shall send them with Joulas' people. I also bought 2 artabas of lentils, and Satrios is not willing to take them. The mattress is 5 by 3 (cubits), 36 drachmas; the towel is 10 (?) drachmas; the linen cloth 6 drachmas. I write these things to you so that our relatives may not know and give me trouble. I have safely received the 24 drachmas which you sent by Satrios. I for my part will supply the balance. If it is possible, send Apollos or someone trustworthy before Epeiph 25 so that if I receive my wages I can send you the 240 drachmas for the unsettled business of (the past) two years. All that is fitting for my mother I shall send her, if she wants anything. Have a cloak made for me by her so that I do not buy one again and get smeared too; everyone will be paid. Concerning Neilos, let me know what he wants. I greet Joulia my sister and Hephesta. Pauni 25."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>McNamee K, ZPE 46, 128-33, 1982, Pl IV 2 -- SB XVI 12694 (and XVIII, p. 484) -- BL IX, 289 (l. 13)</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:16:12694</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1850&amp;viewid=3164V.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1850&amp;viewid=3164V.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1850&amp;viewid=3164V.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
