<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tax Roll</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3830</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3830</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.mich.4.1.224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0163;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;4.1;224</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11999</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11999</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4171</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Tax register, recording day by day the collection of money taxes.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; some writing on the Verso</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.Cair. Inv. 57187; P.Iand. VII, 141; P.Mich. Inv. 2830; 3159; 4910</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 35.5 x 29.7 cm.</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">This light-brown papyrus is regularly cut at the right and the left. Kollesis at the right. (TC)</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">1-40</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto, col. 66 (ll. 2655-2695)</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Written in a quick but clear cursive. The scribe separated a new entry from the preceding one by underlining the name of the tax payer. Diairesis used occasionally. (TC)</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0172" notAfter="0173">172-173 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Ninis, son of Asklas, grandson of Ninis, mother Tabous (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 191)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sambas, son of Peteesis, grandson of Apollonios, mother Tanomgeus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 223)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Keras, son of Sisois (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 182)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tauris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 240)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pykta (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 221)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Artemas, son of Heron, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 155)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kastor, his son, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 181)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petsiris, son of Pasion, grandson of Petsiris, mother Taonnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 211)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heron, son of Pekmeis alias Heuremon, mother Sambathion  (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 157)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides, son of Abykis, grandson of Abykis, mother Herais (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Onnophris, son of Sisois, grandson of Petsiris, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 192)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petalion, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Petalion, mother Tepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 208)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Harsiesis, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 201)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Horion, son of Maron, grandson of Horion, mother Thermouthis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 249)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptollas, son of Petsiris, grandson of Heras, mother Isidora (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 221)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petheus, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 202)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Psenesis, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Komonis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 248)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Petesouchos, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Tasoucharion (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 210)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Leouas, son of Petheus, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Tapapeis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 184)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Tamystha, daughter of Menches (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 233)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Kolkalos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 183)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ptolemaios, son of Petheus the younger, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Aunchis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 218)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Herakleides, son of Esouris, grandson of Kollouthes, mother Taonnophris (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 167)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Phaesis, son of Sisois, grandson of Phaesis, mother Thaesis (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 244)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Heras, son of Souchas, grandson of Heras, mother Tapetheus (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 169)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aphrodous, daughter of Horos (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 158)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apynchis, son of Pnepheros (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 154)</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Karanis, Herakleidou meris, Arsinoite nome, province of Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>see electronic version of P.Mich. IV, 224;</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
               <term type="genre_form">documentary</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>"(Column) 66:;Ninis, son of Asklas, grandson of Ninis, mother Tabous, drachmas 4;;Sambas, son of Peteesis, grandson of Apollonios, mother Tanomgeus, drachmas 8;;Keras, son of Sisois through the agency of Tauris (Pykta);;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 4 obol 1.5 chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives obols 3.5, naubion obols 2.5 chalki 2, surcharges drachma 1 obol 0.5;;(in left margin: drachmas 20 obols 15) eparourion drachmas 2 obols 5, surcharges obol 1.5, kollybos drachmas 9 obols 4;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 10 obols 5, surcharges obols 4 chalki 2, in total drachmas 11 obols 3 chalki 2;;in total for the day drachmas 48 obols 15.;(Pachon) 22 likewise:;Artemas, son of Heron, grandson of Petheus, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8;;Kastor, his son, mother Thaesis, drachmas 8;;Petsiris, son of Pasion, grandson of Petsiris, mother Taonnophris, copper tetradrachmas 4;;Heron, son of Pekmeis alias Heuremon, mother Sambathion, drachmas 8;;Herakleides, son of Abykis, grandson of Abykis, mother Herais, drachmas 4;;Onnophris, son of Sisois, grandson of Petsiris, mother Thaesis, drachmas 4;;Petalion, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Petalion, mother Tepheros, drachmas 8;;Petheus, son of Harsiesis, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetheus, uperetes,;guard tax drachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 52;;(Pachon) 23 likewise:;Horion, son of Maron, grandson of Horion, mother Thermouthis, drachmas 16;;Ptollas, son of Petsiris, grandson of Heras, mother Isidora (see P.Mich. IV/2, p. 221);;Petheus, son of Pasoknopaios, grandson of Petheus, mother Tapetheus, copper tetradrachmas 4;;Psenesis, son of Petheus, grandson of Esouris, mother Komonis, drachmas 4;;Petesouchos, son of Petesouchos, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Tasoucharion, obols 28;;Leouas, son of Petheus, grandson of Sokmenis, mother Tapapeis, drachmas 4;;Tamystha, daughter of Menches (Kolkalos);;orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachmas 2 obols 3, tax on the produce of olives obols 2 chalki 2, naubion obol 1.5, surcharges obols 3.5 chalki 2;;(in left margin: drachmas 12 obols 9) eparourion drachma 1 obols 4, surcharges obol 1, kollybos obol 0.5 chalki 2, in total drachmas 5 obols 4 chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 6 obol 1.5, surcharges obols 2.5, in total drachmas 6 obols 4;;Ptolemaios, son of Petheus the younger, grandson of Petesouchos, mother Aunchis, drachmas 24 obols 28;;Herakleides, son of Esouris, grandson of Kollouthes, mother Taonnophris, copper tetradrachmas 4;;in total for the day drachmas 96 obols 6.;(Pachon) 24 likewise:;Phaesis, son of Sisois, grandson of Phaesis, mother Thaesis, drachmas 16 obols 28;;Heras, son of Souchas, grandson of Heras, mother Tapetheus, drachmas 4;;Aphrodous, daughter of Horos (Apynchis, son of Pnepheros);;(in left margin: drachmas 8 obols 25) orchard taxes for the 12th year apomoira drachma 1 obols 5 chalki 2, tax on the produce of olives obols 2, naubion obol 1 chalki 2, surcharges obols 3;\;eparourion drachma 1 obol 0.5, surcharges obol 0.5 chalki 2, kollybos obol 0.5, in total drachmas 4 obols 2 chalki 2;;geometria for the 12th year drachmas 4 obols 4.5, surcharges obols 2, in total drachmas 5 obol 0.5;;naubion of katoikoi for the 13th year obols 4, surcharges obol 0.5, kollybos chalki 2, in total obols 4.5 chalki 2."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Rep Editor - Pearl OM;    Rep Ser. - Diss;    1938;    pg. 9 - 10 Youtie HC, PMich IV, 1, 224, 1937 -- CPJ 3, 492 (lines with Sambathion) Pearl OM - Youtie HC, PMich IV, 357 C, D, 1939</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Mich.:4:1:224</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3830&amp;viewid=4171_66R.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3830&amp;viewid=4171_66R.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-3830&amp;viewid=4171_66R.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
