<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale of a courtyard</title>
            <author>Ophelas also called Besas, son of Sarapas and Apollonous, of Oxyrhynchos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1261</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1261</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.20.14199</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;20;14199</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;20;14199</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">23689</idno>
            <idno type="TM">23689</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Corn. Inv. MSS. A 101. III</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Contract of a sale of 50 nsquare cubits or 1/200 arourae (nearly 14 sqare metres) of a court attached to a house at Oxyrhynchus from Ophelas, acting as the representative of Artemidoros, to Eudaimnois, the price being 500 drachmae of silver</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">The traces on verso are not noted in ed. princ., but cf. Pruneti, p. 64, footnote 5</note>
                     <note type="general">Location: Ann Arbor</note>
                     <note type="general">Pub. status: Recto; Verso is unpublished</note>
                     <note type="related">+ P.S.I. IX 1035 (aquired in Cairo in 1927 and edited in 1929)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 11  x  47 cm</support>
                        <condition>
                           <ab type="conservation">The papyrus kept in the Library is the upper part of a contract. The lower part is kept in Bibliotheca Medicea Laurenziana, Florence. The first eight lines are well preserved, line 9 has some lacunae and l. 10 preserves just a few letters. The verso contains traces of three and a half columns written upside down in relation to the text in recto, and only a few letters can be read</ab>
                        </condition>
                     </supportDesc>
                     <layoutDesc>
                        <layout>
                           <ab type="lines">10 lines [+ PSI IX 1035, 19 lines]</ab>
                           <ab type="recto-verso">Source of description: Recto</ab>
                        </layout>
                     </layoutDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
                  <handDesc>
                     <p>Small letters written by an experient scribe. The papyrus preserves 11  foldings, and the right one is the smaller, that is the papyrus was folded from the right to the left. The top margin is c. 4.3 cm., the left c. 2.5 cm and the right  c. 0.8 cm.</p>
                  </handDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0179">23 August, 179 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>Oxyrhynchos, Oxyrhynchite nome, Egypt</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Ophelas also called Besas, son of Sarapas and Apollonous, acting as representative of the seller in the contract</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapas, father of Ophelas and husband of Apollonous</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollonous, mother of Ophelas and wife of Sarapas</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Artemidoros, son of Amenneus (I) and Thakoris, grandson of Artemas, acting as a seller in the contract</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Amenneus (I), father of Artemidoros, son of Artemas, husband of Thakoris</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thakoris, mother of Artemidoros, daughter of Amenneus (II), wife of Amenneus (I)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Amenneus (II), father of Thakoris, grandfather of Artemidoros</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Eudaimonis, also called Plutarche, daughter of Sinthonis, one of the byuers in the contract</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sinthonis, mother fo Eudaemonis, daughter of Pekysis and Teenkegous, one of the buyers in the contract</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pekysis, father of Sinthonis, grandfather of Eudaimonis, husband of Teenkegous</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Teenkegous, wife of Pekysis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonios (I) also called Dionysios, son of Ammonios (II) and Harasis, acting as guardian of Eudaimonis</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Ammonios (II) father of Ammonios (I)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Harasis, wife of Ammonios (II) and mother of Ammonios (I)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Pachnubis, brother of Sinthonis, son of Pekysis and Teenkegous, acting as guardian of Sinthonis (i.e. his sister)</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Diogenes, neighbour of the courtyard</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Sarapion, son of Thaisous, neighboour of the couryard</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Thaisous, mother of Sarapion</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Lucios Herennios Crispos, neighbour of the courtyard</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Oxyrhynchos, Oxyrhynchite nome, Egypt</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Oxyrhynchon polis;Tanais;Quarter of Pammene's Garden</term>
               <term>House selling--Egypt--Bahnasïa .</term>
               <term>Contracts--Egypt--Bahnasïa .</term>
               <term>Guardian and ward</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyrus</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Ophelas also called Besas son of Sarapas and Apollonous, of Oxyrhynchos, appointed as a representative by Artemidoros son of Amenneus son of Artemas, his mother being Thakoris daughter of Amenneus, also of Oxyrhynchos, by the terms of a deed of representation drawn up through the registry-office at Oxyrhynchos in the present month,of which a copy is appended, to Eudaimonis also called Plutarche stated as the daughter of Sinthronis daughter of Pekysis, and her mother Sinthronis daughter of Pekysis and Teenkegous, both of Tanais, jointly, each with her guardian, in the case of Eudaimonis also called Plutarche, Ammonius also called Dionysius son of Ammonius and Harasis, of Oxyrhynchus, and in that of Sinthronis, her full brother Pachnubis, greeting. I acknowledge that I have sold to you of the parental house and yard and adjoining court which belong to the aforesaid Artemidoros whom I represent, at the said city in the quarter of Pammenes' Garden, of the said court in the eastern portion of it 50 square cubits extending from north to south as far as the end of the whole court and from east to west as far as the said 50 aquare cubits reach. The adjacent areas of the portion of the court sold to you by me, by survey 50 cubits, are, on the south the land of Diogenes and others, on the north that of sarapion stated as the son of Thaisous, on the east that of Lucios Herennios Krispos  and others, on the west the reamining places of the said court. The sum mutually agreed upon between us as the price of the said land sold to you by me, by survey 50 square cubits, namely 500 dtachmae of Imperial silver coin, I have received on the spot from you from hand to hand in full (at this point P.Corn. is broken and the remaining lower part of the contract is preserved in PSI  IX 1035]</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P Pruneti, Vendita di un cortile in Ossirinco (P.Oxy. III 505 + PSI IX 1035), Analecta Papyrologica 2, 1990, 63-74, photo in pp.68-69 -- SB XX 14199 Grenfell BP-Hunt AS, POxy III, 505, 1903 Mitteis L, Chrestomathie, no 350, 1912</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB.:20:14199</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            <p>
               <ref target="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/image-idx?view=entry&amp;subview=detail&amp;cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1261&amp;viewid=C0_IIIR.TIF">Original record</ref>.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="figure">
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto thumbnail</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/a/apis/thumb/I/I/r/C0_IIIr.jpg"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto medium</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1261&amp;viewid=C0_IIIR.TIF&amp;quality=medium"/>
            </figure>
            <figure>
               <head>Overview</head>
               <figDesc>Recto large</figDesc>
               <graphic url="http://images.umdl.umich.edu/cgi/i/image/getimage-idx?cc=apis&amp;entryid=X-1261&amp;viewid=C0_IIIR.TIF&amp;quality=large"/>
            </figure>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
