<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.16/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
     n="0239;8;9924a"
     xml:id="sb.8.9924a"
     xml:lang="en">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>sb.8.9924a</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">sb.8.9924a</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;8;9924a</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;8;9924a</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14302</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14302</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Duke Databank of Documentary Papyri. This work is licensed under a <ref type="license" target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p/>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <handNotes>
            <handNote xml:id="m2"/>
            <handNote xml:id="m3"/>
         </handNotes>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
          <change when="2020-07-13T10:48:55-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/james.cowey">Finalized - Ready.</change>
          <change when="2020-07-06T06:36:24-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/james.cowey">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Fine</change>
          <change when="2016-08-13T14:56:01-04:00" 
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/gclaytor">Submit - Added Hagedorn's corrections from ZPE 183</change>
          <change when="2020-07-06T07:26:16-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/james.cowey">Finalized - Decided to finalize this to preserve discussion of readings suggested through the editor. These discussions postdate the corrections made by D. Hagedorn in ZPE 183. For that reason I have chosen only to include the published corrections in the mark up</change>
           <change when="2020-07-06T05:46:50-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/james.cowey">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Be careful to account for both Gad's suggestions and Hagedorn's corrections.</change>
          <change when="2018-05-29T11:13:29-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/Myrto%20Malouta">Vote - AcceptText - I also completely agree with Usama's reading of Καρανίδ(ος) in line 5. In line 4, instead of Epeiph I read Καισαρείο(υ) quite clearly. But the four(?) letters before that are very hard to reconcile with μηνός: though I think the sigma is safe, it would be a stretch even for this hand to read the first letter as mu. Usama and Josh's idea to read them as numbers is palaeographically convincing, but I can't find any parallels for dates formed as day(s) then month. This is not conclusive, but I'll go with "Accept text" to move things along, so l. 5 can be corrected and l. 4 partly corrected if a second reader agrees with the suggestions so far. In any case I think there is more that's wrong with this text, such as the rendering of Trajan's name, which seems to me more heavily abbreviated than the editor suggests.</change>
          <change when="2016-11-21T13:18:38-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/joshuad.sosin">Vote - DEFER - Lin5 καρανιδ is pretty clear on the digital image : http://opes.uio.no/papyrus/scan/134r.jpg ; good catch. &#xD;
 &#xD;
 -At lin4, though, I cannot read κβ̣ ἕως κη Ἐπεὶφ ; I think I can see what is proposed for Ἐπεὶφ, which seems to involve a phi whose belly was written and vertical stroke omitted. I can be persuaded of κβ̣, five days from which would be κϛ; I could convince myself to read “κβ κϲ” (where stigma lacks the tail and looks rather like lunate sigma) with no ἕως between (quite common without it); the traces after that stigma I might consider compatible with phi, but I cannot read pharmouthi or phamenoth. &#xD;
 &#xD;
 So, the new reading at Lin5 seems pretty secure to me; the new reading at lin4 seems to head in the right direction and to improve on “κώμης Καρανίδ(ος)”, but I cannot quite confirm on the digital image. An editor with a better eye than mine should have a careful look.</change>
          <change when="2014-10-03T15:40:35-04:00" 
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/Gad">Submit - Through the digital image, I was able to suggest these readings. My start point was καὶ Ἀπιδ(  ) in l.5, where one expect the village to whome the work is accredited. So, the image confirmed my suspicion. I read a clear καρανιδ( ).Then just over this, one expects the duration of the work, I was surprised to see the reading κώμης Καρανίδ(ος) at the end of this line i.e. l.3. The kappa at the beginning is clear to me as well as Ἐπεὶφ at the end, even though I'm not comfortable with the omicron-shaped Phi. I tried to read  a number before Ἐπεὶφ, and reading backwards I saw κη before that ἕως. But the letter before ἕως doesn't look like a delta. It is more like a Beta, but this makes 8 days not five as stated in l. 3 and as usual. I think this is not a problem since  this formulaic first part of the certificate was written beforehand, but the actual work recorded by the supervisor  was 8 days. These items were recorded in the spot, so the change of the hands; one added the date- and place-information , then two supervising officials signed. </change>
          <change when="2011-12-14" who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/gabrielbodard">rationalized languages in langUsage</change>
          <change when="2011-12-14" who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/gabrielbodard">changed editor names to URIs</change>
          <change when="2010-05-05" who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/gabrielbodard">changed schema; added xml:space=preserve; indented; moved title/@n to idno</change>
          <change when="2009-11-12" who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/gabrielbodard">Added language la-Grek</change>
          <change when="2009-06-27" who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/gabrielbodard">Converted from TEI P4 (EpiDoc DTD v. 6) to P5 (EpiDoc RNG schema)</change>
          <change when="2008-12-23" who="http://papyri.info/about">Automated split from transcoder files</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <head n="14302" xml:lang="en">
            <date>AD 114-15</date>
            <placeName>Karanis</placeName>
         </head>
         <div xml:lang="grc" type="edition" xml:space="preserve"><ab>
    <lb n="1"/>ἔτους ὀκτωκαιδεκάτου <expan>Αὐτοκράτορο<ex>ς</ex></expan> <expan>Καί<unclear>σ</unclear><supplied reason="lost">αρ</supplied>ο<ex>ς</ex></expan> 

    <lb n="2"/>Νέρουα Τραιανοῦ <expan>Ἀρίστο<ex>υ</ex></expan> Σεβαστοῦ <expan>Γερμανι<ex>κοῦ</ex></expan> Δακικοῦ 

    <lb n="3"/><expan><unclear>ε</unclear>ἴ<unclear>ρ</unclear>γ<ex>ασται</ex></expan> ἐφʼ <expan>ἡ<ex>μέρας</ex></expan> πέντε <num value="5"/> ὑπὲρ <expan>χωματικ<ex>ῶν</ex></expan> 

    <lb n="4"/><unclear>ἔ</unclear>ργων τοῦ <expan>αὐ<ex>τοῦ</ex></expan> <num value="18">ιη</num> <expan><ex>ἔτους</ex></expan> <app type="editorial"><lem resp="D. Hagedorn, ZPE 183 (2012) 185-186"><num value="22">κβ</num> <num value="26">κϛ</num> <expan>Καισαρείο<ex>υ</ex></expan></lem><rdg>κώμης <expan>Καρανίδ<ex>ος</ex></expan></rdg></app>

    <lb n="5"/>ἐν ὀρινῇ <expan>Πατσώ<ex>ντεως</ex></expan> <app type="editorial"><lem resp="D. Hagedorn, ZPE 183 (2012) 185-186"><expan>Καρανίδ<ex>ος</ex></expan></lem><rdg>καὶ <abbr>Ἀπιδ</abbr></rdg></app>

    <lb n="6"/><handShift new="m2"/> <expan>Ἀγχορίμ<ex>φις</ex></expan> <expan>Ἰεμούθο<ex>υ</ex></expan> <expan>το<ex>ῦ</ex></expan> <app type="editorial"><lem resp="D. Hagedorn, ZPE 183 (2012) 185-186"><expan>Πεθέω<ex>ς</ex></expan></lem><rdg><expan>Πετεῶ<ex>τος</ex></expan></rdg></app> <supplied reason="lost"><expan><ex>μητρὸς</ex></expan></supplied> <expan>Σοήρεω<ex>ς</ex></expan>. 

    <lb n="7"/><handShift new="m3"/> Κράτων <expan>σεση<ex>μείωμαι</ex></expan>. </ab></div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
