<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Private Letter</title>
            <author>Aria</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1961</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1961</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.14.11588</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;14;11588</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;14;11588</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">32936</idno>
            <idno type="TM">32936</idno>
            <idno type="filename">32936-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 337</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.965564-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>My lord son [Dorotheos] from your mother Aria, greetings. Before all else, I pray  to the Divine Providence that is with God that you may be in good health and prosperous when my letter is given to you. I want you to know that of the 1000 myriads I received nothing from [--]nianus except the 500 myriads in Alexandria. And with reference to what you said about getting the two hundred myriads from the apprentice of Ameinias, I did not find him. And about the 500 myriads, will you please get them and send them? You know where I got them. I went to the bleacher for the three and a half lbs. And as you said, "Go to my sister Maria, and she gives them to you," I went and she gave me nothing. For what does go right for me? Know this too, that the orphan child is in my house, and I myself have need of expenses. And about the two and a half lbs., 2 1/2, I owe nothing except the pay for the bleacher. And if I do owe anything, I pay with these goods of mine. For in fact I have sold some of the same linen stuff at 10 myriads for 1 lb. I marvel at how you have neglected me. I salute you all, each by name. [--]es and our own people, each by name, salute you.;;(Verso);;Deliver to Dorotheos, son of Philippos, from Aria, his mother.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, ZPE 22, 63-68, 1976 -- SB XIV 11588 Youtie HC, Scriptiunculae I, 345-350, 1981</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
