<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<bibl xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="b97503" type="article" subtype="journal" xml:lang="en">
  <title level="a" type="main">Extreme Climate after Massive Eruption of Alaska's Okmok Volcano in 43 BCE and Effects on the Late Roman Republic and Ptolemaic Kingdom</title>
  <author n="1">
    <forename>Joseph R.</forename>
    <surname>McConnell</surname>
  </author>
  <author n="2">
    <forename>Michael</forename>
    <surname>Sigl</surname>
  </author>
  <author n="3">
    <forename>G.</forename>
    <surname>Plunkett</surname>
  </author>
  <author n="4">
    <forename>A.</forename>
    <surname>Plunkett</surname>
  </author>
  <author n="5">
    <forename>W.M.</forename>
    <surname>Kim</surname>
  </author>
  <author n="6">
    <forename>C.C.</forename>
    <surname>Raible</surname>
  </author>
  <author n="7">
    <forename>A.I.</forename>
    <surname>Wilson</surname>
  </author>
  <author n="8">
    <forename>J.G.</forename>
    <surname>Manning</surname>
  </author>
  <author n="9">
    <forename>F.</forename>
    <surname>Ludlow</surname>
  </author>
  <author n="10">
    <forename>N.J.</forename>
    <surname>Chellman</surname>
  </author>
  <author n="11">
    <forename>H.M.</forename>
    <surname>Innes</surname>
  </author>
  <author n="12">
    <forename>Z.</forename>
    <surname>Yang</surname>
  </author>
  <author n="13">
    <forename>J.F.</forename>
    <surname>Larsen</surname>
  </author>
  <author n="14">
    <forename>J.R.</forename>
    <surname>Schaefer</surname>
  </author>
  <author n="15">
    <forename>S.</forename>
    <surname>Kipfstuhl</surname>
  </author>
  <author n="16">
    <forename>S.</forename>
    <surname>Nojtabavi</surname>
  </author>
  <author n="17">
    <forename>F.</forename>
    <surname>Whilhelms</surname>
  </author>
  <author n="18">
    <forename>Th.</forename>
    <surname>Opel</surname>
  </author>
  <author n="19">
    <forename>H.</forename>
    <surname>Meyer</surname>
  </author>
  <author n="20">
    <forename>J.P.</forename>
    <surname>Steffensen</surname>
  </author>
  <date>2020</date>
  <ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2002722117"/>
  <biblScope type="pp" from="59" to="88">59-88</biblScope>
  <relatedItem type="appearsIn" n="1">
    <bibl>
      <ptr target="https://papyri.info/biblio/2419"/>
      <!-- ignore - start, i.e. SoSOL users may not edit this -->
      <!-- ignore - stop -->
    </bibl>
  </relatedItem>
  <biblScope type="issue">117</biblScope>
  <idno type="pi">97503</idno>
  <idno type="bp">2020-0762</idno>
  <seg type="original" subtype="index" resp="#BP">214</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="titre" resp="#BP">Joseph R. McConnell et al., Extreme Climate after Massive Eruption of Alaska's Okmok Volcano in 43 BCE and Effects on the Late Roman Republic and Ptolemaic Kingdom.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="publication" resp="#BP">Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United Sctates of America 117 (2020) No. 27, pp. 15443-15449, figg.	</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="resume" resp="#BP">The assassination of Julius Caesar in 44 BCE triggered a power struggle that ultimately ended the Roman Republic and, eventually, the Ptolemaic Kingdom, leading to the rise of the Roman Empire. Climate proxies and written documents indicate that this struggle occurred during a period of unusually inclement weather, famine, and disease in the Mediterranean region; historians have previously speculated that a large volcanic eruption of unknown origin was the most likely cause. Show using well-dated volcanic fallout records in six Arctic ice cores that one of the largest volcanic eruptions of the past 2,500 y occurred in early 43 BCE, with distinct geochemistry of tephra deposited during the event identifying the Okmok volcano in Alaska as the source. Climate proxy records show that 43 and 42 BCE were among the coldest years of recent millennia in the Northern Hemisphere at the start of one of the coldest decades. Earth system modeling suggests that radiative forcing from this massive, high-latitude eruption led to pronounced changes in hydroclimate, including seasonal temperatures in specific Mediterranean regions as much as 7 °C below normal during the 2 y period following the eruption and unusually wet conditions. While it is difficult to establish direct causal linkages to thinly documented historical events, the wet and very cold conditions from this massive eruption on the opposite side of Earth probably resulted in crop failures, famine, and disease, exacerbating social unrest and contributing to political realignments throughout the Mediterranean region at this critical juncture of Western civilization.</seg>
  <seg type="original" subtype="nom" resp="#BP">McConnell</seg>
</bibl>
