<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Official letter from Marres : to Menches</title>
            <author>Marres</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">berkeley.apis.397</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(CU)397</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.tebt.1.31</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0206;1;31</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.tebt;1;31</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">3667</idno>
            <idno type="TM">3667</idno>
            <idno type="filename">3667-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Tebt.0031</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:21.139914-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(2nd h.) Received in the 5th year, Phamenoth .. (1st h.) Marres to Menches, greeting. A copy is appended of the letter from Horos, Basilikos Grammateus, about the cession which he states has been made to Dionysios son of Dionysios by Menandros son of Pantauchos of a holding near Kerkeosiris. The 5th year, Phamenoth .. Horos to Marres, greeting. Appended is a copy of the letter of Aristippos, overseer of the arrangement of katoikoi hippeis, about the cession which he states has been made by Menander to Dionysios son of Dionysios. The 5th year, Phamenoth 22. Aristippos to Horos, greeting. I have appended a copy of the petition which has been presented to me by Dionysios son of Dionysios, a Macedonian, about the holding of 34 3/32 arouras near Kerkeosiris in the division of Polemon which he states has been ceded to him by Menander son of Pantauchos. Please therefore give instructions for the said land to be registered on your list too under his name. The 5th year, Phamenoth 22. To Aristippos, one of the first friends and overseer of the arrangement (of katoikoi hippeis), from Dionysios son of Dionysios, Macedonian. As Menander son of Pantauchos has ceded to me his holding of 34 3/32 arouras near Kerkeosiris in the division of Polemon, but the scribes being ignorant of the transaction which has taken place continue to register the aforesaid holding under the name of Menandros, I beg you to direct a letter to be sent to the Basilikos Grammateus in order that he being informed may register the aforesaid 34 3/32 arouras under my name, and so I may obtain redress. Farewell.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Tebt., I.31</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
