<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Petition to Menches</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">berkeley.apis.427</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(CU)427</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.tebt.1.47</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0206;1;47</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.tebt;1;47</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">3683</idno>
            <idno type="TM">3683</idno>
            <idno type="filename">3683-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Tebt.0047</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:21.234409-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(To Menches, komogrammateus of Kerkeosiris, from N.N. and N.N.,) cultivators of Crown land and inhabitants of the said village. On the 8th of Mesore of the 4th year as we were in the fields at work upon the land which we cultivate near the village, Pyrrhichos son of Dionysios, a catoecic cavalry-soldier, and Herakleios son of Poseidippos, an inhabitant of the said village, invaded our house with many other persons armed with swords and incontinently knocked down the street door, and placing this against the tower broke through part of it. Having effected an entry an knocked down the remaining doors they carried off the articles mentioned below, although there was no dispute whatever between us and them. We therefore, being hindered in our work and that too while the water is out, present to you this complaint in order that you may subscribe to our statements and further forward a copy of the petition to the proper officials, so that we may recover our property and the accused may receive the punishment which they deserve. Farewell. The itemized list is: a door of tamarisk wood two hoes, 200 drachmas of bronze.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Tebt., I.47; Plate: P.Tebt., I, pl. VII</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
