<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title type="main"> HGVTITLE (DDBTITLE) </title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">hgv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="TM">gv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">hgv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.lond;4;1333dupl</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-04-22T10:38:35-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/>. . . . fugitives. On receiving the present letter, therefore. . . .  six men of those whose duty it is to . . . . such . . . .  , dealing with such of them as have fled to each pagarchy in accordance with the instructions which we have laid down for you at the foot <milestone n="5" unit="line"/> of the present letter, sending to them (i. e. the fugitives) men (lit. someone) who are capable and trustworthy and able to write, with instructions to proceed with them to the commissioners for the fugitives, and to take down in their presence the name and patronymic of each, stating also from what place each fled and to what place and what pagarchy, both in the case of those who are being sent back <milestone n="10" unit="line"/> to their homes and in the case of those who are allowed to remain where they settled on condition of contributing (to the taxes); in short, they are to discover all that is to be known. Order them to set about their work energetically and not to receive from anyone anything whatever by way of gratuity; for you will be aware that if anyone of the persons <milestone n="15" unit="line"/> you send is convicted of having received a gratuity from anyone whatsoever, the danger is yours and you will receive punishment along with the guilty person. But send off the said men promptly to the aforementioned commissioners for the fugitives, and let me not find you guilty of causing any impediment to this <milestone n="20" unit="line"/> or of delaying the despatch of the full number which we have written to you, lest you fall into danger. Written the 29th Choiach, 7th indiction. 
Memorandum. 6 men. To Salāmah b. Yukhāmir in Arcadia, 2 persons. 
To Shuraih (?) b. Al-Wāsil in the Thebaid, 2 persons. 
<milestone n="25" unit="line"/> To ʿAbd Allāh b. Shuraih on the Frontier, 2 persons.

            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
