<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<bibl xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
      xml:id="b87884"
      type="article"
      subtype="book"
      xml:lang="en">
   <title level="a" type="main">Kings, Taxes and High Priests: Comparing the Ptolemaic and Seleukid Policies.</title>
   <author>
      <forename>Gilles</forename>
      <surname>Gorre</surname>
   </author>
   <author>
      <forename>Sylvie</forename>
      <surname>Honigman</surname>
   </author>
   <date>2013</date>
   <note resp="#BP">1. Justifying the comparative perspective: 1.1. Differences in cultic organisation between Egypt and Judaea; - 1.2. The high priest of Ptah as compared to the local and provincial high priests of the Seleukid realm; - 1.3. Comparing the economic policies of the Achaemenids and Hellenistic dynasties towards the temples. - 2. The high priests of Ptah in Memphis and the Seleukid provincial high priests: 2.1. The high priest of Ptah in Memphis and the reform of the apomoira; - 2.2. The Seleukid high priests. - 3. The lower-ranking representatives of the royal administration within the temples: 3.1. The increasing grip of the royal administration on the Egyptian temples; - 3.2. Simon the prostates and the Babylonian paqdu. - 4. A hellenistic innovation: meddling with the high priests: 4.1. The high priests of the Egyptian temples under the Ptolemies; - 4.2. The deposition of Onias III by Antiochos IV. - Conclusion.</note>
   <note type="illustration">1 tabl.</note>
   <relatedItem type="appearsIn">
      <bibl>
         <ptr target="http://papyri.info/biblio/84646"/>
         <!--ignore - start, i.e. SoSOL users may not edit this-->
         <title level="m" type="main">Egitto dai Faraoni agli Arabi. Atti del Convegno Egitto: amministrazione, economia, società, cultura dai Faraoni agli Arabi. Égypte: administration, économie, société, culture des Pharaons aux Arabes, Milano, Università degli Studi, 7-9 Gennaio 2013</title>
         <editor>
            <forename>Silvia</forename>
            <surname>Bussi</surname>
         </editor>
         <!--ignore - stop-->
      </bibl>
   </relatedItem>
   <biblScope type="pp" from="105" to="119">105-119</biblScope>
   <idno type="pi">87884</idno>
   <idno type="bp">2013-0749</idno>
   <seg type="original" subtype="index" resp="#BP">214 630 712 714</seg>
   <seg type="original" subtype="titre" resp="#BP">Gilles Gorre &amp; Sylvie Honigman, Kings, Taxes and High Priests: Comparing the Ptolemaic and Seleukid Policies.</seg>
   <seg type="original" subtype="publication" resp="#BP">Silvia Bussi (ed.), Egitto dai Faraoni agli Arabi. Atti del Convegno Egitto: amministrazione, economia, società, cultura dai Faraoni agli Arabi. Égypte: administration, économie, société, culture des Pharaons aux Arabes, Milano, Università degli Studi, 7-9 Gennaio 2013 = Studi ellenistici. Supplementi. 1 (Pisa - Roma, 2013) pp. 105-119, 1 tabl.</seg>
   <seg type="original" subtype="resume" resp="#BP">1. Justifying the comparative perspective: 1.1. Differences in cultic organisation between Egypt and Judaea; - 1.2. The high priest of Ptah as compared to the local and provincial high priests of the Seleukid realm; - 1.3. Comparing the economic policies of the Achaemenids and Hellenistic dynasties towards the temples. - 2. The high priests of Ptah in Memphis and the Seleukid provincial high priests: 2.1. The high priest of Ptah in Memphis and the reform of the apomoira; - 2.2. The Seleukid high priests. - 3. The lower-ranking representatives of the royal administration within the temples: 3.1. The increasing grip of the royal administration on the Egyptian temples; - 3.2. Simon the prostates and the Babylonian paqdu. - 4. A hellenistic innovation: meddling with the high priests: 4.1. The high priests of the Egyptian temples under the Ptolemies; - 4.2. The deposition of Onias III by Antiochos IV. - Conclusion.</seg>
   <seg type="original" subtype="nom" resp="#BP">Gorre Honigman</seg>
</bibl>
