<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<bibl xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"
      xml:id="b87923"
      type="article"
      subtype="book"
      xml:lang="en">
   <title level="a" type="main">The Trade with India and the Problem of Agency in the Economy of the Roman Empire.</title>
   <author>
      <forename>Kai</forename>
      <surname>Ruffing</surname>
   </author>
   <date>2013</date>
   <note resp="#BP">Owners of cargo (principals) often had to make use of persons organizing the selling of the goods (agents). Within the framework of trade in the Red Sea, agents were used on different points of the route, but their social status and consequently the legal and/or social form of principal-agent relationship depended on the social and cultural background of the people engaged in this trade: Romans used freedmen and slaves as agents, while Alexandrians and other people of Roman Egypt preferred to use free agents.</note>
   <relatedItem type="appearsIn">
      <bibl>
         <ptr target="http://papyri.info/biblio/84646"/>
         <!--ignore - start, i.e. SoSOL users may not edit this-->
         <title level="m" type="main">Egitto dai Faraoni agli Arabi. Atti del Convegno Egitto: amministrazione, economia, società, cultura dai Faraoni agli Arabi. Égypte: administration, économie, société, culture des Pharaons aux Arabes, Milano, Università degli Studi, 7-9 Gennaio 2013</title>
         <editor>
            <forename>Silvia</forename>
            <surname>Bussi</surname>
         </editor>
         <!--ignore - stop-->
      </bibl>
   </relatedItem>
   <biblScope type="pp" from="199" to="210">199-210</biblScope>
   <idno type="pi">87923</idno>
   <idno type="bp">2013-0773</idno>
   <seg type="original" subtype="index" resp="#BP">241 Mer Rouge 250 630 730</seg>
   <seg type="original" subtype="titre" resp="#BP">Kai Ruffing, The Trade with India and the Problem of Agency in the Economy of the Roman Empire.</seg>
   <seg type="original" subtype="publication" resp="#BP">Silvia Bussi (ed.), Egitto dai Faraoni agli Arabi. Atti del Convegno Egitto: amministrazione, economia, società, cultura dai Faraoni agli Arabi. Égypte: administration, économie, société, culture des Pharaons aux Arabes, Milano, Università degli Studi, 7-9 Gennaio 2013 = Studi ellenistici. Supplementi. 1 (Pisa - Roma, 2013) pp. 199-210.</seg>
   <seg type="original" subtype="resume" resp="#BP">Owners of cargo (principals) often had to make use of persons organizing the selling of the goods (agents). Within the framework of trade in the Red Sea, agents were used on different points of the route, but their social status and consequently the legal and/or social form of principal-agent relationship depended on the social and cultural background of the people engaged in this trade: Romans used freedmen and slaves as agents, while Alexandrians and other people of Roman Egypt preferred to use free agents.</seg>
   <seg type="original" subtype="nom" resp="#BP">Ruffing</seg>
</bibl>
