<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Contract of obligation of service (paramone)</title>
            <author>Aurelia Taesis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1649</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1649</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.4.7358</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;4;7358</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;4;7358</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14011</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14011</idno>
            <idno type="filename">14011-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 2819</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.442908-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Aurelia Taesis, daughter of Asklepiades and Sarapous, from the city of Memphis, has acknowledged to have received from Aurelia Thaisarion, daughter of Komon, from the village of Karanis, the capital sum of one myriad eight-thousand (18,000) silver drachmai, i.e. three talents, which, as Aurelia Taesis has further acknowledged, have been paid for a debt of her aforementioned father Asklepiades; and that she, the first party, will of necessity stay by Aurelia Thaisarion, performing the weaving and houselhold tasks that she knows in place of the interests of the capital sum. If she wants to give up, (she acknowledges that) she will also of necessity repay the aforementioned three talents of silver without delay, and that the right of execution on demand shall rest with Aurelia Thaisarion against the first party, Aurelia Thaesis, or against all her property, as if in accordance with a legal decision. This document written as a single copy shall be valid, anywhere it may be produced. And in response to the formal question, she has so agreed.;(2nd hand) I, Aurelia Taesis, have received the aforementioned thre talents of silver and shall stay (by her) for service of my craft and other household tasks. If I give up, I shall repay the aforementioned money, as aforementioned. And in response to the formal question, I have so agreed. I, Aurelius Horion son of Soterichos, from the quarter of Phremei, have written for her because she is illiterate.;[In the . . . year] of our lord Probus Augustus, Tybi 15.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak AER, ASAE 29, 47-49, 1929 -- SB IV 7358 -- BL II 2, 134-135 (on lines 6,18); BL VI, 136; BL VII, 192-193 (on lines 2-5,12, 14-18, 22, 24, 25). Youtie HC, ZPE 13, 235-237, 1974, Pl. XIV</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
