<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Declaration of Landholdings</title>
            <author>Gaius Gemellus Horion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1685</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1685</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.4.7360</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;4;7360</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;4;7360</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14013</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14013</idno>
            <idno type="filename">14013-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 2916</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.012477-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>To Kopres, village secretary of the village of Karanis, from Gaius Gemellus Horigenes, Roman and Antinoite, who is afflicted with weak vision. I declare the (following properties) belonging to me, &lt;formerly owned by&gt; my grandfather on the father's side, Gaius Iulius Niger: in the plain of Psenarpsenesis, one and one-half aroura of an olive grove cleared of trees in the place called Poulitas and (another) one-half aroura in the place Tesnekiauan and (another) one and one-half aroura in the place Soplou, (all three olive groves) which have been cut down already for a long time ago and can be transferred to (the register of) the corn-producing lands; and near Karanis, &lt; a parcel&gt; of the old canal &lt;in&gt; the place called Pagou, covered with sand. Therefore I submit (this declaration), asking that the latter be taken off of the (register of) property admittedly liable to taxation of the village and that the other (parcels, which have been changed) into corn-producing lands, be transferred from the money assessment to the corn revenues. These are one and one-half aroura in the place Poulitas and one-half aroura in the place Tesnekiauan and one and one-half aroura in the place Soplou, for a total amount of three and one-half arourai transferred to the corn-producing (lands). Farewell.;I, Gaius Gemellus Horigenes, have submitted. I, Titus Aelius Sarapammon, have written for him, who doesn't know letters.;In the 22nd year of the Emperor Caesar Marcus Aurelius Severus Antoninus Parthicus Maximus Britannicus Maximus Germanicus Maximus Pius Augustus, Phamenoth 8.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Boak, AER, ASAE 29, 51-54, 1929 -- SB IV 7360 -- BL II 2, 135 (on line 3); BL VII, 193 (on  lines 3, 4, 7, 11, 15) Youtie HC, ZPE 13, 249-251, 1974</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
