<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Decisions [199-200 AD] </title>
            <author>Septimius Severus, Roman emperor between 193 and 211 AD</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p339</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa3475</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.6.123</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14250</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14250</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;6;Apokrimata</idno>
            <idno type="filename">14250-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 516</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:24.54981-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>In Alexandria.
1-4: Copies of responsa posted in the Stoa of the Gymnasium.
	Year 8, Phamenoth 18. Imperator Caesar Lucius Septimius Severus Pius Pertinax Arabicus Adiabenicus Parthicus Maximus Augustus and Imperator Caesar Marcus Aurelius Antoninus Augustus
5-7: To Ulpius Heraclanus, also called Kallinikos.
	We remitted the penalties which had been imposed upon Alexandrians or Egyptians but added a time limit to the benefaction.
8-10: To Artemidoros also called Achilleus.
	Having placd yourself in agreement with the decisions (rendered), too late you take umbrage at the judgments (given).
11-12: To the Aurelii Artemidoros and Anoubion and others.
	Comply with the opinions rendered.
13-17: To Kill.[..]dis alias Midas, through Philokrates his son.
	Since you feel decisively that the instrument of sale of the mortgages was unjustly voided, the prefect of the province will issue the order that you regain possession of the plots seized by force without an agreement.
18-20: To ...thalge, daughter of Ambrelos, through Abdomanchos her son.
	Women are not forbidden to obligate themselves for loans or to exact payment in behalf of others.
21-24: On  the 19th, likewise published in the same Stoa:
	To Apollon son of Harnektotes, and others.
	The judgments regarding inspections (of land) have generally provided due care for Egyptians.
25-27: To Aurelius Sarapion.
	Some time ago we forbade that priesthoods come down in succession from the mother's side.
28-34: To Proklos son of Apollonios.
	It is not just that the heirs designated (in the will)-even if the will is said to have been forged-should be dispossessed. The officials charged with (the supervision of) legal proceedings shall take pains to cite the accused persons, if indeed the matter comes within the category of cognitiones.
34-39: To Kronios son of Herakleides.
	Transient sicknesses do not afford relief from municipal liturgies, and those who are physically sick are subject to liturgical services if they are mentally capable of conducting their household affairs.
40-44: On the 20th, likewise:
	To Dioskoros son of Hephaistion anda to Pieseis son of Osiris, and others.
	We have forbidden you to pay money in place of grain.
45-51: To Isidoros son of Dios.
	His excellency, Fulvius Plautianus, prefect of the camps and our household companion, will conduct the investigation of the audacious actions (emanating) from Komon. In respect to Apion, the tax collector, if he is not involved with Komon in the charges, you will have the prefect of the province as your judge.
52-56: To Isidoros also called Herakleides, through Apollonios.
	As you withdrew from your paternal inheritance and you do not have any assistance on the basis of your age, comply with the law concerning (bankruptcy) sales, since you assert that the estate has (already) been confiscated.
57-60: To ...elatheos son of Kairenos.
	If you take guardians for orphans outside of the (regular) order, in respect to their properties a judge will be given against those who are administering them.

</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. VI 123 <note>Republished with corrections and new legal commentary by H.C. Youtie and A.A. Schiller in CdE 30 (1955) 327-45 with new readings and printing of a new text; .MDIT/SB.MDNM/ VI 9526; see .MDIT/BL.MDNM/ IV  pp. 17-18 and .MDIT/BL.MDNM/ V pp. 23-24</note>
               </bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
