<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Extract from Census Register</title>
            <author>Unknown census official</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2277</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2277</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.6.9555</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;6;9555</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;6;9555</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14262 14263</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14262 14263</idno>
            <idno type="filename">14263-2</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 4716</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.89372-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Verso);;(Lines 3-24) From the census register incorporating descriptions of the 23rd year for the village of Karanis, from volume 3, Quarter of the Isieion, column 18, . . . buildings, inherited from the {mother} 'grandmother', belonging to the persons indicated below.;Ptolemaios, son of Kastor, grandson of Papos, whose mother is Kastorous, age 47 years.;Kastor, son, whose mother is Tasoucharion, daughter of Aunes, age 17 years.;Kastor also called Ptolemaios, another son, age 1 year.;Achillas, brother of Ptolemaios, age 30(?) years.;Kastor, son, whose mother is Aphrodous, daughter of Areios, age 15 years.;Kastor the younger, another son, age 1 year.;Womenfolk: Tasoucharion, daughter of Aunes, son of . . ., whose mother is Tape . . ., wife of Ptolemaios, age . . years.;'That . . . of them(?)';Onesime, daughter of them both, age 25 years, 'wife of K . . .'.;(In margin of line 18) Tasoucharion, another daughter, age . . years.;'Ptolemais, daughter of them both, age 5 years.';Aphrodous, daughter of Areios, granddaughter of Areios, whose mother is Ta . . ., wife of Achillas, age 38 years.;Serapias, daughter of them both, age . . years.;Tapiamis, another daughter, age 12 years.;(Lines 1-2, added in upper margin) And there belong to Tasoucharion in the same village a house and a courtyard, and in another location '2' houses and courtyard and a half share of a house and courtyard.;(Two lines in left margin of lines 3-13, perpendicularly to the main text, are washed off);;(Lines 25-36)  . . . 32.;Sab(  ), son of Sarap(  ), grandson of Euemeros, whose mother is Thais(  ), daughter of Onnophris, age 29 years.;Sarap(  ), son, whose mother is Thaisas, daughter of Didym(  ), age . . years.;Didymion, another son, age 1 year.;Womenfolk: Thaisas, daughter of Didym(  ), whose mother is Taesis, wife of Sab(  ), age 2 . years.;And there belong to Sab(  ) and his brothers in the village by equal shares from their mother a house and courtyard and another house and courtyard 'and another house', and to Thais(  ), wife of Sab(  ), from her mother, a half share of a house and courtyard and another house and courtyard.;;(Recto, second text);Kastor, son of Ptolemaios, grandson of Kastor, whose mother is Tasoucharis.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Pearl OM, CE 28, 346-352, 1953 -- SB VI 9555a -- The first editor doesn't mention the second text of recto, which is clearly related to the verso (name of the person for whom the extract was written?). - Line 2, read oiki(ai) '2', instead of oiki(a); line 11: age of Achillas quite uncertain (40 instead of 30?)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
