<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Request for parathesis</title>
            <author>Tharmouthis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">oslo.apis.87</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NoOU)87</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.6.9625</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;6;9625</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;6;9625</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14272</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14272</idno>
            <idno type="filename">14272-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Oslo inv. 1152</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:31.203682-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>To Sarapion, also called Agathos Daimon, and ..., ex-exegetes, keepers of the archives of the Arsinoite nome, from Tharmouthis ..., of the village of Tebtynis, acting with her guardian Andronikos, son of Eutychi..., of the quarter of Syriake. [I have bought,] in virtus of a public deed executed on the present day through the record-office here, in the neighbourhood of the village Pseonnophris, one half of a third part, that is the sixth part - which was owned in common and undivided - of a catoecic holding, consisting of 8 aruras, or however many they may be, in one area, at a cession price of ... drachmae, from Ammonia, daughter of Akosion ....., son of Proklos, of the quarter of the Store-houses, who had made the annotation through you.;Wherefore I present this application in order that the annotation may be made in conformity with the copy of the cession, which I have deposited. For when I make the declaration of the property, I will show that it belongs to me and is free; but if another person should be proved to have a right to it or a hold upon it recorded through the archives-office, the present notification shall not stand in th way of this claim.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
