<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Return of a loan</title>
            <author>Chration, son of Horion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">berkeley.apis.439</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(CU)439</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.10.10539</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;10;10539</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;10;10539</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14316</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14316</idno>
            <idno type="filename">14316-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Tebt.0596</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:20.881361-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Year eight of Imperator Caesar Nerva Trajanus Augustus Germanicus Dacicus, Phaophi 21, in Theogonis of the division of Polemon in the Arsinoite nome. Chration, son of Horion, about forty-six years old, with a scar on his left shin, acknowledges to Thaesis, daughter of Kronion also called Psenkebkis the son of Marsisouchos, about forty-seven years old, with a scar on her right shin, acting with her guardian, her relative Marepsemis son of Marepsemis, about thirty-seven years old, with a scar on the left side of his nose, that he has received from her, Thaesis, from hand to hand out of the house, two thousand four hundred forty-eight silver drachmas plus interest, which Thaesis owed to Chration by the terms of a contract of loan drawn up by the record-office in Tebtunis in the sixth year of Imperator Caesar Nerva Trajanus Augustus Germanicus Dacicus in the month of Kaisareios on the second intercalary day; and he has turned this contract over to Thaesis for cancellation and invalidation. Neither he, Chration, nor his assignees shall take action against Thaesis or her assignees either about this or about any other matter whatsoever from past time up to the present day. Signatory: Marepsemis son of Herieus. (2nd h.) I, Chration son of Horion, acknowledge that I have received from Thaesis, daughter of Kronion also called Psenkebkis the son of Marsisouchos, the two thousand four hundred forty-eight silver drachmas plus interest which she owed to me by the terms of the afore-stated contract; and I shall not prosecute, as stated above. (3rd h.) Registered by Glaukos, in charge of the record-office of Theogonis. (Title on verso) Agreement of Chration with Thaesis concerning the receipt of 2,448 drachmas.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Tebt., II.596; SB, X, no. 10539 <note>Shelton, J.C. BASP v. 6 (1969), p. 31-34 with photo (p. 32-33)</note>
               </bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
