<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Contract</title>
            <author>Psenkebkis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">berkeley.apis.665</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(CU)665</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.12.11006</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14391</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14391</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;12;11006a</idno>
            <idno type="filename">14391-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Tebt.0447</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:20.287728-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>The eighteenth year of Imperator Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrianus Antoninus Augustus Pius, Epeiph 21, at Tebtunis in the division of Polemon of the Arsinoite nome. Psenkebkis son of Marepsemis, about 35 years old, with no distinguishing mark, acknowledges to Thenmarsisouchos, daughter of another Marepsemis, about 37 years old, with no distinguishing mark, with her husband Pakebkis, son of Harpokration, about 45 years old, with no distinguishing mark, as guardian, that he has received from her, Thenmarsisouchos, from hand to hand, four hundred sixty silver drachmas owed to him, Psenkebkis, by her brother Pakebkis according to the terms of a contract of loan drawn up by the same record-office in the twelfth year of Antoninus Caesar the Lord, Pharmouthi 1; and he has turned this contract over to her for invalidation and he, Psenkebkis, will not take action concerning these or the interest of these, since this also has been repaid, or concerning any other matter whatsoever down to the present day. (2nd hand) I, Psenkebkis, son of Marepsemis, have received from Thenmarsisouchos the four hundred sixty drachmas plus interest which she owed him (sic!) and will not take action, as stated above. I, N.N., have written for him because he is illiterate. (3rd hand) Registered by the record office in Tebtunis.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Tebt., II.447; SB, v. 12, no. 11006 <note>On line 5 see BL 7, p. 224. J.G. Keenan, ZPE v. 9 (1972), p. 87-89.</note>
               </bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
