<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>contract of loan</title>
            <author>Aurelius Aphonis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1398</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1398</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.14.11386</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;14;11386</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;14;11386</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14442</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14442</idno>
            <idno type="filename">14442-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1353</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.555109-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>"Year four of Imperator Imperator Caesar Gaius Aurelius Valerius Diocletianus and year three of Imperator Caesar Marcus Aurelius Valerius Maximianus, Pii, Felices, Augusti, 21 Dystros = Tybi in Ptolemais Euergetis of the Arsinoite nome.;Aurelius Aphonis, son of Eisoukas and Amis, from the village of Philadelphia of the Herakleides meris, about 40 years of age, with a scar on the right shin, acknowledges to Aurelius Apeis, son of Demetrius, acting through his agent Theon, that he, the party of the of the first part, has received from Apeis  acting through Theon, from hand to hand, the capital sum of one silver talent; and the party of the first part shall of necessity return the aforesaid capital sum to Apeis through Theon on the 20th of the coming month Mecheir of the present 4th and 3rd year without delay. If the party of the first part fails to make return on the due date, he shall be subject to the interest legally fixed per mina per month; and on request Apeis, acting through Theon, shall have the right of execution against both the party of the first part, Aphonis and all his property as if in consequence of a court decision or even a prefectural judgment. When asked the formal question I [sic] so declared.;(2nd hd.) I, Aurelius Aphonis, son of Eisoukas, acknowledge that I have received the one silver talent, and I shall return it on the date fixed, as stated above. I, Aurelius Dioskoros, son of . . ., from the Linen Weavers' Quarter (of Arsinoe) wrote on his behalf, as he is illiterate."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Shelton JC, JJP 18, 160-2, 1974 -- SB XIV 11386 (and p. 479) -- BL IX, 273 (l. 6)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
