<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lease.</title>
            <author>Psoiphis, son of Paopis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">berkeley.apis.664</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(CU)664</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.14.11487</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;14;11487</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;14;11487</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14463</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14463</idno>
            <idno type="filename">14463-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Tebt.0441</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:20.378341-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Eleventh year of Imperator Caesar Domitianus Augustus Germanicus (month, day) in Tebtunis in the division of Polemon of the Arsinoite nome. Psoiphis, son of Paopis, about twenty-six years old, with a scar on the first finger of the right hand, acknowledges to Eutuchos, son of N.N., about twenty-five years old, with a scar on the little finger of the left hand, that he has leased to him, Eutuchos, for the coming twelfth year of Imperator Caesar Domitianus Augustus Germanicus from public plots which Psoiphis farms around Tebtunis two and one-half arouras, or however many there may be, which are in one parcel in the so-called "Forty-arouras plot", adjacent on the south to Marepsemis son of Psoiphis, for sowing of hay and cutting and drying, the provision of the seed and cutting of the hay being the responsibility of Eutuchos, and all the farm labor and transport charges being the responsibility of Psoiphis, and Psoiphis has received from Eutuchos the entire agreed-upon price in advance from hand to hand from the house, and Psoiphis will guarantee to Eutuchos the aforementioned two and one-half arouras, with every guarantee ... (Here the papyrus breaks off.)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Tebt., II.441; SB, v. 14, no. 11487 <note>T.C. Carp, ZPE 16 (1975), p. 55-58.</note>
               </bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
