<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Contract of Sale of Wheat in Advance</title>
            <author>Aurelius Aunes son of Kastor</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1751</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1751</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.14.12109</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;14;12109</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;14;12109</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14545</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14545</idno>
            <idno type="filename">14545-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 3036</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.282479-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>(Recto);;(1st hand) In the year after the consulship of our lords the eternal Augusti, Valens for the fifth time and Valentinianus the younger for the first time, Mecheir 19. Aurelius Aunes, son of Kastor and Alis, of the village of Karanis, acknowledges to Aurelius Melas, son of Pnas and Kyrillous, from the same village of Karanis, that he, the acknowledging party, Aunes, has received from him the price agreed upon for nine artabai of clean wheat, which he will necessarily deliver to Melas in the month Pauni of the sixth indiction in the village of Karanis by the four-choinix measure. And Melas shal have the right of execution on demand against the acknowledging party, Kastor &lt;read: Aunes&gt;, and against all his property as if by a court decision. In response to the formal question, he has so declared.;(2nd hand) I, Aurelius Aunes, son of Kastor, have received from Melas the price agreed upon the nine artabai of clean wheat, and I will deliver them at the appointed time as aforesaid. I, Aurelius Apollonios, son of Nemesinus, wrote for him because he is illiterate.;(1st hand) The contract was executed by me, Paulos.;;(Verso);Chirograph of Aunes, son of Kastor, from Karanis, for 9 artabai of wheat, to Melas, son of Pnas, from the same village of Karanis.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie LC, ZPE 24, 140-142, 1977 -- SB XIV 12109</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
