<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>agreement in duplicate</title>
            <author>Chairas</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1522</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1522</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.14.12171</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;14;12171</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;14;12171</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14554</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14554</idno>
            <idno type="filename">14554-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 176</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.646949-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>". . . that I, Chairas, have restored to Nilos, of the properties in the neighborhood of Kerkesoucha, in the topos of Sokration, two arouras; in the topos of the Embankment, one aroura out of three arouras of newly planted land and three-fourths aroura of an olive grove; and that I, Chairas, (have also restored to him) the remainder of my properties in the neighborhood of the village of Kerkesoucha, in all five arouras in two parcels - in the topos of Herakleides three (arouras) and two out of three arouras; and in the neighborhood of Karanis one aroura of a palm grove; and that I shall bring no charges against Nilos concerning the arouras that I have surrendered to him, nor shall I bring suit against him, nor will his agents bring charges against me in respect to the accusations and the submission of petitions which he made earlier, nor concerning any other matter at all in any way. Let this chirograph, written in duplicate, be valid wherever it is produced, as if it had been deposited in a public archive. And whenever he wishes, let him declare the arouras that belong to him to the bureau of property registration. The thirty-second year of Lucius Aelius Aurelius Commodus Antoninus Caesar, our lord, Tybi 3."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Youtie HC, ZPE 28, 259-261, 1978 -- SB XIV 12171</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
