<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>receipts</title>
            <author>unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1431</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1431</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.16.12332</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;16;12332</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;16;12332</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14587a 14587b 14587c 14587d 14587e 14587f 14587g 14587h</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14587 14587 14587 14587 14587 14587 14587 14587</idno>
            <idno type="filename">14587h-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 1434</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.120555-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>No. 1, recto, col. II, lines 1 - 9: "In the ? year of Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, Phaophi 24, [NN], a shepherd, son of Mysthes, whose mother was Aplonia, daughter of [NN], paid through [NN] the cheiristes hissyntaximon of Philadelphia for the same year in debased silver, eighth drachmas equal 8 drachmas; and on the ? of the month Neos Sebastou 8 drachmas equal 8 drachmas; and on the 24th of the month Neroneios Sebastos four drachmas equal 4 drachmas; and on the ? four drachmas equal 4 drachmas; and for the accounting on the 30th of Mecheir bu paid on 9th of Phamenoth eight drachmas equal 8 drachmas; and on the ? four dracmas equal 4 drachmas; and on the 29th of Pauni four drachmas equal 4 drachmas; and on the ? four drachmas equal 4 drachmas; . . .";No. 4, recto, col. I, 10-16: "In the ? year of Imperator Caesar Vespasianus Augustus , on the ?,  Herakles, son of Pasion, grandson of Herakles, with a mother Thaesis, daughter of Nepheros,;has paid through Apollonios, cheiristes, his syntaximon of Philadelphia for the same year in debased silver, eight drachmas and 2 chalkoi equal 8 drachmas and 2 chalkoi, and for swine tax   1 drachma and an obol; and on the ? of ? ? (= amount); and onthe 28th of Choiak four drachmas equal 4 drachmas; and on the ? of ? ? (= amount); and on the 30th of Phamenoth eight drachmas equal 8 drachmas; and on the ? of Pachon ? drachmas; and on the 14th of ? four drachmas equal 4 drachmas; and . . .";No. 5, recto, col. I, lines 17-20: "In the ? year of Imperator Caesar Vespasianus  Augustus, on the ? of Phaophi, Herakles, son of Pasion, grandson of Herakles, with a mother Thaesis, daughter of Nepheros, paid through Apollonios, cheiristes, his syntaximon of Philadelphia for the same year  in debased silver ? drachmas and two chalkoi, and his swine tax 1 drachma and an obol; and . . .";No. 2, recto, col. II, lines 21-30: "In the thirteenth year of Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, on 29 Phaophi, Herakles, son of Pasion, grandson of Herakles, ann unskilled laborer, whose mother was Thaesis, daughter of Nepheros, paid through Apollonios, cheiristes, his syntaximon of Philadelphia for the same year in debased silver, eight drachmas equal 8 drachmas; and on 24th of Neroneios Sebastos four drachmas and 2 chalkoi equal 4 drachmas 2 chalkoi, for pig tax 1 dracma 1 obol; and on the 17th of Tybi, four drachmas equal 4 drachmas; for the accounting on the 30th of Mecheir, but paid on the 9th of Phamenoth, eight drachmas equal 8 drachmas; and the 30th of Phamenoth four drachmas equal 4 drachmas, and . . .";No. 3, recto, col. III, lines 31-43: In the 2nd year of Servius Galba Imperator Caesar Augustus, on the ?th of ?, NN, an unskilled worker has paid through Apollonios, cheiristes, his syntaximon of Philadelphia of the same year. . . in the month of Neos Sebastos . . . and on the 21st of Choiak . . .; anon the ? of Mecheir . . . of Caesar Augustus . . .  the same . equal 8 drachmas, and for swine tax 1 drachma and 1 obol . . .";No. 6, verso, col. I, lines 44-47: (Hd. 2) "In the 14th year of Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, on the 4th of Tybi, Herakles, son of Pasion, paid his beer tax of Philadelphia in person through Petermouthis, one of the presbyters of the village, for the 13th year, four drachmas equal 4 drachmas; and on the21st of Phamenoth three drachmas and 4 obols equal 3 drachmas and 4 obols.";No. 7, verso, col. I, lines 48-53 (hd. 3): "In the 2nd year of Servius Galba Imperator Caesar Augustus, on the 29th of Choiak Herakles, son of Pasion, paid in person, through Petermuthis, his tax of Philadelphia on his account, four drachmas  equal 4 drachmas; and on Phamenoth 4 drachmas and 3 obols, in total 3 drachmas and 4 obols. . . ;No. 8, verso, col. I, line 53: ". . . of Vespasianus . . .";No. 9, verso, col. II, lines 54-58 (hd. 4): "In the 3rd year of Imperator Caesar Vespasianus Augustus, on the 1st of Tybi Herakles paid, through Pet[  , his beer tax (?) of Philadelphia for the same 3rd year, 4 drachmas equal 4 drachmas; and on the 20th of Mecheir three drachmas and 4 obols, equal 3 drachmas and 4 obols.";No. 10, verso, col. II, lines 59-64 (hd. 3): "In the year . . ."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Hanson AE, BASP 19, 47-60, 1982, Photo -- SB XVI 12332</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
