<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Census declaration by house owners</title>
            <author>Philippiatote; Ploution; Isidora</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.1245</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)1245</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.20.14303</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;20;14303</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;20;14303</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14858</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14858</idno>
            <idno type="filename">14858-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Corn. Inv. II 16</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.748115-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>col. I [fragmentary];col. ii;To Eudymos, strategos of the Arsinoite nome, Herakleidou meris, and to Hermaios, also called Dryton, royal secretatry of the same division, and to Herakleidou and Eubulos, secretaries of the metropolis and to Herakleides, chief, and his fellow collectors of money-taxes of the metropolis, and to Herodes, amphodarch of the quarter of the Hiera Pyle ("Sacred Gate"), and to Maron laographos of the same quarter:;From Philippiaina, daughter of Zoilos, son of Apollonios, enrolled in the house census on another memorandum in the qurater Moeris with her legal representative, her husband Ploution son of Komon, catoecus of the 6475. I ownin the same quarter Moeris a fourth part of a fourth share of a house and two-thirds of a second (house) in which I declare the following persons for the house to house census of the past second year of Hadrian Caesar our lord in the quarter of the Hiera Pyle in which also they were returned in the house to house census of the seventh year of the divine Traianus. They are, including those in the second house, Zois, daughter of Herakleides, son of Sokrates, aged 53: her son Sokrates son of Dioskoros who has passed his examination, aged 32, without distinguishing mark; a daughter Aphrodous, aged 13; another daughter Aphrodous, married to her brother Sokrates mentioned above, aged 28; and the elderly paternal aunt of the foregoing who lives with Sokrates, Isarous, aged 70. Therefore I give in (the declaration) to the appointed strategos and to all the others. Year 3 of Hadrianus Caesar our Lord, Phamenoth 22.;To Protarchos, strategos of the Arsinoite nome, Herakleidou meris, Hermaios royal secretary of the same division, Maron secretatry of the metropolis, Didas collector of Moeris, Ptolemaios amphodarch, Dios laographos, and Antoninos also called Hermaios , appointed official, from Ploution son of Komon son of Heron, his mother being Ptollarous, also called Ptolema, daughter of Apollonios, catoecus of the 6475, enrolled in Moeris quarter.;col. iii;...on another memorandum:;There belongs to me in the quarter of Apollonios Parembole a ... share of a house in which I declare the following residents for the house census of the past 16th year of Hadrianus Caesar our lord, in the quarter of ...;Sokrates son of Dioskoros, of the selected class, aged 46, without distinguishing mark, and his ... wife who is registered as his wife and sister born of the same mother, Aphrodous, aged 42, both registered for the 2nd year in the Hiera Pyle; and their children, Dioskroros enrolled in the birth register, aged 12; and Onesimos enrolled in the birth register, aged 10; and Asklas, enrolled in the birth register, aged 8; and a daughter Zoidous, aged 6; and Herais, aged 2. therefore I hand in the memorandum to the srategos appointed and to all the other officials. Year 17 of Hadrianus Caesar our lord, Epeiph 28.;To Maximos also called Nearchos, strategos, Herakleides, royal secretatry of the Arsinoite nome, Herakleides meris, and Sabinos and Antoninos, secretaries of the metropolis:;From Isidora daughter of Heron third, son of Heron, her mother being Isidora daughter of Asklepiades, declared and registered through another memorandum in the quarter of Apollonios Hierakeios with her legal quardian, Asklepiades, son of Asklepiades. There belongs to me in the quarter Moeris a fourth share of a house and courtyard in which I hereby declare as residents for the house to house census of the past 9th year of Antoninus Caesar our lord (in the quarter) in which also they were enrolled in the census of the 16th year of Hadrianus ... ;col. IV;[fragmentary]</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Westermann WL - Kraemer CJ, PCorn, 16, 1926 Bagnall RS, BASP 28, 18-27, 1991 -- SB XX 14303 -- BL IX, 227; BL XI, 229 (l. 23)</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
