<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lease of Land</title>
            <author>Didymos [the younger?], son of Lysimachos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2924</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2924</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14864</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14864</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;20;14315</idno>
            <idno type="filename">14864-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 669</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.93692-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>[Taorses, daughter of Eutychos, - - -, with, as guardian(?),  me(?)] Didymos [the younger(?)], son of Lysimachos, (who is) 38 years old, with a scar on his right shin, [has leased] to Lysas, son of Orsenouphis, a Persian of the epigone, (who is) 26 years old, with a scar on the first finger of his left hand, the 10 arourai of a [[catoecic]] allotment which belong to the four sons of Taorses, Lysimachos and Lysas and Eutychas and Galates, the four sons of Galates, and another 10 arourai, or however many there are, of me, Dionysos, in one parcel called Saeil, these arourai being police land, for 3 years from the coming 20th year: for 1st and 3rd year for the sowing of wheat at a rent - together with 20 artabai of wheat as seed - for the whole area yearly being 260 artabai (as measured) by the four-choinix measure of the granary of Eirenion; for the 2nd year for the sowing of grass for the grazing of sheep, at a rent of 160 drachmai. The cash payment (is due) in Mecheir and Phamenoth, while the rent in kind (is payable) in the month of Pauni at the threshing floor. The transport charges and  the transport of sacks and sheaves are the responsability of [Taorses(?)], and Didymos [- - -] each year 3 artabai of wheat(?) and to Lysas the elder son 2 artabai of wheat.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Jenkins FW, BASP 29, 36-40, 1992, Pl. 4 -- SB XX 14315 -- Several corrections made. To be republished. (PH)</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
