<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Account</title>
            <author>Unknown</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3148</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3148</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14886</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14886</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;20;14525</idno>
            <idno type="filename">14886-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 880</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:27.497572-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Column I;"Account of the sheep of Lucius for year 2 of Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, in Pachon (26 April-25 May 56):;Phepheros the shepherd has 53 female sheep, 27 males, 22 lambs.;Total: 80 sheep in all, 22 lambs.;Of these, there perished in Pachon (26 April - 25 May 56) through the same shepherd 2 females,;In Pauni (26 May - 44 June 56) 1 female,;In Mesore (25 July - 23 August 56) 1 male, 2 lambs. Total, 3 females, 1 male and 2 lambs. Total, 6. Remainder, 50 females, 26 males, 20 lambs. Total, 96.;Account of receipts from Pachon to Mesore (26 April -23 August 56) of year 2 of Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator:;In Pachon, for the price of 3 skins, through Sakolaos the Jew 12 dr.;... likewise to Isak the Jew, thorugh Pouoris, son of Pabos, 8 dr.;[three lines badly damaged];... for the price of 1 female and 3 males 50 dr.;... for the price of 1 female and 2 males 40 dr.;... for the price 1 female and 1 male 40 dr.;... through (?) Pnepheros; total 150 dr.;Column II;Expenditures of these items, in Pachon (26 April-25 May 56):;To Theon the farmer, for the price of 2 arourae of hay 64 dr.;For cutting the aforesaid 2 arourae 12 dr.;To Pnepheros the shepherd, wages for 4 months, at 16 dr. per month 64 dr.;For the price of 2 keramia of wine 6 dr.;For bath tax, hemiartabion 3 dr.;For beer tax for the same shepherd 10 dr.;Total, 159 dr., and for expenses, 9 dr. - on the estate of Lucius.;Year 3, likewise, account of the sheep of Lucius, through the same shepherd Pnepheros:;In the month of Sebastos (29 August - 27 September 56), he had 50 females, 26 males, 20 lambs.;Total, 76 sheeps, 20 lambs.;Of these there perished through the same shepherd in the same month of Sebastos 2 females, 1 lamb. Total lost, 2 females, 1 lamb.;In Phaophi and Hathyr (28 September - 26 November 56), 3 lambs. Total, 3 lambs . . .;In Hathyr (28 October - 26 November 56), in the Forty-Arourae plot through Theon (?) and through the same Pnepheros the shepherd, to Isak the Jew, for sale, 3 males.;Column III;In Tybi (27 December 56 - 25 January 57), through Apollos, son of Sosippos, and Pnepheros the same shepherd to the same Isak the Jew, likewise for sale, the amount (?) of 5 females and 1 lambskin.;Total sold, 8 sheep and 1 skin.;And in the 100-arourae plot, through Pnepheros the shepherd and Sambas, Arab, likewise for sale to Isak the Jew, 4 males.;Total, 7 females, 7 males, 5 lambs;Remainder, 43 females, 19 males, 15 lambs, 77 in all.;Account of receipts of the same third year:;In the month of Sebastos, through Isak the Jew and through Pnepheros the shepherd, for the price of wool (?) 12 dr.;And to Isak the Jew throug the same shepherd ... 3 dr.;In Phaophi to Isak the Jew for one lambskin 2 dr.;In Hathyr likewise to the same Isak the Jew for the price of 3 skins 7 dr.;In Tybi through ... and the same shepherd ...;Column IV;To Isak for sale, the same amount (?) of 5 female sheep and 1 lambskin.;Im Mecheir likewise, in the 100-arourae plot, through [Sambas or Pouoris (?)], Arab, 4 males. Total, for receipts, 186 dr. of silver;And from the price of wool in the month of Sebastos ...;To Pouoris the merchant for 200 females, ... , ... males ...;[The text becomes fragmentary]</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Hanson AE, Life in a Multi-Cultural Society, 140-144, 1988 -- SB XX 14525 -- l.31 en Loukio (not en Loukiou) (TC)</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
