<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Census return</title>
            <author>Paesis, son of Nebteichis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3971</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3971</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.20.14667</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;20;14667</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;20;14667</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">14899</idno>
            <idno type="TM">14899</idno>
            <idno type="filename">14899-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 158</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.149265-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>"From Paesis son of Nebteichis whose mother is Pachomis, from Alabanthis. In accordance with the instructions given by the ex-prefect Furius Victorinus, I declare for the house-by-house census of year 23 of our lord Antoninus Caesar: myself,;Paesis, son of Nebteichis, over-age 72 years; Horus my son whose mother is Athenais alias Kinna daughter of Besis, under-age in Year 23, 8 years; Women: Athenais alias Kinna, my wife 57 years; Tereus, my daughter, whose mother is the same; Athenais 40 years.;And there are in the possession of my wife Athenais daughter of Besis son of Harpechis shares in landed property in Alabanthis, and in other places other shares inherited from her father in other landed property and appurtenances. And I swear by the Fortuna of Imperator Caesar Titus Aurelius Hadrianus Antoninus Augustus Pius and God Maximus" Osirantinoos that no Alexandrian  not registered or foreign or ... otherwise I will be gyilty upon the oath. Year 24  Imperator Caesar Titus Aurelius Hadrianus Antoninus Augustus Pius, Mecheir ...</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Whitehorne J, Symbolae Osloenses 65, 140-1, 1990 -- SB XX 14667</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
