<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Petition to the Dioiketes</title>
            <author>Peteminis (alias Ptolemaios)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3036</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3036</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">8772</idno>
            <idno type="TM">8772</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.mich;18;778</idno>
            <idno type="filename">8772-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 6948</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:30.711908-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>To Athenodoros the dioiketes, from Peteminis from Mouchis of the division of Polemon. I am wronged by Pythion, the oikonomos of the same division. When Onnophris undertook the beer tax of Mouchis for the 13th year, [having . . .]ed in Phaophi . . ., Pythion awarded the contract for Mouchis to Petesouchos, who then held the beer concession for Aphroditopolis and Eleusis at the rate of 42 talents 2000 drachmai, 20 talents . . . to manage the beer shop of Mouchis, and at the same time(?) [according to the] decree, . . . this same Petesouchos . . . [- - -] . . . of Aphroditopolis and Eleusis from the months of Phaophi until Tybi . . . [- - -] . . . When he came to Mouchis, having taken care that . . . [- - -] . . . that the scribe owed, he, using as his excuse, . . . and thus he sent for me . . . and exacted from me 4000 drachmai, in addition to what I gave him as surety, two women's storage chests and one man's storage chest, and . . . which are worth 5 talents 2300 drachmai. When I went to the . . ., . . . I therefore ask you, if you approve, (since Pythion has withdrawn, although I filed a second petition, no justice transpired?), first and foremost, send this petition to the chrematistai, but if not, write to Philon, chief of police, to write an order for me to the police in every village (in order that he be found somewhere) to bring him before you. When this happens, I shall have obtained justice.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Loftus A - Schwendner G, PMich XVIII, 778, 1996, Pl. XV</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
