<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Submission of a List of Liturgists</title>
            <author>Petaus, son of Petaus, komogrammateus of Ptolemais Hormou</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2980</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2980</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">8818</idno>
            <idno type="TM">8818</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.petaus;;47</idno>
            <idno type="filename">8818-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 6875</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:29.755258-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>To Apollonios, strategos of the Herakleides division of the Arsinoite nome, from Petaus, village secretary of Ptolemais Horomou [and other] villages. To be in charge of necessities for the presence of the most illustrious prefect Longaeus [Rufus], so that there is plenty for those who want to [buy] (necessities), as it was ordered, I submit the [following] (names of) people who are wealthy enough and appropriate. [As follows]:;For [bread]:;Dioskoros, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Dioskoros, [who has] property (worth) 1000 drachmai;Ischyrion, son of Ammonios and Herakleia, grandson of Heuremon, similarly: 900 drachmai;Maron, son of Mareinos, grandson of Maron, similarly: 1000 drachmai;Deios, son of Neseus, grandson of Ischyrion, similarly: 900 drachmai;For the wine-merchants:;Pantonymos, son of Ischyrion, grandson of Pantonymos, similarly: 1000 drachmai;Aphrodisios, son of Aphrodisios, grandson of Aphrodisios, [similarly]: 800 [drachmai];Ischyrion, son of Heraklas, grandson of Ischyrion, similarly: 1000 drachmai;And for oil:;Euangelos, son of Heron, grandson of Euangelos, similarly: . . . drachmai;Apynchis, son of Peteeus, grandson of Ischyrion: . . . drachmai;Zosimos or however he is styled, landowner in . . ., [similarly: . . . drachmai];And for meat(?):;[Ischyrion], son of Neseus, grandson of Orsenouphis, [similarly: . . . drachmai];[Ischyrion], son of Orsenouphis, grandson of Philammon, similarly: [. . . drachmai];And for barley:;[Ischyrion], son of Athas, grandson of Maron, similarly: 600 drachmai;[Pnepheros], son of Neseus and Demos, [similarly: . . . drachmai];[Maron], son of Heron, grandson of Maron, similarly: [. . . drachmai];Sokras, son of Petepnoutis, similarly: 500 drachmai;Pamounis, son of Kennas, similarly: 500 drachmai;Ptollis, son of Pathynis, grandson of Ptollis, similarly: 600 drachmai;Paaus, son of Paaus and Thasos, grandson of Theabennis, similarly: 500 drachmai;Paaus, son of Ptollas and Tamarres, grandson of P[. . .], similarly: 600 drachmai;And for wood:;Ischyrion, son of Hierakion, grandson of Phanias, similarly: 600 drachmai;Peebaus, son of Hatres, grandson of Onnophris, similarly: 500 drachmai;And for vegetables and the other necessities:;Akiaris, son of Syros, similarly: 600 drachmai;Karos, son of Papontos, similarly: 500 drachmai;Siasis also called Silbas, similarly: 500 drachmai;Aphrodas, son of Heraklas, similarly: 600 drachmai;Onnophris, son of Akous, similarly: 500 drachmai;Sarapion, son of Ischyrion, also called Pithiaithis, similarly: 600 drachmai;And for registering those (who are) in the praetorium:;Sarapion, son of Ischyrion, similarly: 600 drachmai;Harpalos, son of Harphaesion, similarly: 500 drachmai;Pnepheros, son of Theon, similarly: 600 drachmai;And for fishing boats:;Ischeis, son of Ischeis, similarly: 500 drachmai;Phaseis, son of Neseus, similarly: 600 drachmai;Hatres, son of Neseus, similarly: 700 drachmai;Sarapion, son of Petenouphis, similarly: 600 drachmai;Herakles, son of Paaipis, similarly: 500 drachmai.;;(2nd hand) I, Petaus, have submitted (this).;;(1st hand) [Year] 25 of Marcus Aurelius Commodus [Antoninus] Augustus, Tybi 30.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Hagedorn U - Hagedorn D - Youtie LC - Youtie HC, PPetaus, 47, 1969</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
