<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Application for the Purchase of Unproductive Land</title>
            <author>Alexandros, son of Sarapion</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.2989</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)2989</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">8844</idno>
            <idno type="TM">8844</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.petaus;;23</idno>
            <idno type="filename">8844-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Mich.inv. 6882</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.588862-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>I, Gemellus, [attendant, have transmitted it] on Phamenoth [. .].;;(2nd hand) To Apollonios, strategos of the division of Herakleides of the Arsinoite nome, from Alexandros, son of Sarapion, grandson of Eirenaios, a minor, through his caretaker Herakleides, son of Kallistratos, . . . I wish to buy, for the planting of vegetables to cut,  near the village of Pharbaitha,1 . . aroura of dry, unproductive land, in which (there are) . . . grape-vines, according to the proceedings of the allocation for sale - (a piece of land) of which the boundaries are: on the south, north, and west, private lands; on the east, dry land -, the fixed price being &lt;of . . . drachmai for each aroura&gt;, with the supplementary fees of these drachmai; on the condition that, if this land is assigned to me, I will pay this price and the supplementary fees into the public bank. The possession and title of this (land) will for ever remain irrevocable for me, for my descendants and for my successors, and I will receive the guarantee that it is free from all public taxes and all other dues up to the time of the assignment. And for cultivating it and for regaining it for cultivation, I will have immunity for three years, after which I will pay the taxes which are due in similar cases, if you decide to assign it to me.;I, Alexandros, a minor, though his caretaker, the aforesaid Herakleides, have submitted (this).;Year 2[* of Marcus] Aurelius Commodus Antoninus [Augustus] Pius, Phamenoth 15.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Hagedorn U - Hagedorn D - Youtie LC - Youtie HC, PPetaus, 23, 1969 -- BL VII, 158 (l. 24)</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
