<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lease [269-277 AD]</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p313</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1237</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.10.280</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;10;280</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;10;280</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">22273</idno>
            <idno type="TM">22273</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 513</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>End of a lease of or labor contract for a vineyard; the financial arrangements are not completely clear, especially the nature of the 80 drachmas of lines 3-4 and the amount of the advance loan</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers: about half of the front contains writing; the back is blank; the papyrus is broken on the top and left and shows holes, tears, and wrinkles</note>
                     <note type="general">23 lines of writing by a ligatured inclined hand, which shows some features reminiscent of the chancery</note>
                     <note type="general">There are 7 panels of writing and it is likely that 3 more are missing</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus fragment ; 19 x 25 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0269" notAfter="0277">269 CE – 277 CE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from natives of Oxyrhynchos through Messrs. Peterson and Amundsen in 1927-1928; no. 71 in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Lease of vineyard</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>. . . whatever is necessary . . . it shall be the responsibility of the lessees to irrigate . . . from the same machines for . . . (3) . . . eighty drachmas, which chous the lessees will bring in at their own expense for the . . . (4) the same eighty drachmas, or they will pay eighty drachmas to the lessor . . . (5) . . . of those together with their maintenance according to the things [purchased? which were] agreed upon to be given to the lessees . . .(6) . . . and the lessees agree they have from the lessor one thousand two hundred drachmas on account and the rest (7) of which they will receive one hundred drachmas in Thoth, two hundred drachmas in Mecheir and Phamenoth and from Pharmouthi until (8) Mesore including Mesore (?) drachmas per month; . . . from the advance loan for (our) service of the irrigating of the farm and for the valuation of the pairs of oxen they shall deliver (9) from the produce of the present year six hundred drachmas, from the produce of the coming year six hundred drachmas, (10) . . . The lessees shall carry out the vintage beginning from the 15th of Mesore so that they may complete (11) the other work for the vines in due season, in exemplary fashion, being negligent in nothing and (12) the lessees providing everything necessary for themselves, and the constant weeding and the planting of as many shoots as are necessary (13) in the parts (of the garden) needing it, and let them plant however many as they may wish at their own expense (as long as) satisfactorily carried out and they shall give to the lessor (14) the wine from unfermented, new and unadulterated [vintage] at the vat, for which the lessor will furnish empty wine jars measuring nine cotylas (15) and when they are filled with wine they (the lessees) shall place them [in the sunning area] and they shall move and guard them until they are locked up. And at the end of the period they shall deliver (16) the vineland free of dirt of every kind and filth from post to post and the plants living and flourishing and the machines (17) in working order except for wear and tear and the doors and keys attached or shall forfeit the proper value of whatever is not returned, (18) or for any plant which withers through carelessness twice the amount of damage. And it shall not be in the power of the lessees to give up the lease before the end of the period (19) but they shall also similarly return all the embankments watertight in the last year on the 30th day of Phaophi. (20) He (the lessor) shall have the right of execution against them (the lessees), who are mutual sureties for the payment, and singly, and against whichever of them he chooses, and against all that they have acquired in consequence of their service, (21) and against their sureties, and against all their property as one does when bringing a dike. The lease is normative. Year 2 of Emperor Caesar Marcus Aurelius [. . . Pius Felix Augustus . . .] (2 H.) I [. . .] son of [. . .]nios, steward for the aformentioned Heraklas have leased and have given of four thousand [as written above.]
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. X 280 <note>Plate 37 in P.Col. X; cf. P.Col. X 255</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:10:280</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>