<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sworn Declaration to Agents from the Centurion Cattius Catullus:  P.Col. inv. 90</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p516</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa3692</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.thomas.5.</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">44491</idno>
            <idno type="TM">44491</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col. inv. 90</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Oath dated sixth year of Claudius, in which the person taking the oath agrees to do something in fifteen days from a given date (lost).  The names Anoubion, Nemesion and Diodoros are mentioned</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; on the verso, traces of a washed out text</note>
                     <note type="general">18 lines: broken on both sides</note>
                     <note type="general">At least three hands: the main hand is a clear, upright script; bilinear with most letters formed separately although some ligatures are used.  The other hands are small, closely written cursives</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus fragment;  13.1 x 28 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0046">24 July 46 AD</origDate>
                     <origPlace>From Philadelphia</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from M. Nahman through H.I. Bell, in 1924; no. II.158 in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(m. 1) Psonsneus, about 38 years, medium height, honey-complexioned, long-faced straight-nosed, with a scar beneath the right knee. (m. 2) Psonsneus, son of Praxias, of those from Philadelphia of the Herakleides division of the Arsinoite nome, to agents from Cattius Catullus, centurion. I swear by Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator that I willingly have become surety for Praxias, son of Diodorus, my father, and Thaesis, daughter of Anoubion, my mother, whom I shall also present to Nemesion, praktor of the same village in the public logisterion of Herakleides (division) in the twenty-five days from the present day.  If I do not present them, I shall pay their debts with interest to the public (bank).  To me swearing honestly, may it be well, but to me forswearing, the opposite.  I, Nikanor, son of Nikanor, wrote for him when asked because he says he does not know letters.  Year 6 of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, Epeiph thirtieth.  (m. 3) Dositheos, I have signed. Year 6 of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, Epeiph thirtieth.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Thomas 5</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Thomas:5:</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>