<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Contract [between 245 and 244 BC]</title>
            <author>Asklepiades, 6 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 305</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p84</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1396</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.4.85</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;4;85</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;4;85</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">1798</idno>
            <idno type="TM">1798</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 228 recto</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Agreement of sale, which is supplementary to an original lease: Asklepiades, a hundred aroura holder of the troops of Antiochos who had leased his holding to some farmers, agrees to share the crops on the basis that two-thirds go to him and one-third to the lessees</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written across the fibers in a proficient, regular hand; on the back P.Col. IV 120</note>
                     <note type="general">The date in the editio princeps (244-243 BC) was corrected in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI</note>
                     <note type="general">2/5 of the original is lost at the right; a fake margin was created by pasting a strip on the right edge</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus ; 21.6 x 7.6 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="-0245" notAfter="-0244">245 BCE – 244 BCE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from M. Nahman and New York dealer J. Brummer, through H.I. Bell, November 1925; no. 25 (original no. 46) in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Names of farmers, -- Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, sec.IX</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>In the fourth year of the reign of King Ptolemy, son of Ptolemy, and Arisinoe, brother-sister gods, when Archelaos, son of Damas, was priest of Alexander and of the brother-sister gods, and Arsinoe, daughter of Polemokrates, was basket bearer of Arsinoe Philadelphos, in the month [ - - - - - - Agreement of Asklepiades], son of Magnes, hundred aroura holder of the troop of Antiochos, with the farmers. On these conditions [Asklepiades,son of- has agreed to sell] all the crops in the allotment to Pokas, son of Pames, and Petobastis, (son of -----, and - - - - - - ) and Pasis, son of Petos, and Gampis, all farmers from Herakleopolis, on condition that [they do all the farm work at the proper times] as fixed in [the contract] of lease of the allotment. When the crops have been freed (of all the obligations due to the Basilikon], at the same time Asklepiades is to take two thirds of the crop and the farmers are to receive one third. [If the farmers do not hand over the two thirds, they are to pay as penalty] one and a half times (the value of the two thirds agreed upon). Regarding all other matters let the arrangements between them be, each toward the other, as the contract [of lease provides].
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. IV 85 P.Col.Zen. II 85 <note>Correction to line 1 by H. Harrauer, CdE 58 (1983) 201</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:4:85</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>