<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Loan 372 AD</title>
            <author>Aurelia Tetoueis, daughter of Hatres and Tapaeis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p218</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1305</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.7.183</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;7;183</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;7;183</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10538</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10538</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 181 (28)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Loan of money to be repaid with wheat, barley, and vegetable seed; the borrower is Aurelia Tetoueis and the lender a legionary soldier</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; on the back there is the docket; a space of 6 cm. is left blank underneath the text</note>
                     <note type="general">20 lines of writing, plus 1 line on the back; the hand is fast and cursive; the ink on the back is almost completely faded</note>
                     <note type="general">Part of an archive of documents concerning Aurelia Tetoueis: P.Oslo II 38; P.Mert. I 37; P.NYU 24; P.Col. VII 182, 184, and perhaps 187</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus ; 13.2 x 26.9 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0372">372 CE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from Mr. Blanchard through H.I. Bell in 1924; no. 28 in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Flavius Venaphrios, -- soldier</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>	In the consulate of Domitius Modestus the illustrious Praetorian Prefect, and Flavius Arinthaeus, the illustrious Count and Master of the Infantry Force, Hathyr 27. Aurelia Tetoueis daughter of Hatres and Tapaeis from the village of Karanis, acknowledges to Flavius Venaphrios, soldier of the Legio I Maximiana, which is stationed at Oxyrhyncha, that she, Tetoueis, the acknowledging party, has received the price agreed upon for six artabas of clean wheat and six artabas of clean barley and three artabas of clean vegetable seed, which she will necessarily repay to Venaphrios, by the four-choinix measure, in the month of Pauni of the second indiction, at the city, and the vegetables by the twelve-mation measure, and upon default, Venaphrios is to have the right of execution both from Tetoueis, the acknowledging party, and from all her property as though by legal decision, and when the formal question was put to her, she acknowledged (the above). 

Back 
	Tetoueis, daughter of Hatres, of Karanis: note of hand [for 6 artabas of wheat and 6 artabas of barley] and 3 artabas of vegetables. 
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. VII 183 <note>Plate, P.Col. VII, Microfiche 2; published by Day and Porges, AJP 81 (1960) 157-75, SB VI 9603</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:7:183</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>