<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Receipts [308-310 AD]</title>
            <author>Aurelius Valas, tesserarius</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p179</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1266</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.7.141</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;7;141</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;7;141</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10494</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10494</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 60</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Receipts for chaff, wheat, fodder and other items given to Isidoros and members of his family; in col. IV a receipt for cast bronze</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers with 104 lines; the back is blank</note>
                     <note type="general">The color of the pieces varies from light to dark brown</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>4papyrus pieces from a roll ; 166 x 26.5 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0308" notAfter="0310">308 CE – 310 CE</origDate>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Herodianos, apaitetes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Sarapion, apaitetes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Seuthes, apaitetes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Eudaimon, apaitetes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Isidoros, quadrarius</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Anouphis, tesserarius</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Kopres, quadrarius</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Kopres, apaitetes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Arpalos, apaitetes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Atres, apaitetes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Pleein, sitologos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Ision, sitologos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Horos, sitologos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Paona, sitologos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Sotas, apaitetes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Serenos, apaitetes</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from M. Nahman through H.I. Bell in 1924; no. 11 in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Aurelius Isidoros, -- son of Ptolemaios</term>
               <term>Palemon, -- son of Ptolemaios</term>
               <term>Taesis, -- daugther of Kopres</term>
               <term>Herois, -- daughter of Chairemon</term>
               <term>Tax receipts</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
  <facsimile>
    <surfaceGrp n="A">
      <surface type="recto">
        <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/c0/columbia.apis.p179a.f.0.600"/>
        <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/a2/columbia.apis.p179.f.0-0.600"/>
        <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/07/columbia.apis.p179.f.0-1.600"/>
        <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/dc/columbia.apis.p179.f.1-1.600"/>
      </surface>
    </surfaceGrp>
    <surfaceGrp n="B">
      <surface type="recto">
        <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/f7/columbia.apis.p179b.f.0.600"/>
        <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/80/columbia.apis.p179.f.0-2.600"/>
        <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/1b/columbia.apis.p179.f.0-3.600"/>
        <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/6a/columbia.apis.p179.f.1-2.600"/>
        <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/07/columbia.apis.p179.f.1-3.600"/>
      </surface>
    </surfaceGrp>
    <surfaceGrp n="C">
      <surface type="recto">
        <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/75/columbia.apis.p179c.f.0.600"/>
        <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/c4/columbia.apis.p179.f.0-4.600"/>
        <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/da/columbia.apis.p179.f.0-5.600"/>
        <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/4e/columbia.apis.p179.f.1-4.600"/>
        <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/84/columbia.apis.p179.f.1-5.600"/>
      </surface>
    </surfaceGrp>
    <surfaceGrp n="D">
      <surface type="recto">
        <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/99/columbia.apis.p179d.f.0.600"/>
        <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/8b/columbia.apis.p179.f.0-6.600"/>
        <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/fa/columbia.apis.p179.f.0-7.600"/>
        <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/e3/columbia.apis.p179.f.1-6.600"/>
        <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/36/columbia.apis.p179.f.1-7.600"/>
      </surface>
    </surfaceGrp>
  </facsimile>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>    Column I

    Aurelius Isidoros son of Ptolemaios, through Ision, for produce of the 16th and 4th year ... and in the name of Palemon ... likewise art. 13 1/4. Epeiph 24, likewise, art. 12.
    
    Column II
    
    (M2) Isidoros gave for the price of fodder 12 tal. Likewise the same man for the price of fodder, 12 tal.
    
    Column III
    
    [1st two receipts not translated]
    (M4) Isidoros son of Ptolemaios paid in my presence five thousand five hundred drachmas. The same man through Heron, dr. 2800. Palemon son of Ptolemaios, dr. 2000.
    (M5) And on the 14th of Pharmouthi the same Isidoros in the name of Palemon son of Ptolemaios, dr. two thousand nine hundred, that is, dr. 2900.
    
    Column IV
    
    (M6) Aurelius Valas, tesserarius, to Aurelius Isidoros son of Ptolemaios and his brothers, greeting. I have received from you, in accordance with the divine command, for the village of Karanis and the horiodiktia of Karanis, thirteen pounds, six and a half ounces of poured copper material not given by you for the cleansing at the time when it was ordered, and in the name of Palemon son of Ptolemaios, likewise of poured copper material, one pound six ounces, and in the name of Taesis daughter of Kopres, ten ounces of poured copper; altogether for the total receipt, fifteen pounds, ten and a half ounces, that is, 15 lbs., 10 1/2 oz. I, Aurelius Isidoros, quadrarius, wrote this. Year 17 and 5, Tybi 6.
    (M7) And on Pachon 18 I received from you in full the price of green fodder according to your assessed share of that furnished for the feeding of army horses.
    
    Column V
    
    (M8) Aurelii Herodianus and Sarapion and Antinoos, apaitetai of chaff for the village of Karanis and its horiodiktia, to Aurelius Isidoros son of Ptolemaios, greeting. You have delivered to the harbor of Leukogion for produce of the 17th and 5th year, ten sarganai of chaff, that is, 10 sarg., up to Mesore 15.
    On the 19th, likewise, one sargane, that is, 1 sarg. And on the 7th day before the Calends of September, from the receipt given by Souchammon, four sarganai, that is, 4 sarg.
    
    Column VI
    
    (M9) Aurelii Seuthes and Eudaimon, apaitetai of the delegatio of the 17th and 5th year for the horiodiktia of Karanis, to Aurelius Isidoros and his brothers, greeting. We have received from you for the delegatio of the same year two talents and a thousand, four hundred drachmas, that is, 2 tal. 1400 dr. 17th and 5th year, Mesore 29.
    And for the primipilum for the 18th and 6th years, dr. 1100, and through Heron another dr. -,100.
    (M 10) Aurelius Anouphis, tesserarius, and Kopres, quadrarius, of the village of Karanis and of the horiodiktia of Karanis, to Aurelius Isidoros son of Ptolemaios, greeting. We have received from you in the name of Palemon toward the quarterly account, of silver, one talent and four thousand one hundred fifty drachmas, that is I tal. 4150 dr. l8th and 16th year, Phaophi 6.
    
    Column VII
   
    (M 11) Aurelius Heron son of Heron and Kapeeis son of Apollonios through me, Heron, to Aurelius Isidoros son of Ptolemaios and [his] brothers, greeting. You have delivered to the harbor nineteen sarganai of chaff for the produce of the 14th year. I, Aurelius Ision, wrote for them because they are illiterate. Thoth 7. Year 18 [and] 6.
    (M 12) Aurelii Heron, son of Heron, and Kapeeis, through me, Ptollas son of Onomastos, to Aurelius Isidoros and his brothers, greeting. He has paid to us for the price of chaff for the 3rd part, one talent and three thousand nine hundred drachmas, that is, I tal., 3900 dr. I, Ision, wrote for them because they are illiterate. Year 18 and 6, Thoth 7. And likewise through Heron, three thousand five hundred drachmas, dr. 3500.
    And likewise the same men paid for the price of meat of the same 3rd part through Doulos and Aphys, one talent and four thousand six hundred drachmas, that is, 1 tal. 4600 dr.
    
    Column VIII
    
    (M 13) Aurelii [Kopres] and Harpalos and Hatres and their partners, all apaitetai of chaff of the village of Karanis for the new assessment, to Aurelius Isidoros son of Ptolemaios, greeting. We have received from you for the same assessment in the name of Herois daughter of Chairemon ... and for the same name, dr. 5800. I, Kopres, have signed. (M 14) I, Hatres, have signed. Year 18 and 16, Phaophi 9.
    
    Column IX
    
    (M 15) Aurelii Pleein and Ision and K... and Horos and H.. and Paona, all sitologoi of the village of Karanis and the horiodiktia for produce of the 16th and 4th year: there was  measured to us in the granary in the same village and horiodiktia with the level modius  measure in the name of Isidoros son of Ptolemaios, seventy artabas, a half, a fourth, of wheat with . . . art. 70, 1/2, 1/4. I, Ision, wrote for them because they are illiterate. In the consulate of our masters Valerius Licinianus Licinius Augustus and Flavius Valerius Constantinus the son of the Augusti.
    There was measured to us likewise for the new assessment, eighteen artabas, a half, art. 18 1/2. Choiak 28 .
    Aurelii Kopres and Sotas, both apaitetai of the horiodiktia of Karanis, to Aurelius Isidoros son of Ptolemaios, greeting. We have received from you for the delegatio of the 18th and 6th and 4th and 2nd year three thousand one hundred drachmas, that is, dr. 3100. For the primipilum for the 19th and 7th and 5th and 3rd year, nine hundred drachmas, dr. 900. In the consulate of Statius Andronicus and Pompeius Probus, the most illustrious prefects, Phaophi 2l.
    And likewise through Serenos and Sarapion the apaitetai of the village of Karanis for the delegatio of the same year, in the name of Palemon for the delegatio and the primipilum for the 19th and 7th and 5th and 3rd year, two thousand seven hundred drachmas, that is, dr. 2700. I, Ision, wrote for them because they are illiterate.
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. VII 141 <note>Related texts: P.Cair.Isid. 47-50; translation of lines 27-28 in P.Oxy. XLVIII p. xvii, reference to P.Oxy. XXXIII 2673.22; plate, P.Col. VII, Microfiche 1</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:7:141</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>