<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letters [May 16, 243 BC]</title>
            <author>Eukles, 1 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 329</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p87</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1399</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.4.88</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;4;88</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;4;88</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">1801</idno>
            <idno type="TM">1801</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 214 recto</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Drafts of 3 letters written by Eukles: the first is about the price of pottery and sale of wine; the second was addressed to Anosis, the village scribe of Philadelphia, angrily charging him that he had been careless and dishonest so that the state had incurred some losses: in the future his accounts were going to be checked; the third letter is addressed to Dionysios about the same accounts of Anosis</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">35 lines written along the fibers in a small, neat hand, perhaps Eukles' himself; there are corrections and words written over the line</note>
                     <note type="general">Written on the other side of P.Col. IV 87 and at a later time</note>
                     <note type="general">There are two paragraphoi (and not 1 as in the edition): one separates the second from the third letter and one at the end; the first letter is separated by a large space and probably by another paragraphos which is not visible any more</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus fragment, broken at top ; 12 x 30 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="-0243">243 BCE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from M. Nahman and New York dealer J. Brummer, through H.I. Bell, November 1925; no. 11 (original no. 9) in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Anosis, -- 1 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 287</term>
               <term>Amosis, -- priest, Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 285</term>
               <term>Apollonios, -- secretary, 14 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 293</term>
               <term>Lykophron, -- fficial, 2 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 362</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab> 
 - - - - - - and in respect to the price of the pottery - - - - - - -
 and the sale which he made of the native wine Amosis the priest (has written) so that you may be informed. Good-by. Year 4, Phamenoth 26.

 [7-29] Eukles to Anosis greeting. I learn that you have deposited in the record office the accounting of the pottery without bringing into it even the breakage which has occurred through the donkey drivers, and, in the matter of the pay still due in the case of the potters, that you have entered 8 drachmas per hundred pots instead of the 6 drachmas pay which had been given them; and that, too, although I am unable to obtain from them even what they agree (to furnish); and that, up to the present, you have not handed in to the record office the accounting of the hogs ready for slaughter; and that, on the whole, you have begun to act like a scoundrel - - - - - - -- If therefore, any of these charges are true you do not appear to be to blame, but I (appear so) to myself. Nevertheless I have written regarding these matters to Lykophron and to Apollonios that, if they discover any discrepancies from the accounts handed in by you, they write to me immediately in order that I, being present in person, may have my case judged in relation to you. For it is right that you, who are entering excess charges and are not reporting the totals correctly throughout the accounts, should pay the discrepancies, not I. For the future I will try, although I have often been fooled by you, to change my attitude and plan better. Good-bye.

[30-36] To Dionysios. You will do me a favor by compelling Anosis also to deposit the same accounts, all of them, which Apollonios, my secretary, is handing in so that if any differences are recorded, our case in relation to him may be decided immediately.
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. IV 88 P.Col.Zen. II 88 <note>Photo in P.Col. IV facing p. 100; corrections by Peremans-Van 't Dack, and Youtie, BL III p. 45; Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p.128</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:4:88</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>