<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Memorandum and notes [ca 325-350 AD]</title>
            <author>Horion, advocate</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p209</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1296</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.7.174</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;7;174</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;7;174</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10528</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10528</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 181 (27)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Memorandum and notes written by (or for ) an advocate for a trial before a high court: Sambathion and Heras are unjustly taxed for land that belongs to Alexandros and Heraklas; the land was farmed by some villagers who became fugitives after the land became dry</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers in two cols.; on the back a docket with 4 lines</note>
                     <note type="general">Main text, written first: 19 lines of writing in right col. by a large hand, with crucial names and phrases overlined</note>
                     <note type="general">In the left margin notes written by a second, smaller hand, 38 lines; they intrude into the main text on the right; selection of points for use in court; a list of farmers at the end</note>
                     <note type="general">The docket on the verso was written by a small, third hand</note>
                     <note type="general">Two paragraphoi separate parts of the notes</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus ; 34 x 26.5 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0325" notAfter="0350">325 CE – 350 CE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from Mr. Blanchard through H.I. Bell in 1924; no. 27 in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Heraklas, -- landlord</term>
               <term>Alexandros, -- landlord</term>
               <term>Collapse of irrigation system; depopulation of villages</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>	Nomikos (?). We are speaking on behalf of Sambathion and Heras, of the village of Karanis. In the previous census records our clients registered considerable land of different categories in the territory of the village of Karanis in the Arsinoite (Nome), viz. Sambathion ninety arouras of royal and ten of private land, and Heras ninety of royal. But after the reservoir collapsed and the land was no longer being watered, it came to pass that these arouras remained unsown and brought an enormous loss upon our clients. With them in dire straits on this account, the collectors add a still greater injury. For Alexandros and Heraklas--his heirs are here present--registered in that area an enormous amount of land, and this was then being farmed by some fellow-villagers, and as they have become fugitives the collectors are improperly attacking these (our clients) and are compelling them, who are neither owners nor registrants nor holders (of the land), to pay the taxes--which they ought properly to collect from those who registered and own it and contracted these obligations, but they have proceeded instead against law-abiding peasants. We beg this high court, inasmuch as the very census records are in hand in which the lands are proved to belong to none other than Heraklas and Alexandros, that they, living in the city, be compelled to acknowledge their liability for the taxes of the lands and that our clients not be troubled, inasmuch as the former, being very powerful and oppressive in the region, are inflicting their own taxes upon the peasantry. 

(In the margin) 
	Our clients: Sanbathion and Heras, of the village of Karanis. 
	Opponents: Alexandros and heirs of Heraklas. 
	They registered in the census records: 
		Sanbathion 	royal 90 ar. 
				private 10 ar. 
		and Heras 	royal 90 ar. 

	But after the reservoir collapsed and the lands [came to be] in dry state, the collectors pressured them not only for their own property but also for Alexandros' on the pretext [they had farmed the land of that person?] a long time before. . . . [The actual farmers] have resorted to flight, but they were able to return as they (the collectors) again pressured them to farm it, and they are pressuring these (our clients). We beg (you), since registrations already exist and the owners are here present, to order ... and to compel them to direct their demand to the (actual) farmers. Our clients ... names. 
	The farmers farmed: 
		Orsenouphis 16 
		Soueis 20 
		Asklas 5 
		Heras 5
		Panouphis 2
		Kastor  4 1/2
		Heron 2 1/2 

(Docket on verso)
 On behalf of Sambathion of the village of Karanis, Horion, advocate. 

</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. VII 174 <note>Editio princeps: Lewis and Schiller, "Daube Noster" (1974) 187-200; plate, P.Col. VII, Microfiche 1; objections to the resolution of the abbreviation N(omikos): Lewis, P.Rain.Cent. pp 121-26; Youtie, "Scriptiunculae Posteriores" I pp. 1-15; Rupprecht, "Zeitschrift der Savigny-Stiftung," 99 (1982) 373; other examples of this kind of document: P.Lips. 41, P.Thead. 16 P.Princ. III 119, P.Panop. 31; P.Vindob.Gr.inv. 39757 (BASP 15 [1978] 115-23</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:7:174</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>