<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
           <title>Statement of Witnessing to a Deed of Gift</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1132</idno>
           <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.964</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                 <idno type="invNo">O.Col.inv. 964 </idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                 <summary>the text is a deed of gift and mentions a witness on the back; it could be a practice piece of an apprentice scribe</summary>
                 <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">8 lines of black writing on the front; 7 in red on the back.  The back is written by turning the ostracon over, such that the back is upside down relative to the front.</note>
                     <note type="general">The text is written on both sides by a proficient regular hand with huge letters, comparable to hands in the 6th century.</note>
                     <note type="general">Besides being on stone, the text shows some divergences from typical witness texts.  This text is either likely the product of an apprentice scribe copying various parts of a documentary formula (examples of apprentice work survive from Deir el-Bahari, also written on limestone, but in Coptic: e.g., O. Col. inv. 744); or perhaps a written assurance of someone ready to give witness to the deed of gift.  The gift itself (and names of other witnesses) was likely recorded on a separate piece of writing material, probably papyrus. The witness, whose name was probably written in the 1st line, may have been asked separately, his name to be added later to the contract.  The editor suggests that if this is a real document, that it most likely did not carry any legal force.
                                                         </note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                 </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                       <support>1 ostracon ; limestone ; 14.2 x 13.5 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                    <origDate notBefore="0500" notAfter="0699">500 CE – 699 CE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                    <p>From Thebes, Deir el Bahri; excavated by the Metropolitan Museum in 1926-29; Burton photo M10C 17. Formerly property of the Metropolitan Museum; sold to Columbia University in 1958 (MM acc. # 64.11.296).</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">in Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
              <term>Ostraca</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
           <listBibl>
               <bibl>N. Salem. ZPE 184 (2012): 289-92.</bibl>
           </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>