<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Account [IV AD]</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p273</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1197</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.8.238</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;8;238</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;8;238</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">32868</idno>
            <idno type="TM">32868</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 108b + Princeton GD7890A</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Private account of parcels of land, arranged by cultivator, probably listing rents; the crops are wheat, barley, flax, and hay; these are the accounts of a large landowner</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">The Princeton piece is the upper part; together with the Columbia piece the text is almost complete</note>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; the text continues on the back across the fibers</note>
                     <note type="general">35 lines of writing all together; the Columbia piece includes part of line 11, lines 12-19 and 31-35; the hand is large, with many flourishes, and should belong to the 2nd half of the century</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus ; 30.5 x 20.5 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0301" notAfter="0399">301 CE – 399 CE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>The Columbia fragment was purchased by Columbia University from M. Nahman through H.I. Bell, in 1924; no. 2 (box 3, 7) in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Private account of land</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Front)
From the 29 ar., 1 3/4 1/16 ar. of hay at the rate of 1/2 1/8 sol. per ar., 1 1/8 sol.  And from the estate of 4 ar. of Panechotes, 1 1/4 1/16 1/32 1/64 ar., of which 1/4 1/8 1/16 1/64 in wheat at a rate of 7 art., including the hundredths, 3 1/2 art.  In barley, 1/4 1/8 1/16 1/64 ar. at a rate of 7 art., including the hundredths, 3 1/2 art.  In flax, 1/4 1/8 1/16 1/64 ar. at a rate of 14 bundles of tow, including the twentieth, 6 1/2 1/8 bundles.  Total, 10 3/4 art. wheat, 12 1/4 art. barley, 33 1/6 bundles of flax, 1 1/8 solidi as value of hay.
(5) Elias son of Maria from the same hamlet is paying himself also on what he farmed from the aforesaid estate of Nam[  ], from 2[.] ar., 1 3/4 ar.: in wheat, 1/2 1/16 ar. at a rate of 7 art., including the hundredths, 4 1/2 art., 4 choinikes; [in barley, 1/2 1/16 ar.] at a rate of [7 art. of barley, including the hundredths], 4 1/2 art., 4 choinikes of barley; in flax, 1/2 1/16 ar. at a rate of 14 bundles of tow, including [the twentieth, 8 1/4] bundles; and from the estate of Melanthios, out of 22 1/8 ar., 1 1/2 ar., of which 3/4 ar. in flax at [17] bundles, including the twentieth, 13 1/2 bundles; and in fodder hay, 3/4 ar. at a rate of 2 art., including the hundredths, [1 1/2 art., 6 choin.].  And from the estate of 4 ar. of Panechotes, out of 4 ar., 1 1/2 1/16 1/32 ar., of which in wheat 1/4 1/8 1/16 1/32, at a rate of [7 art., including the hundredths, 3 1/2 1/8 art.]; in barley, 1/4 1/8 1/16 1/32 ar. at a rate of 7 art. of barley, including the [hundredths], 3 1/2 [1/8 art.] of barley; [in flax, 1/4 1/8 1/32 ar.] at a rate of 14 bundles of tow, including the twentieth, 6 1/6 bundles.  And from the estate of 8 ar. on the north of the hamlet of Netneou, but on the south of the dike in the marshlands, one aroura of barley at a rate of 7 art., including the hundredths, 7 [1/2 art. 8 choin. ]
(14) And from the estate of Phanes, from 6 1/4 1/8 ar., 2 1/8 ar. at a rate of 1/2 1/8 sol. per aroura, 1 1/3 sol.  Total, .. 1/4 art. wheat, 17 1/2 art. 4 choin. of barley, 28 bundles, 1 1/3 sol. of money. 
(16) The union of the farmers of the hamlet of Netneou are paying themselves also for what they farmed from the estate at ... on the north of the hamlet of Netneou but on the south of the dike, in the marshlands, [1/2 1/8] 1/64 [ar.] of barley at a rate of 6 art., 3 3/4 art. 4 choin. of barley; and from the estate of Megal(  ), of the south parcel, [1 1/2 1/8] 1/16 ar. at a rate of 1/2 1/8 sol. per aroura, 1 1/8 sol.; total, 3 3/4 art., 6 choin. of barley, 1 1/8 sol. of money.

(Back)
(20) Atolas son of Paulos from the same hamlet pays for what he farmed in the estate of Nitechoche from the 20 1/2 1/16 arouras, 2 3/4 arouras: of wheat, 3/4 [1/8] aroura at a rate of 7 art., including the hundredths, 7 1/4 art.  In hay, 3/4 1/8 aroura at a rate of 7 art., with the hundredths, 7 1/4 art.  In flax, 3/4 1/8 aroura at a rate of 14 bundles, including the twentieth, 13 bundles.  And from the estate of Melanthios out of 22 1/8 ar., 1 1/2 1/8 ar., of which in flax, 3/4 1/16 ar., at a rate of 17 bundles, with the twentieth, 14 1/2 1/8 bundles.  In fodder hay, 3/4 1/16 ar. at a rate of 2 art. of barley, including the hundredths, 1 3/4 art. 2 choin.  And from the estate of Pekysios from 3 ar., 1 ar. in barley, at a rate of 7 art., including the hundredths, 7 1/2 art., 8 choin.  And from the estate of Megal(  ), from the eastern parcel, out of 6 1/4 ar., 3 1/8 ar., of which 1 art. in barley at a rate of 7 art., with the hundredths, 7 1/2 art. 8 choin.  In flax, 1 1/8 ar. at a rate of 14 bundles of tow, with the twentieth, 16 1/2 bundles.  In hay, 1 ar. at a rate of 1/2 1/8 solidus.  And from the estate of Zenon, out of 37 1/2 ar., 5 ar., of which 2 3/4 ar. in barley at a rate of 6 art., with the hundredths, 18 art. 6 choin.  In flax, 2 1/4 ar. at a rate of 12 bundles of tow, with the twentieth, 27 1/4 bundles.  And from the field of Apollonios ... of the same estate of Zenon, 1 1/4 ar. in flax, at a rate of 12 bundles of tow, with the [twentieth], 16 1/4 bundles.  Total, 7 1/4 art. of wheat, 42 1/2 art., 4 choin. of barley, 89 2/3 bundles of tow, value of hay, 1/2 1/8 sol.
(33) Apollos son of Germanos, surnamed Ptaxouar, from the village of Nesminis, paying on behalf of what he farmed in the estate of Brickworkers (?), 5 ar., of which 2 1/2 ar. in wheat at a rate of 7 art., including the hundredths, 19 1/4 art.  In hay, 2 1/2 ar. at a rate of 7 art. of barley, including the hundredths, 19 1/4 art., total 19 1/4 art. of wheat, 19 1/4 art. of barley.
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. VIII 238 P.Princ. III 136, publication of the upper part <note>Plates 56 and 57 of the 2 fragments reunited in P.Col. VIII; cf. J. Gascou, "Les debuts du codex" pp. 86-87; cf. also P.Bon. 39, reedited in ZPE 52 (1983) 247-54</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:8:238</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>