<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Loan 372 AD</title>
            <author>Aurelia Tetoueis, daughter of Hatres and Tapaeis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p219</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1306</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.7.184</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;7;184</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;7;184</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10539</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10539</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 181 (30)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Loan of 3.600 talents of Augustan silver coinage to be repaid in kind; the borrower is Tetoueis and the lender Venaphrios</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; on the back there is the docket; a space of 6 cm. is left blank on the front underneath the text</note>
                     <note type="general">25 lines of writing, plus 1 line on the back</note>
                     <note type="general">Part of an archive of documents concerning Aurelia Tetoueis: P.Oslo II 38; P.Mert. I 37; P.NYU 24; P.Col. VII 182, 183, and perhaps 187</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus ; 14.2 x 26.7 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0372">372 CE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from Mr. Blanchard through H.I. Bell in 1924; no. 30 in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Aurelius Venaphrios, -- son of Sarapion</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>	In the consulate of Domitius Modestus the most illustrious Praetorlan Prefect and Flavius Arinthaeus, the most illustrious Count and Master of the Infantry Force, Choiak 2 1. Aurelia Titouis, daughter of Hatres and Tapais, of the village of Karanis of the Arsinoite Nome, to Aurelius Venaphrios, son of Sarapion, of the city of the Arsinoites, greeting. I acknowledge that I have received and had counted from you for myself three thousand six hundred talents of Augustan silver coinage, which are for the price of six artabas of barley (6 art.), which I will repay to you in the month of Pauni of the second fortunate indiction with no delay and without any dispute, and you are to have right of execution from me or even from all of my property of all kinds and sorts, and when the formal question was put to me, I acknowl- edged (the above). 1, the aforementioned Aurelia Titoueis, received the three thousand six hundred talents, which are for the price of six artabas of barley (6 art.) and I shall make repayment at the appointed time, as aforesaid. I, Aurelius Petros, son of Nemesianos, have written on her behalf since she is illiterate. 

Back 
	Note of hand: Titoueis, daughter of Hatres, of the village of Karanis, barley, 6 art. 
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. VII 184 <note>Plate, P.Col. VII, Microfiche 2; published by Day and Porges, AJP 81 (1960) 157-75, SB VI 9603</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:7:184</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>