<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter July 17, 257 BC</title>
            <author>Apollonides, 2 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 291</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p15</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1327</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.3.15</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;3;15</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;3;15</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">1735</idno>
            <idno type="TM">1735</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 382 + 297</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Apollonides writes to Zenon about mattresses for Kriton; he delivered them to him and received money for wool, sewing and dyeing; he also bought pigs for Kriton</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written across the fibers with 7 lines; on the back, along the fibers, address and docket</note>
                     <note type="general">Calligraphic hand but not completely regular</note>
                     <note type="general">Written to Zenon during his stay at Arsinoe in the Delta, near Alexandria</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus fragment ; 6.5 x 15.5 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="-0257">257 BCE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from Dr. Kondilios through H.I. Bell, 1st fragment in December 1926, no. 136 in Bell's inventory; 2nd fragment in July 1925, no. 104 in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Kriton, -- 2 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 357</term>
               <term>Cost and method of manufacture of mattresses</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Apollonides to Zenon, greeting. You wrote me to give to Kriton, instead of the two mattresses of forty minas' weight, a mattress of a talent's weight. But I have had made for you, instead of those of forty minas' weight, two purple-bordered ones of fifty minas' with excellent seaming. And for these two I have received from Kriton as labor charge 2 1/2 obols per mina, total for the 100 minas, 41 drachmas 4 obols; and for dyeing of both mattresses, 20 drachmas; and pay for seaming, 1 drachma: total, 62 drachmas 4 obols. And I have given him both the mattresses. For the seven [mattresses] which you wrote me to have prepared, I have 400 drachmas, pending account. It will be carried out, therefore, as you have ordered. I have also bought up the pigs for him. 
	Good by. Year 29, Pachon 25. And for whatever else you may need, write to me.
[Verso:] Apollonides regarding mattresses 	To Zenon. 
and pigs which he gave to Kriton. 
Year 29, Daisios 23. In Arsinoe. 
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. III 15 P.Col.Zen. I 15 <note>Correction in line 2 by Skeat, JEA 21 (1935) 85; BL III p. 43</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:3:15</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>