<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Receipts [334-335 AD]</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p182</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1269</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.7.144</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;7;144</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;7;144</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10498</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10498</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 181 (37)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Receipts for delivery of wheat issued to Valerius and Aion with mention of the boat to which delivery was made; the first receipt was written at a different time than the remainder</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers with 24 lines; the back is blank</note>
                     <note type="general">Written in four different hands, all ligatured and medium-sized</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus ; 33 x 28 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0334" notAfter="0335">334 CE – 335 CE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from Mr. Blanchard through H.I. Bell in 1924; no. 37 in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Valerius, -- son of Antiourios</term>
               <term>Aion, -- son of Sarapion</term>
               <term>Ptollas, -- son of Aion</term>
               <term>Ouranios, -- collector</term>
               <term>Souchidas, -- collector</term>
               <term>Timotheos, -- collector</term>
               <term>Ision, -- sitometres</term>
               <term>Receipts for deliveries in kind</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>     Tybi 28. Valerius son of Antiourios delivered in the harbor of Leukogion [for the -th indiction] for the account of villagers of Karanis, ninety-one artabas of clean wheat, art. 91 only. I, Ouranios, have signed.
    (M2) Phaophi 24. Aion son of Sarapion delivered in the harbor of Leukogion for the ninth indiction for the account of villagers of Karanis, twenty-eight artabas of clean wheat, art. 28 only. I, Souchidas, have signed through me, Timotheos.
    (M3) Hathyr 6. Aion son of Sarapion delivered for the account of villagers of Karanis in the harbor of Leukogion for the ninth indiction, three artabas of clean wheat, art. 3 only. I, Timotheos, have signed.
    (M4) Phaophi 15. Aion son of Sarapion delivered in the harbor of Leukogion to the boat of Papnouthis son of Hermias for the eighth indiction for the account of villagers of Karanis, six artabas of clean wheat, art. 6 only. And through Ptollas son of Aion, two, a half, a third artabas of clean wheat, art. 2 1/21/3. I, Ision, sitometres, have signed.
    (M2) Phaophi 24. Aion son of Sarapion delivered in the harbor of Leukogion for the ninth indiction to the boat of Ammonios from Leukogion, for the account of villagers of Karanis, two, a half, a third, a twelfth artabas of clean wheat, art. 2 1/2 1/3 1/12. I, Timotheos, sitometres, have signed. Likewise the same man for the same indiction, four artabas of clean wheat, art. 4 only. I, Timotheos, have signed.
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. VII 144 <note>Plate, P.Col. VII, Microfiche 1</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:7:144</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>