<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Loan [September 19, 326 AD]</title>
            <author>Aurelius Stephanos, son of Euporos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p320</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1244</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.10.287</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;10;287</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;10;287</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">22278</idno>
            <idno type="TM">22278</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 166</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Acknowledgement of a loan of 90 artabas of wheat, which is written in duplicate</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; broken on the left and possibly on the bottom; the back is blank</note>
                     <note type="general">37 lines of writing in rapid cursives</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus fragment ; 15.3 x 17.8 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0326">326 CE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from M. Nahman through H.I. Bell, in 1924; no. 70 (box XIVb) in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Loan of wheat; duplicate document</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>In the consulate of our masters Constantinus Augustus for the seventh time and Constantius the most illustrious Caesar for the first time, to Flavius Dionysios, former centurion of the staff of the rationalis, from Aurelius Stephanos son of Euporos, former archon, councillor of the glorious and most glorious city of the Oxyrhynchites, greeting. I acknowledge that I have received and have had measured out from you, on loan, from your house, ninety (90) artabas of wheat, the principal including the additional half, (measured) by the tenth measure, which wheat new, clean, without dirt or barley, sifted, using the measure with which I received it, at the place where I had it measured out to me, I shall perforce repay you without delay or excuse in the month of Epeiph of the present year 21 and 11 and 3. If not, I shall pay you a penalty at the rate of fifty percent on each artaba for the excess time, and you retain the right of execution on me and all of my possessions of whatever kind.  This contract, written in duplicate, is normative wherever it may be produced and for whoever produces it on your behalf. After having been questioned, I consented. During the aforesaid consulate, Thoth 22.
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. X 287 <note>Plate 44 in P.Col. X; published by B.E. Nielsen, BASP 27 (1990) 95-101</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:10:287</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>