<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Loan 3 February 373 AD</title>
            <author>Aurelia Tetoueis, daughter of Hatres and Tapaeis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p217</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1304</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.7.182</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;7;182</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;7;182</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10537</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10537</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 59</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Loan of wheat and 3.000 talents in Augustan silver coinage made to Tetoueis by Aurelia Koutinon; the money was to be repaid in barley</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; on the back there is the docket</note>
                     <note type="general">32 lines of writing on the front and 1 line on the back; the hand is small and cursive on the front, but it becomes larger in the docket</note>
                     <note type="general">Part of an archive of documents concerning Aurelia Tetoueis: P.Oslo II 38; P.Mert. I 37; P.NYU 24; P.Col. VII 183, 184, and perhaps 187</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus ; 10 x 25.9 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0373">373 CE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from M. Nahman through H.I. Bell, in 1924; no. 9 in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>	Aurelia Titoueis daughter of Hatres, of the village of Karanis of the Arsinoite Nome, to Aurelia Koutinon, of the city of the Arsinoites, greeting. I acknowledge that I have received, and have had measured from you nine artabas of wheat, (9 art.), including interest of one-half, and three thousand talents in Augustan silver coinage (3000 tal.) which are for the price of six artabas of barley (6 art.), which I will repay to you, in full, in the month of Epeiph of the second fortunate indiction with no delay and without any dispute, the right of execution belonging to you from me or even from all my property of all kinds and sorts for you at execution as though by a legal decision, and when the formal question was put to me I acknowledged (the above). In the consulate of Domitius Modestus, the most illustrious Praetorian Prefect, and Flavius Arinthaeus, the most illustrious Count and Master of the Infantry Force, Mecheir 9. I, the aforementioned Aurelia Titoueis, received the nine artabas of wheat (9 art.) and the six artabas of barley (6 art.) and I will repay them at the appointed time, as aforesaid. I, Aurelius Petros, son of Nemesianus, have written on her behalf because she is illiterate. 

Back
	Note of hand: Titoueis from the village of Karanis, 9 artabas of wheat, and &lt;6 art. of&gt; barley. 
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. VII 182 <note>Plate, P.Col. VII, Microfiche 2; published by Day and Porges, AJP 81 (1960) 157-75, SB VI 9603; about the date: Packman, CdE 50 (1975) 285-96; Bagnall, "Consuls of the Late Roman Empire " p. 279</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:7:182</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>