<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Extract from property register [208-209 AD]</title>
            <author>Flavia Ptollarous, daughter of Marcus Flavius Diogenes</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p307</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1231</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.10.274</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;10;274</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;10;274</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10563</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10563</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 30</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Extract from the property archives of the Arsinoite: Flavia Ptollarous declared that she obtained from her father some land as an "irrevocable gift"</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; the back is blank</note>
                     <note type="general">16 lines of writing by 2 hands: the first is neat and calligraphic, while the second, which writes in red ink, is cursive and faster</note>
                     <note type="general">Lines of x's in red and black ink define the document or are used as line fillers</note>
                     <note type="general">Portions of the papyrus are damaged by insects</note>
                     <note type="general">The text sheds light on the nature of the "irrevocable gift," in this case a gift of land by a father to his daughter</note>
                     <note type="general">It is intersting that, although the land belonged to Stratippos, Diogenes' son, it is the father who has the power to donate it to his daugher</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus fragment, broken on the left ; 21.5 x 21.8 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0208" notAfter="0209">208 CE – 209 CE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from M. Nahman through H.I. Bell, in July 1923; no. 39 (IV.29) in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Red X's)
From the property archives of the Arsinoite (nome), from the depositories of the Roman purchasers (. . . from the nth) volume, 200th column, for 5 (columns) (red x's).
[Flavia] Ptollarous, in year [1]7, on the 5th of Pharmouthi, submitted a memorandum through (her) guardian ---doros, notifying that she has obtained by an irrevocable deed of gift (made) through the record office in the --- year in the month of Phamenoth by her father Marcus Flavius Diogenes, (of property belonging?) to his son Marcus Flavius Stratippos, not yet being of age, around the village of Philadelphia, in the Herakleides Division: [numeral] arourai of katoikic land in two places and [ ]3 arourai of katoikic land and 2 1/2 arourai of . . . land from clearance of an olive orchard, domain land . . ., (having been presented as a gift?) by (her) father Flavius Diogenes through a public notarization (validated?) in the preceding year in the month of Kaisareion through the registry of Ptolemais Arabon, in order that a deposit may be made in accordance with the referred agreement . . . write(s) the statements.
(2nd hand) . . .  year seventeen of Emperors Caesars Lucius Septimius Severus Pius Pertinax Arabicus Adiabenicus Parthicus Maximus and Marcus Aurelius Antoninus Pius Augusti and Publius Septimius Geta Caesar Augustus . . . fifteenth (red x's).
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. X 274 <note>Plate 29 in P.Col. X</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:10:274</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>