<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Receipts [301-302 AD]</title>
            <author>Aurelius Horion, dekaprotos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p175</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1262</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.7.137</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;7;137</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;7;137</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10490</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10490</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 68</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Receipts for taxes: most of them were given by the dekaprotoi for grain, some were given in cash to the apaitetai for delegatio for the price of chaff and meat; the taxpayers were members of Isidoros' family</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; the back is blank; in all 116 lines of writing</note>
                     <note type="general">The hands are many, all proficient and ligatured</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus divided into 2 parts ; 75 x 25 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0301" notAfter="0302">301 CE – 302 CE</origDate>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Philotas, dekaprotos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Severinus, dekaprotos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Andreias, dekaprotos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Didymos, dekaprotos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Sarmates, dekaprotos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Arabikos, son of Ptollas, apaitetes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Achillas, apaitetes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Heron, dekaprotos</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Gerontios, dekaprotos</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from M. Nahman through H.I. Bell, in 1924; no. 27 in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Taesis, -- daughter of Kopres</term>
               <term>Pelenis, -- apaitetes</term>
               <term>Heras, -- brother of Isidoros</term>
               <term>Heras, -- Taesis' husband</term>
               <term>Tax receipts</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <facsimile>
     <surfaceGrp>
       <surface type="recto">
         <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/30/columbia.apis.p175a.f.0.600"/>
         <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/ff/columbia.apis.p175.f.0-0.600"/>
         <graphic url="http://papyri.info/images/52/columbia.apis.p175.f.1-0.600"/>
       </surface>
     </surfaceGrp>
   </facsimile>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>    
    Column I
    
    Year 17 and 16 and nine, Pharmouthi 24. Isidoros son of Ptolemaios and Taesis daughter of Kopres paid as price of chaff and meat for the first delegatio for the village of Karanis, a hundred fifty-two dr., dr. 152, (paid) through Achillas and Arabikos and their partners, apaitetai. And for the village horiodiktia of Karanis, price of chaff and meat for the fourth divine delegatio, dr. three thousand eight hundred, dr. 3800, (paid) through Achillas and Pelenis, apaitetai.
    (M2) [Year 17] and 16 and 9, Pharmouthi [..]. Isidoros son of Ptolemaios [paid] for the divine [delegatio] for the 15th and 14th and [7th year for the village of] Karanis as price of chaff [and meat?, one thousand] nine hundred [dr.], dr. 1900. I, Aurelius [-, have signed].
    (lines 14-19 too fragmentary to translate)
    
    Column II
    
    (M5) Year 17 and 16 and 9 of our lords Diocletianus and Maximianus Augusti and Constantius and Maximianus the most noble Caesars, Pharmouthi 29. Aurelii Horion and Philotas, dekaprotoi of the 4th and 5th toparchy of the Herakleides Division: paid to us in the granary of the village of Karanis, by level public measure, for produce of the 15th and 14th and [7th year] and 16th and 15th and 8th year, for the village of New Ptolemais, in the name of Thaesion daughter of Kopres, through Isidoros, two and a half artabas of clean wheat with the twelve percent, art. 2 1/2. I, Aurelius Philotas, have signed. I, Horion, have signed.
    (M6) Year 17 and 16 and 9 of our lords Diocletianus and Maximianus Augusti and Constantius and Maximianus the most noble Caesars, Pachon 11. Aurelii Severinus and Andreias, former exegetes, councillor of Alexandria, and the heirs of Sarmates, and Sabinos, former gymnasiarch, (all) dekaprotoi of the 4th and 5th toparchy of the Herakleides Division: paid to us in [the granary] of the village of Karanis for the horiodiktia for the divine delegatio on the crop [of the 17th and 16th] and 9th year, . . . artabas by the level public measure; (and in the name of) Taesis daughter of Kopres, two-thirds artaba of clean wheat . . . (lines 35-41 are too fragmentary for translation).
    
    Column III
    
    (M8) Year 17 and 16 and nine of our lords Diocletianus and Maximianus Augusti and Constantius and Maximianus the most noble Caesars, Pachon 5. Aurelius Didymos, former gymnasiarch, councillor, dekaprotos of the 1st and 6th toparchy of the Herakleides division through me, Heron son of Onomastos: paid to me in the granary of the village of Karanis by the level public measure, for produce of the 16th and 15th and 8th year and 15th and 14th and 7th year and 14th and 13th and 6th year in the name of Taesis, daughter of Kopres, twelve, a half, a fourth artabas of clean wheat, art. 12 3/4. And in the name of Herais daughter of Chairemon through Isidoros, ten and a half artabas of clean wheat, art. 10 1/2, total for the receipt altogether, art. 23 1/4. I, Aurelius Heron, have signed through me his son Pikos.
    (lines 56-70 are too fragmentary for translation)
    
    Column IV
    
    (M 12) Year 17 and 16 and nine of our lords Diocletianus and Maximianus Augusti and Constantius and Maximianus the most noble Caesars, Mesore 17. Aurelii Horion and Sarmates, dekaprotoi of the 4th and 5th toparchy of the Herakleides Division: paid to us in the granary of the village of Karanis for the horiodiktia of Karanis from the new crop in the name of Isidoros son of Ptolemaios, for the crop of the same 17th and 16th and ninth year, forty-four and a fourth artabas of clean wheat, that is, 44 1/4 art. clean wh., and the authorized percentage. And in the name of Heras son of Ptolemaios, twenty-three artabas of clean wheat, art. clean wh. 23 and the percentage. And in the name of Taesion daughter of Kopres through Heras, a half artaba of clean wheat, that is 1/2 art. clean wh. And in the name of the same woman, for New Ptolemais, four and a half artabas of clean wheat, that is 4 1/2 art. clean wh. and the authorized percentage. I, Aurelius Horion, have signed. (M 13) I, Aurelius Sarmates, have signed.
    (lines 88-117 are too fragmentary for translation.)
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. VII 137 <note>Corrections to line 76 by Hagedorn, ZPE 40 (1980) 86 and by B. Palme, MPER NS 20 (1989) 245, note 145; related texts: P.Mert. II 88 and P.Cair.Isid. 41; plate, P.Col. VII, Microfiche 1</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:7:137</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
