<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale 342 AD</title>
            <author>Aurelius Klemitos, son of Heras and Alous</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p216</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1303</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.7.181</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;7;181</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;7;181</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10536</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10536</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 181 (2)</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Sale of 9 1/2 arouras of land for 50 talents of silver; the land belonged to Klemitos and Tapaeis who had inherited from their mother Alous; it is sold to Atisios and Antiourios</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; on the back the docket</note>
                     <note type="general">19 lines of writing plus 1 on the back; practiced hand of medium size</note>
                     <note type="general">Faulty grammar, especially with regard to case and number</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus ; 41.5 x 21 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0342">342 CE</origDate>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelia Tapaeis, daugther of Heras and Alous</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from Mr. Blanchard through H.I. Bell in 1924; no. 2 in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Aurelius Atisios, -- son of Leonides</term>
               <term>Aurelius Antiourios, -- son of Abous</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>	In the consulate of our lords Constantius for the 3rd time and Constans for the 2nd, Augusti, in the month of Apellaios/Phaophi 21, in Ptolemais Euergetis of the Arsinoite Nome.
	Aurelil Klemitos and Tapaeis, both children of Heras and Alous, Klemitos about 42 years old with a scar on the front of his left knee, Tapaels about 22 years old with a scar on her left hand, of the village of Karanis in the 5th pagus of the Arsinoite Nome, acknowledge to the Aurelil Atisis son of Leonides and Taesis, about 45 years old with a scar on the shin of his right leg, and Antiourios son of Abous and Allous, about 49 years old with a scar on his right foot, both of the village of Karanis in the Arsinoite Nome, that the acknowledging parties have sold to the party of Antiourios and Atisios from the present day unto all time the nine and one-half arouras of private arable land belonging to them in the horiodiktia of the village of Karanis, in section 6 in the locality called Tmeitelas, listed in the name of Alous, as the boundaries are given in the declaration made under the then censitor Sabinus, with all their present limits and with the aforesaid boundaries and locations; that the acknowledging parties have received from Atisios and Antiourios in full in person the fifty talents of silver agreed upon as the price; that they, the acknowledging parties and their representatives, will guarantee to Atisis and Antiouris and their representatives with every guarantee the terms of sale of the aforesaid arouras, which they will deliver unencumbered, not liable to distraint, free of lien, and clear of every obligation-of government taxes, annona assessments and every imposition from the present time through the sixteenth indiction, and of private obligation and every claim forever;
	and that from the present Atisis and Antiourios are to have and to hold these (arouras), are to appropriate all the produce to their private possession, are to manage and administer them as they please, and are to pay to the imperial treasury all government taxes, annona assessments and impositions upon them from the seventeenth indiction unto all time; and that neither the acknowledging parties nor anyone else in their behalf will institute adverse proceedings in any way but will themselves immediately at their own expense repulse any who shall in any way whatsoever bring suit or claim, and further (if they fail so to act) they will in addition pay one and a half times the (purchase) price and double the fees and expenses, aside from the aforegoing terms also remaining valid.
	As to the accuracy and correctness of these terms thus stated, they put the formal question to each other and gave their acknowledgment.

Verso 

Sale, private arable land, 9 1/2 ar.
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. VII 181 <note>Published by Lewis, P.Coll.Youtie II 78; plate, P.Col. VII, Microfiche 2</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:7:181</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>