<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Memorandum and report [243-242 BC]</title>
            <author>Zenodoros, 5 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 332</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p89</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1401</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.4.90</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;4;90</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;4;90</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">1803</idno>
            <idno type="TM">1803</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 208</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Memorandum of Zenodoros about the loss of farm implements for which he was responsible; he asks that the money to cover the loss be supplied out of salary credits in his favor; the report of Apollonios, secretary of Eukles, follows: instead of the claim made of 95 drachmas the accountant rounds off the sum at 80</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">28 lines written along the fibers; on the back the address along the fibers</note>
                     <note type="general">The two documents, which are separated by a paragraphos, were copied by the same hand; a second hand adds the sum total underneath; the address on the back was probably written by a third hand</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus ; 10.4 x 28.2 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="-0243" notAfter="-0242">243 BCE – 242 BCE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from M. Nahman and New York dealer J. Brummer, through H.I. Bell, November 1925; no. 5 (original no. 39) in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Eukles, -- 1 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 329; correction to line 27 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 128</term>
               <term>Apollonios, -- 14 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 293</term>
               <term>Hermaphilos, -- oikonomos, 1 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 326</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Memorandum of Zenodoros. X (who has been placed in charge?) of the servants who formerly (worked about) Philadelphia, (checking?) at the store house the iron tools and the rest of the implements which are being delivered at Philadelphia, together with the royal scribe and the village scribe, has decided that fifteen mattocks have been lost, and Eukles, the oeconomus, is compelling me alone to cover the deficit. There is still owing me salary for four months of year 2 and for three months of year 3, seven months in all, at 5 drachmas per month-total 35 drachmas-and clothing allowance for three years at 20 drachmas per year-total 60 drachmas. Total 95 drachmas apart from the oil allowance. Therefore, in order that the mattocks may be restored, since the exaction falls upon me alone, and that I myself may not be dragged off by the praktor, I beg that you give orders to Hermaphilos that the money and clothing allowance due me be looked into and paid in order that there may be no deficit in respect to the store house accounts. The amount still owing, as Apollonios the clerk has presented it, is: fromMecheir to Pachons for year 2, salary, copper standard, 20 drachmas; and oil allowance for four months, 8 kotylai at 2 obols, 2 drachmas 4 obols; and for year 3, from Hathyr to Tybi, salary for three months, 15 drachmas; and oil allowance, 6 kotylai at 2 obols, 2 drachmas standard, 20 drachmas;
 and clothing allowance for year 2, copper and for year 3 likewise, copper standard, 20 drachmas.
[2d hd.:] Total, 79 drachmas 4 obols. Sum total, 40 X 2, 80 drachmas.
 
[Verso:] To Apollonios.
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. IV 90 P.Col.Zen. II 90 <note>R. Scholl, "Corpus der ptolem*auischen Sklaventexte" (1990) no. 254; correction to lines 1 and 6 by Clarysse, personal communication</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:4:90</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>