<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter [between 246 and 240 BC (?)]</title>
            <author>Apollonios, brother of Zenon, 10 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 292</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p80</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1392</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.4.81</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;4;81</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;4;81</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">1794</idno>
            <idno type="TM">1794</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 218</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Letter to Zenon from his brother Apollonios about jars of wine among the possessions of Sostratos: he lists the jars according to types and location</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">26 lines written along the fibers on the front; the address is on the back, across the fibers</note>
                     <note type="general">The hand is small and not completely regular: it should be the hand of Zenon's brother</note>
                     <note type="general">Paragraphoi alone or with space in the line indicate new items; after the greetings there is a postscript.</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus ; 8.5 x 15.5 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="-0246" notAfter="-0240">246 BCE – 240 BCE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from M. Nahman and New York dealer J. Brummer, through H.I. Bell, November 1925; no. 15 (original no. 38) in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Sostratos, -- 3 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 424</term>
               <term>Menodoros, -- 5 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 367</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Apollonios to his brother, greeting. I sent Menodoros to bring you a letter (stating) how many jars there are among the possessions of Sostratos. Thereafter we found two belonging to him in a certain empty outhouse. As it now stands, none of these are broken. I enumerate below now also how many there are in the storerooms. In the portico, in the corner, 1. Others, lying next to the same, 7 half-Chia, 3 keramia. Next, 6 banotoi. Of Egyptian make, 11. In the first storeroom, to the left as one goes in, in the corner, 11. Further in, on the right, 18; on the left, 8. In the second room, 24, and 1 Chian jar. In the inmost room 8 keramia, 5 of sour wine, I Chian jar. In the small portico, 5 Chian jars. Good-by. Chilon stated that he could not come to you. For his servant was occupied with them (i.e., the jars), he said. I will send another servant to you, whomever you wish.     [Verso:] To Zenon.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. IV 81 P.Col.Zen. II 81 <note>Correction to line 7 by Clarysse, personal communication; Clarysse also states that line 1 contains no writing, only ink traces</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:4:81</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>