<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Receipts 344 AD</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p194</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1281</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.7.158</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;7;158</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;7;158</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10512</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10512</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 307</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>In col. 1 notations of sums of money and a private receipt given to Papeeis, which is written in a confusing way; the 2nd col. contains receipts for wheat and barley delivered by Ammonas</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; the back is blank</note>
                     <note type="general">Margins are preserved on all 4 sides</note>
                     <note type="general">32 lines of writing in 2 cols. by 4 different hands, which are all proficient</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus ; 36 x 25.6 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0344">344 CE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from Dr. Kondilios through H.I. Bell in July 1925; no. 133 in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Ammonas, -- son of Atisios</term>
               <term>Aurelius Alypios, -- veteran</term>
               <term>Aurelius Papeeis, -- son of Atisios</term>
               <term>Receipts for deliveries in kind</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab> (Lines 4ff.)
	(M2) Aurelius Alypius, veteran, of the city of the Arsinoites from the amphodon Phremi to Aurelius Papeeis son of Atisios, from the village of Karanis, greeting. SinceI have received from you a chirographon for twenty-four artabas of wheat, art. 24, of the the twenty-four I have supplied to you, Papeeis, fifteen, a third, a twelfth artabas of grain, art. 15 1/3 1/12. The remainder, eight, a half, a twelfth artabas, 8 1/2 1/12 art. due from me, I will myself supply to you, Papeeis. Aurelius Hol wrote all of this.
 
 Column II
 
	(M3) Epeiph 10. Ammonas son of Atisios delivered in the city harbor for the third new indiction for the account of villagers of Karanis, eight (and) a half artabas of clean wheat 8 1/2 only. (M4) I, Elias, have signed through me, Romanos, for eight (and) a half artabas of grain only.
	(M3) Epeiph 18. Ammonas son of Atisios delivered in the city harbor for the third new indiction for the account of villagers of Karanis, five, a half, a third artabas of clean wheat, art. 5 1/2 1/3 only. (M4) I, Elias, have signed through me, Romanos, for five, a half, a third artabas of grain only.
	(M3) Epeiph 10. Ammonas son of Atisios delivered in the city harbor for the third new indiction for the account of villagers of Karanis, twenty (and) two-thirds artabas of barley, art. 20 2/3 only. (M4) 1, Elias, have signed through me, Romanos, for twenty (and) two-thirds art. of barley only.
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. VII 158 <note>Plate, P.Col. VII, Microfiche 1</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:7:158</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>