<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Receipt [June 5, 395 AD ?]</title>
            <author>Aurelius Herodes, son of Antoninus</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p272</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1196</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.8.237</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;8;237</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;8;237</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10553</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10553</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 42</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Receipt for share of inheritance of 1 solidus that Herodes acknowledges having received from Aurelius Agathos, son of Atin</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; 1 line on the back; the papyrus was folded several times vertically</note>
                     <note type="general">23 lines of writing on the front and 1 line on the back</note>
                     <note type="general">Dating is difficult because of the uncertainty in reading the consulate; Philadelphia, moreover, is not attested after 343 AD</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus ; 11.5 x 37 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0395">395 CE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from M. Nahman and New York dealer J. Brummer, through H.I. Bell, November 1925; no. 51 (IV. 45) in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Receipt for inheritance</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>In the consulate of Fl. Olybrius v.c., Pauni 9.  (2 H.) Aurelius Herodes son of Antoninus from the village of Theadelphia of the Arsinoite Nome to Aurelius Agathos son of Atin from the same village, greeting.  I have received from you for the entire account of the portion falling to me of the inheritance of our relative Asaueis, that is, one gold solidus, and for your security and for my having from now on no claim against you on any matter, either generally or concerning the inheritance, neither written nor unwritten, I have issued to you this document which is decisive, and in answer to the formal question, I have given my assent.
(3 H.) I, Aurelius Herodes, the aforesaid, have received from you, Agathos, one solidus on account of the portion falling to me of the inheritance and from this point on I have no claim against you concerning this as aforesaid.  Aurelius Heron son of Sakaon, from the city of the Arsinoites, wrote on behalf of him because he is illiterate.  (4 H.) Through me ...
(Verso)  (2 H.) Deed of Herodes to Agathos.
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. VIII 237 <note>Plate 47 in P.Col. VIII</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:8:237</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>