<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Receipts [307-308 AD]</title>
            <author>Aurelius Eudaimon, epimeletes</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p176</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1263</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.7.138</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;7;138</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;7;138</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10491</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10491</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 183</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Receipts for deliveries of gold and silver bullion by Aurelius Isidoros and members of his family; the payments are related to the "synone," a governmental buying-up of uncoined gold and silver from landowners</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers with 44 lines; the back is blank; dark brown papyrus</note>
                     <note type="general">The 2 fragments may not have been contiguous</note>
                     <note type="general">Written in various hands, all proficient and inclined to the right</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>2papyrus fragments ; 47 x 26 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0307" notAfter="0308">307 CE – 308 CE</origDate>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Heron, epimeletes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Euporos, epimeletes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Gerontios, collector</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Sarapammon, epimeletes</persName>
                     <persName type="asn">Aurelius Potammon, epimeletes</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from M. Abdullah through H.I. Bell in 1924; no. 5 in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Taesis, -- see P.Mert. I 31</term>
               <term>Aurelius Isidoros, -- son of Ptolemaios</term>
               <term>Aurelius Heras, -- son of Ptolemaios</term>
               <term>Receipts, delivery of bullion</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>    Aurelii Sarapammon and Potammon, epimeletai of uncoined silver, to Aurelius Isidoros son of Ptolemaios, greeting. We have received from you according to the divine command for your property in the village horiodiktia of Karanis, four ounces and six grams of pure uncoined silver. I, Potammon, have signed. In the consulate of our master Maximinus Caesar, 9 before the Calends of January.
    (M2) Aurelius Eudaimon, former chief priest, councillor, epimeletes of gold, to Isidoros, greeting. I have received from you for the assessment imposed according to the divine command for the horiodiktia of Karanis, six and a half grams of pure gold, gr. 6 1/2. I, Eudaimon, wrote the entire document. 10 before the Calends of May.
    (M3) Aurelius Heron, councillor, epimeletes of gold and uncoined silver, to Aurelius Isidoros, son of Ptolemaios, greeting. I have received from you for the assessment imposed according to the divine command for the horiodiktia of the village of Karanis, four and an eighth grams of pure gold, gr. 4 1/8. (M4) I, Heron, have signed. (M3) Year 16 and 4 of our lords Galerius Valerius Maximianus Augustus and Galerius Valerius Maximinus the most noble Caesar, 6 before the Calends of May.
    
    Column II
    
   (M5) Aurelius Heron, councillor, epimeletes, to Aurelius Heras, son of Ptolemaios, from the village of Karanis, greeting. I have received from you for the assessment imposed for the account of the village horiodiktia of Karanis, four grams of pure gold, that is, 4 gr. gold.
   (M4) I, Heron, have signed. (M5) Year 16 and 4 of our lords Galerius Valerius Maximianus Augustus and Galerius Valerius Maximinus Caesar, 5 before the Calends of May.
    (M6) Aurelius Euporos, former magistrate, councillor, epimeletes of gold, to Aurelii Heras and Taesis greeting. I have received from you for the assessment imposed according to the divine command for the village horiodiktia of Karanis, three, a fourth, an eighth, a sixteenth grams, that is, gr. 3 1/4, 1/8, 1/16. (M7) I, Gerontios, have signed. (M6) Year 16 and 4 of our lords Galerius Valerius Maximianus Augustus and Maximinus the most noble Caesar, 2 before the Calends of May. I, Neilos, his son, have signed.
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. VII 138 <note>Related text: P.Mert. I 31, in the same hand; plate, P.Col. VII, Microfiche 1</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:7:138</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>