<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>Sale [160-161 AD]</title>
        <author>Sarapion, son of Apollonios</author>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <authority>APIS</authority>
        <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p257</idno>
        <idno type="controlno">(NNC)aaa1181</idno>
      </publicationStmt>
      <sourceDesc>
        <msDesc>
          <msIdentifier>
            <idno type="invno">Col.inv. 551</idno>
          </msIdentifier>
          <msContents>
            <summary>Sale of the slave Didymos by Sarapion to Agathos Daimon; Sarapion had already
              received a golden ring that he returned when he received the price of the
              slave</summary>
            <msItem>
              <note type="general">Written across the fibers; on the front there is P.Col. VIII
                207</note>
              <note type="general">69 lines of writing in 2 cols.; the hands are 3: the first and
                the third are fast cursive hands; the third is minute and roughly bilinear</note>
              <note type="general">The papyrus underwent a process of silking in the past</note>
              <note type="general">The price is stated both in silver and in bronze currency</note>
              <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
            </msItem>
          </msContents>
          <physDesc>
            <objectDesc>
              <supportDesc>
                <support>1papyrus fragment ; 12.7 x 16 cm</support>
              </supportDesc>
            </objectDesc>
          </physDesc>
          <history>
            <origin>
              <origDate notBefore="0160" notAfter="0161"/>
            </origin>
            <provenance>
              <p>Purchased by Columbia University from M. Nahman through A.E.R. Boak in 1932; no. 6
                in Bell</p>
            </provenance>
          </history>
        </msDesc>
      </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <profileDesc>
      <langUsage>
        <language ident="en">English</language>
        <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
      </langUsage>
      <textClass>
        <keywords scheme="#apis">
          <term>Sale of slaves</term>
          <term>
            <rs type="genre_form">Papyri</rs>
          </term>
          <term>
            <rs type="genre_form">Papyri</rs>
          </term>
        </keywords>
      </textClass>
    </profileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
        <ab> [To the agoranomoi of Oxyrhynchos from Sarapion son of Apollonios, grandson of Apion. I
          swear by the Emperor Caesar] Titus Aelius Hadrian Antoninus Augustus Pius that I have sold
          to Agathos Daimon, freedman of Herakleides and Sarapion alias Dorion, both sons of
          Sarapion, from the same city, the house-born slave belonging to me, which came to me from
          inheritance from my father's paternal uncle and adoptive father, the deceased Zoilos,
          (namely) Didymos, as is and not subject to rejection except for the sacred disease and
          epaphe, and that he is mine and neither mortgaged to others nor alienated in any fashion,
          and that I have received the [thousand three hundred drachmas] of silver of the price,
          [and that I confirm the sale. May it be well to me if I have sworn truly, but the reverse
          if I am forsworn. I, so-and-so, wrote on behalf of him because he was illiterate. Year
          twenty-fourth of Emperor Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrian Antoninus, (month and day) ]. [Year
          twenty-fourth of the Emperor Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrian Antoninus Augustus Pius, (month,
          day, in Oxyrhynchos). Agathos Daimon, freedman of Herakleides and Sarapion bought from
          Sarapion son of Apollonios and ---, grandson of Apion] in the street, the house-born slave
          belonging to him, [which came to him from] inheritance from his father's paternal uncle
          and [adoptive father], the deceased Zoilos son of Zoilos and Sinthoonis, grandson of
          Apion, (namely) Didymos, aged 25, without scar, for whom Sarapion received a golden
          finger-ring as arrabon from Agathos Daimon already on the second epagomenal day of the
          past twenty-third year, from which also Agathos Daimon paid the taxes for the sales-tax of
          the same slave on the same epagomenal days, which slave Didymos Agathos Daimon has
          received herewith from Sarapion, as is and not subject to rejection except for the sacred
          disease and epaphe, and Sarapion has received the agreed-upon one thousand three hundred
          drachmas of imperial silver currency for the price of the [same] slave from Agathos Daimon
          in full, in the form of ten talents three thousand (drachmas) of copper, [and] Sarapion,
          who also returned to Agathos Daimon herewith the golden finger-ring which he had on
          account of arrabon in the same street, sells and confirms the same slave Didymos as stated
          above. Agathos Daimon, freedman of Herakleides and Sarapion alias Dorion, both sons of
          Sarapion, bought as aforesaid. I, Sarapion son of Apollonios, grandson of Apion, sold the
          slave to Agathos Daimon ... </ab>
      </div>
      <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
        <listBibl>
          <bibl>P.Col. VIII 222 <note>Published by W.L. Westermann, Aegyptus 13 (1933) 229-37 (SB V
              7533); plate 32 in P.Col. VIII. Observations and corrections in BL X p. 42</note>
          </bibl>
          <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:8:222</bibl>
        </listBibl>
      </div>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
