<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Contract [July-August 287 AD]</title>
            <author>Aurelius Hol, son of Kopres, komarch</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p314</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1238</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.10.281</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;10;281</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;10;281</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10564</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10564</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 31</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Agreement cncerning the appointment of komarchs of Philadelphia for three successive years: Aurelius Hol agrees to nominate Cornelius to the post on condition that Cornelius nominate Hol's brother for the following term</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; the back is blank</note>
                     <note type="general">26 lines of writing by 2 different hands: the main hand is a standard cursive, while the second is faster, smaller, and writes with a finer pen</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus, broken at the bottom and with the right margin frayed ; 15 x 22.5 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0287">287 CE</origDate>
                     <persName type="asn">Cornelius, son of Posis</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from M. Nahman through H.I. Bell, on July 1923; no. 40 (IV 26) in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Agreement; office of Komarch</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>The Aurelii Hol son of Kopres, whose mother is Apilla, from the village of Philadelphia, komarch of the current (year) 3 and 2, and Cornelius son of Posis, whose mother is Juliana, from the same village, greetings to one another. Whereas I am komarch of the same village, therefore we have mutually agreed that I, Hol, will nominate you, Cornelius, to the komarchy of the same village for the coming year, you completing the designated one year term; and when I, Cornelius, have discharged my duties in like manner, I too will nominate your brother, Dioskoros, for the next year, he completing the same one year period; and likewise I, Hol, stand as surety . . . brother, [Dio]skoros, for [the s]ame period (?)], just as neither of us will be permitted [to breach] the terms of the written agreement forcibly; but if either party should [wrong] the other concerning this matter, the transgressor will pay to the abiding party 2,000 silver drachmas as a penalty and on account of the injury because it was on these terms that they mutually agreed; and in reply to the formal question, we agreed.
(2nd hand) Aure(lius) Hol, about thirty years of age, with a scar above his right brow.
(1st hand) (Year) 3 of our Lord D[i]ocle[tianus and (year) 2] of our Lord [Ma]x[i]mianus Aug[usti . . .
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. X 281 <note>Plate 38 in P.Col. X; published by D. Delia and E. Haley, BASP 20 (1983) 39-47 (SB XVI 12829)</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:10:281</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>