<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter [Late II AD]</title>
            <author>Ammonianos, son of Apollinarios</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p260</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1184</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.8.225</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;8;225</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;8;225</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">27233</idno>
            <idno type="TM">27233</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 320</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Private letter from a son to his father about sending of supplies, a letter of introduction and another document</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; on the back there is the address</note>
                     <note type="general">26 lines of writing on the front and 2 on the back by a medium-size clear hand</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus ; 10.2 x 21.7 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0170" notAfter="0199">170 CE – 199 CE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from Dr. Kondilios through H.I. Bell in July 1925; no. 156 in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Letter</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Ammonianos to Apollinarios his father, many greetings.  Before everything I pray that you are in good health, and I make obeisance for you every day before the lord Sarapis.  I informed you also through Antas that if you want us to stay here through the winter, you should let us know quickly so that we may know what you wish and act accordingly.  I sent to you through him a small basket containing 10 dried fish and 4 pairs of sandals and 4 baskets of empty jars and the letter of introduction and the professio of Herennius.  I want you to know that Marius the beneficiarius took your name and description and says, "Let him come to me and he will find me ready for whatever he wants."  For such are the instructions that Iulianus gave him repeatedly concerning you.  For he is a very great friend of his.  My mother greets all of you, and Iulianus and Kyrillous and Kyria and Ignatius and Paulinus and Isiakos .  Greet warmly my father Diogenes and all those in the house by name.  I pray for your health.
Verso: . . . Deliver to Apollinarios from Ammonianos his son.
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. VIII 225 <note>Published by C.W. Keyes, CP 30 (1935) 148-50 (SB V 7662); correction to line 22 (Kyrillous, see BL VIII p. 331 to SB V 7662); plate 35 in P.Col. VIII</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:8:225</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>