<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lease [May 23, 142 AD]</title>
            <author>Chairemon, son of Chairemon</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p290</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1214</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.10.257</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;10;257</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;10;257</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10558</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10558</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 326</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Chairemon is placing a second, higher bid for the lease of a confiscated property; the bid is preceded by a cover letter addressed to the superintendents of confiscated property</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; the back is blank</note>
                     <note type="general">23 lines of writing apparently from the same hand; the signature in line 8 is by a second hand</note>
                     <note type="general">Probably a copy (retained by Chairemon) of the original</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus, lacking the top right portion ; 11.3 x 20.5 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0142">142 CE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from Dr. Kondilios through H.I. Bell in July 1925; no. 182 in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Sarapion, -- royal scribe</term>
               <term>Lease; confiscated property</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>To the superintendents of sequestered property of Bacchias. Having secured . . . the profit to the fiscus, the responsibility and risk to be yours if you either receive the bid of another, without giving notice to me, or act improperly. In the fifth year of Antoninus Caesar the lord, Pachon 28. (2 H.) I, Sarapion, have signed.
To Sarapion, royal scribe of the Herakleides division of the Arsinoite Nome, from Chairemon son of Chairemon, grandson of Apollonios, from the Syrian ward. I wish to introduce a supplementary bid to the one by which I undertook to lease, in the present year in the month of Pharmouthi, the house and yard in Bacchias from the confiscated property formerly belonging to Apynchis son of Peteuris, for five years for an annual rent in total instead of the eight drachmas promised before by me per year, each year twenty drachmas, which I will pay on the customary appointed days, and after the period of five years I will return it as I received it, if you agree to give the lease.
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. X 257 <note>Plate in P.Col. X; published by J. Sheridan, BASP 24 (1987) 103-108, with plate on p. 106; cf. D. Hagedorn, ZPE 86 (1991) 245-46</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:10:257</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>