<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Receipts [296-298 AD]</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p174</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1261</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.7.136</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;7;136</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;7;136</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10489</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10489</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 67 + 66</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Receipts for transporation charges, price of wine, wheat and other taxes; after col. 1 all the other receipts were written as continuous text by Aurelius Paesis</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; the back is blank; in all 54 lines of writing</note>
                     <note type="general">Written by 2 hands: the first (col. 1) is more inclined to the right than the other (rest of papyrus)</note>
                     <note type="general">Dark brown papyrus, parts of which are black; the height of the roll is common to rolls of this period used for tax receipts</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>2papyrus sheets ; 59 x 12 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0296" notAfter="0298">296 CE – 298 CE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from M. Nahman through H.I. Bell, in 1924; nos. 24 and 23 in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Sarapion, -- son of Onnophris</term>
               <term>Aurelius Pelenis, -- tax collector</term>
               <term>Aurelius Ptollas, -- tax collector</term>
               <term>Receipts</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>    Column I
    
    Year 12 and 11 of our lords Diocletianus and Maximianus Augusti and 4 of Constantius and Maximianus the most noble Caesars Augusti, Epeiph 8. Sarapion son of Onnophris and Chairemon son of Sarapion and Chairemon son of Kopres paid through Isidoros the transportation charges on goods and on salgamum and the price of wine for the 5th epigraphe, a thousand six hundred drachmas, dr. 1600. (M2) We, Aurelii Pelenis and Isidoros, apaitetai, have signed. (M3) We, Aurelii Ptollas and Pankrates, apaitetai, have signed.
    
    Column II
    
    (M4) Year 12 and 11 and 4 of our lords Diocletianus and Maximianus Augusti and Constantius and Maximianus the most noble Caesars, Mesore 11. Aurelil Paesis [and] Leonides and Syrion and Isidoros [all 4] receivers of grain of the village of Karanis: measured [to us] in the granary of the same village by the level public measure.... We, Aurelii Paesis and Leonides and Syrion [and Isidoros, have signed]. I, Paesis, wrote for them since they are illiterate.
    
    Column III
    
    Year 12 and 11 and 4 of our lords Diocletianus and Maximianus Augusti and Constantius [and] Maximianus the most noble Caesars, Mesore 11. Aurelii Paesis [and] Leonides and Isidoros and Syrion, all 4 receivers of grain of the village of Karanis: measured to us in the granary of the same village by the level public measure for the present 12th and 11th and 4th year for the village of Karanis, in the name of Chairemon son of Sarapion, through Isidoros, twenty artabas of clean wheat, that is, art. 20. And for the name of Ptolemaios son of Chairemon through the heirs of Kopres, five artabas of clean wheat, that is, art. 5. And for the horiodiktia in the name of Kopres, one artaba of clean wheat, and for the name of Sarapion son of Onnophris through Isidoros, eleven artabas of clean wheat, that is, art. 11.
    
    Column IV
    
    And for the sowing, twenty and a half artabas of clean wheat, that is, art. 20 1/2. Total for the receipt, art. of wheat 57 1/2. We, Aurelii Paesis and Leonides and Syrion and Isidoros, have signed. I, Paesis, wrote for my partners since they are illiterate. 
    The same Isidoros measured for the name of Sarapion son of Onnophris three artabas of clean wheat, that is, art. 3.
    And in the 14th and 13th and 6th year, Mecheir 30, he paid the price of wheat for the produce of the 12th and 11th and 4th year for the sowing of the horiodiktia, seven hundred twenty drachmas, that is, dr. 720 and the obols and the deposit charge on them. We, Aurelii Paesis and his partners, have signed.
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. VII 136 <note>Related text: P.Cair.Isid. 37, very similar; plate, P.Col. VII, Microfiche 1</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:7:136</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>