<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter September 7, 258</title>
            <author>Philotas, 2 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 437</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p2</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1314</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.3.3</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;3;3</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;3;3</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">1428</idno>
            <idno type="TM">1428</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 299</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Letter of Philotas to Zenon from Syria regarding payment of taxes upon some runaway slaves to be purchased; according to Apollophanes and another agent, Philotas should reach an agreement with the tax collectors; Philotas consulted Herodes; the slaves were then guarded by Herakleides</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Incomplete; written across the fibers with 12 lines; top, bottom and most of right margins preserved</note>
                     <note type="general">Address in the back, along the fibers; there are also very faded traces of other writing</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus fragment ; 8 x 20.5 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="-0258">258 BCE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from Dr. Kondilios through H.I. Bell in July 1925; no. 110 in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Apollophanes, -- 2 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 291.</term>
               <term>Herakleides, -- 12 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 337.</term>
               <term>Herodes, -- 1 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 338.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Philotas to Zenon, greeting. _____ has asked me to write to you regarding the slaves which ran away from _____. But I have not done so because my time has been consumed by Apollophanes and _____ himself (who demanded) that I assist them in dealing with the tax farmers and pay to _____ ______ as soon as possible (what is owing to them). When I went for this purpose to Herodes the tax farmer I found that ____ had already made an agreement with him to pay  in full a tax of 80 drachmas to Apollophanes. Therefore I first annulled the contract; and I am making another contract to pay half to Apollophanes, so that I have taken 40 drachmas off the tax agreed upon; and I have come to an agreement with (Herodes regarding the incidental fees?) And I brought in the slaves to Herakleides and gave (them over to him [?], since) he said that he would guard them. He did not permit me to conduct the affair though I wished (to guard them myself). I have therefore written to you that you may be informed. You would do me a favor by purchasing and sending to me the things about which (I have already written) you. You also write regarding any favors which you may desire, (knowing that I will do them for you) eagerly.     Year  28, Panemos 27    [Verso, docket:] From Philotas.        To Zenon.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. III 3 P.Col.Zen. I 3 PSI VI 602 preserves left part (central part of the lines missing) PSI 863 (g) P.Cair.Zen. V 59804, new edition of all the pieces <note>About lines 1-4 see Edgar, Archiv 11 (1935) 219, note 1; on line 4 see Wegener (BL. III p. 41); on line 10, see Youtie, AJP 56 (1935) 178</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:3:3</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>