<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letters [ca. summer of 244 BC]</title>
            <author>Apollonios, secretary of Eukles, 14 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 293</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p86</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1398</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.4.87</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;4;87</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;4;87</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">1800</idno>
            <idno type="TM">1800</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv.214 verso</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Drafts of letters to Eukles by Apollonios, his chief secretary; the main subject is the rebates granted to farmers upon the rent of the land formerly held by Apollonios the dioiketes; after surveying the situation, the secretary requests that someone, and possibly Eukles himself, be sent to settle the accounts with the farmers; Apollonios also refers to some Syrian workers</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">26 lines written across the fibers; on the other side there is P.Col. IV 88</note>
                     <note type="general">The hand is small and proficient, but the text shows lots of minute interlinear corrections and additions, since it is a draft</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus fragment, broken at bottom ; 12 x 30 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="-0244">244 BCE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from M. Nahman and New York dealer J. Brummer, through H.I. Bell, November 1925; no. 11 (original no. 9) in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Eukles, -- 1 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 329</term>
               <term>Many people mentioned, -- see Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, sec. IX</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab> [Erased line:] To Eukles from Apollonios greeting. I have sent you - - - -
To Eukles. I have made up the grain account of the leasing of year 3 on the basis of the remission granted in accordance with the decision taken in Memphis, and I find that the overpayments, as converted into wheat, are 4430 artabs and that the remainder of the price of - - - which is at the bank - - - - -- at the value of the 2000 (artabs) already measured, totals, on the copper standard, 500 (drachmas); and that the same is likewise true on the basis of the accounting by individuals. For, whereas Aristandros formerly, according to the (original) survey, owed 750 artabs in wheat conversion he now pays in a surplus of 600 artabs according to the remission granted. Therefore, if you please, preferably send Herakleides the farmer, if he has the time, but if not, let him send an order to Herakleides the sitologos, or let him send Chairigenes, in order that if possible he may reject - - - (or ask) me to present the accounting by individuals in order that the (remainder) from the farmers (may not be lost to the royal revenues [?]. For if they) make the repayment of surplus in the produce of year 2, it will be satisfactory. If the account is rendered still showing discrepancies, it will be difficult. For I have not met with the temple scribes or those serving with Alexander. For it would be most desirable to compare the grain accounts so that, if you devised some better plan, we might there in your presence follow it. But as to the Syrian laborers, of whom you state in the list of the workmen that some are engaged in the vineyard work, and others at the farming, I think you are not unaware that they have been taken away.
</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. IV 87 P.Col.Zen. II 87 <note>Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 201: year 2-3 of Ptolemy III; corrections to lines 1-6 by H. Cuvigny, "L'arpentage par esp*egces" pp. 28-29, and correction to line 3-4 by S. Follet in Cuvigny's vol.; reprinted by R. Scholl, "Corpus der ptolem*auischen Sklaventexte" (1990) no. 172 with corrections to lines 12 and 17; corrections to lines 23-24 by Scholl, "Sklaverei in den Zenonpapyri" p. 91</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:4:87</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>