<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>List [Early III AD ?]</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p265</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1189</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.8.230</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;8;230</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;8;230</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">30718</idno>
            <idno type="TM">30718</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 752</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>List of nominees for sitologos: at least 31 names are mentioned for Karanis and 21 names for the harbor of Kerke</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">68 lines in two cols. by a practiced hand, which is inclined to the right and could even belong to the IV AD</note>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; back blank</note>
                     <note type="general">Perhaps the document is a preliminary draft</note>
                     <note type="general">Some of the names are marked by checks in the left margin</note>
                     <note type="general">It is surprising that Karanis is linked with Kerke, rather than Philadelphia</note>
                     <note type="general">Dated, with some uncertainty, on the basis that instances of selection by lot do not seem to occur after 230 AD; the appearance of deacons in lines 18 and 47 raises the question if they belonged to the Christian diaconate and the document should be dated to the IV century</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus fragment, broken at the bottom and perhaps at left ; 23.7 x 25.8 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0201" notAfter="0230">201 CE – 230 CE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from Prof. Jeffery in 1946; no. 55 in the inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Iulius, -- son of Eudas, sitologos</term>
               <term>List of nominees for sitologos</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Column I    For Karanis.  Local sitologoi:  Harpalos son of fPtolemaios, likewise 800 drachmas.  Iulius son of Ptolemaios and (or grandson of) Tasieus, likewise 700 drachmas.  Syrion son of Abous, likewise 800 drachmas.  Sarapion son of Ammonas, grandson of Ptolemaios, likewise 700 drachmas.  Moros son of Sempronius, likewise 800 drachmas.  Ptolemaios son of -- , grandson of Isnthreus, likewise 700 drachmas.  Petheus, laborer of Dioskoros, likewise 800 drachmas.  Sarap--  son of -- , grandson of Ischyras, likewise 700 drachmas.  Seuthes son of [Ho?]rion, likewise 800 drachmas.  Leonides son of Sarapion, likewise 700 drachmas.  Demetrios son of Phantio(  ), likewise 800 drachmas.  Sabinus son of Ischyras, likewise 700 drachmas.  Sapros son of Koprilla, likewise 800 drachmas.  Syrion de(  ), likewise 700 drachmas.  Tourbon son of Eleis, likewise 800 drachmas.  Anchophis servant, likewise 700 drachmas.  Onnophris son of Kmeeis, likewise 700 drachmas.  Neilos ..., likewise 700 drachmas.  Hatres ..., gardener, likewise 800 drachmas.  Horos ..., cake-baker (?), likewise 700 drachmas.  Mieus son of Apollonios, likewise 800 ddrachmas.  Panouphis son of Kmeis, likewise 700 drachmas.  Petesouchos son of Petesouchos, likewise 800 drachmas.  Ision son of Aphrodisios, likewise 700 drachmas.  Ptolemaios son of Ammon, grandson of Nikoeis, likewise 800 drachmas.  P--- son of NN and Tamystha, likewise 700 drachmas.  Anchoophis son of Horieusis, grandson of Petheus, his mother Tolis, likewise 800 drachmas.  Esouris son of Antonius, shepherd, likewise 700 drachmas.  Apollos son of Phaseis, grandson of Pouteis, likewise 800 drachmas.  Petheus son of Kmeeis, likewise 700 drachmas.  Abous son of Sotas, grandson of Psenasein, likewise 800 drachmas.    Column II    Pakysis son of Psenamounis, likewise 700 drachmas.  Abous son of Sotas, likewise 800 drachmas.  Ptolemaios son of Korax, likewise 700 drachmas.  Apolinarius, laborer of Horion, likewise 800 drachmas.  Iulius Eudas, likewise 700 drachmas.  Kalaelpis (?) son of Petheus, likewise 800 drachmas.  Ptolemaios son of Chairemon, lame, likewise 700 drachmas.  Sokrates son of Themeus, cowherd, likewise 800 drachmas.  Kerdon son of Rufus, likewise 700 drachmas.  Paesis son of Ptolemaios, barber, likewise 800 drachmas.  Echel, oilmaker, likewise 700 drachmas.    For the harbor of Kerke:  Sansneus servant, likewise 800 drachmas.  Kastor son of Petheus, cowherd (?), likewise 700 drachmas.  Dioskoros son of Kiamoul, likewise 800 drachmas.  Ptolemaios son of Iason, likewise 700 drachmas.  Ammonios son of Touamsaithis, likewise 800 drachmas.  Kelolis cowherd, likewise 700 drachmas.  Petermouthis son of Soteis, likewise 800 drachmas.  Horion son of Bacchion, likewise 700 drachmas.  Plein cowherd, likewise 800 drachmas.  Petermouthis son of Kametis, likewise 700 drachmas.  Horos son of Pl-- , likewise 800 drachmas.  Sarapion son of Satabous, grandson of Strouthos, likewise 700 drachmas.  Aunes son of Sabel, likewise 800 drachmas.  Polion son of Panameus, likewise 700 drachmas.  Ptolemaios son of P-- , likewise 800 drachmas.  Pakysis son of -- , likewise 700 drachmas.  Paneilos son of Kelolis, likewise 800 drachmas.  Horigenes son of Kyrilla, likewise 700 drachmas.  Pabous son of K-- , moneychanger, likewise 800 drachmas.  Saras son of NN, likewise 700 drachmas.  Pasis, business agent of Aretion, likewise 800 drachmas.  NN, likewise 700 drachmas.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. VIII 230 <note>Plate 40 in P.Col. VIII</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:8:230</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>