<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lease [August 24-29 311 AD]</title>
            <author>Aurelius Pareitis, son of Paulos</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p317</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1241</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.10.284</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;10;284</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;10;284</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">22276</idno>
            <idno type="TM">22276</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 41 +</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Application for a two-year lease of vineyard irrigation by Pareitis; the vineyard belonged to 3 women</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; the back is blank</note>
                     <note type="general">The papyrus suffered from abrasion and folding</note>
                     <note type="general">22 lines of writing in a ligatured hand bent to the right</note>
                     <note type="general">The papyrus is a duplicate of P.Heid. V 344, which helps in restoring some lacunae</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus fragment ; 19.8 x 13.1 cm. (Col.)</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0311">311 CE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from M. Nahman through H.I. Bell, in July 1923; no. 50 (III.23) in Bell</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Aurelius Serenos, -- scribe</term>
               <term>Lease of vineyard irrigation</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>In the consulship of our masters Galerius Valerius Maximianus Augustus for the eighth time and Galerius Valerius Maximinus Augustus for the second time. To Aurelia Techosous also called Eudaimonis and Aurelia Eudaimonis also called Horigenia and Aurelia . . ., from Aurelius Pareitis son of Paulos and Thaisous, from your epoikion called Petrok near the village of Dositheou. I willingly undertake to lease for a period of two years from the first day of the month of Hathyr of the incoming 20th and 8th year, all the irrigating operations of the third share from the enclosed vineyard belonging to you called Petrok, which is the aroura of Apphous, whatever the area of the whole portion in arouras may be, which irrigation I shall perform . . . (7) irrigation machines at the proper times and to your satisfaction, with the concurrence of your agents (8) in everything . . . and I shall necessarily perform all the labors at the proper times, the labors of maintaining the dikes and the irrigations . . . (9) . . . the share of the wine pertaining to me on the same terms as the other lessees (10) and further, to possess the share of the vineyard and the share of the sale of fruits of the date-palms and fruit-trees that falls to me and (11) having finished completely all the aforementioned and the extra payments on the twenty-eighth day of Pharmouthi and at the (12) vintage and having on loan two young oxen and which advance payment I shall receive . . . (13) and I shall perform all the labors and the other customary . . . (14) . . . and I undertake to lease for these two years from the incoming 20th and 8th year . . . (15) . . . cultivating the lots and the  . . . (16) . . . in the presence of the aforesaid Apphous which he shall cultivate, (17) everything guaranteed against any risk. When this undertaking is secured to me I will of necessity accomplish all the operations at their proper time, without delay and everything done at the proper time, and at the end of the period I shall return the vineyard cared for with the irrigations and the plants living and flourishing always, and you have the right of execution against me and against all my property. The undertaking is normative and after having been formally questioned I have agreed. In the aforesaid consulship, Mesore epagomenal day -. I, Aurelia --, have received the copy of this document. (2 H.) I, Aurelius Serenus and however I am styled wrote on her behalf since she is illiterate.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. X 284 <note>Plate 41 in P.Col. X; published by B.E. Nielsen, ZPE 106 (1995) 179-88 and Tafel V; reference in BL XI p. 65</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:10:284</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>