<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Sale [August 26, 178 AD]</title>
            <author>Asklas, son of Asklas</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p296</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1220</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.10.263</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;10;263</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;10;263</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">22264</idno>
            <idno type="TM">22264</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 20</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Sale of a female donkey by Asklas to Epimachos, from Philadelphia</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Written along the fibers; the back is blank</note>
                     <note type="general">28 lines of writing by 2 hands: the main hand is ligatured and slightly bent to the right, while the hand of the subscriber is smaller and upright</note>
                     <note type="general">The price seems relatively high</note>
                     <note type="general">The buyer may be identical with the Epimachos mentioned in P.Oxy. XLI 2981 and may have been a dealer in animals</note>
                     <note type="general">It is notable that the buyer is from the Fayum and that probably he was not buying for his own use, but to resell; A. Joerdens, Tyche 10 (1995) 37-100, argues that this was not usually the case</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus ; 15.9 x 6.3 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0178">178 CE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from M. Nahman through H.I. Bell, in July 1923; no. 28 (IV.24) in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Epimachos, -- son of Ploution</term>
               <term>Sale of a donkey</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Asklas son of Asklas, from Memphis, acknowledges to Epimachos son of Ploution, from the village of Philadelphia of the Arsinoite (nome), that he, Asklas, has sold to Epimachos an ostrakon-colored female donkey which has a small bump on the middle of its belly and that herewith Asklas has received from Epimachos a mutually agreed-upon price of 172 drachmas of silver and Asklas will guarantee this sale in every way from any complainant.  18th year of the Emperors Caesars Marcus Aurelius Antoninus and Commodus Armeniaci Medici Parthici Germanici Sarmatici Maximi, epagomenai 3. Asklas, about 65 years old, with a scar on his left hand.  (Second Hand) I, Asklas son of Asklas, agree that I have sold the donkey and that I have received the price of 172 drachmas of silver and will guarantee this to you with every guarantee.  I, Apollonios son of Ptollas, wrote this on his behalf [because he is illiterate.]</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. X 263 <note>Plate 17 in P.Col. X.</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:10:263</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>