<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Petition [end of 245 or early 244 BC]</title>
            <author>Antipatros, 4 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 289</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">columbia.apis.p82</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNC)aaa1394</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.col.4.83</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0094;4;83</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.col;4;83</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">1796</idno>
            <idno type="TM">1796</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Col.inv. 272</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Petition of Antipatros, a resident of Philadelphia, against Nikon: Antipatros' wife, Simon, borrowed money from Nikon at an usurious rate; Antipatros left Philadelphia because of some trouble and brought his wife and son to Hermopolis, where he opened a shop; the creditor followed them, threatened Simon and induced her and her son to follow him; Simon escaped but the boy was still in detention</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">18 lines written along the fibers in a clear and calligraphic hand with no corrections</note>
                     <note type="general">On the back there are two erasures</note>
                     <note type="general">There is no notation of the strategos recommending some action by Zenon; since the petition was found among his papers, it is to be assumed that the matter was referred to Zenon in a covering letter</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1papyrus ; 33.5 x 23 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="-0245" notAfter="-0244">245 BCE – 244 BCE</origDate>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>Purchased by Columbia University from Dr. Kondilios through H.I. Bell in July 1925; no. 30 in Bell's inventory</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term>Nikon, -- 7 in Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 377</term>
               <term>Other people, -- see Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, sec. IX</term>
               <term>Interest rate in loans; usury; enslavement</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>To King Ptolemy greeting from Antipatros, resident of Philadelphia. I am being wronged by Nikon. For having loaned seventy silver drachmas to my wife Simon at an interest rate of six drachmas per mina each month and having totaled (the interest) with the principal he drew up a contract of loan with her for 115 drachmas in which I myself was entered as security.  After I had gone away from Philadelphia because I was being falsely accused by Artemidoros, agent of Apollonios, the dioecetes, and had opened a shop in Upper Hermopolis, Nikon wrote a letter to Philadelphia to a certain Menestratos who belongs to our family in which he includes the statement, made upon royal oath, that he will draw up an agreement with us for the principal by itself, namely, the seventy drachmas. When Menestratos wrote me at Hermopolis to come to Philadelphia and I sailed down there, Nikon sailed up to   Hermopolis and said that he would hand my wife over to the praktor in the matter of the loan unless she followed him of her own accord. Simon, impelled by fear, sailed down with Nikon together with her boy, and Nikon led them to Herakleopolis and shut them up with certain persons, apart from each other. Then Simon escaped and came away; but the boy he holds in detention even now. And when we demand that he give him back, sometimes he acknowledges that he has seized him as pledge for the debt and is still holding him, sometimes he denies it. I beg you therefore, O King, to send my petition to the chremalistai, and if I prove that the allegations set forth in the petition are true, I beg that Nikon may meet with fitting punishment both in the matter of the interest which he has contracted for contrary to the ordinance and because by his own authority he has placed in  detention and holds (the boy), a free person; and I beg that the boy be restored to me in order that I, having fled to you for help, O King, may meet with justice.  Farewell.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Col. IV 83 P.Col.Zen. II 83 <note>Hengstl, "Griechischen Papyri aus *Augypten" no. 41; plate in P.Col.  IV facing p. 84; the left hand portion stands on the cover of BASP starting from vol. 13 (1976); related texts: SB III 6763 and Pap.Lugd.Bat. XX 21; Rupprecht, "Darlehen," "M*uunchener Beitr*auge zur Papyrusforschung" 51 (1967) 86-87; correction to line 6 by van Groningen, BL III p. 45 and to line 9 by Boswinkel, Pap.Lugd.Bat. XXI, p. 128</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Col.:4:83</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>