<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter</title>
            <author>Valerius Paulinus alias Ammonas</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3466</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3466</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.6.9636</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;6;9636</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;6;9636</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">45063</idno>
            <idno type="TM">45063</idno>
            <idno type="filename">45063-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P. Corn. inv. I 64</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.492925-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>"Valerius Paulinus also called Ammonas, to his brother Valerius Apollinarius, warmest greeting. I want you to know that I am in service next year only, and (then) I am released: if the god wishes, I will come to reverence your countenance along with the ancestral gods. Now then I ask you, receive with my recommendation the discharged soldierTerentianus who brings you this letter, and let him know what sort of villagers we have, lest he get into trouble. Since he is a man of means and desirous of residing there, I have urged upon him that he pay for my house for the current year (a rental of) 60 drachmas, and that he have my field on lease for the coming 21st year of Hadrianus Caesar for 60 drachmas, and that with the 120 drachmas he buy for me through you from our friend the linen-merchant by the precinct in the city two . . . and two couches and two pillows (?) with their stuffing and . . .";(Along the left edge of the papyrus, written from top to bottom): "Eat yours (?) and drink. If you don't have, I'll give: don't worry.";(Adress on verso): " . . . letter (?) of Paulinus, discharged soldier, to Apollonius . . . his brother."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Silvia Strassi, SB VI 9636 (P.Cornell I, 64) e l'archivio di Tiberianus, in Michele Faraguna - Vanna Vedaldi Labez, Studi in onore di Filippo Cassola. Dunasthai didaskein, Trieste 2006, 361-373 Lewis N, TAPA 90, 139-146, 1959 -- SB VI, 9636 Lewis N, in Hanson A E (ed.), On Goverment and Law in Roman Egypt, ASP 33, 65-72, 1995</bibl>
               
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
