<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Receipt for payments of syntaximon and merismoi</title>
            <author>Hereus, son of Harpagathes and Tanouphis</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">oslo.apis.61</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NoOU)61</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.24.16185</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;24;16185</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;24;16185</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">45408</idno>
            <idno type="TM">45408</idno>
            <idno type="filename">45408-1</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Oslo inv. 1509</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:31.275553-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>Section 1:;In the thirteenth year of the Emperor Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrianus Antoninus Augustus Pius: on the 27th of Phaophi, Hereus, son of Harpagathes, son of Hereus, his mother being Tanouphis, has paid through Charmion and his fellow tax collectors at Soknopaiou Nesos for the syntaximon of the same year eight drachmae, total 8. And on the 24th of Hathyr likewise (has paid) another four drachmae, total 4. On the 27th of the month Hadrianus likewise (has paid) four drachmae, (total) 4. On the 28th of Tybi likewise 8 drachmae, (total) 8. On the 25th of Mecheir likewise another eight drachmae, total 8 drachmae. On the twenty sixth of Phamenoth likewise another four drachmae, total 4 drachmae. On the twenty first of Pachon likewise for the support of the guards two drachmae and three and a half obols, total 2 dr. 3 1/2 obols. For the river guard one obol. On the twenty second of Payni likewise another eight drachmae, half of an obol and two chalkoi, total 8 dr., 1/2 obol, 2 chalkoi. For support of the watchtower guards 4 1/2 obols. For the support of the prison guards 1 obol. For the billeting of soldiers 1 obol. For the animal tax 1/2 obol and 2 chalkoi.On the 28th of Epeiph likewise for the support of the poor eight drachmae, total 8 dr. On the 21st of Mesore likewise for the tax for the support of the poor another four drachmae, total 4 dr. On the 30th of Mesore likewise another three drachmae and three obols, total 3 dr. and 3 obols. For the support of the guards another one drachma and five obols, total 1 dr. and 5 obols.;Section 2:;In the fourteenth year: on the 13th of Phaophi, the same (person) has paid through Apynchis and his fellow tax collectors from Soknopaiou Nesos for the syntaximon for the same year twelve drachmae, total 12 dr. On the 7th of Hathyr likewise another four drachmae, total 4 dr. On the 3rd of Hadrianus likewise another four drachmae, total 4 dr. Likewise another four drachmae, total 4 dr. On the 3rd of Tybi likwise another 4 drachmae, total 4 dr. On the 25th of Mecheir likewise another four drachmae, total 4 dr.On the 26th of Phamenoth four drachmae, total 4 dr. On the 24th of Pharmouti likewise another four drachmae, total 4 dr. On the 20th of Pachon likewise 1/2 obol and two chalkoi. For the support of the guards  two drachmae and four obols, total 2 dr., 4 obols. For the watchtower guard three obols. On the 26th of Payni likewise another (four drachmae), total 4 dr. For the support of the guards ( ). For the support of the watchtower guard one obol. For the river guard 2 1/2 obols and 2 chalkoi. For the prison guard one obol. For the billeting of soldiers one obol. For the animal tax one obol. For the support of the poor four drachmae, total 4 dr. For the fifteenth year: On the 17th of the month Thoth for the tax for the poor one obol. For (the tax for the) poor fifteen drachmae and three obols, total 15 dr. and 3 obols. For the guards one obol. For the poor two drachmae and four obols, total 2 dr. and 4 ob.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
