<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Acknowledgements of Debt for Seed Advance</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <idno type="filename">1000281</idno>
            <idno type="TM">1000281</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">1000281</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid"/>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-07-21T11:16:32-05:00" who="HGV">Xwalk from Pylon</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
<p>
<milestone n="1" unit="line"/> In the name of God, the Compassionate, the Merciful.
<milestone n="2" unit="line"/> Ḥarīr b. Muḥammad has acknowledged and given testimony against himself willingly, while sound in mind and body, fully competent, under no constraint or coercion that he owes, is liable for, and is a debtor from his own funds and under his own responsibility to Muḥammad b. Ayyūb. He owes him, in sifted and winnowed |<hi rend="superscript">4</hi> clover seeds, two-thirds of an <emph rend="italics">irdabb</emph>, that constitutes a confirmed debt and an obligatory, binding right. He has acknowledged this in the presence of the witnesses of this document. He may neither dispute it, nor invoke any evidence, nor offer any excuse to be released from the debt, whose repayment is guaranteed by ʿUmar b. Aḥmad. 
<milestone n="10" unit="line"/> He has given testimony against himself in the month of Shawwāl, of year four hundred and forty-one. 
<milestone n="12" unit="line"/> Ḥafāẓ b. Kinānī testifies to all the contents of the document. 
<milestone n="13" unit="line"/> Written on his behalf with his permission and in his presence. 
<milestone n="14" unit="line"/> Jamāʿa testifies that the obligor acknowledges the content of the document. 
<milestone n="15" unit="line"/> Written in his own hand, on the date recorded in the document.
</p></div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
