<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Cair. Zen. 3, 59379</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">1022</idno>
            <idno type="TM">1022</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">1022</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.cair.zen;3;59379</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-07-18T21:00:10-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 268)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T20:57:14-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 268)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T20:56:51-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 268)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T20:56:35-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Commit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 268)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T20:53:28-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> To Zenon, greetings, Ammeneus, swineherd. Per your instructions to us for rearing the pigs for the festival of Arsinoe, 
having put my himation down as a pledge, I bought the pigs and reared them, so that you might not find fault with me. 
But as I was bringing them down, going off into the… 2 of our pigs were lost, and I found the man who had them; 
but he will return neither of them to us until you write to him, and by a crocodile… I did not take them away for myself… 
by those in the village that he may not take them (?). So write to them, and to Timotheos, so that no such thing may happen. 
And Se[..].s, concerning whom I gave you the petition, is not allowing me to graze the pigs. Farewell.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="11" unit="line"/> These are the names of the men who have taken the pigs for themselves:
K…[.]pis, son of Psenpesos, kômarchês, 1 pig.
Aristoboulos, 1 pig; I pointed him out to the phylakitai.
And at night 1 pig was lost, concerning which I went to see the phylakitai, and they said that it was at Leukippos’ house.
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 268)
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
