<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Cair. Isid., 3</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">10359</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10359</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10359</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.cair.isid;;3 sb;5;7669 chla;41;1199</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-08-30T14:05:30.845-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-30T14:05:30.837-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-07-03T00:39:51.769-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/gwschwendner">Put in the translation from P.Cair.Isid. Not sure i did the line numbering thing right.</change>
         <change when="2012-06-30T23:44:59-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <div n="1" type="textpart">
<p> 
              
The 7th consulship of our lord Diocletian Augustus and the 6th of our
lord Maximian Augustus. To Julius Septimius Sabinus censitor from Aurelia Herois, daughter of
Chaeremon, of the village of Karanis in the first and sixth toparchy of the Heraclides division of the Arsinoite nome.
In conformity with the imperial edict of our lords the invincible kings
Diocletian and Maximian, Augusti, and Constantius and Maximian, the
most noble Caesars, I declare to you that I possess land in the vicinity of
the aforementioned village of Karanis and that I have ascertained the
measurements of the arouras of my estate in the village. Aphrodisius and
Paulinus, surveyors, measured the areas in the presence of Apollonius,
Kopres, and Heron, iuratores; of Syrus, <milestone unit="line" n="10"/> assistant to the dekaprotoi of the
toparchy; and of Pannes the horiodeiktes, who have appended their signatures.
The parcels are as follows:
In the 16th section, in the hamlet called Kiamoul, three and twenty-
nine thirty-seconds arouras of uninundated royal land, 3 29/32 ar., of which the adjacent areas are: on the east a canal, beyond which is waste land entirely unowned, and on the west the estate of ... Maron.
<milestone unit="line" n="15"/> Likewise, in the hamlet called . .. nineteen sixty-fourths of an aroura of a productive olive-grove on private land, 19/64 ar., of which the adjacent
areas are: on the east waste land which is entirely unowned, and on the west a canal( ?), beyond which is the estate of Kapeiis.
Likewise, in the same hamlet, twenty-six and <milestone unit="line" n="20"/> nine sixteenths arouras of uninundated royal land, 26 9/16 ar., 
</p>
</div>
<div n="2" type="textpart">
               <p>
                 
of which the adjacent areas are: on
the east the estate of Kape'is, and on the west a canal, beyond which is the estate of Panteris.
I swear by the Tyche and Victory of our lords the invincible kings that I have made this declaration in accordance with the truth.
Year 16, 15, and 8 of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Augusti, and Constantius and Maximian, <milestone unit="line" n="25"/> the most noble Caesars, Thoth 14.
Total, in various hamlets, of uninundated royal land 30 15/32 ar. <milestone unit="line" n="30"/> of productive olive-grove on private land 19/64 ar.
(2nd hd.) I, Aurelia Herois, have declared the aforementioned arouras,
and I have ascertained the measurements as given above, with an oath by the Augusti. I, Aurelius Horion, son of Heron, have written for her since she is illiterate.
(3rd hd.) I, Aurelius Aphrodisius, surveyor, acting with my associate
surveyor Paulinus, have measured the aforementioned arouras belonging to Herois.
(4th hd.) I, Aurelius Paulinus, <milestone unit="line" n="35"/> surveyor, acting with my associate surve
yor Aphrodisius, have measured the aforementioned arouras belonging to Herois.
(5th hd.) I, Aurelius Apollonius, councillor and iurator, was present at the survey.
(6th hd.) I, Aurelius Kopres, councillor and iurator, was present at the survey.
(7th hd.) I, Aurelius Heron, councillor and iurator, was also present at the survey.
(8th hd.) I, Aurelius Syrus, assistant to the dekaprotoi of the toparchy, have verified the survey.
(9th hd.) I, Aurelius Panous, horiodeiktes, have exhibited all the aforementioned <milestone unit="line" n="40"/> arouras, and I have omitted nothing.
(10th hd.) Aurelius Herodes, didaskalos: (this declaration) was drawn in my office.
(11nth hd.) I, Julius Septimius Sabinus, censitor, have received and countersigned this declaration.
        </p>
                      </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
