<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>BASP 53 (2016) S. 110 Nr. 4</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">10554</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10554</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10554</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">basp;53;110_4 p.col;10;249</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2023-04-27T05:20:57-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> <note>Body contract</note> In the [thirty]-ninth year of the dominion of Caesar, son of a god,
                         [on the ninth of the month] Daisios, ninth of Pharmouthi, in Philagris
                         [of the Themistos meris of the Arsinoite] nome. Harthotes,
                         son of Marres, [Persian of the epigone (?)], acknowledges to Theon, son of Petermouthis, oil maker
                         of the oil mill on the estate of Livia and Germanicus Caesar in Philagris,
                         that he has received from him eighty drachmas of minted silver as a capital sum
                  <milestone n="7" unit="line"/> and in return for these he will provide his daughter Tahaunes who will remain
                         with Theon for two years and six months from the month
                         of Pachon of the present thirty-ninth year of Caesar,
                         feeding olives at the indicated oil mill as well as
                         staying and doing everything that is ordered, not being
                         absent by night or by day, but following him
                         everywhere throughout the nome, being fed and clothed by
                         Theon. <milestone n="14" unit="line"/> And for each day on which she is absent within the
                         period he will pay one drachma. So it shall not be permissible for Harthotes
                         to remove his daughter within the period nor for her to leave.
                         If they remove her or the daughter herself leaves or she is caught stealing
                         or damaging or removing anything belonging to
                         Theon <note>vacat</note>
              <milestone n="20" rend="break" unit="line"/> <note>Registration docket</note> Year 39 of Caesar, Pharmouthi 9, in Philagris.
                         Registered through NN.
              <milestone n="21" rend="break" unit="line"/> <note>Subscription</note> I, Harthotes, son of Marres, Persian of the epigone, acknowledge
                         that I have received from Theon, son of Petermouthis, oil maker
                         of the oil mill on the estate of Livia and Germanicus
                         Caesar in Philagris
                         eighty drachmas of minted silver as a capital sum and in return for these I shall provide
                         my daughter Tahaunes to remain
                         with Theon for two years and six months from the month of Pachon
                         of the present thirty-ninth year of Caesar,
                <milestone n="29" unit="line"/> feeding olives at the indicated oil mill
                         as well as staying and doing everything that is ordered,
                         [not] being absent by night or by day,
                         but following him everywhere
                         throughout the nome, being fed and clothed
                         by Theon. <milestone n="34" unit="line"/> And for [each] day on which she is absent
                         I shall pay one [drachma] and I shall do the other things as
                         aforesaid. Ptolemaios, son of Ptolemaios, was asked and [wrote for him]
                         because he is illiterate.
                         <note>Translation: G. Claytor – N. Litinas – E. Nabney, BASP 53 (2016) 111-113</note>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> [Contract] of paramone of a girl for two years, six months for Theon
                         [son of Petermouthis] by Harthotes son of Marres.
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
