<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Fam. Tebt., 10</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">10727</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10727</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10727</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.fam.tebt;;10</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2020-10-03T16:44:40-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> The 11th year of Imperator Caesar Nerva Trajanus Augustus
                      Germanicus Dacicus, Phamenoth 2nd, at Tebtunis in the Polemon district of the Arsinoite
                      nome. Kastor, son of Kronion, son of Kastor, aged about 22 years, having a scar on the
                      left side of the throat, acknowledges to Herakleides, son of Maron, aged about 68 years,
                      having a scar on the left brow, brother from the same mother of his (viz. Kastor’s) own
                      deceased mother Apollonarion, daughter of Lysimachos, that he has received from him,
                      Herakleides, from hand to hand out of his house 401 silver drachmae and 2 obols, being
                      the remaining part due to him, Kastor, of the 1204 silver drachmae which have been in
                      the hands of Herakleides and belong to the 2000 silver drachmae granted by Herakleides’
                      deceased mother, Thaubarion, daughter of Mysthes, to Kastor’s mother Apollonarion,
                      daughter of Lysimachos, by a deed of syngraphodiatheke registered at the record-office
                      of the metropolis in the 6th year of Domitianus, month of Kaisareios, 6th supplementary
                      day - - -, also in conformity with the bond written by Herakleides and by Apollonios
                      and Lysimachos also called Gaion, his brothers from the same mother, both sons of
                      Lysimachos, in favour of the father of Kastor and his brothers Dioskoros also called
                      Kastor and Lysimachos, Kronion son of Kastor, in the 10th year of Domitianus, month
                      of Tubi, 2nd day, concerning the 2000 drachmae which they owe him; and the order of
                      payment just concerning the 1204 silver drachmae which have been in the hands of
                      Herakleides, as appears from the aforesaid bond, is nullified, since Herakleides has also
                      paid back to the brothers of Kastor, Dioskoros also called Kastor and Lysimachos, the
                      parts due to them of the same 1204 drachmae, in conformity with the receipts which
                      Herakleides got from them; which receipts shall remain valid. And neither Kastor nor his
                      representatives shall proceed against Herakleides or his representatives neither on account
                      of the sum received as aforesaid nor of the interests of that sum nor of the interests which
                      Kastor’s father Kronion received when Kastor was still a minor, from former times up to
                      the present day. (Subscriptions of Kastor and Herakleides. Docket of the record-office
                      at Tebtunis.)
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
