<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Fam. Tebt., 11 Kol. II</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">10728b</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10728</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10728b 10728a</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.fam.tebt;;11colii p.fam.tebt;;11coli</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2020-10-05T07:25:47-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> (Kol. i) I, Herakleides, son of Maron, and my wife, Didyme, with my assistance, to my son, Herakleides also called Valerius. We have borrowed from you Herakleides and Didym[..] - - - also called Sambatheios - - - from the heritage left to Didyme by Isidora daughter of Lysimachos - - - and with the guarantee of all the possessions belonging to - - - Lysimachos, under the name of Didymos, my minor son whose guardian I am - - - arourae of catoecic kleros-land near Kerkesephis - - - you having the right of execution on all our revenues and possessions - - - the syngraphodiaktheke (registered) in the record-office at Tebtunis in the past 10th year of Trajan our lord, month of Mesore, 6th supplementary day - - - This document shall be valid wheresoever it will be produced, as if it had been publicly registered. I, Herakleides, have also written on behalf of my wife who is illiterate and I shall guarantee her assent with each of the aforesaid clauses. (Date and subscription for Didyme.)

(Kol. ii) I, Herakleides, son of Maron, to my son, Herakleides also called Valerius, greeting. I acknowledge that I have received from you from hand to hand out of your house a deposit of one thousand two hundred drachmae of coined silver, say 1200 dr., which I shall refund to you whensoever you, Herakleides also called Valerius, wish, without any delay or subterfuge, you having the right of execution on myself and on all my property as if in accordance with a legal decision; the agreements which I have made with you, also in the name of your mother Didyme, remain valid. This document is valid. (Date).
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
