<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Fam. Tebt., 13</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">10730</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10730</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10730</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.fam.tebt;;13</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2020-10-05T07:28:42-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="1" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/>Copy of divorce. The 17th year of Imperator Caesar Nerva Trajanus Augustus Germanicus Dacicus month - - at M - - in the Polemon-district of the Arsinoite nome. Kronous also called Philoumene, daughter of Kastor, 20 years old, having a scar on the right shin, with the assistance of her own father, Kaston, son of Pyrion, aged 44 years, having a scar on the right of the forehead, - - and Lysimachos, former husband of Kronous also called Philoumene, son of Herakleides, aged 30 years, having a scar on the left knee, - - that they have dissolved their marriage with one another, - - which had existed between them on the strength of a deed of acknowledgement written in former times in the record-office at Tebtunis. Each of them shall be free to manage his own affairs as he wishes, and Kronous to conclude a new marriage with the man whom she prefers, (without intervenience?) of Lysimachos. And Kastor mentioned above acknowledges  that he has forthwith received from Lysimachos, the husband of his daughter Kronous - - through the (record-office) at Tebtunis the dowry in gold and silver and - -. And none of the aforesaid persons shall proceed against one another in any way, neither on account of the possessions belonging to the marriage nor on account of any other matter written or unwritten, a debt or an agreement whatsoever, from the former times up to the present day. To Lysimachos and Kronous is born from one another a son named Herakleides also called Valerius. Nullified are the bonds which the two, Lysimachos and Kastor, have from one another. Signatory for Kronous also called Philoumene is her aforesaid father, Kastor, son of Pyrion, who is also appointed as her guardian. This act of divorce shall be valid wheresoever it is produced - - I Kronous also called Philoumene, with the assistance of my father, Kastor, son of Pyrion, and - - Kastor already mentioned, we acknowledge that we have dissolved the marriage - - which had existed with Lysimachos on the strength of a deed of acknowledgement written in former times in the record-office at Tebtunis. I, Kastor, have received the agreed dowry in gold and silver mentioned in it, and various paraphernalia. And each of us shall be free etc. (Similar subscription of Lysimachos).
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="39" unit="line"/>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
