<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Fam.Tebt. 22</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">10740</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10740</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10740</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.fam.tebt;;22</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2020-10-02T11:01:35-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2020-07-09T05:52:46-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ok</change>
         <change when="2019-07-26T04:48:58-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/WesselvanDuijn">Submit - Translation added</change>
         <change when="2019-07-26T04:48:45-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/WesselvanDuijn">Commit - Translation added</change>
         <change when="2019-07-26T04:45:20-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               [Translation from P. L. Bat. 6] The 7th year of Imperator Caesar Trajans Hadrianus Augustus, the month of August the 20th, at Tebtunis in the Polemon district of the Arsinoite nome. Herakleides also called Valerius son of Herakleides son of Maron, registered in the Treasuries quarter, <milestone n="5" unit="line"/>Persian of the epigone, about 46 years old, having a scar on the left knee, acknowledges to Tamystha daughter of Didymos also called Mystharion, about 35 years old, having no distinctive mark, with the assistance of her husband Lysimachos son of Apollonios, about 38 years old, having a scar on the right foot, that he has received from her, Tamystha, forthwith from hand to hand out of her house a loan of the capital sum <milestone n="10" unit="line"/>of 212 drachmae of coined silver bearing interest; and the acknowledging party Herakleides also called Valerius is bound to repay to Tamystha the capital sum of the loan, say 212 dr., with the interest, on the 20th of the month of Tybi of the present 7th year <milestone n="15" unit="line"/>without any delay or subterfuge. If Herakleides also called Valerius fails to repay as is written, he shall pay to Tamystha the aforesaid capital with a surplus of 50% and the simple interest, Tamystha having the right of execution on Herakleides also called Valerius and on all his property. (Subscriptions of Herakleides-Valerius and of Lysimachos on behalf of his wife). 
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
