<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
    <teiHeader type="text">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">P.Fam. Tebt., 3</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
                <idno type="filename">10748</idno>
                <idno type="TM">10748</idno>
                <idno type="HGV">10748</idno>
                <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.fam.tebt;;3</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
                        a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
                <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
                <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
                <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
                <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
                <language ident="la">Latein</language>
                <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2024-05-23T11:42:39-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">
                Added via github because the file was stuck in finalization in the editor.</change>
            <change when="2020-10-02T10:24:53-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">
                Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Add attribution in a note.</change>
            <change when="2020-10-02T16:44:48-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/EllisCuffe">
                Commit - Added Groningen 1950 English translation. Typographical errors have been corrected.</change>
            <change when="2020-10-02T03:47:22-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/>Copy of contract. The 11th year of Imperator Caesar Domitianus Augustus Germanicus, month of Daisios the 21st, of Pharmouthi the 21st, 
at Ptolemais Drumou of the Arsinoite nome. <milestone n="3" unit="line"/>Areios son of Areios, 45 years old, having a scar on his right shin, acknowledges to - - -, - - years old, 
having a scar on the left knee, assisted by her husband - -  son of Lysimachos the son of Didymos, 35 years old, having a scar on the right of the forehead, that he, 
the acknowledger, has sold to her through this contract from now for evermore one aroura, or how much it may be, of a vineyard near Kerkesis in the district of Polemon, 
and together with it one eight of an aroura as additional quantity, with all the appurtenances, the storehouse thereon being common to the land of Kerkesis, 
and moreover the dike and the chasing and fishing being common with Ammonios, the neighbour, because the two arourae form one plot. <milestone n="13" unit="line"/>It has been bought, as Areios asserts, 
already a long time ago in the said conditions. Neighbours of the said aroura are: to the south, a canal through which the aroura is watered; to the north, a public road; 
to the west the aforesaid aroura of Ammonios; to the east, the children of Sarapion, son of Achilles, with their reed-land. 
<milestone n="17" unit="line"/>And he declares to have received (the price) of sevenhundred and sixty silver drachmae in full through Didymos’ bank - - . 
He confirms to her with every guarantee that it is free from all kind of public duties in corn and money and from all fines in any form, 
beginning with former times up to the present eleventh year of Imperator Caesar Domitianus Germanicus inclusively, because the yearly rent belonged to Areios (?). 
(It is also free) from private dues and claim of any sort for ever. The rest is accordingly.
<note>Translation: B.A. van Groningen, P.Fam. Tebt. 3</note>
            </p>
         </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
