<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Fam. Tebt., 23</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">10741</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10741</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10741</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.fam.tebt;;23</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2020-10-23T10:24:51-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> The 7th year of Imperator Caesar Trajanus Hadrianus Augustus,
                      Phamenoth 21st, at Tebtunis in the Polemon district of the Arsinoite nome. Didyme,
                      daughter of Lysimachos, son of Lysimachos, aged about 75 years, having a scar on the left
                      brow, with the assistance of Valerius, son of Herakleides, aged about 46 years, having a
                      scar on the right knee, acknowledges to Lysimachos, son of Didymos, son of Lysimachos,
                      aged about 68 years, having a scar on the right knee, that she has ceded to him, Lysimachos,
                      as well as to his descendants and their cessionaries, from the said day for ever, out of
                      the 10 1/2 1/16 arourae, with 1/4 aroura allotment to the village, total 10 1/2 1/4 1/16 arourae
                      (now) belonging to herself, Didyme, near the village of Ibion Eikosipentarouron in the
                      aforesaid district, and formerly to Herakleides, son of Maron, and assigned to her by a deed
                      of partition which she drew up with three partners in the 3rd year of Hadrian Caesar the
                      lord month of Pachon 28th through the registrar’s office here, the 5 1/2 1/64 arourae of
                      catoecic land, with 1/8 aroura allotment to the village, total 5 1/2 1/8 1/64 arourae situated
                      in the northern part of the whole, from west to east, and at the same time the entire proceeds
                      of them during the present 7th year and the fourth part of the watchtower there,
                      which belongs to the ceded arourae. <milestone n="7" unit="line"/> And from the ceded area, Lysimachos shall reserve for
                      the arourae in the south which remain Didyme’s property, a drying place in the south-west
                      of the tower, 4 square ammata in the superficies, for the - - -, and the crops which will be sown
                      on them. Neighbours of the ceded arourae are, as they have unanimously declared: in the
                      south, the arourae which remain Didyme’s property; in the north, the lot belonging to - - -
                      and Lysimachos and Arios, the three sons of Apollonios; in the west, a field belonging
                      to the state behind which there is a canal irrigating the ceded arourae; in the east, another
                      canal. - - - all the rights of irrigation Didyme is entitled to by virtue of the aforesaid deed
                      of partition. Valid shall also be the transactions registered in the list of katalochismoi of
                      the katoikoi. <milestone n="12" unit="line"/> The acknowledging party, Didyme, has received from Lysimachos forthwith
                      from hand to hand out of his house the whole sum of 2000 silver drachmae fixed for the
                      cession of the ceded 5 1/2 1/64 arourae with the allotment; and Didyme and her cessionaries
                      shall guarantee with full security for Lysimachos and his cessionaries the aforesaid ceded
                      property, which she transfers neither encumbered, nor liable to distraint, nor mortgaged,
                      and free of all public duties, artaba-taxes, naubia and any kind of payments due for the
                      past up to the former 6th year included, as well as from private obligations and every
                      claim whensoever. She shall neither accuse nor dispute nor prosecute with a view to the
                      aforesaid agreement, and if she prosecutes or accuses, the prosecution and accusation shall
                      not be valid; <milestone n="17" unit="line"/> and Didyme shall pay to Lysimachos, if she does not guarantee or transfer
                      forthwith, the cession sum which she received, with a surplus of 50%, twice the amount
                      of the damage and a penalty of 1000 silver drachmae, besides to the Treasury the same
                      sum and nothing less, apart from the fact that the agreement shall remain valid and unchanged
                      forever - - - the cession shall be valid. <milestone n="20" unit="line"/> Registered by Lourios also called Apollonios,
                      chief of the registrar’s office of Tebtunis and Kerkesouchon Oros, in the 7th year
                      of Hadrian Caesar the lord, 27th of Phamenoth.
             <milestone n="22" unit="line"/> To Dionysios and Herakleides, ex-gymnasiarchs, keepers of the archives of enkteseis
                      in the Arsinoite nome, from Lysimachos, son of Didymos, son of Lysimachos, registered
                      in the Tharapeia quarter. As a supplement to the returns presented to your predecessors,
                      I herewith return the cateocic land which has today been transferred to me with your
                      permission by Didyme, daughter of Lysimachos, son of Lysimachos, registered in the
                      Treasuries quarter, who had delivered a return to your predecessors, viz. 5 1/2 1/64 arourae
                      and 1/8 aroura allotment, total area 5 1/2 1/8 1/64 arourae, reaching from west to east in the
                      northern part of 10 1/2 1/4 1/16 arourae near Ibion Eikosipentarouron, free from every debt
                      and mortgage, at the price of 2000 drachmae. <milestone n="25" unit="line"/> Therefore, I present this return. - - -
                      ex-gymnasiarch through Apollonios secretary. Entered in the register. 7th year of Hadrian
                      Caesar the lord, Phamenoth 27th.
                      <note>Translation: B.A. van Groningen, P.Fam. Tebt. 23</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
