<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
    <teiHeader type="text">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>P.Fam. Tebt., 4</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
                <idno type="filename">10751</idno>
                <idno type="TM">10751</idno>
                <idno type="HGV">10751</idno>
                <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.fam.tebt;;4</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
                        a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="fr">French</language>
                <language ident="en">English</language>
                <language ident="de">German</language>
                <language ident="it">Italian</language>
                <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
                <language ident="la">Latin</language>
                <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2024-05-23T11:42:39-04:00"
                who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Added via github because the file was stuck in finalization in the editor.</change>
            <change when="2020-10-02T10:24:53-04:00"
                who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey"> Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Add attribution in a note .</change>
            <change when="2020-10-02T16:44:57-04:00"
                who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/EllisCuffe">Submit - Added Groningen 1950 English translation in support in PhD research.</change>
            <change when="2020-10-02T16:44:48-04:00"
                who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/EllisCuffe">Commit - Added Groningen 1950 English translation. Typographical errors have been corrected.</change>
            <change when="2020-10-02T16:44:40-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> Authentic act. The 13th year of Imperator Caesar Domitianus Augustus Germanicus, Tubi 10th, 
at Tebtunis in the Polemon district of the Arsinoite nome. <milestone n="5" unit="line"/> Chairemon, aged about 25 years, having a scar on his left shin, 
and Kronion, aged about 22 years, having a scar in the middle of the forehead, both sons of Akousilaos, Persians of the epigone, 
being mutual security for payment, acknowledge to Lysimachos, son of Didymos, son of Lysimachos, aged about 32 years, having a scar on the right wrist (or: corner of the eye), 
that they have received from him a loan, bearing interest, of 9 2/3 artabae of new, pure and unadulterated wheat, measured with the 4 choinikes-measure owned by Lysimachos; 
<milestone n="14" unit="line"/> and the acknowledging persons, Chairemon and Kronion, being mutual security, 
are bound to return to Lysimachos the 9 2/3 artabae of wheat in the month Pauni of the present 13th year of Imperator Caesar Domitianus Augustus Germanicus 
in the aforesaid village of Tebtunis without any delay or subterfuge, Lysimachos having the right of execution on the acknowledging persons and 
on each of them whomsoever he chooses, and on all their property as it in accordance with a legal decision. 
<milestone n="23" unit="line"/>The signatory for the acknowledging party is Ischyrion son of Achilleus, aged 50 years, having a scar on the left side of the chin. 
(Signature of Ischyrion). <milestone n="33" unit="line"/>The acknowledgment has been made to me Lysimachos as stated above.
                      <note>Translation: B.A. van Groningen, P.Fam. Tebt. 4</note>
            </p>
         </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
