<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
    <teiHeader type="text">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">P.Fam.Tebt. 5</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
                <idno type="filename">10757</idno>
                <idno type="TM">10757</idno>
                <idno type="HGV">10757</idno>
                <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.fam.tebt;;5</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
                        a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
                <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
                <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
                <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
                <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
                <language ident="la">Latein</language>
                <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2020-10-02T10:24:53-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">
                Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Add attribution in a note.</change>
            <change when="2020-10-02T16:44:48-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/EllisCuffe">
                Commit - Added Groningen 1950 English translation.</change>
            <change when="2020-10-02T03:49:48-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/>To Hermes, son of Didymos. From Polemon, son of Heuremon, Persian of the epigone. 
<milestone n="1" unit="line"/>I wish to lease from you the beans sown by you in the present second year of Imperator Caesar Nerva Trajanus Augustus Germanicus 
and the turnips sown between the beans on two arourae out of the three arourae of kleros-land, forming part of six arourae, 
the rent of the whole of the two arourae being, in kind, 25 artabae of beans measured with the 4 choinikes-measure owned by yourself, 
Hermes, and in money 40 silver drachmae, besides 2 artabae of turnips measured with the aforesaid measure. 
<milestone n="10" unit="line"/>I shall pay to you the 40 drachmae and 2 artabae of turnips on the 15th of the coming month of Tybi of the present second year, 
and the beans on the - - of the month of Pauni. The transport-charges for the expedition concerning the 2 arourae shall be chargeable to me, 
but the transport of the crops up to the village to you. And you shall also guarantee the lease, 
you having no power to transfer it or to work the land yourself, also remaining valid the lease with payment in advance which I got from you, 
Hermes, on three arourae of wheat forming part of the six arourae mentioned above. 
<milestone n="21" rend="break" unit="line"/>(Date and subscription on behalf of the lessee who is illiterate).
<note>Translation: B.A. van Groningen, P.Fam. Tebt. 5</note>
            </p>
         </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
