<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Fam. Tebt., 9</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">10766</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10766</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10766</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.fam.tebt;;9</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2020-10-03T16:41:47-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> The 11th year of Imperator Caesar Nerva Trajanus Augustus
                      Germanicus Dacicus, month of Neos Sebastos the 25th, at Tebtunis in the Polemon
                      division of the Arsinoite nome. <milestone n="3" unit="line"/> Herakleides aged about twenty-seven years, having scar
                      on the left part of the forehead, and Apia also called Herakleia, aged about thirty-eight
                      years, without distinctive mark, both of them children of Didymos the Elder, son of
                      Herodes, Apia being assisted by her husband Didymos, son of Lysimachos, aged about
                      forty-six years, having a scar on the right cheek, acknowledge both to Thaesis, daughter
                      of Psenkebkis also called Kronion, son of Marsisouchos, aged about fifty years, having
                      a scar on the right shin, assisted by her relative Marepsemis, son of Marepsemis, aged
                      about thirty years, having a scar on the middle of the nose, <milestone n="10" unit="line"/> that they received from
                      Thaesis in cash twelve hundred twenty four silver drachmae with the interest, which
                      Thaesis owed to Herodiana, the sister of both Herakleides and Apia, who demanded it
                      through a bond executed in the record-office at Theogenis in the eighth year of Trajan
                      Caesar, our lord, month of Kaisareios the 16th; which document they have delivered to
                      Thaesis for annulment and invalidation; <milestone n="15" unit="line"/> and neither Herakleides and Apia, the both of
                      them, nor their cessionaries shall proceed against Thaesis and her cessionaries neither
                      concerning the sum which they received as stated above nor concerning any other thing
                      whatsoever up to the present day,, whereas (name), the mother pf both Herakleides and
                      Apia, shall incur no loss as to the money capital which Thaesis owes her by virtue of a
                      deed, on the conditions which it contains. Subscriber of the women is either’s assistant.
             <milestone n="22" unit="line"/> [2nd Hand] We, Herakleides and Apia also called Herakleia, children of Didymos, son
                      of Herodes, Apia being assisted by her husband Didymos, son of Lysimachos, acknowledge
                      to have received from Thaesis the capital of twelve hundred twenty four drachmae and
                      the interest – - -
                      <note>Translation: B.A. van Groningen, P.Fam. Tebt. 9</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
