<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Fay., 91</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">10934</idno>
            <idno type="TM">10933</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">10933</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.fay;;90</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2020-07-11T08:02:24-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> Phaophi 18, agreement of Thenetkoueis with Lucius. The third year of the Emperor Caesar Nerva Trajanus Augustus Germanicus, Phaophi 18, at Euhemeria in the division of Themistes of the Arsinoite nome. Thenekoueis, daughter of Heron, olive-carrier, a Persian, aged about 26 years, having a scar on the right shin, acting with her guardian, her kinsman, Leontas, son of Hippalus, aged about 54 years, having a scar on the forehead to the right, acknowledges to Lucius Bellenus Gemellus, discharged from military service with the legion (?), aged about 67 years, having a scar on the left wrist, that she has received from him directly from hand to hand from his house 16 drachmae of silver as unexceptionable earnest money. Thenetkoueis is accordingly obliged to carry at the olive-press belonging to Lucius Bellenus Gemellus at Euhemeria from whatever day he orders her olive produce included in the present third year, performing all that a carrier should until the completion of the entire oil-manufacture, and receiving from Lucius Bellenus her daily wage at the same rate as the carriers in the village; and Lucius shall reckon off the 16 drachmae of silver by instalments from her wages. If Thenetkoueis does not act in accordance with the conditions above written, she shall pay back to Lucius double the earnest money, and he shall have the right of execution upon her and upon all her property as if in accordance with a legal decision. Attestor on behalf of Thenetkoueis, Leontas the aforesaid. (Then follows the signature of Thenetkoueis written by her guardian Leontas, the docket of the record office at Euhemeria, and the signature of Epagathus on behalf of Gemellus acknowledging that he had received back the 16 drachmae.)
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
