<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Cair. Zen. 3, 59509</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">1147</idno>
            <idno type="TM">1147</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">1147</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.cair.zen;3;59509</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-07-14T20:42:36-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement pp143–144)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-14T20:35:40-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp143–144)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-14T20:35:20-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp143–144)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-14T20:34:54-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Commit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp143–144)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-14T20:33:42-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> To Zenon, greetings, Somoelis, phylax from Philadelphia. We have sown the [land?] of Amand[ --- ]. 
There belongs to you from me 20 artabas of grain for seed. I am sending these up to you; and let nothing be wronged by Etearchos, 
with regard to this or anything else. For he has worn me down… pressing me into service for everything. 
Therefore, you would do well to write a letter to him for me, so that he may know about us in advance, and we may not be wronged. 
And I am able, also, to buy up for you 1000 artabas of barley from the hippeis, but not from any farmer, so that no one may disagree (?). 
And if it is possible, get ready in advance another granary. For the one you have is not sufficient to contain the grain from this year. 
I am guarding the granary here, though I get nothing, but those from Philadelphia are giving me 1.5 artabas of grain. 
This, however, is not enough to feed my children, if I don’t get something in addition. Farewell.
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp143–144)
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
