<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
    <teiHeader type="text">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main"> P.Lond. 2 143</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
                <idno type="filename">11628</idno>
                <idno type="TM">11628</idno>
                <idno type="HGV">11628</idno>
                <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.lond;2;143</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
                        a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="fr">French</language>
                <language ident="en">English</language>
                <language ident="de">German</language>
                <language ident="it">Italian</language>
                <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
                <language ident="la">Latin</language>
                <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2024-05-28T15:35:34-04:00" 
                who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Added via github because the file was stuck in finalization in the editor.</change>
            <change when="2020-09-06T06:27:08-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> In the first year of Emperor Nerva Caesar Augustus on the 6th of the month Artemisios, Phamenoth 6, 
in Karanis of the Herakleides division of the Arsinoite nome. <milestone unit="line" rend="break" n="3"/> Kephalas, son of Petosiris, about thirty four years old, 
scar over his right eyebrow, acknowledges to Tapontos, daughter of Chairemon, about forty years old, scar on her right shin, with as her guardian her husband Mikkalos, 
son of Ptolemaios, about forty seven years old, scar on the middle of his forehead under his hair, that he has received back from her immediately, hand to hand, out of the house
one hundred sixty silver drachmas, which are the remainder of two hundred silver drachmas, <milestone unit="line" rend="break" n="11"/> which Tapontos owed to him, hand to hand, 
without written record, already from the eighth year of Domitian from an account of a pledge for a plot of two and a twentieth arouras, 
since Kephalas had previously received from Tapontos forty drachmas towards full payment of the two hundred silver drachmas 
according to another agreement drawn up through the same writing office in the month of Sebastos of the present year, which remains valid. 
<milestone unit="line" n="18"/> Neither Kephalas himself nor his agents may initiate proceedings against Tapontos or her agents, neither concerning the two hundred silver drachmas
which he has received (now) and which he previously received as aforesaid, nor concerning any other matter all, neither a written nor an unwritten debt, 
from the past until the present day in any way. Subscriber for the acknowledging party: Heron, son of Satyros, about 27 years old, scar on the middle of his forehead. 
<milestone unit="line" rend="break" n="26"/>I, Kephalas, son of Petsiris, acknowledge that I have received back from Tapontos, daughter of Chairemon, hand to hand, out of the house
one hundred sixty silver drachmas, which are the remainder of two hundred silver drachmas, which she owed , hand to hand, 
without written record, already from the eighth year of Domitian from an account of a pledge for a plot of two and a twentieth arouras, 
through the previous receipt of forty drachmas towards full payment of the two hundred silver drachmas 
according to another agreement drawn up through the same writing office in the month of Sebastos of the present year, which remains valid
and I will not initiate proceedings, as is stated. <milestone unit="line" n="35"/>Heron, son of Satyros wrote on his behalf, because he does not know letters.
Registered through the grapheion in Karanis.
                  <note>Translation: W.G. Claytor (via PN) 2015</note>
               </p>
         </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
