<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Lips. 1, 27</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">11620</idno>
            <idno type="TM">11620</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">11620</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.lips;1;27</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2017-10-02T10:44:18-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/james.cowey">Finalized - Ready.</change>
         <change when="2017-10-02T10:33:04-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/james.cowey">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Fine</change>
         <change when="2017-10-02T10:32:29-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/james.cowey">Submit - Rename properly</change>
         <change when="2017-03-14T08:22:19-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Finalized - ready&#xD;
</change>
         <change when="2017-03-14T08:21:21-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Commit - changed notation authorial notes</change>
         <change when="2017-03-14T08:19:54-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Commit - changed notation authorial notes</change>
         <change when="2017-03-14T07:35:43-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Had already been checked by two persons here in Leiden</change>
         <change when="2017-03-10T10:01:11-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Submit - added translation</change>
         <change when="2017-03-10T10:00:24-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Commit - added English translation</change>
         <change when="2017-03-10T09:53:43-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              (From J.E. Grubbs, Women and the Law in the Roman Empire, 2002, p. 213.)  <milestone n="1" rend="break" unit="line"/>
In the seventh year of the Emperor Caesar Trajan Hadrian Augustus, 21 Phamenoth, in Tebtunis of the Polemon division of the Arsinoite nome. <milestone n="5" unit="line"/> Thenstotoetis, about sixteen years old, without distinguishing marks, with her kyrios her father Heron son of Neilos about forty-four years old, with a scar on the little finger of his left hand, and the same Heron, and the one who was the husband of Thenstotoetis, <milestone n="10" unit="line"/> Lysas the freedman of Herakleia the daughter of Lysimachos, about twenty-two years old, with a scar on his right cheek, and Sosas, son of Areotos, about fifty-four years old, with a scar on his right shin – these four acknowledge to each other that Thenstotoetis and Lysas have jointly <milestone n="15" unit="line"/> annulled their marriage with each other, which was established by them (and) completed by virtue of a written agreement (homologia) of marriage through the same record-office in the fifth year of our lord Hadrian Caesar, … <note>day missing</note> Hathur, and they have also presented this [agreement] for the purpose of having it  <milestone n="20" unit="line"/> annulled and invalidated. 
	And (they acknowledge) that Heron has back from Sosas the three hundred drachmas of silver (given) through the dowry agreement and all the parapherna. And that it is possible for each [of them] to dispose [his own] things as <milestone n="25" unit="line"/> he or she chooses, and (it is possible) for Thenstotoetis to join herself in marriage again, to [whatever] man she wishes, not [being] open to accusation from Lysas. And that they will not bring charges against each other [about] any aspect of the things connected with the marriage nor about any matter in general <milestone n="30" unit="line"/> up to the present day. [Subscriber] Marepsemis son of Pakebkis, [about] forty-eight years old with a scar on his nose. 
	[written in a second hand] Lysas, freedman of Herakleia, [and] Sosas son of Areotos … that they have jointly annulled the marriage with Thenstouetis <note>sic</note>, and that they <milestone n="35" unit="line"/> will not bring charges against each other in general. Marepsemis son of Pakebkis wrote on their behalf since they do not know letters. 
	<note>in a third hand</note> Thenstotoetis with her kyrios her father Heron – I have annulled the marriage and I have back the dowry. Heron – <milestone n="40" unit="line"/> I wrote on her behalf because she does not know letters.
	<note>in a fourth hand</note> I have signed it. 
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
