<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Monts. Roca 4, 77</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">128573</idno>
            <idno type="TM">128573</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">128573</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.monts.roca;4;77</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2017-06-12T02:53:20-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="exterior" subtype="scriptura" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> In the reign of Ptolemy and Kleopatra son and daughter of Ptolemy and Kleopatra, the Gods Epiphaneis, in the thirty-fourth year,
                         Kallikles son of Diokritos being priest of Alexander and the Gods Soteres and the Gods Adelphoiand the Gods Euergetai
                         and the Gods Philopatores and the Gods Epiphaneis, and the God Eupator and the Gods Philometores. And the athlophoros of Berenike
                         Euergetis being Ergonoe daughter of Alexander, the kanephoros of Arsinoe Philadelphos being Asklepias daughter of Ptolemy
                         son of Asklepiades, the priestess of Arsinoe Philopator being Apollonia daughter of Isokrates, on the twelfth of the month Artemisios,
                         Athyr the twelfth, in Hephaistias in the Arsinoite nome. <milestone n="4" unit="line"/> Herakleides, son of Nikanor,
                         manager of the estate of Euboulos, one of the first friends, has leased to Petosouchos son of Phramenis, Arsinoite, peasant,
                         from the above mentioned estate, of land fifteen and a quarter arouras for the thirty-fourth
                         year for a rent for each aroura for (a plot of) eleven of them of four artabas of wheat, for the remaining
                         four and a quarter arouras for a rent of five and two-thirds artabas of wheat, guaranteed against every risk and not subject to deduction for damage.
                <milestone n="11" unit="line"/> When this land has been irrigated Petosouchos shall sow the land at his own expense, supplying to himself pure grain.
                         If he does not sow the land or if he leaves the lease after having sown, he shall pay the whole rent.
                         And when the land has been sown, Herakleides and Euboulos’ representatives must guarantee to Petosouchos
                         and his representatives the lease and the land [and the crops?] for the agreed period of time.
                         If he fails to guarantee the lease as written above, the above mentioned Herakleides
                         or Euboulos’ representatives, being partners in the guarantee, shall pay a fine of twenty talents of bronze, and the
                         damages and this lease must be no less authoritative. And Petosouchos must be allowed to
                         evict in return anyone who forces his way onto the land, without being liable to any penalty. <milestone n="18" unit="line"/> If the lease is confirmed,
                         Petosouchos shall deliver to Herakleides and the representatives of Euboulos the stipulated rent in the month
                         of Pachon of the same year and he must hand over the crop in the same village [----]
                         Euboulos, wherever they order, in new, pure and unadulterated grain …
                         (transported) to Hephaistias … at their own
                         expense. And for each artaba which he does not deliver, Petosouchos
                         shall pay immediately a fine of one thousand drachmas of bronze or the highest price that may be (charged) at the market of Hephaistias.
                         Let there be for Herakleides and Euboulos’ representatives the right of execution on the person of Petosouchos himself and
                         on all his possessions, as according to the regulation and the laws. This contract
                         is authoritative. <milestone n="27" unit="line"/> Witnesses: Pamenis, priest; N. N.; Diodoros, both Persians; Kallias,
                         Thracian, all three of them hekatontarouroi from the second hipparchy of Aratos; Dorotheos;
                         Ptolemaios, both Macedonians of the Epigone.
                         Keeper of the contract, Pamenis, priest.
                         I, Herakleides, have leased out in accordance with what is written above and have deposited
                         the contract with NN son of -souchos.
                         I, Petesouchos, have leased in accordance with what is written above and have signed the
                         contract. I, Pamenios, have received (the contract in deposit).
                         <note>Translation: S. Torallas Tovar – K.A. Worp, P.Monts.Roca 4 77</note>
               </p>
            </div>
            
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
