<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Eirene 3, 1</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">128642</idno>
            <idno type="TM">128642</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">128642</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.eirene;3;1</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-08-30T14:34:09.887-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-30T14:34:09.873-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-07-14T05:20:16.087-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/dratzan">Entered from transcoded text with Italian translation, w/o checking hard-copy (unavailable).  I reordered the line numbers: ed. pr. begins 1a, 1, 2, etc.: SoSOL ed. begins 1, 2, 3.  I regularized punctuation so as to remove caps from initial words of sentences.  Lines 14, 20 contain uncertain restorations and I tried coding them as such according to the help document.  While the editor accepted my coding, it looks incorrect in the preview.  If I did it incorrectly, I would appreciate an example of how to code what we find in 14, 20.  Line 16 ed. pr. has a gap, but no vacat.  From what I could tell, the gap is meant to convey missing letters, not a vacat, and so I coded accordingly, but this may be wrong (I have no image).</change>
         <change when="2011-11-16T14:30:07-05:00" who="SoSOL">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="it" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <p>
<milestone unit="line" n="1" rend="break"/> Ad Isidoros e ad Antarion alias Arsinoos, ex ginnasiarchi e capi della Conservatoria del Registro Immobiliare dell'Arsinoites.
<milestone unit="line" n="3" rend="break"/> Da parte di Thermutharion, la figlia di Ammonios, nipote di Polydeukes, registrata nel quartiere del Ginnasio e da parte della figlia, Thermutharion, figlia di Dioscoros, 
figlio di Mystharion, registrata nello stesso quartiere, entrambe aventi come tutore il marito di Thermutharion, figlia di Ammonios, e padre della figlia Thermutharion, Dioscoros, figlio di Mystharion. 
<milestone unit="line" n="8" rend="break"/> Dichiariamo la casa che abbiamo acquistato nel giorno presente, 6 di Pa[---], da Herais alias Kalathion, figlia di Isidoros alias […]on, figlio di Aurion, residente nella metropoli, 
iscritta nel quartiere dei Bitini di Ision registrata dagli archivisti prima di voi per avere come tutore lo zio da parte di madre Papos, figlio di Harpocration(?), residente nella metropoli, registrato nel quartiere 
dei Bitini di Ision;  casa nuova, che si trova di fronte alla casa …
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
