<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 75, 5052</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">128893</idno>
            <idno type="TM">128893</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">128893</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;75;5052</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2011-08-18T08:43:14.142-04:00" who="Joshua D. Sosin">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2011-08-18T08:43:14.139-04:00" who="Joshua D. Sosin">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Accept.</change>
         <change when="2011-07-21T06:36:12.48-04:00" who="Sven Tost">Enter regarding to the translation of F. Maltomini</change>
         <change when="2011-07-21T06:26:19-04:00" who="SoSOL">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <p>
               <milestone unit="line" n="1" rend="break"/> [?Tho]nis son of Chaeremon son of . . . , mother Tausiris daughter of Heraclas, from the city
of the Oxyrhynchi, Persian of the epigone, to Thamunium daughter of Harbichis also called Hierax
son of Alexander, with her guardian, her full brother Diogenes, greetings.

<milestone unit="line" n="6" rend="break"/> I acknowledge that I will give back to your daughter Thermuthis daughter of Thonis, within
two years from the month Sebastos of the coming seventh year of Imperator Caesar Domitianus Augustus Germanicus, forty silver drachmas of the imperial coinage, which are the half share which
falls to Thermuthis of the eighty silver drachmas that I owe to her late father Thonis son of Heraclas,
in accordance with a cheirographon and a bank-diagraphe; and, as interest on that sum for the above
period, twelve silver drachmas, and also ten other silver drachmas that I owe her without a contract,
so that the sum total is sixty two silver drachmas, without any delay. If I do not repay her in accordance
with what is written, I will pay . . . with the addition of one half and the appropriate interest for
the excess time, and you and Thermuthium are to have the right of execution upon me and all my
property, as if in consequence of a lawsuit. Regarding the afore-mentioned (debts?) I have notified
. . . , the bankers of the bank at the Serapeum in the city of the Oxyrhynchi. The note of hand is valid
wherever produced and for whoever produces it. Year (6 of Imperator Caesar Domitianus Augustus
Germanicus . . .). (F. Maltomini)
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
