<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 75, 5062</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">128903</idno>
            <idno type="TM">128903</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">128903</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;75;5062</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2011-08-18T08:14:22.949-04:00" who="Joshua D. Sosin">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2011-08-18T08:14:22.946-04:00" who="Joshua D. Sosin">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Accept. For ease of reading--&gt; ((10)) Therefore, if; --&gt;((22)) I will also bring </change>
         <change when="2011-07-21T06:45:40.68-04:00" who="Zdiarsky">Übersetzung im Rahmen des Workshops in Wien</change>
         <change when="2011-07-21T06:27:40-04:00" who="SoSOL">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> Ammonius and Herais and Euporus to Priscus, our lord father, and Thaesis, our lady mother,
and to Herminus, the most notable, many greetings. On the 17th of Epeiph, that is, yesterday, we
received a letter through Chaeremon from Artapatou, by which you say that Cephalon because of
his insolence approached (you) saying that the bond is not his (or there is no bond of his), but also that
he approached the epistrategus—the most ridiculous and astonishing thing, the debtors are trying to
frighten the creditors. 

<milestone unit="line" n="10"/> Therefore, if these things have happened as you say, let him promptly receive
(it) according to what is lawful, and if the hyperetes shows negligence, produce him (= Cephalon) to the
epistrategus and upon the notification let him make the registration, as the laws order. And immediately
send me notice, so that I also contact the higher authority; for it is possible for me to petition
for whatever I may wish. His bond is in the registry with the authority over my subscription that it is
his autograph in accordance with the diastolikon. 

<milestone unit="line" n="22"/> I will also bring to the higher official here the other
document, written in one copy only; this is the critical point, that he receives it and that he registers
himself. If indeed he has chosen to be obstinate, I have many proofs for scrutiny, first the bond, second
some other things. And do not give . . . him in a regular way or (?) approach him, but having the . . .
from me. And . . . nothing else remains for this obstinate man apart from the registration. And nothing
else can happen for you who . . . , except that he receives (the document) and registers himself.
And . . . have (him?) sent for; for I learned that . . . domain (land?) . . . send for him (or: he is sent for).
Greet . . . and her mother . . . by name. We pray for your health to all gods.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="39"/> To Priscus, neokoros, and Herminus, victor in many contests, from Ammonius, diastoleus. (R. Hatzilambrou)
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
