<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 2, 154</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">12939</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12939</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12939</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;2;154</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-09-15T12:07:23.41-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-09-15T12:07:23.303-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:07:28.695-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from Rylands catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-20T17:35:35-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <p>
               <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> ‘Copy of agreement. The 13th year of Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, the 22nd of the month Apellaeus, Phaophi 22, in Bacchias in the division of Heraclides of the Arsinoïte nome. Chaeremon son of Apollonius, a Persian of the Epigone, aged about 34 years, with a scar on the middle of the nose, acknowledges to Sisoïs son of Peteesis, aged about 71 years, with a scar on the left eyebrow, that he has received from him as dowry upon his daughter Thaisarion, who has formerly lived with Chaeremon as his wife, a hundred drachmae of silver coin, and as parapherna a pair of gold ear-rings weighing four quarters, a gold crescent of three quarters, two gold rings of two quarters, a pair of silver armlets to the weight of 44 drachmae of unstamped metal, two bracelets to the weight of 16 drachmae of unstamped metal; in raiment two robes, one white, one narcissus, and five mantles; and bronze utensils and a bath, to the total weight of four minae, and without weight two bronze … , and five minae of tin; and without valuation in usufruct as a gift from the present 13th year of Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator the catoecic
holding of 10¾ arurae the property of Sisoïs in the area of Bacchias in two plots, consisting of 7¾ arurae of a holding in the place called Sade, the boundaries of which are, on the south the holding formerly belonging to Heraclides son of Zoilus, on the north the holding of Apollonius son of Straton, on the west the dyke called that of Archias by which the holding is drained, on the east the holding of Petheus son of Ptollis, separated by a common water-channel by which the holding is irrigated, and the second plot containing the remaining 3 arurae situate in the place called after Pieneouis, the boundaries of which are on the south the holding of Bacchion son of Ammonius, on the north the holding of Pa … eus son of … , on the west the dyke into which the holding drains, on the east the holding of Pisistratus. Let both Thaisarion and Chaeremon the parties to the marriage live blamelessly together as in their previous married life, Chaeremon carrying out all the yearly work of cultivation connected with the holding of 10¾ arurae presented, sowing and harvesting
the yearly produce and surplus produce resulting from them from the said present year, and carrying it to the home of their common wedded life, paying thereon all yearly public charges both of corn and money from the said present year. But if any difference arises between them and they separate the one from the other, either Chaeremon divorcing Thaisarion or Thaisarion withdrawing of her own free will, then the before-mentioned holding of 10¾ arurae shall belong to Thaisarion's father Sisoïs, or, if he be no longer living, to Thaisarion herself; and Chaeremon shall also restore the dowry aforesaid and the parapherna as they emerge from wear and tear, in the case of divorce forthwith, and in the case of voluntary withdrawal within 30 days from the day on which the demand is made to him. In what year soever the separation of the parties to the marriage takes place the proceeds of the holding for the twelve months of the year of separation shall be divided, and Chaeremon shall receive in proportion to the months during which Thaisarion shall have remained in the common house and Sisoïs the remainder, the public dues on the holding and seed-loans having first been deducted. As regards the terms of the contract Sisoïs, or, if he does not survive, Thaisarion and her assigns shall have the right of execution upon Chaeremon and all his property, as if in accordance with a legal decision. The subscriber of Sisoïs is … son of Hermas, aged about 41 years, with a scar on the right side of the forehead, Chaeremon being literate.’
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
