<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 2, 161</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">12949</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12949</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12949</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;2;161</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-09-15T12:08:19.563-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-09-15T12:08:19.524-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:28:22.942-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from Rylands catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:27:43-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <p>
               <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> ‘The third year of the Emperor Titus Caesar Vespasianus Augustus, the 10th of the month Artemisius, Phamenoth 10, in the village of Socnopaei Nesus in the division of Heraclides of the Arsinoite nome. Thases daughter of Panephrimmis son of Panephrimmis, aged about 45 years, having a mole on the right cheek, with her guardian her kinsman Stotoëtis son of Panephrimmis son of Marres, aged about 30 years, having a scar on the right shin, acknowledges to her daughter Stotoëtis’ husband Stotoëtis son of Satabous son of Herieus, aged about 32 years, having a scar on the left shin, that she the acknowledging party has sold to him in accordance with this agreement from the present day for ever the fourth part of a two-storied priest’s chamber and yard, common and undivided, and all appurtenances, belonging to her, Thases, within the enclosure of the temple of the god Socnopaeus in the eastern portion of the said temple; the boundaries of the whole priest’s chamber and yard are, on the south the common entrance and exit, on the north the priest's chamber and yard of Stotoëtis son of Satabous and the vacant space of the children of Teses son of Haruotes, on the west plots belonging to the said temple, on the east the above-mentioned enclosure; and that she, Thases, the acknowledging party, has received from Stotoëtis in full forthwith from hand to hand out of the house the price agreed upon for the fourth part sold of the priest's chamber and yard, [.]8 silver drachmae, and that Thases, the acknowledging party, and her assigns will entirely guarantee Stotoëtis and his assigns from all charges both public and private and from poll-tax from former times until the next census, from public and private charges and every claim for all time, (Stotoëtis having rights over) both entrances and exits, repairing, disposing, and renovating; and that the acknowledging party and her assigns make and will make no claim and will not dispute or attack in any way, transgressing none of the aforesaid provisions. But if she does not guarantee, or does not deliver, the property, she shall pay double the damages and costs and a fine of … silver drachmae and a similar sum to the Treasury. The subscriber of the acknowledging party and her guardian is Satabous son of Herieus, aged about 21 years, having no distinguishing mark, and of Thases, Onnophris son of Onnophris, aged about 32 years, having a scar on the right side of his forehead.’ Subscription and signature of Thases and docket of the record-office of Socnopaei Nesus.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
