<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 2, 155</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">12940</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12940</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12940</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;2;155</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-09-15T12:07:05.125-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-09-15T12:07:05.036-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:09:10.136-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from John Rylands library, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-20T18:01:25-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> ‘The year of the Emperor Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrianus Antoninus Augustus Pius …, in Heraclia in the division of Themistes of the Arsinolte nome. Thases daughter of Patron son of Satabous, a priestess, of the village of Socnopaei Nesus, aged about 65 years, with a scar … having as guardian, and with the subscription of, her son Apunchis son of Stotoetis, aged about 32 years, having a scar on the left side of his forehead …, acknowledges to her daughter Thasos by … son of Onnophris, aged about 42 years, having a scar on the right foot, with her guardian …, aged about 2[.] years, having a scar over the left eyebrow, that she the acknowledging party … has conveyed to Thasos by deed of gift in conformity with the decrees concerning indulgences … with full and undisturbed rights of possession henceforward the … share of a three-storied … house and all appurtenances belonging to her in the village of Socnopaei Nesus, and the … share of a paternal house, likewise of three stories, and all appurtenances, and a … part of priest's lodgings within the precincts of the temple; the boundaries of the .. house are, on the south a public street, on the north the house of Gallio, on the east the ... of Belles son of Castor, on the west a royal road, and the boundaries of the paternal house are on the south the house of Kimekis (?) …, on the north the house of …, on the east a public street, on the west the house of Koueis and … building plots. Thasos shall register as she pleases all the property aforesaid through the property record-office by producing a copy of this deed of gift, and having no need of the concurrence of any other person, but her mother Thases approves and will not proceed against Thasos in any way, because the deed of gift has been made on these terms.’ Subscription of Thases and docket of the record-office of Heraclia.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="1"/>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
