<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 2, 162</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">12950</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12950</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12950</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;2;162</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-09-15T12:06:32.907-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-09-15T12:06:32.881-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:29:48.036-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from Rylands catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:29:10-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <p>
               <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> ‘The 22nd year of the Emperor Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrianus Antoninus Augustus Pius, Pharmouthi 4, in Socnopaei Nesus in the division of Heraclides of the Arsinoïte nome. Thases daughter of Panephrumis son of Herieus, her mother being Tanephrumis, of the village of Socnopaei Nesus, aged about 20 years, having a scar along the right shin, with her guardian her kinsman Harpagathes son of Herieus son of Harpagathes, aged about 30 years, having a scar on the right shin, acknowledges to Taharpagathes daughter of Harpagathes son of Harpagathes, aged about 35years, having no distinguishing mark, with her guardian her husband Stotoëtis son of Stotoëtis, aged about 40 years, having a scar along the right shin, that she the acknowledging party has in accordance with this agreement sold for transference from the present time henceforth for ever to her, her descendants and assigns, the half share of a house and yard belonging to her in the village of Socnopaei Nesus and forming part of her heritage from her mother; the boundaries of the whole house and court are, as stated by mutual consent, on the south the house of … son of Stotoëtis, on the north a dung-hill, on the west a public road, on the east plots of various proprietors; and that she the acknowledging party has received in full forthwith from hand to hand the price agreed upon, 60 silver drachmae, and that she the acknowledging party will guarantee the objects of this sale perpetually with every guarantee against all past charges public and private, and that Taharpagathes, with her assigns, is owner of the half share of the house and court sold as aforesaid, having the right of entry and exit, with all existing entrances, exits, windows, walls, foundations, and other conditions of the sale, enjoying it with all present rights, having the power of sale, mortgage, gift, and appropriation to her private use of everything accruing therefrom. Whatsoever of the aforesaid conditions is transgressed by either the acknowledging party or her assigns, they shall pay double the price received, the costs, and a fine of 30 drachmae of silver, and a like sum to the Treasury.’ Subscription of Thases and docket of the record-office of Socnopaei Nesus.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
