<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 2, 179</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">12959</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12959</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12959</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;2;179</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-11-12T13:21:12.276-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-11-12T13:21:12.248-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:59:14.76-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from Rylands catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:58:00-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> ‘Registered by the record-office of Neilopolis.
The 12th year of the Emperor Caesar Trajanus Hadrianus Augustus, the 12th of the month Neus Sebastus, Hathur, in Neilopolis in the division of Heraclides of the Arsinoïte nome. Pakusis son of Stotoëtis son of Panephremmis …, priest of the first tribe of the great great god Soknopaeus, aged about . . years, having a scar on the left arm, acknowledges to his brother on both his father’s and mother’s side Panephremmis, aged about 50 years, having a scar on the little finger of the … hand, and to Stotoëtis …, the husband of their [deceased] sister Tanephremmis, priest of the said tribe of the said god, aged about 58 years, having a scar …, that he Pakusis, the acknowledging party, brings and will bring no charge nor claim nor will proceed in any way against his brother Panephremmis concerning the inheritance left by their aforesaid sister Tanephremmis ... in accordance with the division made in the 5th year of Hadrianus Caesar the lord, the 13th of the month Phamenoth through the record-office of ... in the … division, in regard to any of its provisions [since each has received his share (?)], nor against Thases daughter of Panephremmis concerning the … received by her from Tanephremmis … and neither Pakusis himself nor his assigns (will bring any charge) on any matter whatever written or unwritten from former times down to the present day in any manner, nor concerning the … apportioned to the aforesaid Tanephremmis by Panephremmis …, nor against Stotoëtis concerning the … arurae ceded by him; and the acknowledgement for 420 drachmae of silver made by Panephremmis to Pakusis the same day through the same record-office remains valid. The subscribers are, for the acknowledging party, Nonnus son of Heraclas, aged about 58 years, having a scar …, and for Panephremmis, Papeis son of Papeis, aged about 45 years, having a scar in the middle of the forehead.’ Signatures of Pakusis, written by Nonnus, and of Panephremmis, written by Papeis.

               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="1"/>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
