<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 2, 171</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">12953</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12953</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12953</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;2;171 pap.choix;;2</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-11-05T17:51:59.152-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-11-05T17:51:59.141-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:40:50.121-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from Rylands catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:40:10-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <p>
               <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> ‘To Euschemon, agent of the estate of Tiberius Claudius Doryphorus, formerly owned by Narcissus, in the Arsinoïte nome, from Papus son of Tryphon, of Heraclia in the division of Themistes, living in the farmstead of Antonia wife of Drusus, through Psenherieus, a Persian of the Epigone. I wish to lease for four years from the coming 3rd year of Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator the twenty-seven arurae ... in the area of the said village ... in two parcels, in one of which are seven arurae . . ., in the other twenty arurae, the adjacent areas being on the south Crown land …, on the north Crown land on the lake-shore, on the west the lands of …, on the east the lands of the estate of Maecenas ; on condition that after receiving for the purpose of tillage and the embankment of the land a grant per arura of … silver drachmae, which are not to be returned, I will pay a total yearly rental on the area which shall result from the survey of … artabae of … per arura, this to include the one artaba of wheat per arura which I shall receive for seed-corn ...’
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
