<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 2, 174 a</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">12957</idno>
            <idno type="TM">12957</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">12957</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;2;174A</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-11-12T13:20:53.142-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-11-12T13:20:53.13-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:48:13.018-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from Rylands catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:47:32-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <p>
               <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> ‘The 2nd year of the Emperor Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrianus Antoninus Augustus Pius, Pauni 3, at
Socnopaei Nesus in the division of Heraclides of the Arsinoite nome. Stotoetis the younger, son of Stotoëtis son of Stotoëtis, aged about 40 (?) years, with a scar on the right eyebrow, acknowledges to Stotoëtis the elder, aged about 30 years, with a scar on the left forearm, and to Stotoëtis the younger, aged about 20 years, with a scar on the left thumb, both of them sons of Panephremmis son of Stotoëtis and priests, the two, that he, the acknowledging party, has received from them forthwith from hand to hand out of the house the capital sum of 168 drachmae of silver which they owed to him in accordance with an agreement executed through the same registry-office in the 9th year of the deified Hadrian, the 19th of the month Pachon, which agreement he has surrendered to them to be annulled and cancelled ; and that he, the acknowledging party, makes no further claim either concerning this money received as aforesaid or concerning any other matter at all, written
or unwritten, in the past down to the present day in any manner or under any pretext. The subscriber … is …, who has written for him as he is illiterate.’ Signature of Stotoëtis the lender.

            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
