<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 2, 88</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">13007</idno>
            <idno type="TM">13007</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">13007</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;2;88</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-09-09T08:35:07.482-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-09-09T08:35:07.463-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-17T15:56:58.886-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from John Rylands Catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-17T15:56:01-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <p>
               <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> ‘To … and Maron son of Maron and … and Syrus son of Petesouchos and … and Draucus son of Ninnas, all six elders of the village of Archelais in the division of Themistes. I, Diogas son of Demetrius son of Maron, my mother being ..., of the metropolis, registered in the quarter of Dionysius’ District, having been presented by you to the office of guard in the metropolis, swear by the fortune of Antoninus Caesar the lord that I will of necessity obey the strategus of the divisions of Themistes and Polemon, Onomastus, from the present day until the 5th intercalary day of the present 20th year of Antoninus Caesar the lord, receiving from you for the whole period of 10 months the sum agreed upon between us, 180 drachmae of silver, and you shall pay me every second month the instalment of 36 drachmae. Nothing is owing to me for the current period. I will perform all the duties pertaining to the office of a guard blamelessly, the responsibility, if anything occurs by my neglect, resting on my private property; otherwise may I be held responsible for the consequences of my oath. Written by Ammonias, scribe of the nome ; Diogas, professing to be illiterate, is aged about 35 years, with a scar on the left cheek and the left calf.’ Date.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
