<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 4, 601</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">13020</idno>
            <idno type="TM">13020</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">13020</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;4;601</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-01-30T08:34:04.249-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2013-01-30T08:34:04.225-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-23T19:53:16.031-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from Rylands catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-23T19:50:25-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> Docket, then (2nd hand) ‘In the 4th year of the dominion of Caesar, divi filius, the … th of the month Hyperberetaios = … th Mesore, in Ptolemais Euergetis in the Arsinoite nome. Demetrius son of Diodotus, Thessalian, has leased to Chaeremon, son of Zenon, and Limnaios, son of Ptolemy, both of them Persians of the epigone, for a period of three years from the fifth year of Caesar the plot of land belonging to him consisting of 49 arourae or such as it may be situated near Psenarpsenesis in the Heraclid division (3rd hand) at the following rent: for the 45 arourae in one parcel (inclusive of 45 artabae of seed corn), 348 artabae of wheat; for the 4 arourae in the other parcel (excluding seed corn) 40 artabae of wheat, plus 4 artabae of new wheat and 2 cocks as special inducements. The yearly rents are to be paid by the lessees to Demetrius on each occasion in the month of Payni at Karanis, in new clean wheat, clear of all trickery, to be … by the 6-choinix trade and market measure of Karanis, free of all risk, and subject to no deduction for spoiling except failure of flood irrigation. But if … 
(4th hand) ‘Year 4 of Caesar, Mesore 7, registered through the grapheon officials.
(5th hand) ‘We, Chaeremon son of Zenon and Limnion, son of Ptolemy, both Persians of the epigone, have leased for a period of three years from the fifth year of Caesar the plot of land of Demetrius near Psenarpsenesis, amounting to 49 arourae or such as it may be, situated in two parcels at the following rent: for the 45 arourae in one parcel (inclusive of 45 artabae of seed corn) 348 artabae of wheat; in the other parcel (exclusive of seed corn) 40 artabae of wheat, plus 4 artabae of wheat and 2 cocks as special inducement; and we shall hand over the rents in the month of Payni at Karanis, measured by the 6-choinix trade measure of the village; and every year we shall rest the land in the large parcel with hay or beans, and we reciprocally guarantee each other to pay in full. I, Limnaios, son of Ptolemy, Persian of the epigone, have joined in the lease and (join in reciprocal guarantee) for payment in full as set out above.’
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="1"/>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
