<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Sakaon, 41</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">13060</idno>
            <idno type="TM">13060</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">13060</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;4;659 p.sakaon;;41</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-03-25T08:56:11.118-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2013-03-25T08:56:10.966-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-23T20:27:54.384-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from Rylands catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-23T20:27:11-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <p>
               <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> ‘To Sabinianus, the most illustrious praeses of Aegyptus Herculia, from Arion son of Dioscorus from the village of Theadelphia in the Arsinoite nome. Your mightiness has ordered, lord praeses, in accordance with the divine order, that no one should be subjected to undue demands but that each man should meet his own burdens. Now I lived with my wife Irene and begot children by her, and she with her children departed this life. Now the local collectors, in contempt of my meek and unobtrusive character and of my age and childlessness no less are attacking me and wishing to do me violence in respect of my father-in-law’s land on the ground that I am not in partnership with him. That is why I pray and beseech your virtue to pity my old age and the disaster of my children’s death that has overtaken me and give instructions most stringent in your reply with the result that with your approval a stop may be put to these local acts of violence that I may be in a position to meet the burdens proper to my land and throughout confess my gratitude to your Genius. Farewell. I Areion have submitted the petition. I, Isidorus, of the same city, have written on his behalf as he claims to be illiterate.’
(2nd hand) ‘Epeiph 20. The Praepositus of the pagus is well aware from whom taxes should be collected in respect of the sacred revenues of the land. Entry 102, volume 1.’
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
