<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Worp, 18</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">13572</idno>
            <idno type="TM">13572</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">13572</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.worp;;18 p.tebt;2;460</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-06-15T01:42:25.53-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-06-15T01:42:25.525-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2011-10-27T07:26:51.762-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Entered Greek text and translation from digital copy of P. Worp 18</change>
         <change when="2011-03-09T05:33:27-05:00" who="SoSOL">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <p>
               <milestone unit="line" n="1"/>In the third year of Imperator Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrianus Antoninus 
Augustus Pius on the 13th of the month Sebastos in Tebtynis of the Polemon district of the 
Arsinoite nome. Tepheros, daughter of Apeis, granddaughter of Collouthos, about twenty one 
years old <milestone unit="line" n="5"/> with a scar on her right foot, with as guardian her paternal uncle Chiales, her 
husband, about sixty years old with a scar on the third finger of his left hand, acknowledges 
to Protas, son of Nephersos, about sixty eight years old, with a scar on the little finger of his 
left hand, that she has received from Protas cash <milestone unit="line" n="10"/> one hundred and twelve drachmas of silver 
and the parapherna, (but) that she cedes the pherne, which they still owe the same Tepheros, 
daughter of Apeis, because she has received the above mentioned sum of money in 
accordance with a deed [of cession], which was perfected through the same notary office in 
the twenty first year of deified Hadrian in the month Mesore, which (deed) <milestone unit="line" n="15"/> Tepheros has also 
handed over to Protas, equally that she shall not lay any claims to him about any matter 
whatsoever nor about the dowry gifts, equally that she shall not proceed against Protas about 
an unbuilt area in Tebtynis estimated at sixty (drachmas), for which Chiales had himself 
appointed guardian at Tepheros’ request (?), in accordance with a written deed <milestone unit="line" n="20"/> of cession, 
because she has received also these (drachmas) from Nephersos. Orsenou(phis) wrote it 
for her.
I, Tepheros, daughter of Apeis, with as guardian my paternal uncle, Ciales, son of Collouthos, 
acknowledge that I have received  from Protas, son of Nephersos, hundred and twelve 
drachmas of silver and the parapherna, that I (cede) the <milestone unit="line" n="25"/> pherne which they owe me 
according to a contract, since/after that she has married in the twenty first year of deified 
Hadrian, after Dionysos, son of Nephersos, himself had finished his life and that I shall not 
proceed against Protas about any matter whatsoever nor about [the unbuilt area] for which 
Chiales, son of Collouthos, had himself appointed guardian of Tepheros, daughter of 
Apeis - - - <milestone unit="line" n="33" rend="break"/> Ciales and Tepheros.
</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
