<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.10/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
    <teiHeader type="text">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">P.Oxy. 78, 5169 </title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
                <idno type="filename">170053</idno>
                <idno type="TM">170053</idno>
                <idno type="HGV">170053</idno>
                <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;78;5169</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
                        a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="fr">French</language>
                <language ident="en">English</language>
                <language ident="de">German</language>
                <language ident="it">Italian</language>
                <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
                <language ident="la">Latin</language>
                <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
                <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2024-05-30T04:04:41.564-05:00"
                who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Added via github because the file was corrupt in the editor.</change>
            <change when="2018-11-05T13:36:58-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
                           <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> Year thirteen of Caesar, Phaophi 12, in the city of Oxyrhynchi in the Thebaid. Arsinoe daughter of Ariston, 
having with her as her guardian her brother Apion son of Ariston, acknowledges to Herceus the elder, son of Petosiris, the three of them in the street, 
that she is in receipt from the said (man) and from his younger brother Herceus, and, in their absence, also from their father Petosiris son of Beniaeus(?), 
of (the sum of?) one hundred drachmas in silver currency, as principal to which nothing was added, 
<milestone n="7" unit="line"/>which Arsinoe lent them in accordance with a contract concluded through the bureau of the record-office in the city of Oxyrhynchi, 
in the tenth year of Caesar in Phamenoth, in consideration of the service of the daughter of Petosiris and sister of the others, 
(namely) Senerceus, not yet of age, for two years, in accordance with the guidelines notified through it; 
<milestone n="13" unit="line"/>and that Arsinoe will bring no claim now or in the future, nor take proceedings, nor will another on her behalf, 
against the aforementioned, nor against the agents, concerning any provision whatever of the contract of service here made known: 
otherwise, apart from any future claim being invalid, Arsinoe or the person who will take proceedings on her behalf will also pay in addition, 
to the aforementioned or their agents, in respect of each claim, both the damages and a fine of three hundred drachmas of silver, 
and an equal number to the treasury and no less. <milestone n="21" unit="line"/>The contract is binding. Arsinoe...
<note>Translation: P.Oxy. 78 5169</note>
              </p>
           </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
