<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 4, 609</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">17309</idno>
            <idno type="TM">17309</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">17309</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">c.ep.lat;;242</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-03-25T09:11:24.612-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2013-03-25T09:11:23.898-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-23T20:12:10.978-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from Rylands catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-23T20:11:21-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <p>
               <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> ‘Flavius Constantinius Theophanes, count, vir illustris, count of the most faithful household troops 
              and of the military administration of the Thebaid frontier to Flavius Verte alias Theodotus the most faithful tribune stationed at Hermopolis. 
              Since I shall be taking steps in accord with the sacred order of our lord Anastasius, the most religious, the conqueror, 
              the perpetual Augustus whereby young men of strong physique are to be attached to units to bring them up to strength, 
              this my order hereby instructs Heracleon, son of Constantinus, a native of the city of Hermopolis to serve in the troop 
              at present entrusted to your care; if he is of military family, is neither of senatorial nor of gubernatorial rank 
              and is not ….. weak physique and is not enrolled on the census list, see to it that his name is entered on the register of the said unit, 
              taking care that he is supplied from the ides of … in the year of the consulate of the most distinguished Sabinianus and Theodorus 
              with the provisions together with the other comrades and that he applies himself to his military duties – the above provided that 
              he is known to have completed his eighteenth year. (2nd hand) Farewell. Checked by me. (1st hand) Farewell.’
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
