<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 4, 662</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">17322</idno>
            <idno type="TM">17322</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">17322</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;4;662</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-08-29T18:15:59.556-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-29T18:15:59.53-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-23T20:30:45.212-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from Rylands catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-23T20:29:41-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> ‘Dated in the year after the fourth consulate of Iulianus and the first of Flavius Sallustius, the most illustrious Prefect of the Sacred Praetorium (A.A. 363.)
‘Aurelia Thaisa, daughter of Papnouthis and Tanophris, of the Arsinoite nome but resident in the most illustrious city of Antinous, and Aurelia Thaesis, daughter of Archias and Tanois from the same city of Antinous, being sureties each for the other for repayment, to Aurelia Tabinis of the same city of Antinous, greeting. We admit to receiving from you on deposit free of all risk and not subject to any deduction eleven thousand six hundred talents of silver, total 11,600 tal., which sum we will repay to you at whatsoever time you please without any delay or prevarication, failing which we will make restitution to you in accordance with the law governing deposits, you having the right of execution on us being sureties each for the other jointly and severally as you may choose for payment or on all our possessions as though in accordance with a legal decision. This deed of deposit which we have herewith issued to you for your security is true and valid and on being asked the formal question we have given our consent. Mecheir 18.
We, Aurelia Thaësa daughter of Papnouthis and Thaësis daughter of Archias the aforementioned, hold on deposit the eleven thousand six hundred talents, and will restore them as aforesaid. I, Aurelius Dorotheus, son of Antinoos, have written for them being illiterate.’
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="1"/>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
