<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Cair. Isid., 1</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>NYU Digital Library Technology Services</authority>
            <idno type="filename">17375</idno>
            <idno type="TM">17375</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">17375</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.cair.isid;;1 sb;5;7622</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2015-04-10T07:59:50.63-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/simoeis">Finalized - Ready</change>
         <change when="2015-04-10T07:59:50.625-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-03-31T22:12:38.276-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/gwschwendner">Added translation from the ed.pr.</change>
         <change when="2012-03-31T20:41:34-04:00" who="SoSOL">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <p>
           Aristius Optatus , the most eminent prefect of Egypt says:
Our most provident Emperors, Diocletian and Maximian, the noble Caesars .... having learned that the levies of the public taxes were being levied capriciously so that some persons were let off lightly  while others were overburdened, decided in the interests of their provincials to root out this most evil and ruinous practice and issue a salutary rule to which the taxes would have to conform.
Thus it is possible for all to know the amount levied on each aroura in accordance to with the character of the land, and the amount levied on each head of the rural population, and the minimum and maximum ages of liability, from the imperial edict which has been published and the schedule attached thereto, to which I have prefixed for public display the copies of this edict of mine.
Accordingly, since in this too they have been treated with the greatest beneficence, let the provincials take care to make their contributions with all speed in conformity with the imperial regulations and in no wise wait for the collector to exercise compulsion.  For it is fitting that each person discharge most zealously the full burden of loyalty, and if anyone should be detected doing otherwise after such beneficence, he will risk punishment.
The magistrates and the presidents of the councils of each city have been ordered to dispatch to each village or place whatsoever a copy of the imperial edict together with the schedule and also this edict (of mine) as well, to the end that the munificence of our Emperors and Caesars may come as speedily as possible to the knowledge of all.
The collectors of every kind of tax are also reminded to look to their duties to the best of their ability, for if anyone should be detected in transgression, he will risk capital punishment.
Years 13, 12 and 5 of our lords Diocletian and Maximian, Augusti, and Constantius and Maximian, most noble Caesars, Phamenoth 20.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>