<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title type="main"> HGVTITLE (DDBTITLE) </title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">hgv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="TM">gv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">hgv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.cair.masp;3;67302</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-02-22T07:56:56-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> ☧ The twenty-ninth year of the reign of our most God-loving Lord Flavius Iustinianus, the eternal Augustus and Emperor, the fourteenth year after the consulate of gloriosissimus Flavius Basileios, on the fourth day of Tybi of the fourth indiction, in the most illustrious Antinoopolis.
† Aurelia ama Rachel, daughter of Kollouthos, of the mother Kyra, coming from Antinoopolis, to Aurelius Isaak, my most legitimate full brother of the same parents, him also being from Antinoopolis.
I, willingly and by my own choice, acknowledge that I have leased from your admirability, for as long as you want counting from the first of the past month of Choiak of the present fourth indiction, the dining room located on the upper floor, inclined to the north, with the bedroom? near (it) inclining to the east that is close, and yet one room under … facing the south, with the right to use the entrance and exit and stairs up and down with all its rights of the entire part of a two-floor house belonging to you, wherever it is located, with the hall and courtyard and all appurtenances and rights, located here in Antinoopolis, in the district gramma, in the upper parts of the city, open to the east, so that I have them for our use and dwelling, and give you on the account of the rents each year twelve carats of gold, that is 12 carats of gold, which rent for the house I will pay you every year without delay. And after as much time as you wish, I will return you the rooms with installed doors and keys, with all its rights. 
The misthosis is valid and firm, and, having been asked a formal question, I consented to all stated terms. 
☧ I, Aurelia ama Rachel, daughter of Kollouthos, have leased your part of the house, and will give you a yearly rent for the house, as stated above.
I, NN …  wrote for her, at her request, as she does not know letters.
I, NN, son of NN, … from … the city, witness to the misthosis having heard the party’s acknowledgements. (translation by Law in Social Networks project)
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
