<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>BGU 4, 1055</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">18499</idno>
            <idno type="TM">18499</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">18499</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">bgu;4;1055</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-08-31T08:58:59-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Finalized - Ready.</change>
         <change when="2022-08-31T08:43:04-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Fine</change>
         <change when="2022-08-31T08:11:42-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Submit - Translation by P. Van Minnen.</change>
         <change when="2022-08-31T08:03:54-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="2" unit="line"/> To Protarchos, 
<milestone n="3" rend="break" unit="line"/> from Apollonios, the son of Herakleides, and from Ammonios, the son of Anoubion, a Persian of the epigone. 
<milestone n="6" rend="break" unit="line"/> Concerning the points at issue, Ammonios agrees that he has received from Apollonios in cash and not through a bank as a loan: 
<milestone n="10" unit="line"/> 64 Ptolemaic silver drachmas without interest, which (loan) he also agrees that he will pay back 
in three months from the present month Pharmouthi of the 17th year of Caesar (Augustus), <milestone n="14" unit="line"/> by necessarily giving each 
day for the three months a jar of eighteen measures (BL1.93; almost 5 liters) of good quality cow’s milk, while 
skipping not a single day, 
<milestone n="20" rend="break" unit="line"/>on the condition that Apollonios on his part will deduct the value of the jar from 
the aforementioned balance, viz. four obols, until the loan is paid off, <milestone n="24" unit="line"/> or else Ammonios agrees that on the day that he skips the 
supply of the milk he is immediately liable to seizure (Mitteis, Chrest.) and can be held under arrest until he pays the whole sum, 
without waiting for the time allotted to him, <milestone n="31" unit="line"/> or what will remain of the debt (BL 1.93) 
along with half as much again and for the time that has gone beyond (the due date) the two drachmas (per 100 drachmas per month) interest 
in accordance with the statute, <milestone n="34" unit="line"/> while the right of execution (of the claim) belongs to Apollonios from both Ammonios himself and from 
all his belongings just as if by virtue of a legal decision, while all safe-conducts (and) every kind of protection he adduces 
are ineffective. <milestone n="40" unit="line"/> This loan is separate from the other (debt) the same Ammonios together with his mother 
owes Apollonios in accordance with another agreement: 100 drachmas, 
<milestone n="45" unit="line"/> the interest of which he has fully paid until the aforementioned month Pharmouthi
<milestone n="47" rend="break" unit="line"/> Year 17 of Caesar (Augustus), Pharmouthi 5.
<note>Translation (as of 31.08.2022) with minor modifications: P. van Minnen, <ref target="https://classics.uc.edu/users/vanminnen/ancient_alexandria/pdf/bgu_4_1055.pdf">../vanminnen/ancient_alexandria/pdf/bgu_4_1055.pdf</ref></note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
