<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>BGU 4, 1050</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">18493</idno>
            <idno type="TM">18493</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">18493</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">bgu;4;1050</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2017-09-27T08:26:28-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/james.cowey">Finalized - Ready.</change>
         <change when="2017-09-27T06:40:44-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/james.cowey">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Fine</change>
         <change when="2017-09-27T06:39:46-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/james.cowey">Submit - Rename this properly</change>
         <change when="2017-03-14T08:25:46-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2017-03-14T07:34:35-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Had already been checked by two persons here in Leiden</change>
         <change when="2017-03-10T10:11:39-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Submit - added translation</change>
         <change when="2017-03-10T10:11:06-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Commit - added English translation</change>
         <change when="2017-03-10T10:10:19-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               (From J.E. Grubbs, Women and the Law in the Roman Empire, 2002, pp. 124-125.)

<milestone n="1" rend="break" unit="line"/>To Protarchos, from Isidora daughter of Herakleides also called Dionysios, with her kyrios, her brother Bakhios, son of Herakleides also called Dionysios from the deme of Althea and from Dionysios son of <milestone n="5" unit="line"/> Dionysios from the deme of Isis. Isidora and Dionysios acknowledge that they have come together with each other in marriage. And Dionysios also acknowledges that he has received from Isidora by hand from her house a dowry of women’s clothes valued at 100 drachmas of silver, a pair of gold earrings of <milestone n="10" unit="line"/> two quarters weight (of a gold didrachmon) and sixty drachmas of coined Ptolemaic silver.
	(They marry on the understanding that) Dionysios, taking the aforementioned dowry, supports and clothes Isidora as befits a married woman, according to his means, and that he not mistreat her or <milestone n="15" unit="line"/> abuse her or throw her out or bring another woman into (the house) or (if he does), he pays back in full the dowry plus 50 percent, there being the right (to Isidora) to exact payment from the same Dionysios and from all his possessions as if by a court judgement. And (on the understanding that) Isidora does not <milestone n="20" unit="line"/> sleep away or be away for a day from Dionysios’ house without Dionysios’ approval, or damage the home, or be with another man, or (if she does), after being judged guilty of having done so, she is deprived of her dowry. 
	(They acknowledge) that <milestone n="25" unit="line"/> they will also deposit a contract about the marriage at the office of the hierothytai within five working days from the day when they announce this to each other, in which will be written both the dowry and the other customary things and the things concerning the death of either one of the spouses, <milestone n="30" unit="line"/> as it is decided (by them) in common at the right time. We ask (that this document be registered). 

            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
