<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
    <teiHeader type="text">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>BGU 4 1133</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
                <idno type="filename">18577</idno>
                <idno type="TM">18577</idno>
                <idno type="HGV">18577</idno>
                <idno type="ddb-hybrid">bgu;4;1133</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
                        a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="fr">French</language>
                <language ident="en">English</language>
                <language ident="de">German</language>
                <language ident="it">Italian</language>
                <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
                <language ident="la">Latin</language>
                <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2024-01-23T10:16:46.256-05:00"
                who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Uploaded through github</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <p>
                <milestone unit="line" n="1"/>From Chaeremon son of Zopyrion, Artemidorus son of Pathreus, Persian of the Epigone, 
                and his wife Hermione daughter of Chaeremon, Persian, with her husband Artemidorus, her guardian. <milestone unit="line" n="3"/>Whereas Chaeremon,
                on the request of Artemidorus and Hermione, had himself named with them in two loans from Artemidorus son of Heraclides, 
                president of the club, so that they might borrow up to – dr. in bronze in accordance with the agreement made on the same day 
                before the same tribunal, <milestone unit="line" n="7"/>Artemidorus and Hermione acknowledge that Chaeremon received absolutely nothing 
                from the above-mentioned sum, but that they have used the whole amount for their own private needs, and they shall pay it back to 
                Artemidorus son of Heraclides in the prescribed instalments according to the terms of the aforesaid agreement, and they shall release 
                Chaeremon from his agreement, and from this time on shall in every way protect him from arrest or exaction in regard to the loan. 
                This they shall do without any dispute. <milestone unit="line" n="15"/>If not, they shall be liable to arrest and detention until they pay 
                whatever they owe on the two loans with a penalty of 50% and the legal interest as well as damages. Chaeremon shall have the right of 
                exaction from both, being mutually liable for payment, or from whichever one he chooses and from all their property as if legal judgement 
                had been given, whatever pacts they may plead of any kind being invalid. <milestone unit="line" n="21" rend="break"/>The 12th year of Caesar. Choiak 18.
                <note xml:lang="en">Translation: Johnson, Roman Egypt, Nr. 282</note>
            </p>
         </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
