<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Cair. Masp. 2, 67129</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">18876</idno>
            <idno type="TM">18876</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">18876</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.cair.masp;2;67129</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-02-22T07:38:42-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> The eight year after the consulate of the gloriosissimus Flavius Basilius, Mesore 21, 13 indiction.
<milestone n="3" rend="break" unit="line"/> To the admirandissimus Flavius Dioskoros, son of Apollos, from the village of Aphrodite of the Antaiopolite nome.
† (From) Psais, son of Besis (pap. Besios) and Tasais, priest from the same village of Aphrodite, greetings. 
<milestone n="7" unit="line"/> I acknowledge through this written security of mine that I owe and I am indebted to you, in earnest and undoubtedly, 
for the sowing and the rent and the irrigation or my three arourae seeded by you, <milestone n="13" rend="break" unit="line"/> from the Athanasias topos, situated at the adjacent corn-bearing piece of land, near fruitful land, 
so that I have it for the payment in wheat in the time of the produce of the, God willing, fourteenth indiction, two and one third gold solidi and one artaba of grain … two … 
<milestone n="19" unit="line"/> and I am ready to pay them to you for the third payment of the tax; first the two … and the third in the time of the harvest of the same thirteenth indiction, the aforementioned solidi, 
each minus two carats, free from any deceit, and with all my personal property subjected until the payment. <milestone n="27" unit="line"/> And having been asked the formal question on all points, I gave my consent. 
Τhe grain at the time of threshing of the same, God willing, 14th indiction. ⳨ 
<milestone n="29" unit="line"/> (hand 2) † Psais, son of Besis, priest, the afore-mentioned, I agree as stated above.
Aurelius Ioannes, son of Victor, I wrote for him, at his request, because he cannot write.
<milestone n="32" unit="line"/> (hand 3) † Flavius Menas, son of Ioseph, I witness the debt.
(hand 1) † Written through me, Pilatos, nomikos. <note>Translation: Law in Social Networks project</note>

            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
