<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Cair. Masp. 2, 67164</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">18920</idno>
            <idno type="TM">18920</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">18920</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.cair.masp;2;67164</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-10T10:46:53-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> Aurelius Kollouthos, son of Lilous, his mother being Maria, greengrocer, hailing from the clara Hermopolis Magna, <milestone n="2" unit="line"/> to Aurelius Kollouthos, son of Georgios, 
pork-butcher, from this Antinoopolis, greetings.
<milestone n="3" unit="line"/> I have and owe you, clearly and without fail, nine and a half carats of gold, that is 9 ½ carats of gold, according to the public weight of Antinoopolis;
and I – along with my heirs of any type - am ready to return them to you and your successors of any type from my entire daily wages.
<milestone n="7" rend="break" unit="line"/> I am now present in this Antinopolis conducting greengrocery business until I will repay these 9 ½ carats to you, 
and if I leave the city first or I will be explaining (myself) before you about that, I will pay to you one solid minus six carats of the same weight without a controversy or trial, 
under the liability of my entire property, through (whoever) brings forward this document. 
<milestone n="11" rend="break" unit="line"/> and for your security I made this (document) with the subscription of one who subscribed for me, I am satisfied as stated above. 
The fifth of Phaophi of the third indiction. † † † sign of Kollouthos, greengrocer from Hermopolis. <note>Translation: Law in Social Network Project (Warsaw)</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
