<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title type="main"> HGVTITLE (DDBTITLE) </title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">hgv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="TM">gv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">hgv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.cair.masp;1;67124</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-12-03T03:26:54-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> Aurelii Charisios, son of Hermauos, and Besarion, son of Dioskoros, protokometai of the village of Aphrodite, to Aurelius Apollos, son of Dioskoros, boethos of the same (village), greetings.
We acknowledge through this written procuratorship of ours, we entrust you and command you, so that, if need invokes, that you borrow on our behalf in Antinoopolis and give for any matter whatsoever pertaining to the public matter of the same village, this we have deemed worthy to do. 
And we are ready to, when you are present in the village, deliver to you the things borrowed by you for this matter of the village.
And for your security we have issued for you this procuratorship with our signature as above.
I, the aforementioned Aurelius Charisios, son of Hermauos, entrust this procuratorship by mutual security as above.
I, the aforementioned Aurelius Besarion, son of Dioskoros, entrust this procuratorship by mutual security as above.
I, Hadrianus, son of Abraham (pap.: Abraamios), soldier of the company of Antaiopolis, am witness to this procuratorship having heard it from the ones who set it and having written the text.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> procuratorship of Charisios and Besarion for Apollos, boethos. /Tr. Law in Social Networks Project (Warsaw)/
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
