<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 2, 77</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">19486</idno>
            <idno type="TM">19486</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">19486</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;2;77</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-09-09T05:52:07.292-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-09-09T05:52:07.274-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-16T20:05:55.377-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from John Rylands Catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-16T19:27:17-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <div n="1" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="28"/> The administrators of the guilds said :— “... has made a pretence of being without means
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="30"/>  in order that he may himself go free and other persons be appointed in his place.” Harpalus said:— “If you think good, order the bail which I provided to be released and the keys of the house to be restored.” The administrators of the guilds said:— “The bail shall be released and you shall receive the keys.” . . . as, assistant, went out. Thus far the copy. The 32nd year, the 29th of the month Epeiph. I pray for your health, dear friends.—And a copy of minutes:— ...there being present at the tribune Dius, gymnasiarch in office, Dionysius also called . . ., exegetes in office, Olympiodorus, advocate, Apollonius son of Heraclapollon, ex-gymnasiarch, and Achilles son of Cornelius, the citizens standing by cried out “Let Achilles be crowned as cosmetes; imitate your father the lover of office, the brave old man”, whereupon Achilles said:— “Obedient to my native city, I offer to undertake the office of a crowned exegetes on the condition that I contribute an annual sum of two talents and am released from the superintendence of land under lease.” Olympiodorus said:— “The fortune of our lord the Emperor provides offices abundantly and augments the prosperity of the city; how can it not, during the delightful praefecture of Larcius Memor? If then Achilles wishes to be crowned as exegetes, let him pay the entrance deposit (?). Otherwise he none the less nominated himself for the office immediately required, that of cosmetes.” Achilles said:- I offered to to undertake the office of exegetes on the condition that I contribute two talents annually; for I am not able to support the office of cosmetes.” Olympiodorus said:— “A person who has offered to undertake the greater office ought not to shun the lesser.” Ammonion son of Dioscorus, interrupting, said:— “All through this day Achilles struck me, and I will certify these very facts by means of your minutes; for I am petitioning his highness the praefect concerning the insult.” Achilles said: “I neither struck him nor insulted him.” Sarapion also called Apollonius, strategus, said :— “What you have said has been recorded; but the cosmetae shall also be summoned in order that you may repeat the same statements in their presence.” After a while Diogenes and Dioscorus and their fellow cosmetae came forward at the Caesareum in the presence of Achilles, and one of them, their spokesman Diogenes, said :— “We have learned that Achilles in our absence put himself forward for the office of exegetes. This however was not permissible; for the most divine Antoninus ordained by decree that three exegetae-designate (?) are necessary for the office of exegetes, and when, therefore, there are many designate he ought to pass on to the office immediately required; and I will read the decree to you to that effect.” When he had read a copy of the decree of Marcus Aurelius Antoninus Caesar, Aspidas father of Hermas, ex-cosmetes, who was present said :— “On my personal responsibility I crown Achilles for the office of cosmetes.” Olympiodorus said: “We now have the declaration of Aspidas that he crowns him on his own responsibility ; and he ought to be crowned, for the office is now secured to the city.' The strategus directed the statements to be entered on the minutes. Read by me.—A copy of a further missive:—The magistrates of Hermopolis the Great to their dearest Sarapion also called Apollonius, strategus of the Hermopolite nome, greeting. Achilles son of Nearchidas also called Cornelius, ex-agoranomus, on being presented to the office of cosmetes by certain cosmetae offered in your presence to become exegetes. But when we urged him to undertake the office of cosmetes, since the city had not many cosmetae while the exegetae-designate were more numerous, Aspidas father of Hermas, ex-cosmetes, crowned him as cosmetes on his own responsibility, as was inserted in your minutes. Since, therefore, the office is secured to the city through one or other of them, notice is given you in order that you may arrange to carry out the consequences of the proceedings before you, so that the city may obtain the magistracy. The 32nd year, Pharmouthi 13. The exegetes and gymnasiarch signed.
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
