<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 2, 78</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">19487</idno>
            <idno type="TM">19487</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">19487</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;2;78</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-09-09T05:51:54.589-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-09-09T05:51:54.579-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-16T20:10:53.537-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from John Rylands catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-16T20:07:51-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <div n="1" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="17"/> The packet of letters which you say you have not received and which was previously sent by me as long ago as . . . including one from his highness the praefect concerning the decree issued to sitologi . . . was then forwarded by me through Claudius . . . and given to the heirs of Ischyrion, ex-basilicogrammateus . . . ,
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="23"/> while the dispatches of Demetrianus, knight, were given to the overseer at the station of Basilius, where I conjecture that the packet has remained, no messenger being there from your nome to carry it to you according to the orders. If you have not yet received it, take care to send somebody at once to take it. I am sending you a letter of his highness the praefect about the collection of the corn due from Hierax son of Cebes from the produce of the . . . year, and 7 dispatches, viz. to the strategus of the Heracleopolite nome about the conduct of his business and unanswered letters 1, to the strategus of the Bubastite nome 3, one about petitions and other matters, the two others about the collection of . . ., to the strategus of Antinoopolis concerning the search for Panther, a pilot, 1, . . . 2 written to the heirs of Ischyrion, ex-basilicogrammateus, who are landholders in the nome, one concerning the report of judgements, the other concerning the . . . statements of the privy purse. I have already sent to you on the ... a packet of letters containing one from his highness the praefect concerning persons owing sums to the strategus of the Hermopolite nome and a copy of his answer. I pray for your health, dearest friend. Through Serenus, secretary. The 20th year of the Emperor Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrianus Antoninus Augustus Pius, Pachon 30.
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
