<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 2, 102</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">19498</idno>
            <idno type="TM">19498</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">19498</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;2;102</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-09-09T08:55:39.134-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-09-09T08:55:39.105-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-17T17:31:03.421-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from John Rylands Catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-17T17:28:02-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <div n="1" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="1"/>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="26"/> ‘The 9th year of Domitian, quarter of the Western Guard-house, 4th amphodarchy (?), page 17. Isidote called elsewhere Taseis, daughter of Horion and Demetrous, and co., (daughter of?) Herrnaeus son of Sarapion, her mother being Thermouthis daughter of Petosiris, aged 58 years, (returning) among others her son Dius, having the aforesaid mother, aged . years, (and among other) women Aphrodisia her twin-daughter, aged 6 years.’

‘The 11th year of Nero, West-end quarter, vol. i, page 31. Ammonius also called Hermaeus, son of Hermaeus the elder, son of Hermias, his mother being Aphrodisia, aged 14 years, (returning) his brother Eutychides, having the same mother, aged 9 years, another Hermaeus having the same mother, aged 2 years, (among other) women his daughter Dionysias, aged 5 years.’

‘Registration in the list of minors from the gymnasium, quarter of the Western Guard-house, Herodes also called Polydeuces, son of Polydeuces and Tereus daughter of Dioscorus, aged 1 year in the 21st year of the deified Hadrian.’

‘The 9th year of Antoninus Caesar the lord, quarter of the Western Guard-house, 15th amphodarchy (?). Return of Polydeuces also called Sabourion, son of Herodes and Sparte also called Taphealis, daughter of Hermaeus, from the gymnasium, registered in the quarter of the Western Guard-house, (returning) among others himself Polydeuces also called Sabourion, from the gymnasium, aged 39 years, having a scar on the forehead, his son Herodes also called Polydeuces, his mother being Tereus daughter of Dioscorus, previously registered, from the gymnasium, aged 10 years, another son Achillas, having the same mother, aged 6 years, and among other women his wife Tereus daughter of Dioscorus and Otas, from the gymnasium, (registered in) the quarter of the Western Guard-house, aged 33 years.’
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
