<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 2, 120</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">19507</idno>
            <idno type="TM">19507</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">19507</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;2;120</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-09-10T04:49:58.042-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-09-10T04:49:58.023-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-17T18:31:18.233-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from Rylands catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-17T18:30:23-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <p>
               <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> ‘Archias, priest and exegetes of Hermopolis Magna, from … , daughter of … and …, of Hermopolis, registered in the quarter of ... , with my representative, for the purposes of this petition, Demetrius son of … also called Heliodorus, whose mother is Helene, of Hermopolis, registered in the quarter of the Eastern …, who is writing on my behalf as I am illiterate. In accordance with the permissive ordinance of the most illustrious praefect Flavius Titianus I choose through you Herminus son of Hermaeus son of Ammonius, his mother being Helene, registered in the quarter of …, to be assigned as my guardian and to write on my behalf who am illiterate. I am mortgaging to Herminus son of Dioscorus son of Didymus, his mother being Thermouthis, of the same city, registered in the quarter of the Western Guard-house, a … share belonging to me in 10½ arurae of catoecic land, common and undivided, in the Upper Leucopurgite district near Terton … and similarly in Hermopolis in the quarter of the Western Guard-house a fourth share of a house and yard and all appurtenances, entrances, and exits, in return for a loan of 600 drachmae, on condition of a right of usufruct and power of leasing in place of the interest at i drachma per month per mina, the loan to be for a period of 5 years from the present day at the termination of which repayment of the aforesaid sum will take place. The guardian is to be appointed for this transaction only, which will be carried out by a payment through the Bank of Lessees in Hermopolis. I therefore beg you to permit me to employ this Herminus son of Hermaeus in accordance with the present request ; the 9½ obols ordered to be paid to the ... on account of the petition I have paid to the public bank in Hermopolis and have presented to you the receipt. I am making this petition to you since (my regular guardian) is away to appear before his highness the archidicastes.’ Date, signatures of Demetrius and Herminus, and endorsement of the exegetes.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
