<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 2, 117</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">19505</idno>
            <idno type="TM">19505</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">19505</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;2;117</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-09-10T04:50:29.967-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-09-10T04:50:29.906-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-17T18:02:35.334-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from Rylands catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-17T18:01:45-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="1"/>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> ‘Aurelius Tyrannius also called Ammonius, strategus of the Hermopolite nome, to Hermes assistant … A copy is forwarded to you of the petition of Aurelia Tinoutis also called Theodora daughter of Pinoution in order that you make it known to the person therein stated. The 1st year of our lord Claudius Caesar Augustus, Pachon 26. Signed by me.’
‘To Aurelius Tyrannius also called Ammonius, strategus of the Hermopolite nome, from Aurelia Tinoutis also called Theodora, daughter of Pinoution son of Morus also called …, of Hermopolis, registered in the quarter of the Western Guard-house, with the concurrence of my husband Aurelius Nilammon son of Pinoution son of ..., his mother being Thaesis, of the same city, the subscription being written for us by Aurelius Copreas also called Agathodemon, of the same city, registered in the East-end quarter, since we are illiterate. As you are aware, it is clearly stated in the Imperial laws that those who have inherited nothing from deceased persons cannot be held responsible for their debts or the claims made against them. Whereas then my brother on my father's side Aurelius Copreas, with whom I have no partnership and who lived alone …, died intestate and childless, and whereas I touched nothing of his nor entered upon the inheritance, and whereas Aurelius Eudaemon, cosmetes, son of Eudaemon ex-agonothetes and ex-senator of the same city of Hermopolis, professing to be a creditor of his persecutes and annoys me unjustly, and I am ignorant whether there are other creditors of my said brother, I therefore am compelled to present this petition to you, renouncing and resigning to Eudaemon the inheritance of my said brother in compensation for the sums due to him and for any others which may be claimed on my said brother's account, and I request you to instruct an assistant to present a duplicate of this petition to him for his information, so that I may keep my property in freedom, inviolate, and undisturbed in respect of my brother, of whose property I possess nothing, according to the Imperial ordinances. Farewell. 
The 1st year of the Emperor Caesar Marcus Aurelius Claudius Pius Felix Augustus, Pachon 17.’ Signatures of Aurelia Tinoutis and her husband, written by Copreas, and of Aurelius Eudaemon acknowledging receipt of the document.
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
