<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 2, 164</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">19514</idno>
            <idno type="TM">19514</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">19514</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;2;164</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-09-15T12:37:48.088-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-09-15T12:37:48.049-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:32:47.651-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from Rylands catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:32:08-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <p>
               <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> ‘… arion daughter of Hexakon son of Cornelius, of Hermopolis, registered at the Western Guard-house, my mother being Olympias … with my guardian my husband Metocus son of Achilles, to Hermaeus son of Diogenes of the same city, greeting. I acknowledge that I have sold to you from the present day for ever the 11… arurae of catoecic land not subject to demand belonging to me in the ... at Tertesmonis in the holding of Asclepiodorus, together with their yearly rentals, and will transfer these severally in good condition for sowing, in full, measured by the just measure used in the settlement, free from the cultivation of royal land and every impost whatever, contained in 4¾ common and undivided plots in which are watering-places and a quay of baked brick, also common, at the price mutually agreed upon of … drachmae. From this sum I have here received from you from hand to hand three thousand drachmae, total 3,000 silver dr. The remaining … drachmae you will pay me by the 30th of the present month Hathur of the current 12th year of Aurelius Antoninus the lord, and I will make the conveyance whensoever you please by an official deed through the record-offices in Hermopolis in order that you may receive the authorization of the land-registry office free from all liability. For the public dues on the holding and all additional levies from former times up to the past 11th year of Marcus Aurelius Antoninus Caesar the lord I, the vendor, am responsible, while you are responsible for those from the present 12th year inclusive; and I will henceforth guarantee the said land with every guarantee. The land-specifications and the conditions of sale will be included in the deed of conveyance.’ Date, signatures of the writer (?), of the vendor and her guardian, and possibly of the purchaser.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
