<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 2, 165</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">19515</idno>
            <idno type="TM">19515</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">19515</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;2;165</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-09-15T12:37:18.513-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-09-15T12:37:18.463-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:34:06.814-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from Rylands catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:33:14-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> ‘… The 13th year of the Emperor Caesar Publius Licinius Gallienus Germanicus Maximus Pius Felix
Augustus, Pharmouthi a. A payment through the . . . bank in Hermopolis. Isidora also called Souerous daughter of Didymus also called …, registered in the Eastern … quarter, and Theodora daughter of Hierax, of the same quarter, Isidora also called Souerous acting with … son of Herminus and Theodora acting with Aurelius Ammon …, (notify) … Juliana, matrona stolata, daughter of Cusonius I . . ., late (?) praefect of Egypt, acting without a guardian by the right of children according to Roman usage and having as her appointed representative Dio ... of the legio Traiana Fortis Germanica …, appointed in accordance with the provisions of ... of which a copy is appended, that she (the latter) has sold to them jointly in equal half shares the four arurae of catoecic land belonging to her in the holding of Deiphilus, which she will transfer severally in good condition for sowing and in full, measured by the just measure of the settlement, free from the cultivation of royal land and from every impost whatever, at the price of 1,600 drachmae of old Ptolemaic silver coin. This sum she has received here from the purchasers in equal half shares in accordance with this deed, … and they and their assigns have the ownership of the land, administering it as they please for ever ... The 13th year of Gallienus, Pharmouthi 2.’

               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="27"/>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
