<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 2, 177</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">19521</idno>
            <idno type="TM">19521</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">19521</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;2;177</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-11-12T13:21:52.898-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-11-12T13:21:52.868-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:52:02.812-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from Rylands catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:51:29-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <p>
               <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> ‘Loan of 1,920 dr. Aurelius Melas son of . . . and Teeus, aged about 60 years, with a scar on the middle finger of the left hand, and Silvanus son of Chaos and Tanechotis, aged about . . years, with a scar on the … finger of the left hand, both of the village of Magdola Mire in the district of the Lower Suburb, to Aurelius Soïs son of Chaus and …, of Hermopolis, greeting. We acknowledge that we have received from you from hand to hand out of the house a loan at interest ... of one thousand nine hundred and twenty silver drachmae, total 1,920 silver dr., which we will repay on our joint responsibility on ... of the present 4th year of the Marci Julii Philippi Caesars and lords Augusti with no delay. For the security and repayment of these sums we hereupon mortgage to you in accordance with this deed the half share of a new house and yard belonging to us jointly in equal shares and of all its furniture and appurtenances and entrances and exits, formerly the property of Pekusis, of the said village. The adjacent areas of the whole house are, on the south the house of Teres son of Menches, on the north …, on the east a street by which is the entrance and exit, on the west the homestead of Phoebammon son of Tryphon. The mortgaged half share of the house we will preserve unalienated and uninvolved until either we make repayment or distraint is made upon us, as aforesaid, the right of execution lying with you upon us or upon whichever of us you choose, since we are jointly responsible for repayment, and upon all our property and upon the mortgage itself, as if in accordance with a legal decision ; and we will guarantee it with every guarantee both from public and private claims and all claims whatsoever, the debts which one of us, Aurelius Melas, owes to you remaining valid ; and in answer to your question whether this has been rightly and fairly done we have given our consent.’ Date and signature of Aurelius Copreas on behalf of the debtors.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
