<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 2, 181</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">19523</idno>
            <idno type="TM">19523</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">19523</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;2;181</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-11-13T16:11:24.535-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-11-13T16:11:24.528-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T15:01:25.429-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from Rylands catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T15:00:50-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> ‘Sarapion and Hermes also called Marcullus, both sons of Hermes, and their brother on the mother’s
side, Achilles son of Polydeuces, minor, all three sons and heirs of Victorina, the said minor Achilles acting through his father Polydeuces, all four being citizens of Hermopolis, to Herm … and … and …, our three uncles on our mother's side, sons of Diogenes, ex-cosmetes of the said city of Hermopolis, greeting. Whereas your father Diogenes son of Hermaeus while yet alive desired, according to his written deed, that a certain annual allowance should be furnished in perpetuity from the 8th year of the lords and Emperors Severus and Antoninus to our mother his daughter Victorina and her descendants by you his sons, and after Diogenes’ death you furnished the allowance specified by the deed until the 12th year; and whereas on the death of our mother Victorina we have now agreed with you to receive a fixed amount of 20 artabae in discharge of all allowances for the future; we acknowledge that we have here received from you the amount agreed upon in discharge of all the said allowances for ever, and that we make and shall make no claim against you or your assigns on any point whatever concerning the said allowances henceforth for ever in any manner or under any pretext, because we have come to the present agreement, and any person making a claim upon you in our name with regard to the allowance we will repel …’

               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="17"/>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
