<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 2, 176</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">19520</idno>
            <idno type="TM">19520</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">19520</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;2;176</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-11-12T13:21:07.023-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-11-12T13:21:06.99-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:50:39.619-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from Rylands catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:50:01-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <p>
               <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> ‘The … year of the Emperors and Caesars Lucius Septimius Severus Pius Pertinax Arabicus Adiabenicus Parthicus Maximus and Marcus Aurelius Antoninus Pius Augusti and Publius Septimius Geta Caesar Augustus, Hadrianus . ., a payment through the bank under supervisors in Hermopolis. Souerous daughter of Thaibis, of Hermopolis, registered in the quarter of the Western Guard-house, with her guardian Hermes … (notifies) to … daughter of …, of Hermopolis, from the quarter of the Eastern Guard-house, with her guardian her son … son of … os son of Titianus that she (the latter has received) from her the sum which she was induced to accept in discharge of the 1,500 silver drachmae which were owing from her to the other in accordance with a receipt drawn up [through the said bank (?) in the … year …], to be repaid at the date specified in the receipt, and of the interest, at the 1 drachma rate, accrued after the expiration of the time-limit, and of the expenses and taxes paid by her, making a total of … drachmae, and of the 8 arurae which she mortgaged out of the 245/6 arurae belonging to her in the area of Tertesmonis in the holding of …, which 8 arurae she (the other) had assigned to herself for the purposes of execution, namely the present … payment— not including those drachmae the claim to which she has waived and for which she will not take any proceedings whatsoever— of two thousand drachmae of silver, total 2,000 dr. of silver, in order to annul the said receipt and the designation for execution of the 8 arurae which have been hereby restored and the legal acts of (distraint ?)…’
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
