<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Lond. 5, 1712</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">19729</idno>
            <idno type="TM">19729</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">19729</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.lond;5;1712</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-09-18T11:07:46-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Finalized - Ready.</change>
         <change when="2022-09-17T07:05:15-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Add line breaks where helpful</change>
         <change when="2022-09-16T09:17:40-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/marianowak">Submit - A new translation by M. Konstantinou Rizos checked by Warsaw project</change>
         <change when="2022-09-16T09:16:51-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/marianowak">Commit - A new translation by M. Konstantinou Rizos checked by Warsaw project</change>
         <change when="2022-09-16T09:15:48-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> In the fourth year of the reign and consulship of our divinissimus lord Flavius Iustinus the eternal Augustus Emperor, twenty first Epeiph of the third indiction, 
☧ in the most glorious Antinoopolis.
<milestone n="4" rend="break" unit="line"/> We, on the one part Aurelius Mathias, son of Phoibammon, from the mother Helene, skipper, on the other part Aurelia Kyria [pap. Kyra], daughter of Ioannes, 
of the mother Tanoe, both hailing from Antinoopolis, conclude and make between us the written separation, that is divorce, in two identical copies.
<milestone n="8" rend="break" unit="line"/> We acknowledge to each other the terms stated below, since long ago we were united with each other in lawful marriage and shared life, 
in good hope and in view of conceiving good legitimate children, but now that dispute has come to us by the mischievous demon, we have separated from each other. 
For that reason we have resorted to this written separation. 
<milestone n="11" unit="line"/> We acknowledge, and each person acknowledges to get back their own property from the whole, 
without having any claims neither now nor in the future against each other neither concerning household utensils or goods, not concerning bridal gifts, 
nor with regard to cohabitation, nor about any other matter in general, small or big, written or unwritten, which is understood or not, 
<milestone n="15" rend="break" unit="line"/> which has come to mind or not, mentioned herein or unmentioned, to not prosecute each other now or at any time in the future in any court or out of court, 
so that we be set free in general, be finished and break up from each other, and that each of us may be united in a different marriage, 
if he/she wishes, without hindrance, impediment or dispute, 
<milestone n="19" unit="line"/> and on all these each party made the most terrifying oath to abide by all the terms written herein and to not violate in any way, 
<milestone n="21" rend="break" unit="line"/> and if one of us may violate what is herein written, the party which does not abide to it acknowledges (to give) to the party which abides to it as a fine 
two gold nomismata to be demanded as a matter of fact and with full legal power, and after it has been paid, this separation which we conclude between us, 
<milestone n="24" unit="line"/> may be valid and secure, and having been asked the formal question on everything, we consented. 
We also decided between us that if the baby of the aforementioned Kyria may be saved and born that the aforementioned Mathias, the skipper, 
must give for her childbirth six carats of gold without judgment or lawsuit and that the little child will have its father. <note>Translation: Law in Social Networks Project (Warsaw)</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
