<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Lond. 4, 1339</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">19797</idno>
            <idno type="TM">19797</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">19797</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.lond;4;1339</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2024-04-20T10:11:20-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/paulpeters">Finalized - Bereit.</change>
         <change when="2024-04-20T09:05:40-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/paulpeters">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Literaturverweis ergänzen. Zeilenzählung anpassen.</change>
         <change when="2016-04-29T11:23:13-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/EugenioGarosi">Submit - Entered translation according to BELL, H. I., Translations of the Greek Aphrodito Papyri in the British Museum.Part I , Islam, 2 (1911) p.273</change>
         <change when="2016-04-29T11:04:42-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> … On receiving the present letter, therefore, come down to us
                      with all speed, bringing with you the men from your district whom
                      we named to you in our former letters, and in addition a register of
                      places giving the male population in each, with the poll-tax to which
                      they are liable and the amount of each man's holding in land, both
                      vine-land and arable land, and the services he has rendered with
                      instructions and without, and a register of the names and patronymics
                      of the fugitives in each place; in short make clear to us in your register
                      all that you know, not giving any cause of complaint against yourself
                      whatever in this matter. <milestone n="11" unit="line"/> And we have instructed the present messenger
                      not to remain with you more than two (or?) three days, until you
                      come down to us, telling those who come down with you from each
                      place in your district to bring with them the accounts of their place,
                      in order that if we seek information from them on any subject they
                      may be found prepared to tell us all they know and can communicate.
                      <milestone n="17" unit="line"/> You will be aware that we shall not accept from you any ground of
                      excuse whatsoever; therefore do not require another letter from us
                      about this after the present one, lest retribution overtake you which
                      shall destroy your life and property. <milestone n="21" unit="line"/> Written the 12th Phaophi, 8th
                      indiction.
                      <note>Translation: H.I. Bell, Translations of the Greek Aphrodito Papyri (1911) 273</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
