<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Lond. 4, 1337</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">19795</idno>
            <idno type="TM">19795</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">19795</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.lond;4;1337</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-04-29T10:17:17-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> ….and neglect to send out to us the sailors who were requisitioned from your administrative district for the carabi and dromonaria and other ships of the raiding fleet of Egypt in the 8th indiction, we have instructed Hayyān b. 
(5) Shuraih to hire those with whom you are in arrear in accordance with the rate (of wages) stated in our demand notes. On receiving the present letter, therefore, send with all speed, in accordance with the account enclosed with the present letter, 
(10) the money for their wages, not keeping back one single solidus of it. For indeed we know that it is no concern to you nor yet to the people of your district to carry out or perform any sort of duty, unless you are importuned for the arrears in your payments,
(15) except in accordance with the instructions contained in our demand notes. But we will not allow this to be so; for we shall not treat the capable and efficient man who zealously performs his duty in the same way as him who through corruption falls short 
(20) in the tasks entrusted to him by us. Therefore if you have any sense perform the command given by our letter, not sending any of these moneys negligently but discharging your duty zealously. Written the 13th Thoth, 8th indiction.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
