<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">Oath of an Estate Farmer</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <idno type="filename">19977</idno>
            <idno type="TM">19977</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">19977</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">pylon;8;8</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-12T12:17:33-06:00" who="HGV">Xwalk from Pylon</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">

<p>
“ … about 50 years old, mark on his left shin.
Paneus son of … from Herakleia to the agents of Probus, (slave) of Tyrannos, (slave) of Gaius Caesar Augustus Germanicus. I swear by Gaius Caesar Augustus Germanicus that I will farm from the present fourth year of Gaius Caesar Augustus Germanicus three arouras of the fields around the said village, which belong to the estate of Gaius Caesar Augustus Germanicus, previously belonging to Dionysodoros, on behalf of which I will perform all requisite agricultural tasks at my own expense and I will receive seed for the fields and I will measure out the customary rents on the fields with surcharges … the leasehold. If [I] keep the oath, may it be to my benefit, but if I break the oath, the opposite. The notary of Herakleia wrote [for him because] he [does not know] letters. Year 4 of Gaius Caesar Augustus Germanicus, <emph rend="italics">n</emph>th of the month Gaius Augustus.”
</p>
</div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
