<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 7, 1032</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20328</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20328</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20328</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;7;1032</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-24" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 7</note>
              To his highness the epistrategus Vedius Faustus from Ammonius and Martheis, both children of Diogenes, of the city of Oxyrhynchus. The following is a copy of the petition which we presented to Volusius Maecianus, ex-praefect, and of the endorsement upon it which we received: “To Lucius Volusius Maecianus, praefect of Egypt, from Ammonius and Martheis also called Heracleia, both children of Diogenes son of Diogenes, of the metropolis of the Oxyrhynchite nome. As long ago as the 11th year of the deified Aelius Antoninus we converted out of our own ancient plots which formerly belonged to our deceased paternal grandfather Diogenes, whose mother was Sepsarion, near Senepsau in the said Oxyrhynchite nome, as was conceded to us, 7/16 of an aroura of vine-land, on which the sum owing as apportioned was paid, and concerning this the local comogrammateus reported that the registration had been carried out accordingly out of our own plots ... Whereas then we have now discovered that in the time of this comogrammateus and another a report was made whereby it is declared that the owners concerned when warned in writing to do so had not sent in a statement, and that the land was planted (because Sempronius Liberalis the ex-praefect in the circuit of the nome held in his time in the zoth year of the deified Aelius Antoninus had made an endorsement ‘If they fail to present a statement within two months they shall be liable to the prescribed penalties’), and since from the remarks which we have now seen appended to the report in the hands of the basilicogrammateus of the nome we have learnt that a certain Dionysius, who was assistant of the strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome in the 23rd year, has made an endorsement that he had given information to Diogenes the grandson of our aforesaid grandfather, and this Diogenes to whom he says he gave information and who was our brother died in Thoth of the ... year of the deified Hadrian, so that from this fact the malice of the assistant Dionysius with intent to defraud us is proved, for he could not in accordance with the order produce the acknowledgement of the recipient that he had in truth given the information, but, as stated above, our brother Diogenes died long before the endorsement which has been made: therefore, lord praefect, we have perforce taken refuge with you, the saviour and benefactor of all, begging you, if your fortune sees fit, to write to the strategus and basilicogrammateus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, in order that, on our presenting the statement originally required, we may suffer no damage in consequence of the endorsement wrongly made by the assistant, and so may obtain relief. Farewell.” And of his endorsement this is a copy: “Let those who have presented these documents, ten in number, apply to his highness the dioecetes Vonasius Facundus, to whom copies have been sent. Make this public. The 1st year of the Emperor Caesar Marcus Aurelius Antoninus Augustus and the Emperor Caesar Lucius Aurelius Verus Augustus, Epeiph ... Published Epeiph 14. Since therefore, sir, his highness the dioecetes, being appealed to by us and learning that Dionysius was not then present, referred this matter also to you in the following terms: “Vonasius Facundus gives sentence: You accuse the assistant and the case must be investigated in the presence of Dionysius; apply therefore to his highness the epistrategus, who, when Dionysius appears, will give judgement in the case,” we request you, if it seems good to your fortune, to decide about the case, so that we may obtain relief. Farewell.
              (Signed) Ammonius and Marthion, both children of Diogenes, have presented this petition through one of us, Ammonius.
              (Endorsed) The 2nd year, Pharmouthi 20. To the administration: he shall be heard.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
