<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 7, 1031</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20327</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20327</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20327</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;7;1031</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-24" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 7</note>
              To Aurelius Demetrius also called Alexander, ex-chief priest, and Aurelius Dioscorus, agoranomus, both senators of the city. of Oxyrhynchus, elected by the most high senate to superintend the distribution of seed of the present 8th year in the upper toparchy, from Aurelius Biaeus son of Biaeus and Taïolle, from the village of Episemus. I request that there be assigned to me as one of the loans of seed from the wheat crop of the past 7th year for the sowing of the present 8th year, for the public land which I cultivate at a rent of not less than 2 artabae near the village of Sko in the name of Lucius Aurelius Apollonius and his son Lucius Aurelius Matreas also called Heraiscus, in the holding of Odeas 26 1/2 arourae and in the holding of Pedieus 3 /12 arourae, total 30 arourae, a loan of 30 artabae, which I will clear of barley and darnel and plant upon the land honestly and in good faith under the cognizance of those appointed for that duty, and I will repay out of the new crop an equivalent amount with the accompaniments at the same time as the regular dues upon the land for the present 8th year by the public half-artaba measure and according to the measurement ordered; and I swear by the fortune of Marcus Aurelius Severus Alexander Caesar the lord that I have made no false statement. <note>Date and signature of Aurelius Biaeus.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
