<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 7, 1028</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20324</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20324</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20324</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;7;1028</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-24" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 7</note>
              To Claudius Macedonius, strategus, and Gaius, basilicogrammateus, and Dionysius and Philiscus, ex-gymnasiarchs, and Apollonius and Theon, city-scribes, from Taorseus daughter of Thompsemis son of Thoönis, of the city of Oxyrhynchus, with her guardian Thompsemis son of Thoönis. In accordance with the orders concerning the selection of boys approaching the age of 14 when their parents on both sides are residents of the metropolis rated at 12 drachmae, I declare that my son Chaeremon son of Onnophris son of Sois, pastophorus of Sarapis the most great god, registered in the quarter of the Hippodrome, has reached the age in the present 5th year and that he is a person rated at 12 drachmae, and that his father my late husband Onnophris son of Soïs, pastophorus of the said god, registered in the same quarter among those rated at 12 drachmae, died in the 1st year of Domitian the lord, and that my father Thompsemis son of Thoönis, registered at the Thoëreum Thenepmoi among those rated at 12 drachmae, died in the 2nd year of the deified Titus; and I swear by the Emperor Caesar Domitianus Augustus Germanicus that I have made no false statement. <note>Date, and signature of Taorseus.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
