<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 7, 1033</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20329</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20329</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20329</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;7;1033</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-24" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 7</note>
              In the 2nd consulship of our sovereign Arcadius, eternal Augustus, and of Flavius Rufinus the most illustrious, Phaophi 21. To Septimius Paulus and Claudius Tatianus, riparii of the Oxyrhynchite nome, from Aurelius Gaius and Aurelius Theon, both night-strategi of the said city. Being entrusted with the care of the peace we are irreproachable in our obedience to public orders, and also intent upon the guardianship of the city. We are often called upon for the production of various persons in accordance with the command of our lords the superior officials, but having no assistance either of public guards or inspectors we often run the risk almost of our lives because these assistants have been taken from us and we go about the city on the watch all alone. Therefore to safeguard ourselves we present this petition requesting either that we should be given the proper assistance of the public guards and the inspectors as aforesaid or that we should have no concern for the guardianship of the city or the production of persons who are wanted, in order that we may not incur risk.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
