<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 7, 1024</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20323</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20323</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20323</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;7;1024</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-24" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 7</note>
              Asclepiades, strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, to Heraclas also called Heraclides, sitologus of the district of Pakerke in the eastern toparchy, greeting. Measure out, with the authorization also of Hierax the basilicogrammateus, from the best sample, of the produce of the past 13th year, for the sowing of the present 14th year of Hadrianus Caesar the lord, as a loan of seed for Apollonius son of Heliodorus son of Apollonius, his mother being Thaïs daughter of Chaeremon, of the city of Oxyrhynchus, aged about 78, with a scar on the right eyebrow, whom you are to recognize at your own risk, as requested by him for the 1 1/4 arourae of land which he cultivates near the village of Ophis in the holding of Apollonius of the Althaean deme with those of Pyrrhias and Lysimachus, one and one quarter artabae of wheat, pure, unadulterated, unmixed with earth and sifted, according to public measure and regulation measurement, total 1 1/4 art. wheat, without any deduction for debts or any other purpose; and he shall sow it on the land in good faith under the observance of the usual officers, and shall repay an equivalent amount out of the new crop together with the government dues upon the land; and you shall take from him a proper receipt in duplicate and shall give one copy to me. The 14th year of the Emperor Caesar Trajanus Hadrianus Augustus, Hathur 17.
              From Hierax, basilicogrammateus and deputy-strategus: measure out the one and a quarter artabae of wheat, total 1 1/4 wheat, as above.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
