<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 7, 1038</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20333</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20333</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20333</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;7;1038</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-24" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 7</note>
              The 3rd year of the reign and consulship of our most godly and pious sovereign Flavius Justinus, eternal Augustus and Imperator, Mesore 2, 1st indiction. To Flavia Euphemia, the honourable daughter of Musaeus of honoured memory, landholder at this illustrious city of Oxyrhynchus, through you, Flavius Anastasius, her noble agent, and you, Jeremias, her admirable collector, Aurelius Stephanus, baker, son of Heraclammon and Nonna, of the said city, greeting. I undertake of my own free will to lease from the first day of the month Thoth of the coming D.V. second indiction, from your honour’s property out of a house facing south situated in this city in the quarter of St. Euphemia, a complete room on the ground floor also facing south with all appurtenances and the rights attaching to all the house, and I will pay annually as rent for this ten carats of current coinage, total rocarats current, which rent I will pay every year in half-yearly instalments of half the sum, and whenever you wish I will surrender my possession of the room just as I received it. This lease, of which one copy has been made, is valid, and in answer to the question I have given my consent. <note>Signature of Stephanus written for him by the scribe John, signature of John, and title on the verso.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
