<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 7, 1036</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20331</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20331</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20331</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;7;1036</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-24" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 7</note>
              Titus Manlius Serenus and Titus Manlius Alexander, both sons of Titus Manlius Heraclas, through one of them, namely Serenus, have let to Aurelius Heracleus son of Sarapas son of Mo..., his mother being Stephanous, of the illustrious and most illustrious city of Oxyrhynchus, for a term of two years from Thoth of the present 4th year, from his property in the said city in the quarter of Pammenes’ Garden a house and yard and court and all the appurtenances with the exception of one room beneath ... and the plots on the east of the house, at an annual rent of 400 drachmae. When the lease is guaranteed the lessee shall pay the annual rent in half-yearly instalments of half the sum, and shall use the aforesaid house without hindrance for the term, after which he shall restore it free of filth and dirt of all kinds together with such doors and keys as he has received, right of execution lying against the lessee, as is just. The lease is valid, and we have put the question to each other and consented to each other. The 4th year of the Emperor Caesar Lucius Domitius Aurelianus Gothicus Maximus Pius Felix Invictus Augustus, Phaophi 13. (Signed) I, Aurelius Heracleus, have leased the house and will pay the rent as aforesaid, and in answer to the question have given my consent. I, Aurelius Serenus, wrote for him, as he was ignorant of letters.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
