<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 7, 1040</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20335</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20335</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20335</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;7;1040dupl</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-24" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 7</note>
              Aurelius Pekusis, son of Pausiris and Soëris, and his son Aurelius Petenouphis whose mother is Sintheus, both of the city of Oxyrhynchus, to Aurelius Theon son of Didymus, of the said city, greeting. We acknowledge both equally that we have received and had measured out to us from you of the crop of the past 4th year four artabae of wheat at the interest of one-half, making a total, with the interest, of six artabae of wheat, which we will repay to you on our mutual security in the month of Pauni at the threshing-floor of the village of Teruthis, in wheat that is new, pure, unadulterated, without earth or barley, and sifted, as measured into the public granary, by your own receiving measure by which the measurement has been made to us, the measuring to be done by your agents. If I do not repay according to our written agreement the aforesaid six artabae of wheat including the addition, I will forfeit them to you with an increase of one-half and interest for the overtime also of one-half, (and you shall have the right of execution) upon us as mutual securities for the payment or upon whichever of us you choose and upon all our property of every kind, as in accordance with a legal decision. This bond, which is written in duplicate, is valid as if publicly registered, and in answer to your question whether this is rightly and fairly done we have given our consent. <note>Date, signature of Pekusis and Petenouphis written for them by Aurelius Petronius, and title on the back.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
