<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 7, 1061</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20350</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20350</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20350</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;7;1061</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-24" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 7</note>
              Diogenes to his brother Dionysius, many greetings and wishes for good health. Since I have written to you at other times and you have not brought about an agreement between us, and also to your brother Apollonius, I have now been obliged to urge Ptolemaeus the younger, son of Ptolemaeus, to meet Dius and Diogenes son of Demetrius until the unwatered land in the seven arourae and the government dues on it be measured through Dionysius and the remainder paid over to Ptolemaeus. I therefore beg that you will interview Ptolemaeus, both you and your brother Apollonius, until you effect this for me, for you are superior to Ptolemaeus in experience, and if it is necessary to meet the other Ptolemaeus, the elder brother of Ptolemaeus, about this, that he may meet him and do his best until it is effected. If then it please you to reply to me about this and about the other subjects which I asked you about by letter I shall be obliged to you; and do you write to me about anything that you wish and I will most gladly do it. I have written also to Dius, the son of the agent, about this; whom you will meet. Salute all your household; Athenarous and the rest of the children salute you. Take care of your health. Good-bye. The 8th year of Augustus, Epeiph.. (Addressed) To Dionysius also called Amois, son of Ptolemaeus and brother of Apollonius the comogrammateus of Tholthis, who is staying near Theon son of Ischyrion.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
