<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 6, 905</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20369</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20369</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20369</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;6;905</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-20" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 6</note>
              ... Antoninus and Faustina, Augusti. Menodorus son of Horus and Tacallippus of the village of Psobthis has given for partnership of marriage Thatres, his daughter by Thatres, to Apollonius son of Heracles and Tausorapis. The bride brings to her husband in respect of dowry one mina’s weight on the Oxyrhynchite standard of common gold, in kind, according to valuation, and in parapherna in clothing two outer veils, one ..., the other white. Let the husband and wife therefore live together observing the duties of marriage, and the husband shall supply the wife with necessaries in proportion to his means. If a separation takes place after the birth of children or before it, the husband shall restore all the super-dowry at the time of separation, and the dowry in sixty days from the day on which the separation takes place; and Menodorus, the giver of the bride, shall have the right of execution upon the husband and upon all his property. The father of the husband, Heracles son of Morus and Apollonia, of the said village, being present assents to the marriage, and is surety for the payment of the aforesaid dowry. This contract is valid, being written in duplicate in order that each party may have a copy; and in answer to the formal question they have declared to each other their consent. The 10th year, Phamenoth 18.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
