<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 6, 907</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20370</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20370</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20370</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;6;907</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-20" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 6</note>
              Aurelius Hermogenes also called Eudaemon, exegetes, councillor and prytanis of the illustrious and most illustrious city of Oxyrhynchus, dictated the following will in the Greek language, in accordance with the permission, Aurelius Herminus, Aurelius Horion, Aurelius Heraclides, Aurelia Ptolemais and Aurelia Didyme, my five dearest children by my ... wife Aurelia Isidora also called Prisca, a matron wearing the stola, shall be my heirs according to the disposition below written, and on the conditions on which each ..., all other persons being disinherited; they shall proceed to my inheritance in accordance with the bequests made to each of them whenever they ... themselves to be my heirs; they shall be responsible for giving, doing, and providing all this which is written in this my testament, and I confide this to their honour. To Aurelius Herminus, Aurelius Horion, and Aurelius Heraclides my three sons as aforesaid I bequeath jointly in equal shares on behalf of my inheritance the vineyard belonging to me near the village of (?) Istrus by the upper temple of Isis, and all the corn-land and ... and utensils and all appurtenances, and all the corn-land belonging to me at Sepho, and in the metropolis my ... house and all the furniture in it; and to Herminus alone as his special property all the corn-land belonging to me at Sen... jointly with ..., and my slave called Philodioscorus. To Aurelia Ptolemais and Aurelia Didyme my aforesaid daughters ... I give and bequeath likewise jointly, and in equal shares on behalf of my inheritance, the vineyard belonging to me at... jointly with the said... with all the corn-land and the plant, utensils, and all appurtenances. To Didyme alone as her special property I bequeath ... and I also confirm to Ptolemais by this my will the dowry ... which I previously gave her, and I leave to her my slave named Eunoea ; my remaining four slaves, Dioscurides and Sabinus and Herm... and ..., I bequeath to the three sons and one of the daughters, to wit Didyme. To Aurelia Isidora also called Prisca, my wedded wife ... who has conducted herself becomingly in our married life, I leave as her own property all the corn-land belonging to me at... bis jointly with the said ..., which was previously mortgaged by me to her in security for the dowry brought to me with her... I appoint as guardian of my three children aforesaid who are under age, Horion, Heraclides, and Didyme, until the boys attain majority and the girl is married, Aurelius Demetrius son of Dionysotheon, with the concurrence, in all that pertains to the guardianship, of my aforesaid wife Isidora also called Prisca; and accordingly I do not wish any magistrate or deputy or any other person to intrude himself ..., for I further enjoin it upon the piety of my nephew Didymus to assist Demetrius in any way that may be required of him. To my friend Aurelius Dionysammon I bequeath and I wish that there be given him during his lifetime from ... and the corn-land belonging to me at Moa thirty jars of wine at the vintage and ... artabae of wheat by the tenth measure in the month of Pauni. (I direct that there be provided as dowry) for Didyme ... by her brothers four talents of silver... This will was made by me in the illustrious and most illustrious city of Oxyrhynchus in the first year of our lord Marcus Claudius Tacitus, Pauni 7. The first year of the Emperor Caesar Marcus Claudius Tacitus Pius Felix Augustus, Pauni 7. I, Aurelius Hermogenes also called Eudaemon, have made this will with all the above provisions. Opened in the same first year, Epeiph.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
