<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 6, 908</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20371</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20371</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20371</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;6;908</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-20" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 6</note>
              Sarapion also called Horion, son of ... on, through his paternal grandfather Apion, ex-gymnasiarch of Oxyrhynchus, at present eutheniarch of the said city, to Tiberius Claudius Didymus and however he is styled, a victor in the games and exempt from taxation, member of the Dionyseum and the sacred club, and to Theon also called Antimachus and Dionysius also called ... and Achilles also called Isidorus, ex-exegetes, and Horion also called Berenicianus, ex-exegetes, all five gymnasiarchs and eutheniarchs of the said city of Oxyrhynchus, greeting. I have made a compact with you being now eutheniarchs from the (30th?) of the present month Pauni till the 29th of the following month Epeiph in the current 7th year, that one bakery be fitted out by each of you ... the animals being fed by you with grass and barley, on the understanding that they grind daily in each factory as much as 20 artabae of wheat .. . supplying the animals in each factory ... to provide one factory, the fodder being provided by me, and we shall grind at (this) factory an equal amount daily, namely 20 artabae; and it shall be unlawful for any of us to transgress the aforesaid conditions. This contract, done in six copies in order that each of us may have one, is valid. <note>Date and signature of Sarapion.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
