<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 4, 721</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20420</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20420</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20420</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;4;721</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 4</note>
              To Gaius Seppius Rufus from Polemon son of Tryphon and Archelaus son of ... We wish to purchase in the Oxyrhynchite nome of the Crown land returned as unproductive up to the... year of Caesar, from the holdings which were confiscated in the ... year of Caesar and became unfruitful and the holdings confiscated up to and including the ... year of Caesar, exclusive of temple land, for cultivation in the coming 44th year of Caesar—namely Polemon at Thosbis and Tepouis in the upper toparchy fifteen arourae, total 15 arourae, and Archelaus at... in the toparchy of Thmoisepho, four arourae, total 4 arourae, total 19 arourae, with the understanding that on these being assigned to us we shall pay into the local State-bank the price ordered for each aroura, 12 drachmae of silver, and shall have for their reclamation and cultivation immunity from taxation for three years from the coming 44th year of Caesar...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
