<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
    <teiHeader type="text">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>P.Oxy. 4, 724</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
                <idno type="filename">20424</idno>
                <idno type="TM">20424</idno>
                <idno type="HGV">20424</idno>
                <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;4;724</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
                        a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="fr">French</language>
                <language ident="en">English</language>
                <language ident="de">German</language>
                <language ident="it">Italian</language>
                <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
                <language ident="la">Latin</language>
                <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2024-04-30" who="http://papyri.info/users/paulpeters">Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Literaturverweis standardisieren. Bestehende Übersetzung aus XML kopieren und einfügen (dort Literaturverweis standardisieren).</change>
            <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
            <change when="2019-07-18T11:38:12" who="http://papyri.info/users/WesselvanDuijn">Add translation from print edition.</change>
            <change when="2019-07-18T10:11:08-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> Panechotes also called Panares, ex-cosmetes of Oxyrhynchus,
                     through his friend Gemellus, to Apollonius, writer of shorthand, greeting. I have placed with you
                     my slave Chaerammon to be taught the signs which your son Dionysius knows,
                     for a period of two years dating from the present month Phamenoth of the
                     18th year of Antoninus Caesar the lord at the salary agreed upon
                     between us, 120 silver drachmae, not including feast-days;
                     of which sum you have received the first instalment amounting to 40 drachmae,
                     and you will receive the second instalment consisting of 40 drachmae when the boy has learnt the whole system,
                     and the third you will receive at the end of the period
                     when the boy writes fluently in every respect and reads faultlessly,
                     viz. the remaining 40 drachmae. <milestone n="11" unit="line"/> If you make him perfect within the period,
                     I will not wait for the aforesaid limit; but it is not lawful
                     for me to take the boy away before the end of the period, and he shall remain with you after the expiration of it
                     for as many days or months as he may have done no work. The 18th year of the Emperor Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrianus
                     Antoninus Augustus Pius, Phamenoth 5.
                     <note>Translation: B.P. Grenfell – A.S. Hunt, P.Oxy. 4 724</note></p>
         </div>
            <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> Panechotes, also known as Panares, the former kosmetés from the city of Oxyrhynchus,
                     brings his greetings to the shorthand-writer, Apollonius, through the person of his friend Gemellus. I have placed
                     my slave Chaeramon with you to learn the symbols of which your son
                     Dionysius has knowledge. This apprenticeship is to be for a period of two years, excluding feast-days, commencing from the present month of Phamenoth
                     in the eighteenth year of the reign of our lord Antoninus Caesar and at the fee of
                     120 silver drachmas which we agreed to.
                     Of this sum you have received the first instalment of 40 drachmas; the
                     second payment of 40 drachmas you will receive once the boy has absorbed the contents of the entire manual;
                     the third payment of the remaining 40 drachmas you will receive at the completion of the period when
                     the boy is writing and reading flawlessly from every kind of prose. <milestone n="11" unit="line"/> If you complete his training within this period,
                     I will not wait until the end of the apprenticeship stipulated. However, I will have no right
                     to remove the boy from you before the end of the period, and he will remain with you after it for
                     however many days or months as he may have done no work.
                     <note>Translation: M. Joyal, Greek and Roman Education (2009) 189-190</note>
            </p>
         </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
