<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 4, 722</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20421</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20421</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20421</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;4;722</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 4</note>
              The 10th year of the Emperor Caesar Domitianus Augustus Germanicus, on the 6th intercalary day of Hyperberetaeus, dies Augustus, which is the 6th intercalary day of the month Caesarius, dies Augustus, at Oxyrhynchus in the Thebaid, before three agoranomi called Psammis, Achilleus, aged about 20 years, of middle height, fair, having a long face and a scar on the middle of his forehead, and Sarapas, aged about ... years, of middle height, fair, having a long face and a scar on his left ..., both sons of ... son of Ammonius, their mother being Sarapous daughter of ..., all of Oxyrhynchus, have set free under sanction of Zeus, Earth, and Sun (the deed being drawn up in the street) the third part which they jointly own of the slave who has been freed as regards the other two-thirds, Apollonous, aged about 26, of middle height, fair, having a long face and a scar on the right foot, ... for ... drachmae 4 obols of coined silver and the ransom paid to Achilleus and Sarapas by Heraclas son of Tryphon son of ..., his mother being Taonnophris daughter of ... of the said city, aged about 31, of middle height, fair, having a long face and a scar above his right knee, namely 200 drachmae of Imperial silver coin and ... talents 1000 drachmae of copper; Achilleus or any one else on his behalf being forbidden to make any demand of the aforesaid ransom from Apollonous or her assigns, or to ... The certifier of the manumission is ... son of Peteésis, his mother being ..., of the said city, aged about 40, of middle height, fair, having a long face and a sear upon his ... shin, in the same street.
              I, Achilleus, have with my brother Sarapas effected the emancipation of the third part of the slave Apollonous, and I have received the ransom, two hundred drachmae of silver...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
