<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 4, 736</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20436</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20436</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20436</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;4;736</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 4</note>
              The 21st: ... through Zm... for the cloak of Coraxus, 10 drachmae; turnips for pickling 1 dr. 2 obols; for the kettle, payment for enamelling 2 ob.; salt 1 ob.; cost of grinding 1 artaba of wheat on the 18th 3 ob.; omelette for the bread 2 ob.; cost of mending the cloak of Coraxus 1 1/2 ob.; for treating (?) the wife of Gemellus 4 ob.; perfume for the dispatch of the mummy of the daughter of Phna 4 ob. The 22nd: a chous of oil 4 dr. 4 ob.; wax and stilus for the children 1 ob.; pure bread for Prima 4 ob.; for treating Tyche 3 ob. 9th Mecheir ... the 10th: ... for the weaver’s breakfast 1 ob.; ... for the Sarapeum 2 ob.; pure bread for the children 1/2 ob.; beer for the weaver 1 ob.; leeks for the weaver’s breakfast 1 ob.; a pigeon 1 ob.; to Antas 2 dr. 2 ob.; up at the city for the bread, cost of grinding 2 artabae of wheat, through Isas, 1 dr. 2 ob. The 11th: at the camp, through Theodorus, for the bread, cost of grinding 1 artaba of wheat 4 ob.; for the weaver’s breakfast 1 ob.; asparagus for the dinner of Antas when (he went) to the funeral feast of Athe... the fuller 1/2 ob.; and to the slaves (?), for a cabbage for dinner 1/2 ob.; to the child 1/2 ob.; ...The 16th: a relish 1/2 ob.; omelettes for the bread 2 1/2 ob. The 17th: milk for the children 1/2 ob.; pure bread 1/2 ob. The 18th: to Secundas, a cake for the children 1/2 ob. The 19th: barley water for the same 1/2 ob. The 20th: sauce 1 ob.; pure bread 1/2 ob.; for treating Antonia 2 ob.; and for Taptollous daughter of Caecilius 3 ob.; on the birthday of Tryphas, for garlands 2 ob.; on the birthday of ... for garlands 2 ob. The 21st: pomegranates for the children 1 ob.; playthings and ... for the children 1 ob.; beer 3 ob.; sauce 1 ob. The 22nd: sauce 1 ob.; Thaësis ... for 2 days 5 ob.; the mother of Ammonas for . days ...; Taarpaësis for 2 days 5 ob.; Berous similarly for 10 days 4 dr. 1 ob. The 24th: cost of grinding 1 artaba of wheat 4 ob.; 2 ... of pickle 2 ob.; salt 1 ob.; a needle and thread 1 ob.; cost of grinding 1 artaba of wheat, through Theodorus, 4 ob.; cost of weaving a cloak 1 dr. 2 ob.; pure bread for Ph... 1 dr.; a pigeon for the children 1 ob.; pure bread for the same 1/2 ob.; to Secundus for a cake for the children 1/2 ob., and for dry meal 1/2 ob.; milk 1/2 ob.; perfume for the mummy of the daughter of Pasis 1 dr.... The 10th: ... for the women 2 dr. 3 ob.; relishes for the women on 2 days 2 1/2 ob.; cost of tinkering a lamp 2 1/2 ob.; pulse when ... was dining here 1 1/2 ob.; for treating Laodice 2 1/2 ob.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
