<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 2, 243</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20512</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20512</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20512</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;2;243</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 2</note>
              Chaeremon, son of Chaeremon, of the Maronian deme, nominee of Claudius Antoninus, to the agoranomus, greeting. Register a contract of mortgage for Didymus, son of Sarapion, son of Didymus, his mother being Charitous, daughter of Petosius, of Oxyrhynchus, of the property of the mortgager Dionysius also called Amois, son of Phanias also called Amois, son of Phanias, his mother being Zenarion, daughter of Dionysius, of the same city, being a share assigned to him by his mother Zenarion in her lifetime by an agreement of cession executed through the record office of the same city in the month of Mecheir in the tenth year of Nero, of her house near the Serapeum at Oxyrhynchus in the quarter of Hermaeus, containing a two-storied tower and a gateway and passage and hall and chamber, and of the court adjoining the tower on the north side and containing a stone well, and of some open plots of land formerly in the possession of Heracleides, son of Philoxenus, and Ptolema, daughter of Asinis, on the north side starting from the north angle of the gateway towards the south, measuring from north to south on both sides 16 cubits, and from west to east also on both sides 32 cubits, making 512 square cubits, together with all fixtures that may be included in them; the measurements of the court northwards of the tower and containing the well are from north to south on both sides 24 cubits, and from west to east also on both sides 11 cubits, making for the court 264 square cubits, together with all fixtures which may be included in them; total measurements, 776 square cubits, all these particulars being in accordance with the aforesaid agreement. The property has been mortgaged to Didymus by the said Dionysius also called Amois for a sum of 1300 drachmae of silver at the interest of a drachma for a mina each month for a term of twelve months from the coming month Pharmuthi; the value of which sum, reckoned at the rate of 1800 drachmae (of copper) for 4 drachmae (of silver), is 97 talents 3000 drachmae of copper. Farewell. The 11th year of the Emperor Caesar Vespasian Augustus, Phamenoth.
              <note>There follow the signature of Chaeremon authorizing the registration, and the receipt of the bank of Theon and company for 1 talent 5700 drachmae of copper paid by Didymus on account of the tax on sales and mortgages.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
