<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 2, 247</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20516</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20516</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20516</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;2;247</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 2</note>
              To Theon and Epimachus, keepers of the archives, from Panechotes, son of Pausiris, son of Panechotes, his mother being Tsenammonas, daughter of Panechotes, of the city of Oxyrhynchus. I register for my full brother ... of the same city, who is approaching the legal age, in accordance with the commands of his highness the praefect Mettius Rufus, his property at the present date in the Campus near the Serapeum at the city of Oxyrhynchus in the Knights’ Camp quarter, namely a third part of a doubled-towered house, in the middle of which there is a hall, and of the court attached and the other fixtures and the entrance and exit and appurtenances. This has descended to him from the property of the aforesaid and departed Tsenammonas, the mother of us both, in accordance with his rightful claims. The ninth year of the Emperor Caesar Domitianus Augustus Germanicus, Phamenoth 14.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
