<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 2, 268</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20539</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20539</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20539</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;2;268</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 2</note>
              Copy. To Theon, chief justice and superintendent of the chrematistae and the other courts, from Ammonarion, daughter of Ammonius, son of Dionysius, and however else she is described at Ptolemais Hermiu, and from her daughter Ophelous, whose father is Heraclas, of Oxyrhynchus, the two women acting with their guardian, the half brother of Ammonarion on the mother’s side, Besarion, son of Heras, and however else he is described at Ptolemais, and from ... Antiphanes, son of Ammonius, of the said city of Oxyrhynchus. We agree with each other as follows :— Ammonarion and Ophelous have given their consent and have received from Antiphanes from hand to hand in cash the sum which they severally consented to accept, Ammonarion, on account of the dowry, amounting to 800 silver drachmae, which she brought to her late husband, the brother of Antiphanes’ father and the father of Ophelous, Heraclas, son of Antiphanes, of the same city of Oxyrhynchus, in accordance with a settlement completed some time ago through the daybook, and Ophelous on her part resigns to Antiphanes her share of all the property left by her late father Heraclas. The said agreement of marriage is void, and neither Ammonarion nor Ophelous nor any one acting on their behalf has any further claim against Antiphanes or against the property left by Heraclas, Ammonarion on account of the refunded dowry, and Ophelous on account of the resigned inheritance, as is aforesaid; and neither of them has any claim respecting any other matter whatever written or unwritten of past date down to the present day, and any claim that is made shall be void and inadmissible. The above agreement has no ..., for which we make due petition. <note>Date.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
