<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 2, 275</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20546</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20546</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20546</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;2;275</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 2</note>
              Agreement between Tryphon, son of Dionysius, son of Tryphon, his mother being Thamounis, daughter of Onnophris, and Ptolemaeus, weaver, son of Pausirion, son of Ptolemaeus, his mother being Ophelous, daughter of Theon, both parties being inhabitants of the city of Oxyrhynchus. Tryphon agrees that he has apprenticed to Ptolemaeus his son Thoënis, whose mother is Saraeus, daughter of Apion, and who is not yet of age, for a term of one year from this day, to serve and to perform all the orders given him by Ptolemaeus in respect of his weaver’s art in all its branches of which Ptolemaeus has knowledge. The boy is to be fed and clothed during the whole period by his father Tryphon, who is also to be responsible for all the taxes upon him, on condition of a monthly payment to himself by Ptolemaeus of 5 drachmae on account of victuals, and at the termination of the whole period of a payment of 12 drachmae on account of clothing. Tryphon is not to have the power of taking away his son from Ptolemaeus until the completion of the period; and if there are any days on which the boy fails to attend, Tryphon shall produce him for an equivalent number of days after the period is over, or shall forfeit for each day 1 drachma of silver. The penalty for taking him away within the period shall be 100 drachmae, and an equal sum to the treasury. If Ptolemaeus fails to instruct the boy thoroughly he is to be liable to the same penalties. This contract of apprenticeship is valid.
              <note>Date, and signature of Ptolemaeus.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
