<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 2, 278</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20549</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20549</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20549</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;2;278</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 2</note>
              Isidorus, son of Isidorus, has leased to Heracleus, son of Soterichus, a Persian of the Epigone, from the mills which he possesses one perfect Theban mill from the present month Mecheir until the 5th intercalary day of Mesore of the present third year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, at the rent agreed upon by the two parties for the aforesaid mill, namely 2 drachmae 3 obols of silver a month. The lessee shall pay to Isidorus the monthly rent of the mill without any delay. The mill and the rent are guaranteed against all risks, and at the end of the time the servant shall restore the mill safe and uninjured in the condition in which he received it, at whatever spot in Oxyrhynchus Isidorus may require, or shall pay its value as agreed upon, namely, 100 drachmae of silver, and for every month that he fails to return it, 1 1/2 times the rent; Isidorus having the right of execution upon both the person and all the property of the lessee, as by a judicial decision. This lease is valid wheresoever produced.
              <note>Date, and signature of Heracleus written for him by Dionysius.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
