<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 2, 280</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20551</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20551</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20551</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;2;280</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 2</note>
              Dionysius, son of Dionysius, son of Pausirion, of Oxyrhynchus, has leased to Dionysius, son of Harpocration, son of Sarapion, of the same city, a Persian of the Epigone, for four years and four inundations, beginning with the present eighth year of the Emperor Caesar Domitianus Augustus Germanicus, the land belonging to him situated near Tychis Nechotis in the middle basin, and previously held in gift by Artemidorus, his share, namely 5 arourae, on condition that during the first three years the lessee may sow and plant the land with whatever crops he chooses, woad excepted, and in the last year he shall sow half the land with wheat, and plant the other half with beans, of which half half shall be ploughed while the other half is cut, at the fixed rent of 17 artabae of wheat guaranteed for each year appointed against all risks, an allowance being made to the lessee...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
