<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 2, 294</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20565</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20565</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20565</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;2;294</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 2</note>
              Sarapion to his brother Dorion greeting and good wishes for continued health. On arriving at Alexandria on the ... of the month below written, I learned from some fishermen who were at Alexandria that ... and that Secunda’s house has been searched and that my house has been searched, and ... whether this is certainly so. I shall therefore be obliged if you will write me an answer on this matter, in order that I may myself present a petition to the praefect. Be sure to do this; I am not so much as anointing myself until I hear word from you on each point. I am being pressed by my friends to enter the service of Apollonius, the chief usher, in order that I come to the session in his company. The marshal of the strategus and Justus the sword-bearer are in prison, in accordance with the instructions of the praefect, until the session, —unless indeed they persuade the chief usher to give security for them until the session. Let me hear about our bald friend, how his hair is growing again on the top; be sure you do. I told your friend Diogenes not to rob me over the expense of what he has of mine; for I am ... with the chief usher. I beg and entreat you to write me a reply concerning what has happened. Before all else take care of your health. Look after Demetrous and our father Dorion. Good-bye.
              <note>Date. Addressed, 'Deliver to my brother Dorion.'</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
