<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 3, 478</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20614</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20614</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20614</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;478</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 3</note>
              To Hadrion and Zoïlus, keepers of the archives, from Dionysous freedwoman of Dionysia daughter of Dionysius also called Chresimus son of Dionysius, of Oxyrhynchus, with her guardian Eudaemon son of Menoetes, of the same city. In accordance with the orders concerning the selection of boys 13 years of age when their parents on both sides are inhabitants of the metropolis rated at 12 drachmae, I declare that my son Ptollis son of Phaon son of Ptollis registered in the quarter of the Square of Thoëris <note>(interlinear note “the Kmelemus (?) quarter, as he says”)</note> has reached the age of 13 years in the past 16th year of Hadrianus Caesar the lord, and that his father Phaon son of Ptollis son of Phaon, his mother being Athena, was an inhabitant of the metropolis rated at 12 drachmae as shown by a uniform poll-tax list of the 13th year of Hadrianus Caesar the lord at the said quarter, and is now dead, and that the father of my aforesaid patroness Dionysia <note>(interlinear note “he does not agree”)</note>, Dionysius also called Chresimus son of Dionysius, of the same city, was similarly rated at 12 drachmae by the selection of the 7th year of the deified Trajan in the Lycians’ Camp quarter, and died at an advanced age; and I swear by the Emperor Caesar Trajanus Hadrianus Augustus that the foregoing statement is correct. The 17th year of the Emperor Caesar Trajanus Hadrianus Augustus, Tubi 13. I, Dionysous, freedwoman of Dionysia daughter of Dionysius also called Chresimus, have presented the declaration and sworn the oath. I, Eudaemon son of Menoetes, have been appointed her guardian and wrote for her as she was illiterate.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
