<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 3, 483</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20619</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20619</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20619</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;483</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 3</note>
              (To Sarapion, keeper of the public records, from Achillas ... Wishing to mortgage to) ... through his ..., priest of Zeus, Hera and ..., the (6 arourae) of catoecic land which I own near the village of ... in the eastern toparchy in the holding of Zenodorus ...(on condition that the repayment is made) by the sth intercalary day of the month Caesareus of the 22nd year of Trajanus Caesar the lord, at the interest of 1 drachma for each mina per month dating from next month, Pharmouthi, which I will pay off at the conclusion of each twelvemonth, I present this application in order that you may instruct the agoranomi of Oxyrhynchus, who are also recorders, to execute the deed in the proper way. And I swear by the deified Augusti and by the Fortune of the Emperor Caesar Nerva Trajanus Augustus Germanicus Dacicus and my ancestral gods that the aforesaid arourae are my own property and free from all liability either public or private up to the present day. The 11th year of the Emperor Caesar Nerva Trajanus Augustus Germanicus Dacicus, Phamenoth dies Augustus. I, Achillas son of Didymus, have presented the application and sworn the oath.
              Sarapion, joint keeper of the records with Theon, to the agoranomi of the metropolis, greeting. Achillas has the 6 arourae on the register. Execute the deed therefore, as is fitting. <note>Date.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
