<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 3, 490</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20626</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20626</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20626</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;490</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 3</note>
              The 9th year of the Emperor Caesar Trajanus Hadrianus Augustus, Choiach 5, at the city of Oxyrhynchus in the Thebaid, for good fortune. This is the will made in the street by me, Tastraton daughter of Psenosiris son of Atreus, my mother being Penuris, of Oxyrhynchus, while sane and in my right mind, with my guardian my cousin ... his mother being Taamois daughter of Zoilus, of the same city. So long as I survive I am to have power over my own property, to make any further provisions or new dispositions and to revoke this will. But if I die with this will unaltered I leave on account of his affection towards me to Dionysius son of Panechotes, freedman of Petosiris ... his mother being Ammonous, of the same city, who is now a minor, if he live, and if not to his family, the ... share belonging to me jointly with my father Psenosiris son of Atreus and Spokis in the village of Kriethuris in the ... toparchy, of a house and court with entrances and exits, and all else that I leave in any manner whatsoever. If Dionysius happen to die childless and intestate the property devolving upon him from me shall be sent to my nearest relations; but to no one else do I leave any of my property. This will is valid.
              <note>There follow the signatures (1) of the testatrix and her guardian, written for them by a third party, (2) of the usual six witnesses with details of their ages, distinguishing marks, and seals.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
