<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 3, 491</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20627</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20627</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20627</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;491</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 3</note>
              The 10th year of the Emperor Caesar Trajanus Hadrianus Augustus, the 5th intercalary day of the month Caesareus, at Oxyrhynchus in the Thebaid, for good fortune. This is the will made in the street by Eudaemon son of Thonasuchis son of Thonis, his mother being Thaësis, of Oxyrhynchus, shrine-bearer of the most great goddess Thoëris and of Isis ... and the other gods of the temple at the village Mouchinor, being sane and in his right mind. So long as I survive I am to have power over my own property, to make any further provisions or new dispositions I choose and to revoke this will, and any such provisions shall be valid. But if I die with this will unaltered I leave my sons Thonis and Horus and Eudaemon, all three sons of Ta... daughter of Harpaësis also called Horus, each of them, if he lives, and if not, his children, as co-equal heirs of all the buildings, estates and slaves that I may leave, but Thonis alone of all... whatever that he chooses on condition that the said Thonis pays any debts which may be proved against me and gives to his brothers Horus and Eudaemon, if they have at the time of my death completed 20 years, one year after my death, and if they are not so old, then to each of them when he has completed the 20 years, 500 drachmae, making for both of them together 1000 drachmae; and it shall not be lawful for the said Horus and Eudaemon nor for any one of them to sell, mortgage or otherwise dispose of what will come to them from me until each of them has completed 25 years. And if I die before the said Horus and Eudaemon have completed 20 years, their brother Thonis and their maternal grandfather Harpaësis also called Horus son of Thonis shall be guardians of each of them until he completes 20 years. If any of the three sons happen to die childless his share shall belong to his surviving brothers equally; beyond this no one at all shall have power to disobey these provisions and any person so doing shall forfeit to the party abiding by them the damages and a fine of 1000 drachmae of silver and to the Treasury an equal sum, and the foregoing provisions shall none the less remain valid. This will is valid.
              <note>Signatures of Eudaemon and six witnesses with details of their ages, distinguishing marks, and seals, and docket of the record office at Oxyrhynchus.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
