<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 3, 488</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20624</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20624</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20624</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;488</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 3</note>
              To his highness the epistrategus Julius Julianus, from Senphibis daughter of Thortaeus, with her guardian who is her son Psais the elder, son of Lemos, from the village of Ibion Nemna of the lower toparchy of the Apollonopolite nome. I bought, my lord, a long time ago from Apollonius and Didymus, both sons of Origenes, of Lycopolis, 54 arourae of corn-land in the holding called the Diagraphe in the lands of the village of Krikis in the Antaeopolite nome. But a certain Artemidorus, scribe of the komogrammateus of Krikis, somehow registered me as having more land than I actually possess by one whole aroura and more in each year, and in consequence inflicts much loss upon me, I am therefore compelled, since the man oppresses me and I am in danger of abandoning the (land ?), to take refuge with you, the lord and helper of all, and I beg you, if it please you, to order the strategus of the nome to see that the correct registration is made of my land in accordance with the securities which I possess, and not to let me be falsely registered by the komogrammateus, for last year also he made other false entries in his register concerning me besides this, that I may obtain relief. I, Senphibis daughter of Thortaeus with my guardian Psais the elder, son of Lamos (sic), have presented this petition.
              (Deliver) into the hands of (...) of the Antaeopolite nome. She accuses the scribe of the komogrammateus with making a false entry and requests the correct entry to be made...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
