<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 3, 487</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20623</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20623</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20623</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;487</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 3</note>
              To his highness Statilius Maximus, epistrategus, from Nicias son of Harpalus, of Oxyrhynchus. The scribe of the city, Serenus, appointed me guardian of two minors, sons of Dionysius son of Dorion, aged about 25 years, who neither on their father’s nor on their mother’s side had any other persons who from ties of kinship could undertake the business of guardianship. Since I am weighed down by my official duties and have incurred debts, I request you, my lord, if it please your fortune, to instruct the strategus to compel the scribe of the city to appoint some one else in my place to act as guardian to the minors, in order that I may be able to attend to the cultivation of my property and be enabled to pay the debts to which I have become liable in connexion with my office, and that you may not make me an outcast from my property and home, so that I may obtain redress. Farewell. The 20th year of the Emperor Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrianus Antoninus Augustus Pius, the 18th of the month Hadrianus. I, Nicias son of Harpalus, presented this petition.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
