<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 3, 493</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20629</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20629</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20629</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;493</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 3</note>
              <milestone unit="line" n="2"/>... shall have the ownership of the estates and right of domicile in the buildings, the survivor of us, if he pleases, having the power to sell all or any of the slaves belonging to himself or to the one of us who first dies, and with the purchase money to defray the expenses of the funeral and burial of the body and pay the debts of the deceased, and the survivor of us shall similarly be permitted to devise to the children that have been born to us, Sarapas and Apollonius and Diogenes and ..., the last two being minors, the estates, unsold slaves and other effects belonging to himself or to the one who first dies in such manner as the survivor thinks fit and with any division he chooses, but the wife Berenice if she survives shall if she will have the undisturbed ownership, and no one at all shall be permitted to set aside aught of these provisions or to do anything opposed to them, but the aggression shall be invalid and the person attempting to disobey them in any respect or making aggression upon the survivor of us shall forfeit for each aggression the damages and a fine of 2000 drachmae of silver and to the Treasury an equal sum, the foregoing provisions at the same time remaining valid. This will is valid. The witnesses are Lochus son of Lochus son of Sarapion, Sarapion son of Sarapion son of Pasion, Plution son of Cratinus son of Demetrius, Eudaemon also called Amois, son of Amois son of Sarapion, Apollon son of Diogenes son of Theon, Diophantus son of Diophantus son of Aulius, all six of the said city, in the said street. <note>Signature of Pasion the testator.</note>

            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
