<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 3, 492</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20628</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20628</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20628</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;492</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 3</note>
              The 14th year of the Emperor Caesar Trajanus Hadrianus Augustus, Mecheir 28, at Oxyrhynchus in the Thebaid, for good fortune. This is the will made in the street by Thatres daughter of Ammonius son of Sarapion, her mother being Tsenthotoumis, from Ision Tryphonis in the lower toparchy, now living at Oxyrhynchus, being sane and in her right mind, with her guardian the son of Thatres’ cousin Heraclous daughter of Sarapion son of Sarapion, her mother being Tauseiris also called Sarapous, Horion also called Theon, son of Sarapion son of ..., from Ibion Ammonii in the same lower toparghy. So long as I survive I am to have power over my own property, to make any further provisions or new dispositions I choose and to revoke this will, and any such provisions shall be valid. But if I die with this will unaltered and no further provisions made I leave on account of their affection towards me Ptollion son of Theon son of Ptollion, his mother being Isareus daughter of Theon, and his brother on the mother’s side Theon son of Theon son of Theon also called Apollonius son of Theon, both of Oxyrhynchus, if they live, and if not, their children, as joint and equal heirs of the house, court, yard and fixtures belonging to me at Oxyrhynchus in the Knight’s Camp quarter, and any slaves which I may leave and all other property of any kind whatever; and it shall nowise be lawful for my said heirs to receive into my house aforesaid the father of the second Theon, namely Theon son of Theon also called Apollonius son of Theon, his mother being Helene, for the whole of his life under any pretext, nor for any one else to disobey any of my dispositions, and the person attempting to set aside aught of them shall, while not disturbing their validity, forfeit a fine of 1000 drachmae and to the Treasury an equal sum and none the less (shall these provisions hold good); and I leave none of my property to any one else.
              <note>Signatures of Thatres written for her by her guardian Horion, and of six witnesses in the usual style, and docket of the record office.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
