<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 3, 485</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20621</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20621</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20621</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;485</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 3</note>
              To Theon, strategus, from Serenus, freedman of Apollonianus son of Sarapion, of Oxyrhynchus. Appended is a copy of the official response received by me from the record office. Antoninus also called Pudens, priest and archidicastes, to the strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, greeting. Let a copy of the petition which has been presented be served as follows. Good-bye. The 19th year of the Aurelii Antoninus and Commodus the lords Augusti, Phaophi 7. Signed by me, Sarapion. I, Hephaestion also called Sarapion, wrote (on his behalf). To Antoninus also called Pudens, priest, archidicastes and superintendent of the chrematistae and other courts, from Serenus, freedman of Apollonianus son of Sarapion, of Oxyrhynchus. I lent in accordance with a public deed, written in the record office at the said Oxyrhynchus in the past 18th year on the 11th of the month Sebastus, to Sarapias daughter of Podon son of Horus, her mother being Thaësis, of Psobthis, the metropolis of the Small Oasis, the capital sum of 900 drachmae of silver with interest at the rate of a drachma on each mina monthly, the capital to be repaid on the 30th of the month Caesareus in the same past 18th year, with the proviso that if she did not repay the money on the appointed day, instead of the capital sum and any interest that was not paid I and my assigns were guaranteed the possession and ownership of her slave Sarapias, then aged about 25 years, with the various conditions contained in the loan and the provisions therein written for my security concerning the flight or death of the slave. The appointed term having elapsed and the repayment not having been made, I request you to give instructions for a letter to be written to the strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome to present a copy of this petition to Sarapias, if she is still living, and if not, then to her heirs being of age, and if they are minors, to their lawful guardians, whose names will be ascertained on the spot, in order that they may be informed and may make repayment to me or else may know that I shall take the proper proceedings to which I am entitled for entry upon possession, as is right. The 19th year of the Aurelii Antoninus and Commodus the lords Augusti, Phaophi. The strategus ordered that a copy should be served in the proper manner upon Sarapias. <note>Date. (Signed)</note>  I, Sarapias, daughter of Podon, received a copy of this petition. <note>Date.</note> I, Musaeus also called Pausirion, son of ...,am registered as her guardian having been (appointed) by the strategus, and wrote for her as she was illiterate. I, Syrion, assistant, served the petition npon Sarapias, as aforesaid. <note>Date.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
