<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 3, 489</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20625</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20625</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20625</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;489</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 3</note>
              The 20th year of the Emperor Caesar Nerva Trajanus Optimus Augustus Germanicus Dacicus Parthicus, the 4th intercalary day, dies Augustus, of the month Caesareus, at the city of Oxyrhynchus in the Thebaid, for good fortune. This is the will, made in the street, by me, Dionysius son of Harpocration son of Sarapion, my mother being Esorsois, of Oxyrhynchus, being sane and in my right mind. So long as I survive I am to have power over my own property, to use it and make any arrangements or other dispositions concerning it in any manner I choose. But after my death I concede to my wife Diogenis daughter of Ptolemaeus, of the same city, for her lifetime the right to dwell in and use free of rent any one abode which she herself may choose in the stone house belonging to me in the North Quay quarter with exit and entrance. She shall also have the use for her lifetime of the effects and furniture left by me in the said abode and in the house and the service of and the profits from my female slave Ilarous and her children who are to be fed and clothed by the said Diogenis. After her death all my property shall belong solely to our children, which children shall not have the power to alienate what is inherited by them from me except only to their several families; nor shall any one be permitted under any circumstances to proceed against my wife Diogenis concerning any of the provisions of the will, and the person who does so shall forfeit a fine of 1000 drachmae and to the Treasury an equal sum. This will is valid.
              <note>There follow (1) the signature of the testator giving a nearly verbal recapitulation of the substance of the will, and written for him by Heracles son of Apion, (2) the signatures of six witnesses who add as usual particulars as to their ages, personal descriptions and seals, (3) the docket of the record office at Oxyrhynchus, and (4) on the verso the title of the will.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
