<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 3, 496</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20632</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20632</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20632</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;496</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 3</note>
              The 11th year of the Emperor Caesar Trajanus Hadrianus Augustus, Pharmouthi 24, at Oxyrhynchus in the Thebaid, for good fortune, on the day of Julia Augusta, in the street. Sarapion son of Sarapion son of Sarapion son of Sarapion, his mother being Thais daughter of Sarapion, of Oxyrhynchus, has given in marriage his daughter Thais whose mother is ... to Sarapion son of Eudaemon son of Theon, his mother being Heras daughter of ... and Didous, who has received from Sarapion, the father and giver of the bride, a pair of ... weighing 3 minae 14 1/2 quarters, a brooch of 8 quarters, a ... of 6 quarters, a chain with 3 green ... of stone, the gold weighing [.] 1/2 quarters, making altogether on the standard of Oxyrhynchus 5 minae ... quarters, also 2 dresses, 2 girdles, one red the other rose-colored, a ... and a mantle, together worth 560 silver drachmae, and 1860 silver drachmae, the total value of the whole dowry being 4100 drachmae of silver of the Imperial coinage. Besides this the grandmother of the bride, Thais daughter of Sarapion and Heraclous, of the same city, with her guardian who is another son of hers and the full brother of the giver of the bride, Sarapion son of Sarapion, acknowledges in the same street that she has given away Thais in marriage, and she confers upon the said Thais (the possession of the slave) Callityche and her future offspring, the services of and the profits from her to be shared by the husband with the bride so long as they live together; and it shall not be lawful for the husband to ... the slave without his wife’s consent nor anything that is brought to him by his wife, nor to sell or mortgage or otherwise dispose of his property namely a house, yard and court and its fixtures and his slaves Sarapous and Nicarous and the children of Nicarous, Sarapous and Cerdon and Epicharmus, and the future offspring of them or ethers, or any additional property which he may acquire, without the consent of the bride. Let both live blamelessly together, and the husband shall supply the bride with necessaries in proportion to his means; but if any difference arises between them and the bride wishes to separate from her husband, as soon as the separation takes place the bride shall withdraw the slave Callityche and the children that may be born to her, and the husband shall repay to the giver of the bride if he survives, and if not, to the bride herself, the 4100 drachmae of the dowry within ... days from the day on which they are demanded or forfeit this amount increased by one half... And if the bride is at the time of separation in a state of pregnancy the husband shall give her on account of the birth 60 drachmae more. When they come together may they enjoy health; but if either husband or wife should chance to die, the husband shall have power over his own property to make any further provisions he pleases and to divide it among whom he will; but if he makes no further provisions the property shall after his death belong to their children. If the husband dies first the bride shall have... and she or her nearest relation on the one part and whoever shall be appointed by the husband on the other part shall together be guardians, the children being brought up with their mother until they come of age. If the husband appoints no guardian for the one part of the guardianship the bride or her nearest of kin shall act alone, and no one shall be permitted to deprive her of the guardianship nor any part of it. If the bride dies first without their having any children or when those that have been born have died childless, the husband shall repay the dowry namely ... the 4100 drachmae of silver in 60 days and shall send to the said relations of the bride all the rest of her property. Similarly if the husband dies first without their having any children or when those that have been born have died childless, the bride shall ... and withdraw the slave Callityche and the children that may be born to her, and until she has recovered them she shall have control over the whole property, and with regard to all the provisions the choice shall rest with the bride to have either if she prefers the aforesaid gold ornaments included in the dowry at the same weight or their equivalent value, and the bride and her agents shall have the right of execution upon both the husband and upon all his property in accordance with their agreement with each other. The certifier of both parties is Diogenes son of Hierax, scribe, of the same city, in the same street.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
