<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 3, 502</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20636</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20636</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20636</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;502</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 3</note>
              Dionysia daughter of Chaeremon with her guardian her son Apion also called Dionysius son of Diogenes, priest of Faustina Augusta, both of Oxyrhynchus, has leased to Ptolema daughter of Theon, of Antinoë, through Iulas son of Didymus, by adoption son of Demetrius also called Apollonius, of Oxyrhynchus, for one year and six months dating from the 1st of the current month Phamenoth of the present 4th year of the lords and Emperors Antoninus and Verus the house which she owns, and which previously belonged to her second cousin Chaeremon, of Antinoë, at Oxyrhynchus in the Temgenouthis quarter, with the court and two yards in one of which is a well, and the portico which adjoins the house and the other fixtures and the entrance and exit, at a rent for the premises leased of 200 silver drachmae a year. If the lease is guaranteed the lessee shall pay the lessor at the conclusion of each period of six months the proportionate amount of the rent, 100 drachmae, and shall together with her assigns have the use of the premises leased to her as aforesaid for the appointed time without hindrance, and thereafter shall deliver them up free from filth and with the doors and keys received by her of all the premises, and the reel of the aforesaid well provided with a new rope, and the two existing stone presses with the water-pitchers and trough, or shall forfeit the value of anything which she fails to deliver and any arrears of rent increased by one half, and the lessor shall have the right of execution upon the lessee and upon all her property, the lessor being liable for the police-tax and brick-making tax. This lease is valid. The 4th year of the Emperor Caesar Marcus Aurelius Antoninus Augustus and the Emperor Caesar Lucius Aurelius Verus Augustus, Phamenoth 5. I, Apion also called Dionysius, have been registered as my mother’s guardian, and have leased together with the above-mentioned premises the chambers in the court. The same date.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
