<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 3, 500</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20634</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20634</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20634</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;500</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 3</note>
              To Hierax, strategus of the Athribite nome, from Horus son of Psenobasthis and Nekpheros son of Thaisous and ... and the rest... (We wish to lease) 20 1/4 arourae of public land near Tetaphou at 2 artabae of wheat for each aroura, and for the addition upon the whole land 5 artabae of wheat, and near Psenarsiësis in the eastern part of the Thostian district 1 aroura of public land at 3 artabae of wheat, which rent we will measure upon our mutual security into the public granary from the new crop of the said 15th year of Hadrianus Caesar the lord. The 15th year of the Emperor Caesar Trajanus Hadrianus Augustus, Phaophi 5. We, Horus son of Psenomoithas and Nekpheros son of Thaisous, of the village of Sinekthoieku in the eastern part of the Thostian district, have leased the aforesaid 20 1/4 arourae of public land near Tetaphou at 2 artabae of wheat and for the addition upon the whole land 5 artabae of wheat, and near Psenarsiësis 1 aroura likewise of public land at 3 artabae of wheat, and we will measure...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
