<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 3, 506</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20638</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20638</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20638</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;506</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 3</note>
              Copy. The 7th year of the Emperor Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrianus Antoninus Augustus Pius,the of the month Hadrianus, at Oxyrhynchus in the Thebaid. Sarapion son of Herodes son of Exacon, of Oxyrhynchus, his mother being Caecilia Polla, has lent to Thatres and Teteorion, both daughters of Apollonius son of ..., and to their mother Demas daughter of Apollonius son of Panechotes, her mother being Philotera, all three Persians from the village of Pela, each with her guardian, of Thatres her husband Peteuris son of Ammonas son of Sagathes, his mother being Panechotis, of Oxyrhynchus, of Teteorion her maternal uncle Panechotes son of Apollonius and Philotera, of the aforesaid Pela, and of Demas her paternal uncle Hatres son of Panechotes son of Apollonius, of the said Pela, in the street, a sum of 1000 drachmae of Imperial silver coin, to which nothing has been added, at the interest of 3 obols for each mina per month dating from the present month Hadrianus. The borrowers shall pay to the lender the interest at the conclusion of each twelvemonth, the lender having security for everything for which they do not produce his written receipt, and the principal on the 30th of the month Caesareus of the 9th year of Antoninus Caesar the lord together with the interest for the remaining 9 months without any delay. If they fail, Thatres and Teteorion concede that the borrower and his assigns in place of the principal and of all interest which he may not receive shall from the time when the payment falls due have the possession and ownership for ever out of the land owned by them in equal shares near the said Pela in the cavalry-soldier’s holding of Diocles and Ptolemaeus, Persian, namely the third part of what was previously a vineyard but is now dry vine-land, in the most northerly portion of the said third part 1 49/64 arourae with all their contents, of which the adjacent areas are, on the south the land of Stephanus ... and Thatres the aforesaid, daughter of Apollonius, on the north..., on the east a canal ... and the land of Stephanus, on the west ...; and (the borrowers) are compelled to deliver this land to the lender or his assigns guaranteed for all time against all risks with every guarantee and free from obligation to cultivate Crown land or Imperial estates and from all kinds of imposts and all State requisitions and taxes dating from previous times up to the period of Sarapion’s ownership. And until the borrowers repay to the lender the principal and the interest, Thatres and Teteorion have no right to sell this land or mortgage it or dispose of it in any other way or register any one as owning it, while the lender has the right at the expiration of the term of the loan,if he fails to recover it, to assume the ownership of this land in place of both the principal and whatever interest at 6 per cent. he may fail to recover and interest for overtime at the equal rate of 6 per cent., and to make an execution upon the borrowers who are security to each other for payment and upon whichever of them he chooses and upon all the aforesaid land and upon the rest of their property as if in accordance with a legal decision, the lender having the right whenever he chooses to register his mortgage at the property record-office ..., and the said lender shall incur no loss in his right of execution for the other sums which Thatres and Teteorion owe him in respect of another loan drawn up through the said registry-office in the present month Hadrianus for which their mother is security upon the mortgage of the aforesaid 14 1/2 arourae of wheat-bearing land, namely a principal sum of 1 talent 600 drachmae and interest, but all the provisions of that deed are valid.
              This contract is valid.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
