<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 3, 494</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20630</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20630</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20630</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;494</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 3</note>
              Copy. In the 19th year of the Emperor Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrianus Antoninus Augustus Pius, the 30th of the month Germaniceus, at Oxyrhynchus in the Thebaid; for good fortune. This is the will made in the street by me, Acusilaus son of Dius son of Dionysius also called Acusilaus and of Dionysia daughter of Theon, of the city of Oxyrhynchus, being sane and in my right mind. So long as I survive I am to have power over my own property, to make any further provisions and alterations I please and to revoke this will, and any such provisions shall be valid. But if I die with this will unchanged, I set free under sanction of Zeus, Earth and Sun, for their goodwill and affection towards me, my slaves Psenamounis also called Ammonius and Hermas and Apollonous also called Demetria and her daughter Diogenis and Diogenis, another female slave of mine. I bequeath to my wife and cousin Aristous also called Apollonarion, daughter of Heraclides son of Dionysius also called Acusilaus and of Herais daughter of Alexandrus, being well-disposed and showing entire faithfulness towards me, all that I may leave in the way of furniture, effects, objects of gold, clothing, ornaments, wheat, pulse, produce, and all my household stock, and my debts, recorded and unrecorded. I leave my son Dius by my aforesaid wife Aristous also called Apollonarion, if he lives, and if not, his children, heir to all the property that I leave and to my other slaves and the offspring that may hereafter be born to the female slaves aforesaid; but my said wife Aristous also called Apollonarion shall have during her lifetime, after the taxes are paid, the use of and all the revenues from the whole property, together with the service of and profits from those of them who are to receive their freedom after my death. My said wife shall supply to my son Dius every month at Oxyrhynchus for his sustenance and other expenses two artabae of wheat by the measure used for payment... and 60 drachmae and for clothing 200 drachmae yearly. My said wife Aristous also called Apollonarion shall have the right to sell and mortgage on her own authority anything she chooses of whatI leave to my son Dius in property and slaves and to use for her personal requirements the money accruing from the sale or mortgage. My said wife Aristous also called Apollonarion shall pay all the debts that may be proved against me; and my wife, and after her death my son Dius, shall give to my slaves and freedmen for a feast which they shall celebrate at my tomb on my birthday every year 100 drachmae of silver to be spent. Anything that I append to the official copy of the will, whether cancelling or supplementing or making bequests to other persons or with any other purpose shall also be valid as if contained in the actual will; beyond this no one shall have power to disobey it, and anybody who does so shall forfeit to the party abiding by it the damages and a fine of 2 talents of silver and to the Treasury an equal sum, the above provisions remaining none the less valid. This will is valid. I, Acusilaus son of Dius the aforesaid, have made this will, the whole of which with all the above provisions is in my own writing. I am 48 years of age and have a scar on my right foot, and my seal is an image of Thonis. I, Didymus son of Onnophris also called Chaeremon son of Herodes, of Oxyrhynchus, one of the witnesses to the above will, recognized my own seal which is a figure of Hermes and sealed with the said seal. <note>There follow similar signatures of three other witnesses, whose seals represented respectively Sarapis, Apollo, and Heracles.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
