<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 3, 510</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20641</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20641</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20641</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;510</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 3</note>
              ... her mother being Tausiris daughter of..., from Psobthis in the eastern toparchy, with her guardian her said husband Dionysius, acknowledges the receipt from them (the agreement being made in the street) of the capital sum of 472 silver drachmae of the Imperial coinage, lent by him to them in accordance with a contract of loan executed through the record-office in the same city of Oxyrhynchus in the month Caesarets of the 3rd year of Trajanus Caesar the lord, and to be repaid on the 5th intercalary day of the following 4th year, on the security of property of Dionysius in the aforesaid Psobthis consisting of a half-share of some open plots of land and shares of a house that has fallenin and a half-share of a second house and its fixtures and shares of another house and court and open plots and the house and yard and other fixtures formerly belonging to Clandius Theon at the said Psobthis. Artemidorus accordingly in release of the mortgage has forthwith handed over to the other parties to the agreement the binding contract of loan and the tax-receipts to be cancelled, and acknowledges the further receipt from them of the interest upon the capital sum and the taxes which have been demanded from him, and that neither Artemidorus himself nor any other person on his behalf either makes or will make any claim or will proceed against the other parties to the agreement...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
