<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 3, 508</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20640</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20640</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20640</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;508</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 3</note>
              The 5th year of the Emperor Caesar Nerva Trajanus Augustus Germanicus, the 30th of the month Caesareus, at Oxyrhynchus in the Thebaid. Stephanus also called Amoïs, son of Sosibius son of Apollophanes, his mother being Ptollarous daughter of Chaeremon, inhabitants of Oxyrhynchus, acknowledges to Heraclas son of Heraclas son of Harthonis, his mother being Demetrous, also of Oxyrhynchus, in the street, that he, Stephanus, the contracting party, has become security for two loans which Heraclas lent from his own money through the record-office at the said city, the first being in the month of Mecheir of the 2nd year of Trajanus Caesar the lord to Rufus son of Diocles son of Diocles, his mother being Didyme daughter of Rufion, for 450 silver drachmae bearing interest secured upon a mortgage of the real property of Rufus stated in the loan, the second being in Tubi of the following 3rd year to Rufus’ full brother Diocles for 416 more silver drachmae upon a mortgage of his real property stated in the loan, which loans are in Heraclas’ possession, and Heraclas has the right...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
