<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 3, 513</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20644</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20644</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20644</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;513</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 3</note>
              Diogenes also called Dionysius, son of Sarapion son of Hermias, of the Phylaxithalassian tribe and Althaean deme, to Serenus son of Philiscus son of Sarapion, his mother being Helene, of Oxyrhynchus, greeting. Whereas I was assigned by Nemesianus, then strategus of the nome, in the 22nd year of Aurelius Commodus Antoninus Caesar the lord in the month Hadrianus from the unsold property of the Treasury a house, yard, and court with the fixtures, situated in the quarter of the Lycians’ Camp, previously owned by Sarapion, late ..., at 600 drachmae according to the valuation and the extra payments, and whereas I was registered by the basilico-grammateus of the nome, Pericles, as owing this sum together with the additional payments, making 637 drachmae 3 obols, and likewise for interest for the 22nd year 39 drachmae 3 1/2 obols 3 chalci, and as interest for the 23rd year 28 drachmae 2 1/2 obols, making a total of 68 drachmae 3 chalci for interest, and whereas I paid into the public bank for the price of the house in all 637 drachmae 3 obols and likewise for the interest debited to me the sum of 68 drachmae 3 chalci, the receipts for which payments with the signature of me, Diogenes also called Dionysius, I have delivered to you, Serenus, because you have made a higher bid for the aforesaid house and have raised the price to 1800 drachmae, and the property has been made over to you by a letter of his highness the dioecetes, Ventidius Rufinus ..., ex-strategus, in the present 24th year on Mecheir 30 for the 1800 drachmae and extra payments, and the basilico-grammateus has debited you in accordance with the supplementary note which he has issued, after reckoning the 600 drachmae paid by me, with the remaining 1200 drachmae and the additional payments: I acknowledge that in accordance with a communication of Epimachus who farms the bank at the Serapeum at Oxyrhynchus I have received from you the sums which I paid as aforesaid, for the price and the additional payments 637 drachmae 3 obols and for interest 68 drachmae 3 chalci, making a total of 705 drachmae 3 obols 3 chalci, and that I neither have nor will have any claim against you with regard to this or any other matter whatever up to the present day, and if any action is brought against you or your assigns with regard to this, I will take the responsibility upon myself. My father Sarapion son of Hermias son of Hermias, of the Sosicosmian tribe and Althaean deme, being present consents to the aforesaid. This receipt is valid. The 24th year of the Emperor Caesar Marcus Aurelius Commodus Antoninus Augustus Pius Armeniacus Medicus Parthicus Sarmaticus Germanicus Maximus ... I, Diogenes also called Dionysius, son of Sarapion, of the Phylaxithalassian tribe and Althaean deme, have received from Serenus the aforesaid total of 705 drachmae 3 obols 3 chalci in full, and I have no claim against him with regard to this or any other matter whatever, as aforesaid, and if any action is brought against him or his in connexion with this, I will take the responsibility upon myself. I, Serenus son of Philiscus son of Sarapion, my mother being Helene, consent to the aforesaid provisions and have received the receipts with your signature as aforesaid. I, Sarapion son of Hermias son of Hermias, of the Sosicosmian tribe and Althaean deme, consent to all the aforesaid porvisions. Epeiph 4, executed ...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
