<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 1, 37</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20699</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20699</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20699</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;1;37</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 1</note> From the minutes of Tiberius Claudius Pasion, strategus. The ninth year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, Pharmouthi 3. In court, Pesouris versus Saraeus. Aristocles, advocate for Pesouris, said :—"Pesouris, my client, in the seventh year of our sovereign Tiberius Claudius Caesar picked up from the gutter a boy foundling, named Heraclas. He put it in the defendant’s charge. This nurse was there for the son of Pesouris. She received her wages for the first year when they became due, she also received them for the second year. In proof of my assertions there are the documents in which she acknowledges receipt. The foundling was being starved, and Pesouris took it away. Thereupon Saraeus, waiting her opportunity, made an incursion into my client’s house and carried the foundling off. She now justifies its removal on the ground that it was free-born. I have here, firstly, the contract with the nurse; I have also, secondly, the receipt of the wages. I demand their recognition." Saraeus :—"I weaned my own child, and the foundling belonging to these people was placed in my charge. I received from them my full wages of 8 staters. Then the foundling died, and I was left with the money. They now wish to take away my own child." Theon :—"We have the papers relating to the foundling." The strategus:—" Since from its features the child appears to be that of Saraeus, if she and her husband will make a written declaration that the foundling entrusted to her by Pesouris died, I give judgement in accordance with the decision of our lord the praefect, that she have her own child on paying back the money she has received.” 
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
