<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 1, 57</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20719</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20719</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20719</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;1;57</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 1</note> Aurelius Apolinarius, strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, to his dear friend Apion, ex-strategus of the Antaeopolite nome, greeting. Dioscorus, strategus of the Antaeopolite nome, has sent me a despatch which has been delayed until Epeiph 13 of the past third year, explaining that Potamon, also called Sarapion, the collector of the nome, among the receipts of the revenue of the third year when you were in office, received towards the completion of the survey of the dykes and canals in the second year the sum of 3187 drachmae, 3 obols, which he did not pay over to the revenue office within the appointed time. Dioscorus now wishes me to ask that this should be refunded, and to credit it to the nome. In order therefore that you may be acquainted with these facts and lose no time in repaying the money in accordance with his letter....
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
