<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 1, 58</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20720</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20720</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20720</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;1;58</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 1</note> Servaeus Africanus to the strategi of the epistrategia of the Heptanomis and Arsinoite nome, greeting. The accounts have themselves proved that a number of persons wishing to swallow up the estates of the treasury have devised for themselves various titles, such as administrators, secretaries, or superintendents, by which means they secure no advantage to the treasury but swallow up its surplus. It has therefore become necessary to send you instructions to cause the election, on the responsibility of the several councils, of a single trustworthy superintendent over each estate, and to put an end to the other offices. The superintendent elected shall have the power to choose two or at most three other persons to assist him in his work. In this way useless expense will be stopped, and the estates of the treasury will receive proper attention. You will of course take care that only such persons are appointed to assist these superintendents as are in a position to stand the test.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
