<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 1, 91</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20750</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20750</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20750</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;1;91</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 1</note> Chosion, son of Sarapion, son of Harpocration, his mother being Sarapias, of Oxyrhynchus, to Tanenteris, daughter of Thonis, son of Thonis, her mother being Zoilous, of the same city, with her guardian Demetrius, son of Horion and Arsinoe, of the same city, greeting. I acknowledge the receipt from you through Heliodorus and his associate overseers of the bank at the Serapeum near the city of Oxyrhynchus, for which Epimachus made the promise of payment, of four hundred drachmae in imperial coin for wages, oil, clothes and all other expenses during the two years in which my slave Sarapias nursed your daughter Helena, known as her father’s child; who when you took her back had been weaned and had received every attention; and I acknowledge that I neither have nor shall have any complaint or charge to make against you either in connection with this transaction or any other matter whatever up to the present time. This receipt is valid.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
