<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 1, 98</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20757</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20757</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20757</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;1;98</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 1</note> Chaeremon, son of Theon, son of Theon, his mother being Totoeus, of Oxyrhynchus, to Archias, freedman of Amoitas, son of Zoilus, also of Oxyrhynchus, greeting. I acknowledge the receipt from you, through the bank of Heraclides and his partners at the Serapeum near the city of Oxyrhynchus, of a hundred and sixty-eight drachmae of silver, being the balance owing to me from you of the seven hundred drachmae of silver which I lent you by the terms of a contract executed through the bank in the month of Athyr in the twenty-second year of the deified Hadrian which is the first year of our sovereign Antoninus Caesar, the payment of the sum covering 50 months dating from the month Hadrianus of that same year at the rate of 15 drachmae each month. The present payment follows upon the instalment of the seven hundred drachmae, namely five hundred and thirty-two drachmae, which I previously received from you as I acknowledged in the written receipt which I gave you through the said bank in the month of Athyr of the past fourth year....
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
