<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 1, 99</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20758</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20758</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20758</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;1;99</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 1</note> Copy. The second year of Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, on the 6th of the month Audnaeus=Sebastus, at Oxyrhynchus in the Thebaid, before the agoranomi Andromachus and Diogenes. Tryphon, son of Dionysius, about ... years old, of middle height, fair, with a long face and a slight squint, and having a scar on his right wrist, has bought from his mother Thamounis’ cousin, Pnepheros, son of Papontos, also an inhabitant of Oxyrhynchus, about 65 years old, of middle height, fair, having a long face and a scar above his ... eyebrow and another on his right knee, (the document being drawn up in the street) one half of a three-storied house inherited from his mother, together with all its entrances and exits and appurtenances, situated by the Serapeum at Oxyrhynchus in the southern part of the street called Temgenouthis to the west of the lane leading to "Shepherds’ Street," its boundaries being, on the south and east, public roads, on the north, the house of the aforesaid Thamounis, mother of Tryphon the buyer, on the west, the house of Tausiris, sister of Pnepheros the seller, separated by a blind alley, for the sum of 32 talents of copper; and Pnepheros undertakes to guarantee the half share which is sold perpetually in every respect with every guarantee.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
