<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 1, 95</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20754</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20754</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20754</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;1;95</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 1</note> The 13th year of the Emperor Caesar Trajanus Hadrianus Augustus, Payni 29, at Oxyrhynchus in the Thebaid. Agathodaemon also called Dionysius, son of Dionysius, son of Dionysius, his mother being Hermione, of Oxyrhynchus, agrees with Gaius Julius Germanus, son of Gaius Julius Domitianus, (the agreement being executed in the street) that he hereby assents to the autograph contract, made on Tybi 25 of the present 13th year, for the sale to Julius Germanus of a slave named Dioscorous, about 25 years old, with no distinguishing marks, which slave was his by purchase, having previously belonged to Heraclides also called Theon, son of Machon, son of Sosicosmius also called Althaeeus. This slave Julius Germanus then took from him just as she was, free from blemish except epilepsy and marks of punishment (?), at the price of 1200 drachmae of silver, which sum Agathodaemon also called Dionysius thereupon received from Julius Germanus in full together with the autograph contract. In consequence of this contract Julius Germanus paid the tax upon the sale of the said slave Dioscorous on Phamenoth 3 of the same year, in accordance with the receipt issued to him. Agathodaemon also called Dionysius is the guarantor of the said slave Dioscorous in all respects, as the autograph contract states. If the terms of it should be broken or it in any other way be rendered invalid, Julius Germanus has the right to demand...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
