<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 1, 105</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20764</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20764</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20764</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;1;105</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 1</note> The ... year of the Emperor Trajanus Hadrianus Augustus, Tybi 13, at Oxyrhynchus in the Thebaid; for good luck.
               This is the will, made in the street, of Pekusis, son of Hermes and Didyme, daughter of Philotas, an inhabitant of Oxyrhynchus, being sane and in his right mind. So long as I survive, O am to have power over my property, to ... and to alter my will. But if I die with this will unchanged, I leave my daughter Ammonous whose mother is Ptolema, if she survive me, but if not, then her children, heir to my shares in the common house, court and rooms situated in the Cretan quarter. All the furniture, movables and household stock and other property whatsoever that I shall leave, I bequeath to the mother of my children and my wife, Ptolema, the freedwoman of Demetrius, son of Hermippus, with the condition that she shall have for her lifetime the right of using, dwelling in, and building in the said house, court and rooms. If Ammonous should die without children and intestate, the share of the fixtures shall belong to her half-brother on the mother’s side, Antas, if he survive, but if not, to.... No one shall violate the terms of this my will under pain of paying to my daughter and heir Ammonous a fine of 1000 drachmae and (to the treasury an equal sum?) [There follow the signatures of the testator and witnesses.]
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
