<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 1, 125</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20769</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20769</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20769</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;1;125</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 1</note> In the 34th year of the reign of our most godly and pious sovereign Fl. Justinian, eternal Augustus and Imperator, which is the 19th year after the consulship of FI. Basilius the most illustrious, Choiak the 17th, the 9th indiction. To his worshipful lordship the superintendent of the public treasury-office of this city of Oxyrhynchus, the son of the sainted Abraham of the illustrious city of Oxyrhynchus, from Aurelius Pambechis, son of the sainted Menas and Maxima, whose own signature follows, of the same city, greeting. Whereas I presented an appeal to your worship to become my surety with the most illustrious Apphouas, assistant of the village of Sephtha, if he accepted me as his deputy for one year reckoned from the present month Choiak of the current 237th=the 206th year, and of the present 9th indiction, and whereas your worship did this in accordance with my request, your worship at the same time made the reasonable demand to receive from me a written agreement proper to such an appeal. I have accordingly been constrained to enter upon the present appellant’s agreement, wherein I agree not to permit your worship to suffer any damage, loss, annoyance, or trouble on my account in this connexion, whether in court or out of court, but on the contrary to guarantee you against annoyance, trouble, loss and damage. But if the contingency which I deprecate should occur, and your worship should suffer loss or annoyance or trouble, or I should permit you to be reminded of your suretyship for me by any person whatsoever, you are to have the power to distrain upon all my property, personal and real, until you have received satisfaction. To all this I swear the oath by Heaven and the Emperor, that I will abide by and observe these conditions and will in no wise break them; and I pledge for the observance of this appellant's agreement my property present and future, whether held by myself or my family......
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
