<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 1, 136</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20775</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20775</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20775</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;1;136</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 1</note> The terms of the agreement are (11 sqq.):—
               I, Serenus, deacon, principal party to the contract, of my own free will and deliberate choice agree that I have made a contract with your magnificence through your representatives for one year reckoned from the arrears of money payments of the present first indiction and that of the crops and money payments and revenues of the coming (D.V.) second indiction; in which contract I undertake to fill the post of your administrator or steward in the management of the estate of Matreus and your property in and adjacent to the villages of Episemus and Adaeus. I undertake to conduct my dealings with the labourers responsible to me both upon the estate and in the villages and adjacent property in accordance with the requirements notified to me by the worshipful secretaries of your honoured house, so as to collect and pay to your magnificence or to your representatives all that is due, namely, the corn to the official controller of the boats of your honoured house and the money to the most illustrious banker of your said honoured house, in correspondence with the receipts and cheques issued by me to all the labourers under my charge, and in agreement with the performance of my duties and the method of collection adopted by me. And if any deficiency (?) should occur on the estates aforesaid, I am to make it good and it shall be credited to your magnificence in my accounts; and I will gain and collect and pay to the aforesaid owner’s account all the dues in full from the outlying properties. I agree further to gain for your magnificence, as compensation for the measure used in receiving payments, fifteen extra artabae on every hundred. I have also contracted and agreed to give to the honoured house of your magnificence the twelve Alexandrian solidi usually paid as a consideration for the said administration; and to accept the same amount of victuals as the administrator before me. I will render accounts of all my stewardship both of receipt and expenditure and I will make up deficiencies when the accounts are balanced if the comparison of my receipts and cheques as aforesaid shows me to be in arrears. I, Victor, surety, do further agree to become surety and bail for the aforesaid Serenus, deacon and administrator, in the discharge and fulfilment of his steward- ship; and if he is shown to be in arrears in comparison with his cheques and receipts, to discharge the debt and satisfy your magnificence out of my own private means, renouncing the privilege of sureties, and contrary to the new ordinance issued about sureties and persons accepting responsibility. We both pledge for the observance of this contract all our property present and future, whether held by ourselves or our families, to be security and to serve as a pledge. The contract, of which two copies are made, is valid, and in teply to the formal question we have given our consent. (Signatures.)
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
