<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 1, 135</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20774</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20774</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20774</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;1;135</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 1</note> In the 4th year of the reign of our most godly and pious sovereign and greatest benefactor Fl. Tiberius Constantinus, eternal Augustus and Imperator, Phamenoth 25, 12th indiction.
               To the most magnificent heirs of Apion, of glorious memory, patrician, landholders in this illustrious city of Oxyrhynchus, through Menas their servant who is acting on their behalf and assuming for his masters, the said all-esteemed persons, the conduct and responsibility of the transaction, from Aurelius Pamouthius, lead-worker, son of George and Anniana, coming from the city of Oxyrhynchus. I agree of my own free will and with the oath by Heaven and the Emperor to be surety and pledge to your magnificence, through your representatives, for Aurelius Abraham, son of Herminus and Herais, who comes from the estate Great Tarouthinus belonging to your magnificence in the Oxyrhynchite nome, and is entered as your labourer. I engage that he shall continually abide and stay on his holding along with his friends and wife and herds and all his possessions, and be responsible for all that regards his person or the fortunes of him who has been entered as a cultivator; and that he shall in no wise leave his holding or remove to another place, and if he is required of me by your magnificence through your representatives at any date or for any reason whatsoever, I will bring him forward and produce him in a public place without any attempt at flight or excuse, in the keeping of your same honoured house just as he is now when I become his surety. If I do not do this I agree to forfeit for his non-appearance and my failure to produce him 8 gold solidi, actual payment of which is to be enforced. This pledge, of which only this copy is made, is valid, and in answer to the formal question I have given by assent.
               Executed by me, Anastasius.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
