<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 1, 138</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20777</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20777</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20777</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;1;138</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 1</note> In the name of the Lord and Master, Jesus Christ, our God and Saviour, in the first year of the reign of our most godly and pious sovereign and greatest benefactor, Flavius Heraclius, eternal Augustus and Imperator, ..., 14th indiction, year 287=256.
               To Flavius Apion the all-honoured and most magnificent, of consular rank and patrician, landowner at this illustrious city of Oxyrhynchus, through Menas his servant who is acting on his behalf and assuming for his master, the said all-honoured Apion, the conduct and responsibility of the transaction, from John, by the help of God contractor of the racecourse belonging to your honourable house, and of the stable belonging to your said honourable house, son of the sainted Theodorus, coming from the city of Oxyrhynchus. I make the following contract.
               Wishing to take charge of the stable belonging to your honoured house in addition to the racecourse which is under my care, for one year reckoned from Choiak 1g in the present 14th indiction to Choiak 15 in the (D.V.) approaching 15th indiction, I proposed to your magnificence through your representatives that your magnificence should entrust the stable to my care. The representatives of your magnificence accordingly allowed me the charge of it for the one year aforesaid reckoned from Choiak 15 in the present 14th indiction. I agree to undertake this duty and all the services that may arise in connexion with the estate, and to find mounts for the noble superintendents and the most illustrious secretaries and the servants who depart on any service whatsoever connected with the estate, and to give no cause for dissatisfaction, all this being undertaken unequivocally at the risk of myself and my property; and I accept as payment for the said duties for which I have contracted during the year one pound of gold according to the standard of Alexandria, undertaking for my part, as aforesaid, to perform all the duties attaching to the aforesaid stable, and to provide animals for the needs of the estate, at the risk of myself and my property, as is aforesaid, and to find mounts for the noble superintendents and the most illustrious secretaries and the servants who depart, as aforesaid, on service connected with the estate. To all this I swear by Almighty God and by the supremacy salvation and preservation of our most pious sovereigns, Flavius Heraclius and Aelia Flavia, that I will abide by and observe these conditions andin nowise break them; and I pledge for the observance of this contract all my property, [etc.]
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
