<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Fam.Tebt. 33</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">20962</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20962</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20962</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.fam.tebt;;33</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2020-10-02T11:03:24-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2020-07-09T05:55:39-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ok</change>
         <change when="2019-07-26T08:10:15-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/WesselvanDuijn">Submit - Translation added</change>
         <change when="2019-07-26T08:08:40-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/WesselvanDuijn">Commit - Translation added</change>
         <change when="2019-07-26T05:13:08-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               [Translation from P. L. Bat. 6] To ---, nomarch of Antinoopolis, from Lysimachos also called Didymos son of Herakleides, of the Matidian tribe and Callitecnian deme, living in his own house in the alpha quarter, 7th block. Petronius Mamertinus, former prefect, made known to us the benefits granted to us by the deified Hadrianus, the founder of our city, by which he directed that the children of Antinoites <milestone n="5" unit="line"/>who are returned by us, their parents, within thirty days of their birth should be maintained from the proceeds of funds granted by him for this purpose and from other revenues. I therefore return the son born to me, Herakleides also called Valerius, twenty days old, by my wife Ninnarous daughter of Orsenouphis, Antinoite, the fee for whose aparche I paid through the most excellent senate, furnishing three guarantors of the marriage and the parentage, Lysanias son of Didymos, of the Matidian tribe and Plotinian deme, <milestone n="10" unit="line"/>Didymos son of Didymos, of the Matidian tribe and Callitecnian deme, and Ptolemaios son of Herakleides, of the Osirantinoan tribe and Clitorian deme. And I swear by the Fortune of Imperator Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrianus Antonius Augustus Pius and the most great god Osirantinous that the foregoing particulars are true, or may I be subject to the consequences of the oath. (Date and subscriptions of the father and the guarantors). [Bell]. 
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
