<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>PSI 4, 423</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">2106</idno>
            <idno type="TM">2106</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">2106</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">psi;4;423</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-07-18T17:35:43-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 256)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T17:33:13-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 256)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T17:32:32-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 256)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T17:29:27-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Commit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 256)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T17:23:58-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> To Zenon, greetings, Horos the stonecutter. Herieus reports concerning the desmôtai, from the second of Phaophi until the tenth of Choiak, 
that each man has worked 2 cubic cubits every day, there being 10 men in all, so that within each month 600 cubic cubits have been worked and 
within the 2-month period 1200 have been worked and over the course of 8 days 160 have been worked. The total of cubic cubits worked is 1360. 
If it seems best to you, send someone who will make a measurement, for there are 130 who have not yet worked. And know that we have received 
the contract for the excavation of the mine-shafts, so that we may work. But Herieus, after receiving grain from you for the work, has not worked, 
but… the workers (?)…. And the channels for which we received the contract, (at a cost of) 2.5 obols per 5 aôilia of rock and 1.5 obols for those 
transporting 10 aôilia of rock, these I have completed at a cost of 2 obols and 1 obol, respectively. For I have workers here with me, so that the 
work was completed very quickly. And we have worked the royal stone from the rock toward the south at a cost of one obol, and we have received 
nothing for it. Therefore you would do well, if it seems best to you, to please give us some grain, so that we may be able to keep working until you 
make an examination about these maters. Farewell.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="37" unit="line"/> Memorandum from Horos the stonecutter concerning the desmôtai working the aôilia and concerning the mine-shafts.
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 256)
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
