<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 9, 1191</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21578</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21578</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21578</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;9;1191</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-10" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 9</note>
              Aurelius Ammonius to the strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, greeting. In accordance with the orders of his highness my lord the most honourable praefect Hadrianius Sallustius concerning the election of administrators, on every occasion when instructions are issued concerning them do not neglect to take the subscription signifying concurrence of the secretary, in accordance with the orders concerning this. I pray for your lasting health. The sixth year, Hathur II.
              Aurelius Olympius, ex-hypomnematographus, strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, to..., secretary, greeting. A copy is sent to you of the letter which we have received from his excellency Aurelius Ammonius concerning the election of administrators in accordance with the order of his highness my lord the most honourable praefect Hadrianius Sallustius, directing the office of the strategus, on every occasion when instructions are issued by the most high senate concerning the administrators, not to neglect to take your subscription signifying concurrence, as ordered, so that you may be informed and keep the order in view. I pray for your health. The sixth year of our lord Marcus Aurelius Probus Augustus ...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
