<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 9, 1185</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21573</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21573</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21573</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;9;1185</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-10" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 9</note>
              To Magnius Felix Crescentillianus, praefect of Egypt, supplication from Ammonion also called...
              Magnius Felix to the strategi of the Heptanomia, greeting. I have assigned to the most high epistrategi the appeals concerning the offices of gymnasiarch and agoranomus, and an edict has been published concerning this in the most illustrious city of Alexandria.
              A little boy must eat bread, nibble besides some salt, and not touch the sauce; but if he asks for wine, give him your knuckles.
              Greeting, lady Diogenis, I, Ammonion, address
              you.
              Magnius Felix to the strategi of the Heptanomia
              and the Arsinoite nome, greeting. I would have you know that the most divine sovereigns granted to me the money from the so-called eight-drachma tax, and you have not yet up to the present made any payment. If then the centurions are in your districts for long, let them attend with speed at the most illustrious city of the Alexandrians and celebrate
              thefestivalofthesovereign. Otherwise, if any one disobeys this my order...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
