<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 9, 1199</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21584</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21584</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21584</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;9;1199</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-10" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 9</note>
              To ..., ex-gymnasiarch of the most illustrious city of Oxyrhynchus, and his associate, keepers of the archives, from Aurelia Julia Harpocratiaena daughter of Theon also called Asclepiades surnamed Zoilus, her mother being Tatreiphis, of the most illustrious city of Oxyrhynchus, acting in virtue of her children. I have bought in accordance with an autograph deed of sale made in the present seventh year, Hathur 2, from Aurelia Theonis daughter of Theon also called Zoilus, ex-exegetes of the most illustrious city of Alexandria and however he was styled, likewise acting in virtue of her children, her mother being Ptolema, of the same city, the house belonging to her by right of inheritance and formerly the property of her said father Theon son of Zoilus, situated in the same city in the quarter of the South Square with frontage (?) and cellar beneath and all appurtenances as contained in the autograph deed of sale; which having been deposed to by me through the local record-office in the month Hathur of the same seventh year, I bring before you a single copy with the subscription of the tax-farmer and present this memorandum in order that the proper entry may be made; and I declare that the said Theonis registered the aforesaid property ...’
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
