<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 9, 1203</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21589</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21589</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21589</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;9;1203</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-10" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 9</note>
              ... [not only] ... but also ... ventured wrongfully [without our knowledge ?] to alienate at Alexandria the security to Philostratus son of Zoilus, to whom with your just concurrence we presented through you a notification concerning his improper purchase. In addition to this the said Leonides, heedless of the reckoning that would follow, provided himself with a memorandum from the bureau to the collector of external debts here on the plea of other sums being due to him from our father, whereas on the contrary he was our debtor, as stated above, and served upon us a copy of this through his son Apion on the fourteenth of the present month Epeiph. Wherefore we perforce come forward with the request that this memorandum should be duly placed on record, and that a copy of it be served through an attendant both upon Apion on his father’s account and upon the collector of external debts, in order that Apion may know that everything that has been done by his father Leonides to our hurt is invalid and that our claim holds good against Leonides on al the counts that we have against him, and that the collector of external debts may take no step against us in consequence of the aforesaid memorandum before the trial of the case. For we maintain and shall maintain all our subsisting rights. (Endorsed) I, Theon son of Onnophris, assistant, have duly presented a copy of the above memorandum to the collector of external debts.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
