<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 9, 1208</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21594</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21594</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21594</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;9;1208</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-10" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 9</note>
              The seventh year of the Emperor Caesar Gaius Aurelius Valerius Diocletianus and the sixth year of the Emperor Caesar Marcus Aurelius Valerius Maximianus Germanici Maximi Pii Felices Augusti, Xandicus-Mecheir, in the illustrious and most illustrious city of Oxyrhynchus, before Aurelius Agathinus also called Origenes, farmer of the tax payabie to the agoranomi and recorders. Aurelia Thermouthion surnamed Tanechotis, daughter of Nepheros and Tanechotis, of the village of Pakerke in the eastern toparchy, being not yet of age and acting through her father Aurelius Nepheros son of Dionysius, of the said village, acknowledges, in the street, that she hereby deposes at her own valuation to the autograph deed of sale formerly agreed to with her by Aurelius Thonius son of Thonis, of the illustrious and most illustrious city of Oxyrhynchus, and drawn up in the past year on the 11th of the month Epeiph, of which she, the acknowledging party, presented a single authentic copy to the keeper of the record office to be deposited in the local archives. of which the following is a copy.
              Aurelius Thonius son of Thonis and Artemidora, of the illustrious and most illustrious city of Oxyrhynchus, with his father, who has him under power according to Roman law, as co-guarantor, namely Aurelius Thonius son of Serenus and Isarous, of the said city, to Aurelia Thermouthion surnamed Tanechotis, daughter of Nepheros and Tanechotis, of the village of Pakerke in the eastern toparchy, being not yet of age and acting through her father Aurelius Nepheros son of Dionysius, of the said village, greeting. I acknowledge that I have sold and ceded to you from henceforth for ever my property by right of inheritance and formerly belonging to my aforesaid mother Aurelia Artemidora daughter of Pausiris and Iseis, of the said city, who died leaving me and my brothers, namely my full brother Aurelius Demetrius and my half-brothers on my mother’s side, Aurelius Diogenes, Aurelius Isidorus, and Aurelius Iseis, her three children by Hermias, the five of us, her sons and heirs, which was hers by right of inheritance, having formerly belonged to her father Aurelius Pausiris son of Dionysius and Artemidora, of the said city, in accordance with the will left by him in the second year of Claudius which was the first year of Aurelian, the ... of the month Tubi, and opened after his death, and had been bought by the father of Pausiris, Aurelius Herammon son of Pausanias also called Eutychus, his mother being Hermione, of the said city, in accordance with an autograph sale and cession drawn up in the rath vear of Gallienus, Pachon 23, at the village of Pakerke in the eastern toparchy, in the holding of ... with that of Epanthes, the fifth part of four arable arourae of private land, that is 4/5 of an aroura, forming part of a parcel of 8 arourae held jointly with Horion son of Acrono..., which themselves formed part of a total of 28 arourae, or thereabouts, containing irrigators and a machine fitted with al wood-work and iron-work, together with the proportionate share of the irrigators and machine, the boundaries being on the south a road and on the other three sides a canal, at the price and cession-value agreed upon between us for the fifth part of the aforesaid four arourae of private land and irrigators and machine, namely 9,000 drachmae of the Imperial silver coinage, that is one talent 3,000 drachmae of silver, which I have forthwith received from you through your said father from hand to hand in ful, and for which the land is bestowed upon you as a present and gift unchangeable and irrevocable, and to your question whether I have counted the money in full with the concurrence and assistance of my father I have given my assent. You shall therefore possess and own with your descendants and successors the fifth part sold and ceded to you by me as aforesaid of the four arable arourae of private land and the share of the irrigators and machine, and shall have power to use and dispose of it as you choose, no right of proceeding against it or any part of it in any wise being left to me nor to any one else on my behalf, and I will of necessity deliver it to you guaranteed perpetually against al claims with every guarantee, free from cultivation of royal or domain land and from every impost and debt and lien public and private, and from municipal ... and every other impost and from construction and ... of dykes and from public dues and requisitions and contri- butions paid for other purposes of every kind up to and including the present 6th and 5th year, because from the coming 7th and 6th year the proceeds of this property are yours who are purchasing it and having it ceded to you, and who are to be responsible for the public dues and al requisitions from the end of the present 6th and 5th year. And every one who in any manner proceeds against or claims this property, whether the whole or a part of it, 1 will of necessity and at once repel at my own cost, as if in consequence of a legal decision. This sale and cession, of which three copies are made, is valid, and you shall whenever you choose make it public without requiring any further approval from me, because I now approve the eventual publication, and to your question made through your father whether this is rightly and fairly done we have given our assent. <note>Date and signatures of the parties to the contract and of Agathinus, the official of the record office.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
