<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 9, 1223</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21597</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21597</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21597</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;9;1223</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-10" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 9</note>
              To my lord and brother Horion from Hermias. I am surprised if my messenger finds the boat of the landlord with you; if, however, owing to some carelessness he finds it there, make haste to send the sailor to the city at once with the attendant whom I have sent. See that you do not neglect this. If it is calm weather and he cannot bring back the boat today, let the sailor himself return in order to make a bond, for I am being worried not a little. If you neglect it, our house is likely, owing to the absence of the landlord, to be brought to a critical pass through the tiresome Ammonius the speculator and the praefect’s assistant. If you have any silver coins with you or solidi, send me them quickly, for I owe on account of so many obligations and I am no longer trusted, unless I behave fairly. Send and tell your people to hand over to me the remainder of the wine and one and a half units of the general account. The solidus now stands at 2,020 myriads; it has come down. Do not neglect to send the boat or the sailor today. I pray for your lasting health, brother. (Addressed) To my lord and brother Horion from Hermias.’
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
