<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 9, 1209</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21595</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21595</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21595</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;9;1209</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-10" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 9</note>
              The ... year of the Emperors and Caesars Gaius Vibius Trebonianus Gallus and Gaius Vibius Aphinius Gallus Veldumianus Volusianus Pii Felices Augusti, Daisius Pharmouthi, at the city of Oxyrhynchus, before Aurelius Antipater also called Dionysius, farmer of the tax payable to the agoranomi. Aurelius Asclepiades also called Saras, son of Sarapion and Lucilla also called Demetria, of the city of Oxyrhynchus, aged about 32, with no distinguishing mark, has purchased from Aurelius Serenus also called Sarapion, son of Agathinus and Taposiris, of the said city, aged about 34, with no distinguishing mark, in the street, the female slave belonging to him named Tereus, aged about 21, fair, with a scar on her ..., together with her male nursling child named ..., who was purchased by him in accordance with a deed made through the said office of the agoranomi in the 4th year of the Philippi in the month Phamenoth from the mother of the present purchaser Aurelia Lucilla also called Demetria, daughter of Euporus son of Diogenes, her mother being Tauris also called Philumene, of the said city, and was born in her house, which slave together with the nursling the purchaser has forthwith received from the vendor just as they are and unrenounceable, free from epilepsy and external claims, Tereus having been examined as set forth in the former deed; and the price mutually agreed upon for the said slave and the nursling, 2,000 drachmae of silver of the Imperial coinage, has been received by the vendor Aurelius Sarapion also called Serenus from the purchaser Aurelius Asclepiades also called Saras from hand to hand. The vendor sells and guarantees the said slave with the nursling [on the liability of al that stands in (?) his name, as aforesaid, in the same street. and to the purchaser’s question whether this has been rightly and fairly done the vendor has given his assent. <note>Signatures.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
