<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 8, 1102</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21727</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21727</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21727</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;8;1102</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-31" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 8</note>
              Copy of a judgement. ... year, Hathur 21. ... and ... and their associates and Eudaemon and ... being present, Cerealis, priest and recorder, having considered with those in attendance dictated a judgement which was read out as follows :— “In accordance with the decision of the most high and gracious praefect Valerius Proculus, I think it right that Eudaemon, without taking any of his brother’s property, having once entered on the inheritance, should contribute the fourth part of the estate to his native city for the gymnasiarchy, with a deduction of the dowry previously given to the daughter. With regard to the amount, seeing that in answer to my question he made no clear statement, the strategus of the nome shall hold a more exact inquiry in the place where he lives, and if the ... arourae appear not to come under the testamentary covenant according: to the laws and the decisions read to me, ... these arourae shall go to the city. With regard to the furniture and young slaves, a decision has been given by Neocydes, ex-juridicus.” The delegates having requested to remain in possession of the income of the arourae, the priest and recorder said: “The city shall receive the income of one year.” On Eudaemon’s declaring through his companions that his income had been impounded, and requesting that it should be released, the priest and recorder said: “As soon as my orders have been carried out, and the city has received its proper share, it shall be released.” The delegates having made a request for delay and also concerning the property standing in the name of the wife of Apollonius, the priest and recorder said: “Neocydes has delivered judgement ... about this. Sarapion, assistant of the praefect, Trogodyte, went out. Read by me.”
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
