<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 8, 1104</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21729</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21729</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21729</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;8;1104</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-31" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 8</note>
              The sixth consulship of our lords the Emperors Constantius and Maximianus. To his dearest Aurelius Seuthis, also called Horion, logistes of the Oxyrhynchite nome, from Aurelius Hieracion also called Noninus, ex-gymnasiarch, ex-prytanis, senator, prytanis in office of the illustrious and most illustrious city of Oxyrhynchus, greeting. I request that orders may now be given to pay me out of the city’s funds from the sums publicly apportioned ... to be used for the expenses in accordance with the letters of his highness my lord the praefect Clodius Culcianus which I lately handed to you ... a further sum of fifty talents and four hundred and fifty denarii of silver, total 50 tal. 450 den. I think it right that the curator of the civic chest should be sent to make this payment to me, so that there may be no obstruction to the interests of the public baths or to the other interests of my prytany. I pray for your health, dearest friend. <note>Date by the regnal years of the emperors, and declaration of the curator (?) that he had paid over the money and obtained a receipt.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
