<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 8, 1114</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21736</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21736</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21736</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;8;1114</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-31" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 8</note>
              In the consulship of Perpetuus and Cornelianus, in the third year of the emperor Caesar Gaius Julius Verus Maximinus, etc., before Geminius Valens ... of the procuratorship. Marcus Aurelius Saras, ex-gymnasiarch, senator of the city of Oxyrhynchus, son of Marcus Aurelius Diogenes also called Heliodorus, ex-eutheniarch of the most illustrious city of Alexandria, declare [on behalf of(?)] my two daughters Aurelia Stratonice also called Sosipatra and Aurelia Apollonia also called Dieus the inheritance or possession of the property of Aurelia Apollonia daughter of Marcus Aurelius Apollonius son of Demetrius also called Psammis, ex-gymnasiarch and senator of the city of Oxyrhynchus, their mother and my wife, who died intestate at the city of Oxyrhynchus on the day before the succeeding (?) Nones of July at the third hour of the day according to the affidavit made on this matter, of which I append a copy, and certify that the inheritance is of the value of two hundred solidi and free of the tax of a twentieth.
              Copy of the affidavit. In the third year, etc., at the city of Oxyrhynchus. Marcus Aurelius Saras, ex-gymnasiarch and senator of the city of Oxyrhynchus, son of Marcus Aurelius Diogenes also called Heliodorus, ex-eutheniarch and senator of the most illustrious city of Alexandria, and however he is styled, called to witness the persons about to seal the present affidavit that on this day at about the third hour to the loss of our hopes Aurelia Apollonia daughter of Marcus Aurelius Apollonius son of Demetrius also called Psammis, and however he is styled, ex-gymnasiarch and senator of the city of Oxyrhynchus, his wife and the mother of their daughters Aurelia Stratonice also called Sosipatra and Aurelia Apollonia also called Dieus, who are under age, died intestate... <note>Signatures of witnesses and of Marcus Aurelius Saras in Greek and of a notary in Latin.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
