<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 8, 1113</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21735</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21735</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21735</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;8;1113</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-31" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 8</note>
              To the comogrammateus of Sento and other villages in the middle toparchy from Didymus also called Didymion, ex-chief-priest of the most august temple of Hadrian in the city of Oxyrhynchus, and from Diogenes and Sarapion also called Aristocles, both sons of Sarapion and Aristocleia also called Chaeremonis, of the said city. In accordance with the orders of his highness the procurator Claudius Diognetus we register for the current 11th year the unwatered land belonging to us at Sento in the holding of Cleandrus with the adjacent ground standing in the name of (?) Dionysius son of Apion, namely 1/4 arourae of land previously unwatered. <note>Date.</note>
              From Sarapion also called Phanias, ex-gymnasiarch of the city of Oxyrhynchus, and however he is styled, of the city of Oxyrhynchus. In accordance with the orders of his highness the Imperial procurator Claudius Diognetus I register for the 11th year at the village of Psobthis in the middle toparchy in the holding of Philonicus, once belonging to my mother and formerly in the possession of A... son of ... nuptas, .. arourae of unwatered land out of 4 1/12 arourae, and I swear by the fortune of Lucius Septimius Severus Pius Pertinax and Marcus Aurelius Antoninus Pius Augusti and Publius Septimius Geta Caesar Augustus that I have made no false statement. <note>Date.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
