<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 8, 1115</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21737</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21737</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21737</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;8;1115</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-31" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 8</note>
              To Aurelius Philiarchus also called Horion, strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, from Aurelius Isidorus, Aurelius Asclepiades, and Aurelius Plutinus, deliverers of bread. Having been asked by you in consequence of letters sent to you by his honour the praefect Pomponius Januarianus and his honour the dioecetes Aurelius Aristeas for the authentic receipt in our possession for the bread which we have delivered and distributed, we deliver to you the aforesaid authentic receipt and a copy of it which we beg you to sign in order that we too may have the security of the said authentic receipt. “Miccalus, superintendent of the distribution of the annona, to Isidorus and Asclepiades, overseers of the Oxyrhynchite nome. You have delivered in Panopolis in obedience to the order of his highness the dioecetes Aurelius Aristeas, in accordance with the certificates presented by you, to the mobilized (?) soldiers and sailors thirty-eight thousand and four hundred and ninety-six modii(?) of bread, total 38,496. The sixth year of our lord the Emperor Caesar Marcus Aurelius Probus Pius Augustus, Tubi sixteenth, Tubi 16.” (Signed) I, Aurelius Philiarchus also called Horion, strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, have received the authentic receipt, which agrees with the copy above written, and have forwarded it as ordered. Second year, Pachon 26.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
