<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 8, 1121</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21741</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21741</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21741</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;8;1121</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-31" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 8</note>
              In the consulship of the present consuls. To Aurelius Ammonius, beneficiarius of the praefect of Egypt, from Aurelia Techosis daughter of Diodorus and Techosis, of the Small Oasis, now living at the illustrious and most illustrious city of Oxyrhynchus. No small danger and no ordinary severity awaits those who lightly give themselves over to plunder and robbery of the property of others. I therefore, being the victim of a most outrageous attack and robbery, approach you to testify to the assault upon me. Techosis, my aforesaid mother, was stricken with illness, and I in the goodness of my heart nursed and tended her and was assiduous in performing what is owing from children to parents. When a few days ago she died intestate, leaving me her daughter heir in accordance with the law, I provided for her funeral and did all that was fitting on the occasion of her death. While I was occupied with my trouble, I know not on what ground or with what impulse, a certain Sotas and Papontos, who are my neighbours in the same house where my mother lived, possessing themselves of the extensive movables left by her, a considerable amount of gold, a quantity of furniture, some very valuable clothes, and other things, lawlessly carried them all off, on what inducement I cannot tell. I am about to demand satisfaction for this of the superior official, and in order that they may put in an appearance I perforce present this petition, testifying to the assault and requesting that they may be compelled to provide written security that they will stay and appear, since I am already having recourse to the official, and that a copy of this document be prepared through your grace for the praefect’s office. <note>Date and signature of Aurelia Techosis, written for her by Aurelius Agathodaemon.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
