<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 8, 1127</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21745</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21745</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21745</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;8;1127</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-31" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 8</note>
              Apollonius son of Sosus son of Sosus, of the city of Oxyrhynchus, has let to Publius Vettius Diogenes for four years from the first day of Thoth of the coming 24th year the upper room of the house belonging to him at Mouchinor and the pigeon-house there with its wooden ladder at an annual rent and revenue of 60 drachmae of silver free of all risk. The lease being guaranteed, the lessee shall use the room and the pigeon-house for the four years without hindrance, and shall pay the rent annually in two half-yearly instalments of 30 drachmae, and at the end of the term shall return the said room and the pigeon-house in the condition in which he receives them and the two doors and one key attached, or shall pay the value of anything that he does not restore, and shall forfeit one and a half times the amount of any sum owing, right of execution lying against him and all his property. This lease is valid. <note>Date and signature of Publius Vettius Diogenes.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
