<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 8, 1119</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21740</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21740</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21740</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;8;1119</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-31" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 8</note>
              ..., strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, to Aurelius Heras, phylarch for the coming fourth year. I send you the petition of Aurelius Theon and Aurelius Arsinotis, both sons of Theon, Antinoites of the Sebasteian tribe and Dioscureian deme, enclosed in which are copies of two letters, one written by the most high senate of the Antinoïtes to Antonius Alexander the most high epistrategus, the other by the said epistrategpus to the then strategus, and also a copy of the reply made by the then amphodogrammateus. The third year of the Emperors and Caesars Gaius Vibius Trebonianus Gallus and Gaius Vibius Afinius Gallus Veldumianus Volusianus Pii Felices Augusti, Mesore 23.
              To ..., strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, from Aurelius Theon and Aurelius Arsinotis, sons of Theon, Antinoïtes of the Sebasteian tribe and Dioscureian deme. In the previous cycle of the persons about to serve in the quarters of this city, the amphodogrammateus then in office, Aurelius Sarapion, [ignoring our rights,] in the list of burdens submitted by him returned us for the collection of money-taxes in the metropolis, and we immediately on receiving information of it ... did not acquiesce but applied to the most high senate, recounting the audacity and illegality of the said amphodogrammateus, The senate was indignant and sent to the most high epistrategus Antonius Alexander, who, heedful of the rights especially accorded to our native city, sent to the then strategus Aurelius Dius also called Pertinax directing that the amphodogrammateus should be compelled either to present some other persons instead of us for the office, or [to pay the penalty for] his illegality. The strategus sent the whole correspondence to the amphodogrammateus, and he, being aware of the danger hanging over him in consequence of his
              illegal action ..., himself promised in amends for his error, for which he pleaded the excuse of ignorance, to undertake the burden for the future. Now, therefore, in order that the present phylarch may not appear to be ignorant of these facts ... because one of us, Aurelius Theon, is there in our native city attending to the duties to which we have been assigned, since the turn has come to our senate in the present year to ..., we submit to you the following copies, begging that they may be communicated for his information by means of one of your assistants to Aurelius Heras, phylarch of the quarters about to serve. The third year of the Emperors and Caesars Gaius Vibius Trebonianus Gallus and Gaius Vibius Afinius Gallus Veldumianus Volusianus Pii Felices Augusti, Mesore. The copies are as follows :—
              The officials and senate of the illustrious city of the Antinoites, new Hellenes, to Antonius Alexander the most high epistrategus, greeting. You are aware, highest of procurators, you who during your procuratorship have been especially concerned with the exceptional rights claimed by our native city, that originally the deified Hadrian ... [distinguishing] it from the other cities in Egypt clearly established the law that we should bear office and burdens nowhere but at home, and we were relieved of all offices and burdens elsewhere; and next ... his successors on the throne often confirmed our immunity in this respect, and they have been scrupulously followed by the praefects appointed from time to time and by you the most high epistrategi, who not only release us from all external offices and burdens but also punish the lawlessness of those who attempt to offend against the Imperial legislation and the judgements of praefects. Whereas, then, Aurelius Theon and Aurelius Arsinotis ... our fellow-citizens have approached us in a petition accusing Sarapion, amphodogrammateus of the city of Oxyrhynchus, of having illegally nominated them both for the collection of money-taxes in the metropolis, ... we apply to your heedfulness in order that you may direct the strategus of the said nome to have one of two things done, namely that the amphodogrammateus, if he gives way, should nominate to the office other persons in their stead, or else [be compelled to] appear before you at your coming auspicious visit, in order that in accordance with the ancestral usages of our constitution he may render an account for his outrage upon the Imperial laws and the judgements of praefects ... We pray for your health. The second year of the Marci Julii, Hathur 3oth.
              Copy of the letter. Antonius Alexander to the strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, greeting. I have ordered the document sent me by the officials and senate of the illustrious city of the Antinojtes, new Hellenes, to be appended for your information to this letter. See that the amphodogrammateus whom they accuse of having nominated to the office of collector members of their polity appear ... to give an account for his defiance of the law, if he still attempts to subject them to the office as persons within his province. I pray for your health, The second year of the Marci Julii, Mecheir 3.
              Copy of the report. To Aurelius Dius also called Pertinax, strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, from Aurelius Sarapion, amphodogrammateus of the city of Oxyrhynchus. I received from you on Phamenoth the 1st a missive to which was appended a copy of aletter written to you by Antonius Alexander, the most high epistrategus, with an enclosure in the latter of the appeal made to him by the most high senate of the Antinojtes on behalf of Aurelius Theon and Aurelius Arsinoiis, twins ..., who were nominated by me for the collection of money-taxes in the metropolis, one of whom, Arsinotis, ..., directing that I should go down to appear before the most high epistrategus, if I still attempt to subject them to the burden as persons within our province. I have accordingly investigated the matter and found that they possess hereditary Antinoite rights, and I immediately on learning this undertook the burden on their behalf; I accordingly make this report. The second year of the Marci Julii, Pharmouthi 13.
              Presented by us, Aurelius Theon and Aurelius Arsinoüs, sons of Theon.
              Delivered by me, ... 3rd year, Mesore 29 ... pages 25-27.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
