<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 8, 1130</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21748</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21748</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21748</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;8;1130</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-31" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 8</note>
              The year after the consulship of Flavius Troconda the most illustrious, Pachon 9, 7th indiction. Aurelius Abraham son of Ision and Sophia, of the village of Senokomis in the Oxyrhynchite nome, to Aurelius Isaac son of Nilus, of the capital city Alexandria, dealer, greeting. I acknowledge, my former bond remaining valid and secure, that I have now received from you as a loan from hand to hand out of your house for my own pressing need ten solidi of gold of the genuine Imperial coinage, of full weight and unalloyed, total
              10 solidi of gold, as a capital sum, and for interest upon it up to the term herein following I will pay twenty bundles of tow, pure and satisfactory, according to the weight of the village, total 20 bundles. This sum I will perforce repay to you free of all risk in the month Phaophi of the current 161st which = the 130th year, at the beginning of the eighth indiction, without delay or dispute of any kind, with the condition that it shall not be lawful for me to say that I have paid any of the aforesaid debt without a written deed or receipt or before the recovery and annulment of this my bond. If at the expiry of the term I do not make the payment to you and you are willing at my request to grant me another term, I will pay you this sum with the same interest for the overtime, and you shall have the right of execution upon me and all my property. This bond, of which a single copy is made, is valid, and in answer to the question I have given my consent. <note>Signature of Aurelius Abraham written for him by Banos, deacon, signature of the scribe, and endorsement on the verso.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
