<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 8, 1123</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21743</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21743</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21743</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;8;1123</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-31" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 8</note>
              Apion son of Sarapion son of Ischyrion, his mother being Ammonous adopted daughter of Ballarus son of Pe... is, of the city of Oxyrhynchus, to Ta.... daughter of Teos son of Totoeus, her mother being Tsenaphunchis, of the village of Petenouris, with her guardian her husband Thonis son of Diogenes and Tapetsiris, of the city of Oxyrhynchus, greeting. I agree that I will henceforward undertake all the public land registered in the name of your departed father Teos at the village of Petenouris and Panechmothis, and that I will secure you against any trouble or liability in regard to all dues upon the said public land from the present 22nd year of Antoninus Caesar the lord continually; while I make no claim to control any remaining part which may be found to belong to you of your father’s estate, but only to have power to dispose of the land, since you have resigned the cultivation.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
