<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 8, 1134</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21751</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21751</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21751</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;8;1134</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-31" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 8</note>
              The year after the consulship of our lord Theodosius, eternal Augustus, for the ninth time, and of Flavius Constantius, most illustrious patrician, for the third time, Phamenoth 7. Flavius Phoebammon son of Diogenes, ex-member of the body-guard, administrator for the divine house, of the illustrious and most illustrious city of Oxyrhynchus, to Aurelius Maximinus son of Ammon, of the said city, greeting. I acknowledge that I have been paid in full the rents of every sort, whether in kind or money, which you undertook to collect from the responsible cultivators in the administrative district of the village Nesmimis and other places, discharging the function of an agent in faithful accord with the list of dues handed to you by me and in method corresponding to the account given by you of receipt and expenditure in the two past second and third indictions; and that for the future I have no count against you and neither make nor will make any charge against you in respect of produce or money or dues of any other sort or kind of those which you undertook to collect in the said second indiction and in the past third indiction from the responsible cultivators of the village Nesmimis and the other accompanying lands belonging to the divine house and under my administration; and for your security I have issued to you this receipt, of which a single copy has been made, and in response to the question I have given my consent.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
