<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 8, 1133</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21750</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21750</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21750</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;8;1133</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-31" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 8</note>
              The year after the consulship of Flavius Olybrius and Flavius Probinus the most illustrious, Phamenoth 28. Aurelius John son of Sarmates, fruit-gardener of Heracleopolis, now living at the village of Nesus Limenius, ex-primipilarius, to Aurelius Artemidorus son of Calopus, of Arsinoftonpolis, living at the illustrious and most illustrious city of Oxyrhynchus, fruit-dealer, greeting. I acknowledge that I have received from you and have been paid in full the four gold solidi less 600 myriads due for the price of the produce of the said village, and I have no claim upon you in respect of this, and I make and will make no charge against you; and since your bond has been lost and cannot be found I declare that it is null and [void] both for me and every one producing it, and I have issued this receipt for your security and in answer to the question have given my consent. <note>Signatures of Aurelius John, written for him by Aurelius Theodore, and of the scribe, and title on the verso.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
