<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 10, 1293</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21769</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21769</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21769</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;10;1293</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 10</note>
              Theon to his mother Philumene, greeting. Before all else I pray for your health and that of my father. Receive from Saras son of Marcus four and a half metretae of fine aphrodisiac oil;and having done so let mek now. If I do not get letters from him about the amount of the oil which he brings to you, I do not intend to send it (?). You ought to have given him a letter, because it is not Saras but another stranger whose word I have to take that you have received it; so in future write, for I have had no letter about the first four and a half metretae. I do this not on our account but on that of the camel-men, lest one of them should want to leave part behind and not bring it. Saras says to me, “Let the other five metretae about which you write wait for the other load,” and if I cannot find a carrier, I shall do so. I sent my brother Apollonius some wool to be dyed, since I want two quarters (?) and they have not been prompt in bringing it(?) because the days are ... I wrote to him ... Receive from Saras son ofMarcus two sealed baskets ...,one foryou, and one for Plutarche my ... Receive in addition from Apollonius ... Good-bye. <note>Date, postscripts, and address on the verso.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
