<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 10, 1266</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21768</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21768</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21768</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;10;1266</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 10</note>
              [... I declare that I was selected at the selection which took place under] ..., late strategus and Pamphilus, late basilicogrammateus, and the other proper officials in the wth year of the deified Vespasian in accordance with the proofs adduced in his lifetime by my aforesaid father Dionysius also called Amois, son of Psammis son of Ballarus, who was a guard of the palaestra, that his father Psammis son of Ballarus was in the list made in the 34th year of the deified Caesar of those ... in the gymnasium ; and I myself ever since I came up for selection was included in al the lists of the gymnasium ; and I declare that Thermouthion the mother of my son was married to me in the and year of Domitian by an autograph contract which was also made public through the record-office in the following 3rd year, while her father Plution son of Plutarchus, registered at the South Square quarter, was in the same fifth year of the deified Vespasian placed by Sutorius Sosibius, then strategus, and Nicander, then basilicogrammateus, and the other proper officials in the class of persons selected by Quintius (?) Paulinus; and I swear by the Emperor Caesar Nerva Trajanus Augustus Germanicus that I have made no false statement, and that Plution is the son of myself and Thermouthion by birth and not by adoption nor is he supposititious, and that I have not availed myself of credentials belonging to others or identity of names; otherwise may I be liable to the consequences of the oath. The 1st year of the Emperor Caesar Nerva Trajanus Augustus Germanicus, Pauni 16. I, Psammis son of Dionysius also called Amois, have presented the memorandum and sworn the oath.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
