<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 10, 1282</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21767</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21767</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21767</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;10;1282</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 10</note>
              ... The third year of the Emperor Caesar Domitianus Augustus, the 18th of the month Neus Sebastus, at Oxythynchus in the Thebaid. Thnas daughter of Petosarapis, her mother being Heras daughter of Heraclides, with her guardian who is her nephew Thompachrates son of Paapis, his mother being Tekosis daughter of Petosorapis, acknowledges to Amoïs son of Apollonius son of Syrus, his mother being Tekosis, and to his wife Tekosis daughter of Thonis son of Petosorapis, her mother being Eseneus, with her husband Amoïs as guardian, all inhabitants of Oxyrhynchus, the contract being drawn up in the street, that she has received from them the capital sum of four hundred drachmae of Imperial silver money with the requisite interest upon it, which sum was lent to them by the former husband, now deceased, of Thnas, Papontos son of Amojs son of Theon, in his lifetime in accordance with a contract drawn up through the record-office at Oxyrhynchus in the eleventh year of the deified Vespasianus in the month Neus Sebastus, the right of execution for the debt having, as claimed by Thnas, descended with other property of Papontos to her in accordance with the disposition made by Papontos in his lifetime, and that neither Thnas nor any one on her behalf makes or will make any claim or will proceed against the recipients of this acknowledgement or their agents on any point whatever up to the present day, and that she has forthwith restored to them the contract of loan crossed out to invalidate it; otherwise not only shall any future claim be invalid, but Thnas or the person proceeding on her behalf shall in addition pay to the aforesaid persons or their agents for every claim the damages and a fine of a hundred drachmae of silver, and to the State an equal amount, and this contract shall be none the less valid. The third year of the Emperor Caesar Domitianus Augustus, the eighteenth of the month Neus Sebastus, executed by ..., agoranomus.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
