<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 10, 1279</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21771</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21771</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21771</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;10;1279</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 10</note>
              To Petronius Dionysius, strategus, from Ophelas also called Corax, freedman of Apia also called Dionysia, daughter of Dionysius, of Oxyrhynchus. I consent to lease from the State for five years from the present third year of Antoninus Caesar the lord three arurae of unproductive land in the area of Senao in the holdings of Heraclides and Heraclides, of which the adjacent areas are on the south a field, on the north and east a public dyke, on the west the land of Didymion son of Demetrius, on condition that Imay sow and plant the land with any crop which I choose except wheat, woad, and coriander (?), and shall have the pastures and secondary pastures at the annual rent for the pastures of four drachmae in all, which sum I will pay annually in the month of Caesareus. If any part becomes un-watered, an allowance shall be made to me, and at the end of the five years’ period I shall not be forced to take the lease. The 3rd year of the Emperor Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrianus Antoninus Augustus Pius, Hathur 11. I, Ophelas also called Corax, presented this application. Written by Hermes, nomographus.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
