<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 10, 1270</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21773</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21773</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21773</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;10;1270</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 10</note>
              To Phocion, strategus, from Ptolemacus son of Herodes and ..., of Oxyrhynchus. A copy of the communication which I have obtained from the record-office is as follows:
              “Celer, priest and archidicastes, to the strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, greeting. Let a copy of the application presented to me be served, as below. Good-bye. The 22nd year of the Emperor Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrianus Antoninus Augustus Pius, the ... of the month Hadrianus. Signed by me, ... written by me, Sarapion ..., scribe of the record-office. “‘To Celer son of the ex-hypomnematographus ..., ex-strategus of the city, priest, archidicastes, and superintendent of the chrematistae and other tribunals, from Ptolemaeus son of Herodes and ..., of Oxyrhynchus. By the terms of the contract made by me with Ammon.... daughter of Diogenes and Sinthodnis with her guardian her son Diogenes son of Theon, of the said city, in the present 22nd year, she acknowledged that she had ceded to me the sixth part of an arura, or thereabouts, whether more or less, of catoecic corn-bearing arable land, of rectangular shape, belonging to her in the area of the village ... in the holding of Polycleidas, and formerly the property of ... daughter of Diogenes, the whole one arura being held jointly with ... and another, and being adjoined on the south, north, east, and west by ..., and that she had received from me forthwith from hand to hand in full the hundred and six drachmae of the Imperial silver coinage agreed upon between us as the price of the sixth part of an arura, as aforesaid, and that she would guarantee the land with every guarantee as free from the liability of cultivating royal or domain land and every impost and from construction and ... of dykes and also from al public taxes incident in the past down to the end ofand including the 21st year of Antoninus Caesar the lord, because the proceeds henceforth belong to me, Ptolemacus, with the conditions included in the contract concerning the previous cultivation. I beg you to give orders that instructions should be sent to the strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome to serve a copy of this application upon Ammon ..., if alive, or if not,upon her full heirs whose names will be disclosed on the spot, as is fitting, in order that they may know that the contract with al its provisions is valid.’” (Endorsed) Let the proper steps be taken. The 22nd year of the Emperor Caesar Titus Aelius Hadrianus Antoninus Augustus Pius, the ... of the month Hadrianus.” In these circumstances I request that a copy should be served on Ammon ..., as is fitting. <note>Date.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
