<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 10, 1272</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21772</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21772</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21772</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;10;1272</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 10</note>
              To ... from Diemous daughter of Colluthus, of the city of Oxyrhynchus], with her euardian Sarapion son of ..., of the said city .... I shut up the door of my house and the door of the terrace, and on my return I found that a box which I had in the terrace had been unfastened and that there had been abstracted from it two gold bracelets of the weight of four minae, a gold figure of Bes, and two large silver bracelets, and that the door of the terrace had been lifted. As I have some suspicion against my neighbours Heras son of Kalathus, weaver, and those working with him, because my house is easy of access from the house of Heras, I present this petition and request that, if you think fit, you should come for a personal inspection, and that Heras and his associates, whose names he will himself give, should be brought before you and the proper inquiry made, in order that I may be able with your assistance to discover my property. <note>Date and signature of Diemous written for her by Sarapion.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
