<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 10, 1278</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21781</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21781</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21781</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;10;1278</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 10</note>
              Marcus Aurelius Andronicus also called Mithres, and however he is styled, and Aurelia Dionysias also called Chaeremonis through her husband Aurelius Ammonius, gymnasiarch-elect, senator of Oxyrhynchus, and Didyme also called Apollonia and Letodoris also called Dionysothconis, both minors, through their mother Ptolema daughter of Dionysotheon, ex-gymnasiarch of the said city of Oxyrhynchus, herself acting through Epicrates son of Didymus, mutually acknowledge that they have divided among themselves the usufruct of the excellent productive pigeon-house owned by them in equal shares in the farmstead of their vineyard called Perkops for a further period of four years from Thoth 1 of the present 23rd year, and the minors have had allotted to them the usufruct of two years, namely, the present 23rd and the 25th year, Aurelia Dionysias also called Chaeremonis that of the coming 24th year, and Aurelius Andronicus also called Mithres similarly that of the 26th year, and cach party ...; the dung is to go annually to their aforesaid vineyard, and each party is to deliver to the other the said pigeon-house on the 1st of the intercalary days in productive condition, none of the parties having the right to molest another during his aforesaid period. This agreement,done in triplicate in order that each party may have a copy, is valid. The 23rd year of the Emperor Caesar Marcus Aurelius Severus Antoninus Parthicus Maximus Britannicus Maximus Germanicus Maximus Pius Augustus, the 10th of the month Hadrianus. (Signed) I, Aurelius Ammonius, and however I am styled, consent to this joint agreement as aforesaid. ...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
