<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 10, 1276</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21786</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21786</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21786</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;10;1276</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 10</note>
              Aurelius Agathodaemon son of Geminus and Nice, and Aurelia Meïthous daughter of Apion and Herais, both of Oxyrhynchus, Meïthous acting without a guardian in accordance with Roman custom by right of her children, to Aurelius Serenus also called Sarapion, son of Agathinus and Taposirias, of the said city, greeting. We agree that we have sold to you from the present time henceforth for ever the half share of an old house and al appurtenances thereof owned by us in equal portions at the said city of Oxyrhynchus in the Myrobalanus quarter, jointly with you in respect of the remaining half share. The adjacent areas of the whole are on the south a blind street, on the north the house of Theonis daughter of Horus, on the east the house of Diogenis daughter of Diogenes and others, on the west a public street. The sum agreed upon between us for the price of the said half share of the house with the appurtenances, seven hundred drachmae of Imperial silver coin, we have forthwith received from you in equal portions from hand to hand in full, so that henceforward you and your descendants and successors shall possess and own the half share of the house sold to you by us as aforesaid and use and dispose of it in whatever way you choose; and we will guarantee to you the half share completely against all claims by every guarantee, free from persons’ property-returns and the cultivation of royal or patrimonial land and from every impost or debt or lien of any kind and all other liabilities whatsoever. This sale, written in duplicate, is valid, and you shall make it public through the bureau whenever you choose, without requiring a notification or any further concurrence on our part, because we now agree to the publication to be made by you, and in answer to your question whether this is rightly and fairly done we have given our assent. The 6th year of the Emperors and Caesars Marci Julii Philippi Carpict Maximi Germanici Maximi Pi Felices Augusti, Pauni. <note>Signatures of the vendors.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
