<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 10, 1277</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21789</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21789</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21789</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;10;1277</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 10</note>
              Aurelia Sarapias daughter of Arius, citizen, acting without a guardian by right of her children according to Roman custom, to Aurelius Theon son of Ammonius also called Aphunchis,of Oxyrhynchus, greeting. I acknowledge that I have sold to you a three-sided couch with linen coverings embroidered throughout, and four ... linen cushions of the same quality for the price of five hundred drachmae, total 500 dr., which I thereupon received. This contract of sale of which there is a single copy, free from mistake, is valid, and I will guarantee the sale and have been asked the formal question, as aforesaid. The and year of the emperors and Caesars Publius Licinius Valerianus and Publius Licinius Valerianus Gallienus Germanici Maximi and Publius Licinius Cornelius Valerianus the most illustrious Caesar Augusti, Mesore 16. (Signed) I, Aurelia Sarapias, have sold the couch and cushions and received the 500 dr. for the price and will guarantee the sale, and have been asked the formal question, as aforesaid. I, Aurelius Origenes, wrote on behalf of my mother, who is illiterate.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
