<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 10, 1284</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21787</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21787</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21787</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;10;1284</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 10</note>
              The end year of the Emperor and Caesar Gaius Messius Quintus Trajanus Decius Pius Felix and Quintus Herennius Etruscus Messius Decius and Gaius Valens Hostilianus Messius Quintus the most august Caesars, Augusti, Choiak 19. Paid to Aurelius Apollonius and his associate, both senators of the city of Oxyrhynchus, public bankers, to the account of the tax on sales by Tiberius Claudius Diogenes son of Tiberius Claudius Diogenes, ex-cosmetes, ex-president of the games, senator of the city of Oxyrhynchus, on account of the half share ofan old house and al its appurtenances belonging to him in the said city of
              Oxyrhynchus in the North Quay quarter, which was [purchased?] from his foster-child’s mother Aurelia Ammonia daughter of ... and Techosous, of the said city of Oxyrhynchus, in accordance with a privately drawn contract made in the said month Choiak by an irrevocable transfer, on the valuation which he has made of the said half share of the house, namely 3[.]5 drachmae 5 1/2 obols, in payment for libation-money and the tax on sales seventy-three drachmae five and a half obols, total 73 dr. 5 1/2 ob. (Signed) I, Aurelius Apollonius, ex- gymnasiarch, senator, public banker, have certified the seventy-three drachmae five and half obols, total 73 dr. 5 1/2 ob.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
