<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 10, 1255</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21798</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21798</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21798</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;10;1255</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 10</note>
              To Claudius Dioscurides also called Chaereas, ex-strategus of the Diopolite nome, strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, from Aurelius Papontos son of Theon and Aurelius Horus son of Archelaus, both comarchs of the village of Ision Panga for the present 8th which = the 7th year. Having been enjoined by you to keep in safety the crops at the threshing-floors in our lands until the decaproti have received payment in full of the public taxes from each person, we accordingly agree, swearing by the fortune of our lords Diocletian and Maximian Augusti, to be on the watch and to permit no one to touch the produce until each person has paid to the local decaproti the amount due from him, the measurement being made so that no complaint may ensue; otherwise may we be liable to the penalties attaching to the oath. The 8th which is also the 7th year of our lords Diocletian and Maximian Augusti, Pauni 19.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
