<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 10, 1260</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21797</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21797</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21797</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;10;1260</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 10</note>
              To Aurelius Philippus also called Horion, strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, from Aurelius Anicetus son of Olbanus, of the illustrious and most illustrious city of Oxyrhynchus, pilot of a Hellenic boat belonging to the heirs of Tiro, of 350 artabae burden. I have received and embarked upon the aforesaid boat in accordance with the instructions of Ulpius Cyrillus, the most eminent catholicus, from Aurelius Demetrianus and however he is styled, decaprotus of part of the middle toparchy, 75 artabae of new, pure, and sifted barley, belonging to the village of Heracleum, which I will transport to the most illustrious Alexandria and deliver to whomsoever I am ordered to deliver it, and I will produce the certificate of the delivery, because I have been paid all the expenses. This receipt is valid, there being three copies of it, of which I have issued two to you, the strategus, and one to the decaprotus, and in answer to the formal question I have given my consent. <note>Date and signature of Anicetus written for him by Aurelius Silvanus.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
