<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 10, 1252 R</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21799</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21799</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21799</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;10;1252</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="2" subtype="column" type="textpart">
              <p>
                <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 10</note>
                Statement of proofs with regard to Theon, Heraclides, and Thonius, late overseers of the fort at Elensais (?), concerning the fact that nothing was extorted from them by Phileas, in accordance with the order of the praefect.
                To Aurelius Heraclides, exegetes of Alexandria, strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, from Aurelius Thonius and Aurelius Heraclides, both exegetae, and Aurelius Theon, chief-priest, all three councillors of the illustrious and most illustrious city of Oxyrhynchus, formerly overseers of the fort at Elensais. Whereas today, the 18th, you summoned us, and in your memoranda read a letter of our most illustrious praefect Valerius Pompeianus in which he gave orders that if we had suffered extortion from Phileas, ex-magistrate of Alexandria, we were to come with the proofs, but if not, we were to remain at home, and we forthwith declared in your memoranda that we had not suffered any extortion from Phileas, but you desired us to state this fact also in writing, we again affirm our former declaration, that nothing has been extorted from us by him, and we request that these facts should be made known to his highness. The 6th year of the Emperor Cacsar Gaius Aurelius Valerius Diocletianus and the 5th year of the Emperor Caesar Marcus Aurelius Valerius Maximianus Germanici Maximi Pii Felices Augusti, Thoth 18. <note>Signatures of Thonius, Heraclides, and Theon.</note>
              </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
