<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 10, 1264</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21794</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21794</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21794</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;10;1264</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 10</note>
              To Aurelius ... also called Apollonius, ex-gymnasiarch of the illustrious and most illustrious city of Oxyrhynchus, and his associate, both keepers of the archives, from Julius Theon also called Zoïlus, son of Gaius Julius Alexander, of the illustrious and most illustrious city of Oxyrhynchus. I submit to you in duplicate the copy of the memorandum drawn up in consequence of my petition to his excellency Andromachus, ex-dioecetes, concerning the inviolability legally belonging to me and present this memorandum in order that the proper entry may be made against my name through the registers in your keeping, so that al may know the rights belonging to me in virtue of the number of my children; and I swear the oath customary with Romans that I have not made a false statement. The 2nd year of the Emperor Caesar Lucius Domitius Aurelianus Pius Felix Augustus and the 5th year of Julius Aurelius Septimius Vaballathus Athenodorus, most illustrious king, consul, Emperor, general of the Romans, Phamenoth 8.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
