<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 12, 1409</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21819</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21819</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21819</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;12;1409</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 12</note>
              Aurelius Harpocration, strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, to the decemprimi of the nome, greeting. A copy of the circular letter written to us, the strategi and decemprimi of the Heptanomia and Arsinofte nome, by his highness the dioecetes, Ulpius Aurelius, concerning the building up of the dykes and the cleansing of the canals is sent to you, dear friends, in order that you may be informed and follow his instructions. The one of you who is the first to receive this missive should communicate it to the rest. I pray for your health, dear friends. The 3rd year of our lord Marcus Aurelius Probus Augustus, Pharmouthi [.].
              Ulpius Aurelius to the strategi and decemprimi of the Heptanomia and Arsinoite nome, greeting. The season for the building up of the dykes and the cleansing of the canals having arrived, I thought it necessary to announce to you by this letter that all the cultivators and ... ought now to build these up with all zeal on the ... belonging to them, with a view to both the public gain of all and their own private advantage. For I am persuaded that everyone is aware of the benefit resulting from these works. Therefore let it be the care of you, the strategi and decemprimi, both to urge all to devote themselves to this most necessary labour, and to see that the overseers usually elected for the purpose are
              chosen from magistrates or private persons, who will compel every one to perform his proper work by personal service, according to the rule given in the constitution of the appointment, with no malice or favour, so that the dykes are raised to the ordained height and breadth and the breaches are filled up, in order that they may be able to withstand the flood of the most sacred Nile auspiciously approaching, and that the canals are cleansed up to the so-called standards and the usual width, in order that they may easily contain the coming influx of water for the irrigation of the fields, this being for the common weal, and that absolutely no money is exacted from any one in place of work. If any one dare to
              attempt exactions or neglect these orders, let him know that not only his property but his life will be at stake for injuring measures designed for the safety of the whole of Egypt. I pray for your health. The 3rd year ...
              Presented by Aurelius Silvanus, assistant, in the 3rd year, Pharmouthi 6.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
