<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 12, 1405</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21815</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21815</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21815</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;12;1405</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 12</note>
              ... you ceded (your property) ..., it is clear that the cession was made not to our Treasury but to the person who nominated you to the office, who having taken possession of your property will provide the rest of the ... and fulfill the duties of the office; for our Treasury does not desire such cessions. Your citizenship, however, will in no way be injured thereby, nor will you be subjected to corporal punishment. Published at Alexandria in the 8th year, Pharmouthi.
              To Aurelius Leonides, strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, from Aemilius Stephanus son of Hatres and Tasorapis, from the village of Sinkepha. Today I learnt that I had been nominated as his successor by Aurelius Amois son of Patas and Demetrous, of the said village, for the office of collector of the village money-dues of the said Sinkepha for the present 3rd year, as being a person of means and suitable. This is unreasonable and contrary to the just apportionment of the liturgy, so that I resign my, property to him in accordance with the Imperial decree cited above, and declare that I ...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
