<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 12, 1408 Z. 11 - 26</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21818</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21818</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21818</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;12;1408</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 12</note>
              Baebius Juncinus to the strategi of the Heptanomia and Arsinoite nome, greeting. I have already in a previous letter ordered you to search out robbers with every care, warning you of the peril of neglect, and now I wish to confirm my decision by a decree, in order that all inhabitants of Egypt may know that I am not treating this duty as an affair of secondary importance, but offer rewards to those of you who cooperate, and on the other hand expose to peril those who choose to disobey. The said decree I desire to be made public in both the capitals and the most important places of the nomes, penalties including personal risk being laid upon you if in the future evil-doers are enabled to use violence without being detected. I hope for your health. The .. year, Phaophi 28.
              Proclamation of Lucius Baebius Aurelius Juncinus, praefect of Egypt. That it is impossible to exterminate robbers apart from those who shelter them is evident to al, but when they are deprived of their helpers we shall quickly punish them (?). There are many methods of giving them shelter: some do so because they are partners in their misdeeds, others without sharing in these yet ...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
