<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 12, 1413</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21823</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21823</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21823</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;12;1413</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 12</note>
              “and let a resolution be made for him on these terms, that he (is to serve) half (the office) ... I introduce ...” Septimius Serenus also called Ischyrion, exegetes, said, “... on these terms.” The senators said,“ Bravo, exegetes.”
              (The prytanis said,) “... the majesty of our lord Aurelianus Augustus. Accordingly nominate also senators, in order that their payments for crowns (may contribute) to the...” (The senators said,)... The prytanis said, “Do you exegetae press some one.” The exegetae said, “Let Serenus(?)be pressed to take the office of exegetes.” The prytanis said, ... Sabinus and however he is styled, ex-prytanis, said, “Plution still owes the payment for a crown on account of the office of exegetes which he undertook among the magistracies.” The prytanis said, ..., secretary of the city revenues, said, “ Yes.” Julianus also called Dioscurides, exegetes, said, “Plution owes the payment for a crown; therefore he is not...” The senators (?) said, “The person nominated was nominated on the security of his own property.” Septimius Diogenes also called Agathodaemon, ex-hypomnematographus and however he is styled, syndic, said, “... Serenus(?) is a gymnasiarch.” The prytanis said, “Nominate others, that the number of exegetae may be completed.” The exegetae said, “Let Ion son of ... be pressed to take the office of exegetes held by his grandfather.” Secundus son
              of Secundus, chief-priest, said, “Then let the person nominated be subject to overseers.” The prytanis said, “I choose for the post of overseer ... Phileas and Plutinus, that they may discharge this trust for the senate.” The senators said, “ Upright, faithful Phileas; upright, faithful Plutinus.” This question ... having been postponed until the next meeting of the senate, the prytanis said, “Let holders of the other offices also nominate; and nominate senators also.” The members of the third tribe said, “(We nominate ...).” The prytanis said, “Nilus, senator, shall be overseer.” The senators said, “Upright, faithful Nilus; ever-honourable is Nilus; success to him.” The members of the third tribe said, ... Septimius Diogenes also called Agathodaemon, ex-hypomnematographus and however he is styled, syndic, said, “I have impounded the property of ..., that is to say produce deposited at the farmstead of Monimou, and when the amount is known, it shall be laid before you.” ...phus and however he is styled said, “Those who were just now nominated were nominated by Phileas and Heraclidion.” The senators said, “From the whole (tribe?)... Upright, faithful Horion, land-owner at Nesmimis; upright, faithful Leonides, land-owner at Dositheou; upright, faithful Besarion, land-owner at ...” Septimius Diogenes also called Agathodaemon, ex-hypomnematographus and however he is styled, syndic, said, “In order that the persons nominated may be pressed to serve and may take office, the first year’s duty ...”
              (Ptolemaeus, gymnasiarch, said), “... promised to provide oil on Mesore 30. On Mesore 30 he failed to provide oil, but on the first day of the following month he provided it through me ...; on the 2nd oil was provided by ... son of Philosophus; on the 3rd Theodorus son of Ptolemaeus presided and failed to provide oil, but I provided it by a loan. If therefore...” The senators said, “Bravo, Ptolemaeus; bravo, gymnasiarch. The 11th is the day of Dionysius also called Artemidorus, the 12th of Aristion also called Andronicus, son of Asyncritus.” Serenus son of Ammonius (?), gymnasiarch, said, “... the interchange of days.” The senators said, “The resolutions are valid. The 13th is the day of Xenicus and the gymnasiarchs-elect, ...” Serenus son of Ammonius, gymnasiarch, said, “Do not let the interchange of days injuriously affect the resolution concerning me. On the ... even if he failed to provide oil; on the 28th Severus and Epimachus, sons of Philosophus.” The senators said, “Bravo, (Serenus; bravo, gymnasiarch ?).”
              The prytanis said, “The collector for the golden crown and victory of our lord Aurelianus Augustus, Julius (?)... (reported) ... our lord Aurelianus Augustus, and that his crown has already been prepared, and unless the artificers ...; these objects are votive offerings. Let 12 talents more be given to the artificers...” The senators said, “Let the same persons make the demands.” Theon also called Origenes, son of Chaeremon (?) and however he is styled, said, “... you can demand it from them.” The senators said, “Upright, faithful collectors.” Euporus also called Agathodaemon, and however he is styled, said, “..., if the work is not finished.” The prytanis said, “His excellency the epistrategus also ...” Euporus also called Agathodaemon (?), and however he is styled, said, “As soon as he comes, therefore, the work shall be pressed on.” The senators said, “... Euporus; obedient Euporus.” Septimius Diogenes also called Agathodaemon, ex-hypomnematographus and however he is styled, syndic, said, “... if any money is paid in advance for the artificers, it shall be brought to your notice.”
              The prytanis said, “... and the body of cosmetae through Cornelianus and Pausanias was then sent ... reported that before the whole cost was paid ...”
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
