<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 12, 1414</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21824</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21824</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21824</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;12;1414</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 12</note>
              (The prytanis said,) “... is owing, and 14 talents. The value of the 100 (?) garments is 14[0] talents, ... I have received the 63 belonging to the nome on account of the city’s share. Let them be compelled to pay monthly from their own property 74 (?)...”
              The prytanis said, “You examined the list of the temple and fixed a limit, and your resolution was submitted to the strategus, but (the priests?) ... made the excuse that those who undertook the work in question and their wives were unable to spin the yarn, ... (see) that on this point also you fix a limit, for there are only a few villages in your nome which have this material.” The senators said, ... Septimius Diogenes also called Agathodaemon, ex-hypomnematographus and however he is styled, syndic, said, “(The yarn-merchants report that) ... and the price of weaving-yarn is 49 denarii, and 11 denarii were paid to them from the Treasury’s account...” The senators said, “Let the yarn-merchants be content with 19 denarii besides what was paid to them from the Treasury's account.” Septimius Diogenes also called Agathodaemon, ex-hypomnematographus and however he is styled, syndic, said, “ If this is your decision in the case of the weaving-yarn, we will supply a sample and ... to those who are to weave it ... Let the cloth-weavers who are to weave the linen of the temple appoint (?) someone to (test it?).”
              A petition of the city cloth-weavers having been read, to the effect that, besides the ... drachmae paid to them in the past year (for each ...), .. more drachmae should be given to them on account of the rise in the value of the materials and in the wages of their workmen, after the reading the prytanis said, “Let .. more drachmae be given to the cloth-weavers, making 200 drachmae in all, on account of the rise in value of the materials. Decree this... When the bundle (?) has been valued, let these (drachmae) too accrue. Those who pay the value of the (cloth) ... it shall be submitted to you at the next meeting of the senate.” The senators said, “So be it.”
              (Date?) A communication from Terentius Arius, strategus, having been read, concerning the election of ..., it was decided to postpone the matter until the next meeting.
              A communication from the strategus having been read, concerning the election of other convoyers of animals, after the reading the prytanis said, “... especially the convoyers of the animals transported ... I collected some senators who were present and nominated one, Sarapion ... in order that there should not be (any delay)...” The senators said, ‘Invaluable prytanis ; save yourself for us, prytanis; excellent is your rule; excellent...” The prytanis said, “... is in the counting-house.” The senators said, “The prytanis has done right.”
              The prytanis said, “The law commands that the coming prytanis should be nominated six months beforehand. I remind you...” The senators said, “The nomination is made with a resolution...” The prytanis said, “... for I have (long) been ill and have a cough from my lung, as you know, ...” The senators said, “(Illustrious) prytanis, noble prytanis, still labour for us; labour in a manner worthy of the past.”
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
