<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 12, 1434</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21838</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21838</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21838</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;12;1434</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 12</note>
              From Apollonius, lately appointed comogrammateus of the Monimou farmstead and other villages in the upper toparchy. Account of abatements of taxation for the 11th year of the Emperor Caesar Nerva Trajanus Augustus Germanicus Dacicus, as follows. Abatements of which the due amounts in money and corn are reckoned here: to Gaius Julius, son of Gaius Julius Theon, formerly chief-priest and hypomnematographus, of the land in this nome sacred to Isis of Taposiris Aquila conceded in accordance with an application presented by Gaius Julius Theon the father, in accordance with the concession made to him by Gaius Tyrannius by an edict, from the account of Caesar, on condition that he should pay at the city for taxes and other charges 2 talents ... drachmae, at ... this in the holding of Demetrius son of Po... .. arurae, of which .. are in the category of land that is unsown or dry or worn away, .. in the pastures in the estates of the lord Augustus, in place of which there are planted with olives (?), reckoned up to the 20th year in the account of ..., . arurae; at Psobthis taxed at 1 artaba 1 arura, making 1 artaba, taxed at .. 21/64 arur., at Idu ... 3/64 arur., total 1 21/64 arur., at Idu ... 3/64 arur.; money- taxes, for naubion at 200 dr. of copper, for exchange (?) ..., for naubion (?) 221 (?) dr., of which 8(?) dr. ...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
