<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 12, 1452</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21853</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21853</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21853</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;12;1452</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 12</note>
              To Agathodaemon, strategus, and Hierax, basilicogrammateus, and the other proper officials, from Diodorus son of Plution son of Diodorus, his mother being Tatriphis daughter of Amoïs, of Oxyrhynchus. In accordance with the orders concerning the examination of boys who have reached the age of thirteen years, if both their parents are inhabitants of the metropolis rated at 12 drachmae, Sarapion the son of my brother and sister on the father’s side Sarapion and Tnephersoïs, whose mother is Dogumis(?), was put in the list at the Cretan quarter as having reached the age of 13 in the past 11th year of Trajanus Hadrianus Caesar the lord. Wherefore coming forward for his examination I declare that he is rated at 12 drachmae, and that his father, my brother on the father’s side Sarapion, died some time ago being rated at 12 drachmae in an undisputed (?) poll-tax list of the 8th year of Hadrianus in the quarter of Pammenes’ Garden, and the father of my brother and sister on the father’s side and grandfather of the minor, Plution son of Diodorus, died some time ago, being rated at 12 drachmae, who was also registered (?) in the 9th year of Domitian ...
              To Agathodaemon, etc. In accordance with the orders concerning the examination of those who have reached the class of persons belonging to the gymnasium, if they are of this descent, Sarapion, son of my brother and sister on the father’s side Sarapion and Tnephersois, whose mother is in both cases Dogumis(?), was put in the list at the Cretan quarter as having reached the age of 13 in the past 11th year of Trajanus Hadrianus Caesar the lord. Wherefore coming forward for his examination I declare that at the examination of those belonging to the gymnasium held in the 5th year of the deified Vespasian by Sutorius Sosibius, then strategus, and Nicander, then basilicogrammateus, and the other proper officials our father, the grandfather of the minor, Plution, was examined as resident in the Gymnasium Square quarter in accordance with the proofs adduced by his father, who was over age, that his father also, Ptolemaeus son of Ammonius son of Pkaës(?), was in the list of ... of the 34th year of the deified Caesar, which Plution died some time ago, and that the father of the minor, my brother on the father’s side, Sarapion, was likewise examined in the 3rd year of the deified Trajan by Dionysius (?), then strategus, and the other proper officials, as resident in the aforesaid Gymnasium Square quarter ...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
