<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 12, 1451</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21852</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21852</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21852</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;12;1451</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 12</note>
              ..to produce for you the record of the examination held. by Calvisius Statianus, praefect of Egypt, through Juvencus Valens, praefect of the Imperial Alexandrine fleet, on the ... of Phamenoth of the 15th year of Aurelius Antoninus Caesar the Jord, certified by the record-office at ... through Anubion also called Dionysius, keeper of the records, of which a copy is appended, with declarations of three witnesses to the effect that Trunnia Marcella is the sister of Trunnius Lucilianus, and of the examination of my slaves Euphrosynus, ... olytus and Plutarchus; and I swear the usual oath made by Romans that they are my children and I have made no false return, under penalty of being liable to the consequences of the oath, The 16th year of the Emperor Cacsar Marcus Aurelius Antoninus Augustus Armeniacus Medicus Parthicus Germanicus Sarmaticus Maximus, in the month Hadrianus.
              Copy of an examination-certificate. Extract from the volume of examinations held by Gaius Calvisius Statianus, praefect of Egypt, of which the heading is “The hereinafter named veterans, Roman citizens, freedmen, slaves and others were examined by Calvisius Statianus, praefect of Egypt, through Juvencus Valens, praefect of the Imperial Alexandrine fleet, from Phamenoth of the 15th year of Aurelius Antoninus Caesar the lord until Pauni of the same year. The claims presented by them to the aforesaid Juvencus Valens are affixed to each name.” After other details, sheet 74: “Oxyrhynchite nome: Lucius Trunniuvs Lucilianus, illegitimate, aged __ years, Trunnia Marcella, his sister, aged
              __ years; slaves, Euphrosynus aged __ years, ... olytus aged __ years, Plutarchus aged __ years. The mother of the aforesaid children and mistress of the slaves, E...ia Trunnia ..., acting by the ius liberorum, produced concerning herself a tablet of declaration under seal dated in the 15th year of the deified Hadrianus, and concerning the children two tablets of evidence under seal, dated, that of Lucilianus in the 16th year of the deified Antoninus, and that of Marcella in the 4th year of Aurelius Antoninus, in which the aforesaid Trunnia ... testified that the persons under examination were her children by unlawful marriage, and concerning the slaves the certificate that they were born in the house, and a census-return of the 14th year of Aurelius Antoninus, in which the slaves were registered. Trunnia also provided as certifiers ... Hermaïscus and two Julii, Hermippus and ..., who declared jointly with her that no fictitious evidence had been used.” And (a copy) of the description made by the aforesaid Juvencus Valens, in the case of the aforesaid Trunnius Lucilianus “illegitimate, 23 years, with no distinguishing mark”, in that of Trunnia Marcella “illegitimate, 11 years, with no distinguishing mark”, and with regard to the slaves, in the case of Euphrosynus “9 years, with no distinguishing mark”, in that of ...olytus “[.] years with no distinguishing mark”, and in that of Plutarchus “5 years, with no distinguishing mark”.
              Presented by me, Trunnia ... I, Gaius Caecilius Clemens also called Berenicianus, ...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
