<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 12, 1453</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21854</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21854</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21854</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;12;1453</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 12</note>
              Copy of an oath. We, Thonis also called Patoiphis son of Thonis and Heraclides son of Totoës, both lamplighters of the temple of Sarapis, the most great god, and of the Isis-shrine there, and Paapis son of Thonis and Petosiris son of the aforesaid Patoiphis, both lamplighters of the temple of Thoëris, the most great goddess, at Oxyrhynchus, all four swear by Caesar, god and son of a god, to Heliodorus son of Heliodorus and Helio- dorus son of Ptolemaeus, overseers of the temples in the Oxyrhynchite and Cynopolite nomes, that we will superintend the lamps of the above mentioned temples, as aforesaid, and will supply the proper oil for the daily lamps burning in the temples signified from Thoth 1 to Mesore (intercalary day ?) 5 of the present 1st year of Caesar... in accordance with what was supplied up to the 22nd which was the 7th year; and we the aforesaid are mutually sureties and all our property is security for the performance of the duties herein written. If I observe the oath may it be well with me, but if I swear falsely, the reverse. The 1st year of Caesar... <note>Copies of the signatures of the parties, those of Paapis and Petosiris being written by proxies.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
