<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 12, 1449</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21850</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21850</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21850</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;12;1449</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 12</note>
              From the Aurelii, Zoïlus son of Apollonius and Aurelia Achillis, and ... son of ... and Aurelia Taaphunchis, both ..., and their associates, priests of Zeus, Hera, Atargatis, Core, Dionysus, Apollo, Neotera, and the associated gods, and celebrants of the busts of the lord Augustus and his advancing victory and Julia Domna Augusta and his deified father Severus, at their ... temples situated in the metropolis, in the case of Dionysus in the quarter of the Square of Thoëris, in the other case, that of Apollo ... the great god and good genius, and Neotera, in the south-east part of the city in the quarter of ..., in the south-west part of the city ... and in the Broad Street quarter to the south of the shrine of Demeter that of Zeus, Hera, Atargatis Bethennunis, and Core, and in the Gymnasium Square quarter that of Zeus, Hera, Atargatis Bethennunis, and Core, and in the Cavalry Camp quarter, Patemit street, that of Zeus, Tera, Atargatis, and Core, and in ... of the Cynopolite nome that of Zeus and Hera. List of offerings for the 2[.] year of Marcus Aurelius Severus Antoninus Parthicus Maximus Britannicus Max. Germanicus Max. Pius Augustus, as follows. Objects in the temple of Neotera, a representation of our lord the Emperor M. Aurelius Severus Antoninus Felix Pius Augustus and Julia Domna the lady Augusta and his deified father Severus, some of the offerings being inscribed with the names of the dedicators, ... while in other cases we are ignorant of the dedicators, because the offerings have been in the temple from antiquity; a statue of Demeter, most great goddess, of which the bust is of Parian marble and the other parts of the body of wood, ... was not disclosed to us. And with regard to other offerings, which were dedicated in accordance with ancient custom for vows or pious reasons, ... dedicated by Phragenes(?) son of Horion, a small bronze statue of Neotera, 5 rings dedicated by ... son of Didymus, a green robe dedicated by the mother of An ..., ... dedicated by Castor son of Asclepiades, a small ..., on which is a statuette of Neotera ..., a stone ... of well-cut stone, a rudder representing Neotera, a statue of ..., of which the bust is of Parian marble and the amulets are of plaster, a statue of Typhon, part of which ... joined together in the middle, and the ... in a casket, 2 small gold full sacred lamps dedicated by Sarapion son of Sarapion, another small gold full sacred lamp dedicated by Saraeus daughter of Achill ..., (another lamp) dedicated by Ptolemaïs wife of ..., of which the weight is described in the periodical lists, 10 armlets for a child and 1 ring for a child, making in all . quarters of gold, ..., 2 gold spoons, 1 small gold pen, ... 1 small ..., making in all . quarters of gold, 1 gold ... well cut and decorated with silver, weighing 2 quarters, . silver pens, ... a silver bracelet for a child, ... 2 silver armlets, a ... silver crescent ..., in all weighing 8 drachmae 3 obols, a silver pendant ..., a gold ... with a shrine ..., weighing 4 dr. 3 ob., a silver mirror for a child, 6 small silver ..., . fine silver lamps (representing?) Bubastis ..., in all weighing ...
              <milestone unit="line" n="40"/>... (a representation) of our lord the Emperor M. Aurelius Severus Antoninus Felix Pius Augustus and his deified father Severus, and Julia Domna the lady Augusta, a wooden couch ... In .. of the Cynopolite nome a representation of our lord the Emperor M. Aurel. Sev. Ant. F. P. Aug. and his deified father Sev. and Jul. Domna the lady Aug., ... a lamp with a small figure of Core in unstamped silver weighing 1 1b., the interior being of wood, having ..., dedicated by the mother of Dionysia daughter of Dius, of Oxyrhynchus, in accordance with the agreement of Aurelius ..., and a small shrine of Iacchus of foreign stone, dedicated by Andromachus ..., a bronze altar dedicated by Smaragdus, freedman of Apollonius son of Sarapion, in accordance with the agreement of ... Likewise added in the 1st year, a gold lamp having in the middle ..., (an altar) ..., dedicated by Heraclides son of Sarapion, another altar of silver weighing 1 lb. 5 1/2 oz. ..., a statue of ... the most great goddess weighing 15 lb., dedicated by Aurelius Julius in the 1st year, and in the 4th year ..., 1 ... decayed and useless and all the clothing decayed with age and useless, having no traces of ... Added in the 6th year in the month of Thoth at the temple of Core, a statue ..., dedicated by ... ex-gymnasiarch, and in the past month Phaophi a pair of κορδίκια ... In the villages of the nome, as follows: at Sinaru a representation of our lord the Emperor M. Aurel. Sev. Ant. F. P. Aug. and his deified futher Sev. and Jul. Domna the lady Aug...., a dark red covering decayed and useless, 1 bronze folding mirror in new style. At Ta... arepresentation of our lord the Emperor M. Aur. Sev. Ant. F. P. Aug. and his deified father Sev. and Jul. Domna the lady Aug.. in the temple 1 bronze trencher, 2 statuettes of Zeus and Hera, most great gods. At ... a representation of our lord the Emperor M. Aur. Sev. Ant. F. P. Aug. and his deified father Sev. and Jul. Domna the lady Aug., 1 bronze trencher and ... At ... a representation of our lord the Emperor M. Aur. Sev. Ant. F. P. Aug. and his deified father Sev. and Jul. Domna the lady Aug., 1 covering decayed and useless. At Kerkethoëris and Kerke... In the said villages two representations of our lord the Emperor M. Aur. Sev. Ant. F. P. Aug. and his deified father Sev. and Jul. Domna the lady Aug., and there is provided by ..., ex-gymnasiarch, daily 4 cotyle of oil, which goes to ...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
