<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 12, 1468</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21869</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21869</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21869</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;12;1468</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 12</note>
              To Lucius Mussius Aemilianus, the most eminent deputy-praefect, from Aurelius Theoninus also called Aphunchis, son of Dioscorus and Taaphunchis, of Oxyrhynchus. The wicked designs of those who are ready to commit crimes by artifice are not only made to be no avail, but are subjected to the decreed penalties of the laws by your active and in all cases unresting vigilance. Accordingly I, being the victim of such designs, appeal to your nobility with the full confidence that I shall obtain the rights due to me, my lord praefect. The statement of my case is as follows. My mother Taaphunchis obtained by inheritance from her mother, Thatres daughter of Apollonius, a serving-maid Thaësis, daughter of a slave born in the house, called Taaphunchis. This slave she registered in the house to house census in the 9th year of the reign of the deified Alexander, and held the ownership and possession of her for herself. On one occasion, when conducting an inquiry concerning building-land and examining the documents in the local public archives, she discovered that a fraud had been committed. She saw that her maternal uncle Syrus son of Apollonius and his wife registered ... the children born to Thaësis, Apollonius and Harseis, and alienated the rights of lordship and ownership, which was ... and wrong, nay more it was (intolerable ?) that they should take away slaves which did not belong to them as if they were their own. ... (my mother) did not maintain silence about this fraud, (but presented a petition?) to Titianus Clodianus; and during her lifetime the ownership of Harseis and Apollonius and usufruct of them were undisputed, that is to say ... After my mother’s death . months ago, ... the heirs of the aforesaid ... (made) new (declarations) concerning the slaves...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
