<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 12, 1459</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21860</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21860</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21860</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;12;1459</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 12</note>
              To Aurelius Nemesion also called Dionysius, basilicogrammateus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, from Julius Horion, an honourably discharged veteran. I register for the present 5th year of Marcus Aurelius Severus Alexander Caesar the lord in accordance with the commands both of praefects and of Julius Sopater, ex-epistrategus, the unwatered and irrigated land which I own: in the area of the village of Palosis in the holding of Andron with that of Menestheus, entered to Petsiris son of Heracleüs, rated at 1 artaba, unwatered, 2 1/4 arurae; and in the same holding, entered to Heracleüs son of Petsiris, Crown-land unw.,..aru.; and in the holding of ..., entered to ..., unw., 1 aru.; and in the same holding, entered to ... son of Panechotes, rated at 1 1/2 artabae, unw., .. aru.; and in the remainder of Menestheus’ holding, entered to. .., unw., 33/64 aru.; and in the same holding, entered to ... son of Alexander, rated at 1 art., unw., .. aru.; and in the holding of ..., entered to Thatres daughter of Pausiris, rated at 1 art., unw., .. aru.; and in the same holding, entered to Sarapiades son of Ammonius, rated at 1(?) art., unw., 3 aru.; and in the remainder of Menestheus’ holding, entered to Thatres daughter of Aristander, rated at 1 art., unw., 1/2 aru.; and in the same holding, entered to Sarapiades son of Ammonius, rated at 1 1/2 and 1 art., unw., 5 1/3 aru.; and in the same holding, entered to Petsiris son of Panechotes, rated at 1 1/3 art., unw., 7/16 aru.; and in the same holding, entered to Petsiris son of Pausiris, rated at 1 art., unw., 3/8 aru.; and in the same holding, entered to Thermouthion daughter of Aristander, rated at 1 1/2 art., unw., 1 2/3 aru.; and in the remainder of Menestheus’ holding, entered to M. Petronius Priscus, rated at 1 art, unw., 2 1/2 aru.; and in the area of Nicostratou farmstead in the holding of Ptolemaeus and Philippus, entered to Petsiris son of Heracleiis, rated at 1 art., unw., 1 1/2 aru.; and in the same holding, entered to Onnophiris son of Petsiris, rated at 1 art., unw., 1 aru.; and in the area of Sepho in the holding of Parmenion, entered to Petsiris whose mother is Thaësis,Crown-land, irrigated, 1 aru. <note>Date and signature.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
