<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 12, 1469</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21870</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21870</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21870</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;12;1469</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 12</note>
              To Aemilius Rusticianus, the most illustrious deputy in the most eminent office of praefect, from the inhabitants of the village of Paimis in the western toparchy of the Oxyrhynchite nome, through us, the comarchs of the present year, the Aurelii Pibemis and Nemesianus. It is with difficulty, my lord, that even when justice is shown to us in commands concerning us we could accomplish in full our duties, since, if any advantage of us is taken, our weakness will leave us no escape. There is a public dyke to the south of our village, in which there is a gap and places washed away, naturally requiring embankment. This dyke was estimated by the public land-surveyor to require 400 naubia, and the overseer of labour on dykes set us, the local inhabitants, to work, and made us bank up 250 naubia. Nor was this all that was imposed upon our village, since it resulted in the overseer of dykes making us responsible for the whole 400 naubia; but when the distribution of earth for the said dykes was made by the assistant of the strategus, who came first, probably for the sake of base profit—for it is the practice of the public land-surveyor, being cognizant of the localities themselves, to assign the repairs of each dyke to the neighbouring population in accordance with the size of each village—he for gain, as I said, credited us with 100 naubia, although we had already banked up 250, clearly proposing to assign the remaining 150 naubia to others. Since the official entrusted with the dykes by the praefecture than whom there is no better witness, knows of the work done by us, and the unfairness of the assistant of the strategus is evident, we appeal to you by this petition, entreating you to order by your sacred signature whomsoever your highness may approve of, or the overseer of dykes, to measure the embankment again, and to credit us with the naubia which we have previously banked up on the said dyke, we being ready to perform any other work which you may choose for us in the locality to which we were ordered.
              We, the Aurelii Pibemis and Nemesianus, sent the petition to be presented. I, Aurelius Plution, wrote it on their behalf at their request, as they stated that they were illiterate. In the consulship of Anicius Paulinus for the second time and Virius Gallus.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
