<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 12, 1472</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21873</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21873</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21873</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;12;1472</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 12</note>
              To Apollinarius, strategus, from Heraclas also called Heraclides son of Heraclas, of Oxyrhynchus. A copy of the communication which I received from the record-office is appended.
              Demetrius also called Domitius, deputy-archidicastes, to the strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, greeting. Give instructions that a copy of the memorandum which has been presented be served, as follows. Good-bye. The 20th year of the Emperor Caesar Trajanus Hadrianus Augustus, Epeiph 5.
              To Aelianus son of the former exegetes Euphranor, neocoros of the great Sarapis, formerly praefect of the second cavalry cohort of the Commagenes, priest, archidicastes, and superintendent of the chrematistae and other courts, through Demetrius also called Domitius, exegetes-elect and deputy-archidicastes, from Heraclas also called Heraclides, son of Heraclas, of Oxyrhynchus. Whereas I am owed by Diogenes son of Heraclides son of Mincion, of the said city, in accordance with two written deeds of security made in the 12th year of Hadrianus Caesar the lord, the first in Thoth, for deposit, 24 1/2 artabae 9 choenices of barley by the public 1/2-artaba measure, and the second in Phamenoth of the said 12th year, likewise for deposit, 24 art. 3 choen. of wheat by the public 1/2-artaba measure, all of which he agreed to repay me whenever I choose, in addition to taxes on sale and assignment of land, and whereas the periods have elapsed and no repayment has been made and Diogenes has died leaving as his heir his son ..., I beg you to give instructions for a letter to be written to the strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, stating that he is to serve a copy of this memorandum upon...”
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
