<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 12, 1470</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21871</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21871</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21871</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;12;1470</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 12</note>
              The year after the consulship of Julius Constantius, patrician, brother of our master Constantinus Augustus, and Rufius Albinus, under the consuls to be appointed, Phamenoth.
              To ..., strategus (?) of the Oxyrhynchite nome, from Aurelia Theodora daughter of Eudaemon, formerly a veteran, of the said city. A copy of the petition which I presented, appealing to the nobility of my lord Philagrius, the most illustrious praefect of Egypt, and of the communication which I received from him ordering that his commands should be
              carried out, is as follows: “Flavius Philagrius to the strategus(?) of the Oxyrhynchite nome. Aurelia Theodora
              having presented a petition of which the copy is appended ..., See that ... if they acknowledge her claim it is restored to her, or if they object .... Farewell.” Copy of the petition.
              “To Flavius Philagrius, the most illustrious praefect of Egypt, from Aurelia Theodora daughter of Kudaemon also called ...,formerly a veteran, of Oxyrhynchus. My father in his lifetime bought from Pasipentoiis son of Melas, of the said city, in the area of the village of Sento of the Oxyrhynchite nome in the holding of Apollophanes, plot 109, registered in the name of Se.onius Pasis and Inaroous ..., one and a quarter arurae, 1 1/4 aru., of ... land, and paid him in full the price agreed upon ... in accordance with the sale which had been effected and had been arranged in my name. Somehow Demetrianus... Demetrianus, the brother of the man who sold the land to my father, hoping to alienate this land and despising my orphan condition. Wherefore I need your protection, most illustrious praefect, and beg you to give orders through ... Nilus(?), if you so decide, that the said Demetrianus should be compelled to restore the land to me ...,in order that I may by recovering it be enabled to ... Presented by me, Aurelia Theodora”.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
