<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 12, 1473</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21874</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21874</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21874</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;12;1473</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 12</note>
              ... drachmae at the interest of 1 drachma per mina each month, apart from the three talents and more paid by Apollonarion, including the dowry provided by her parents to Horion at the time of their marriage, which contract was discharged in the past 6th year in the month of Thoth through the bank of the Serapeum at Oxyrhynchus. With regard to her other debts at interest Apollonarion shall be responsible for them, delivering to Horion the documents of settlement until the rest of her debts are paid off. Both Apollonarion and Horion acknowledge the son born to them, who was also acknowledged in the deed of divorce, Chaeremon also called Faustus, aged 5 in the present 7th year. Let the parties to the marriage therefore live together blamelessly, as they did formerly, observing the marriage-rights, and let the husband provide the wife with necessaries according to his means; but if, which heaven forbid, they part from each other owing to a dispute, if this takes place before Horion recovers the aforesaid 2 talents 3,000 drachmae and the accrued interest, Horion shall take the revenues of Apollonarion’s property until he recovers the debt, paying the taxes upon them, and for subsistence providing Apollonarion annually with 50 artabae of wheat by the aforesaid measure and 55 jars of wine, and shall repay the other creditors who may appear up to that time. But from the date on which all the debts are paid off, thenceforth Apollonarion shall take her own property, all the provisions of the contract being observed. This contract is valid, and when ever the parties to the marriage or one of them choose they shall effect the publication of it, both parties being responsible for the taxes and scribes’ charges. The 7th year of the Emperors Caesars L. Septimius Severus Pius Pertinax Arabicus Adiabenicus Parthicus Maximus and M. Aurelius Antoninus Augusti, Pharmouthi 13. The copy of the request for a guardian is as follows: Ammonianus basilicogrammateus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, deputy-strategus. If there is no objection, no public or private interests being injured, you are at liberty, as you request, since you know how to write, to employ Eudaemon as your guardian for this transaction only. Signed. The 7th year of L. Septimius, etc., Pharmouthi.. To Ammonianus, basilicogrammateus and deputy-strategus, from Apollonarion daughter of Chaeremon ..., of Oxyrhynchus, her mother being Carpocra... As I know how to write, and am making a marriage-contract with my former husband Horion son of Hierax, ex-exegetes of Oxyrhynchus, by the terms of which Horion obtains security for the sums which he lent me and paid in the past 6th year into the public bank on account of the revenue of vine-land ... demanded from me. and further am acknowledging with him the son born to us jointly, Chaeremon also called Faustus, together with the other provisions concerning our cohabitation to be inserted in the contract by joint agreement, I request that you may appoint as my guardian for this transaction only Fudaemon son of Agenor also called Theoxenus, son of Apollonius, his mother being Taeus also called Demetrous,of the said city, who is present and gives his consent. I have paid the prescribed tax for my request. The 7th year etc., Pharmouthi 1. I, Apollonarion daughter of Chaeremon, have presented the application. I, Eudaemon son of Agenor, consent to it. I, Apollonarion daughter of Chaeremon, have been united to my former husband Horion in marriage, and have received the 2 1/2 talents, total 15,000 drachmae, of silver, and consent to all the aforesaid terms. I, Eudaemon son of Agenor, at her request have been appointed guardian of Apollonarion. I, Horion son of Hierax, have been united to Apollonarion in marriage upon all the aforesaid terms, and have agreed, whenever, which heaven forbid, we are divorced, to give Apollonarion the right of inhabiting her paternal house in the quarter of the Tenth.
              And whereas I desire this contract to be publicly registered, I give to the city, because it is single and does not contain the provisions concerning the disposition (?), the prescribed 12 drachmae, and request you on receiving it from me with my attestation that the signatures appended to it are autographs, the first of Apollonarion, the second of her guardian and co-signatory, the last of myself, Horion, to register it together with this application, the original at the Library of Hadrian and a copy of it at the Library of the Nanaeum, and to give instructions for a letter to be written to the strategus of the Oxyrhynchite nome, stating that he is to serve a copy of this application upon Apollonarion, in order that she may herself know that henceforth the rights in virtue of it are assured to me, as by a public deed.
              This being so, I request that it be served upon Apollonarion in the proper way. The 9th year etc., Pauni 10.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
