<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 12, 1475</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">21876</idno>
            <idno type="TM">21876</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">21876</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;12;1475</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 12</note>
              Aurelius Gaius also called Harpocration, priest and archidicastes, to the keepers of the property-registers of the Oxyrhynchite nome, greeting. A copy of the communication which has been executed follows. Good-bye. The 14th year of Gallienus Augustus, Pharmouthi 18, The examiner-in-chief of the city: she has paid (?), Aurelius Alexander acting.
              To Aurelius Gaius also called Harpocration, priest, archidicastes, and superintendent of the chrematistae and other courts, from Aurelia Thaisous also called Lolliane. A copy of the publication which has been executed follows.
              To Aurelius Gaius, etc., from Aurelia Thaïsous also called Lolliane, daughter of Sarapion also called Agathodaemon, ex-agoranomus of Oxyrhynchus. A copy of the bond issued to me in duplicate with the signature succeeding the date follows.
              “Aurelius Agathinus also called Origenes, son of Varianus also called Clarus and Origenia also called Tauris, of Oxyrhynchus, to Aurelia Tharsous also called Lolliane, daughter of Sarapion also called Agathodaemon, ex-agoranomus of the said city, and of Dionysia also called Diaena, of the said city, acting without a guardian by the ius liberorum, greeting. I acknowledge that I have sold and ceded to you from the present time for ever the property below written, which is mine by right of purchase and formerly belonged to you the buyer, in the area of the village of Païmis in the western toparchy of the said Oxyrhynchite nome in the holding of Nicon also called Nicomedes, consisting of 11 arurae of corn-bearing and other land, in which is a tank in disrepair and the water-wheel likewise partly in disrepair with the apparatus belonging to it, the adjacent areas of the whole being on the south and west a canal, etc., on the north land formerly belonging to Julius Theon, on the east the buildings, open spaces, and existing orchard mentioned below, and in the said village in the northern and western parts of it two houses with al their fittings and appurtenances and the open spaces to the north and west of these with the intervening orchard which is now dry, of the extent of 13/16 arura more or less, and the existing well, the adjacent areas of these buildings, open spaces, and orchard, when they are surveyed in one piece, being on the south the parts of the metropolis along the desert, on the north the circumference of the village, on the east a hawk-shrine, on the west the aforesaid corn-land, in all respects according to just sale and cession. And I have herewith received from you from hand to hand in full the sum jointly agreed upon for the price and cession-money of al the aforesaid property, 9,700 drachmae of Imperial silver coin, making 1 talent 3,700 drachmae of silver. Wherefore you and your descendants and heirs are masters and owners of the property ceded by me as aforesaid, and have power to use and administer it as you choose, and I am bound to deliver it to you guaranteed and free from claims in my name only or by any one else in my name, you being satisfied with the guarantee from yourself to me concerning all charges up to and including the past 13th year, because the products of the property from the present 14th year henceforth belong to you the buyer, who are also responsible for the taxes beginning with the calends of the said 14th year. This sale and cession, written in duplicate, is valid, and whenever you choose you may publish it through the record-office without requiring further concurrence on my part, because I hereby concur in the publication to be made by you; and having been asked by you the formal question whether this is done rightly and fairly I have given my consent. The 14th year of P. Licinius Gallienus, etc., Hathur 23. I, Aurelius Agathinus also called Origenes, have sold and ceded to Lolliane also called Thaisous the aforesaid property and al the constructions appertaining to it, and have received the 1 talent 3,700 drachmae of silver for the price, and will guarantee the property from claims in my name only, and I consent to the publication to be made by you, and in answer to the formal question have given my consent.”
              Wishing that one copy of this duplicate bond should be made public, I pay to the city the prescribed 12 drachmae and the sum prescribed for the publication, and request that, on receipt of the bond from the person whom I have dispatched, Aurelius Nilus, with his attestation that the signature after the date is the autograph of Aurelius Agathinus also called Origenes, you will register the original with this application in the Library of Hadrian, and a copy of it with the application in the Library of the Nanacum, in order that the rights derived from it may be assured to me, as from a public deed, because Aurelius Agathinus also called Origenes has consented to the publication of the bond. The 14th year of Gallienus Augustus, Phamenoth 24.
              And whereas I desire that this should be communicated to the keepers of the property-registers of the Oxyrhynchite nome, I request that, on receipt ofthe aforesaid publication duly signed, you will give instructions for a letter to be written to them for their information.
              Let due steps be taken. The 14th year of Gallienus Augustus, Phamenoth 27.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
