<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Rein. 2, 103</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">23022</idno>
            <idno type="TM">23022</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">23022</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;2;178 bgu;2;583 c.pap.gr;1;14 sb;5;7619 p.rein;2;103</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-11-12T13:21:52.384-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-11-12T13:21:52.333-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:56:54.977-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from Rylands catalogue, updated by Roberta Mazza (University of Manchester)</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:53:02-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <p>
               <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> The 12th year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, Pachon 26th, in the city of Oxyrhynchus, Thebaid. Taseus, daughter of Peteeus, Persian of the Epigone, with her husband Petsiris, son of Horus, Persian of the Epigone, who is also her guardian and surety for the fulfilment of all the terms of this contract, both residents of the village of Tanais in the middle toparchy, enter into an agreement with Paapes, son of Phlias, in the street , that they have received from him on the 17th of the present month of Pachon the female child to whom he has given the name Thermoutharion, whom he picked up from a dung heap to rear as a slave. Taseus is to rear and suckle it with her own milk, and is to care for it for a term of 2 years from the present 17th of Pachon, in return for the agreement made by Paapes to provide food and clothing and all other expenses incurred for the child paying therefor 60 drachmae a year. Taseus further acknowledges that she together with her husband Petsiris, who is also her surety, has received 60 dr. in advance for the first year in cash from his house. At the end of this year Paapes will pay at once 60 drachmae in silver for the second year, and further he agrees to provide 2 cotylae of oil per month for the 2 years. Accordingly Taseus will of necessity provide every assistance and care for the child as is incumbent on heris her duty . She will not have intercourses with her husband so as not to harm the milk, nor will she become pregnant, nor suckle any other child nor … (PRyl 178) and she shall give back the child to Paapes well nourished as is incumbent upon her. If the child suffers any fatality which is plainly accidental, Taseus will be held blameless, and if Paapes picks up another child to put in her care, she shall nurse it for the remaining period on the aforesaid terms; but if she does not wish to do so, she shall repay whatever she appears to owe for the term of nursing which still remains. If she violates the contract made in these terms she shall repay to Paapes what she has received from him in silver, with an addition of 50% and 200 dr. as compensation for damages and penalty and an equal sum to the fiscus. Paapes shall have the right of exaction from the aforesaid parties and from whichever one he chooses and from all their property. This agreement is valid. (2nd hand) I, Taseus, daughter of Peteeus, have concluded the agreement. I shall nourish the infant Thermoutharion for 2 years. I have received 60 dr. in silver for its support, and I shall perform all the provisions of the aforesaid contract. I, Petsiris, son of Horus, have subscribed to this document as guardian of my wife and I am her surety for the fulfilment of the above conditions. Heraclides, son of Theon, wrote on their behalf as they are unlettered. (3rd hand) Paapes, son of Philas, consents to the above contract. (4th hand) … honey-coloured, roundfaced, with a scar on the right knee.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
