<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Flor. 1, 93</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">23587</idno>
            <idno type="TM">23587</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">23587</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.flor;1;93dupl chr.mitt;;297</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2023-01-26T10:26:49-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Finalized - Ready.</change>
         <change when="2023-01-25T10:05:38-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Looks good.</change>
         <change when="2022-09-14T07:17:50-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/marianowak">Submit - New translation created</change>
         <change when="2022-09-14T07:17:29-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> χμγ 9
<milestone n="2" rend="break" unit="line"/> † In the fourth year of the reign and consulship of our divinissimus lord Flavius Justin the eternal Augustus Emperor, eighth Thoth of the third indiction in the most glorious Antinoopolis.
<milestone n="4" unit="line"/> On the one part Aurelia Amaresia, daughter of Proous, the trader, of the mother Fania, hailing from the fair city of Antinoopolis, and on the other part Aurelius Theodoros, son of Georgios, 
from the mother Nonna, hired baker, hailing from the same Antinoopolis, conclude and make jointly and willingly this written agreement to each other in two identical copies, 
the following as stated verbatim:
<milestone n="10" rend="break" unit="line"/> Long ago we were united with each other in marriage and shared life, n view of conceiving good legitimate children, believing we would live a peaceful, noble married life, 
during the whole time of our shared life; on the contrary, we do not know how we, beyond expectation, suffered by the wicked evil having attacked us, to separate from each other. 
<milestone n="14" unit="line"/> For this reason we have resorted to the present repudium acknowledging that we have no claim against each other, presently or in the future, from now and forever, 
concerning any matter written or unwritten, adjudicated or not, neither concerning the union of marriage and its bridal gifts and dowry and marriage expenses 
nor about household utensils which were brought in for each other by each other, nor concerning any matter in general, 
<milestone n="19" unit="line"/> but also that I, the aforementioned Theodoros give up what is shared between us for the children (we had) so far together with the baby in the womb, 
my inhabited house, together with all its legal rights and my things which belong to it, except for my bed and my clothes;
<milestone n="23" unit="line"/> and we acknowledge that each part of us be allowed to be united in a different marriage, if they may wish, necessarily without hinder or dispute, 
and may no one be able to lay claim against the other in any way or at any time or place for whatever reason in any court or out of court, concerning any matter in general, 
so that we be set free and break up from each other vigorously and completely, <milestone n="27" unit="line"/> and if any of us dares to lay claim against the other, 
they will be issued a fine of six gold solidi of full weight, as well as the same party shall necessarily abide with all the above written, 
and having been asked the formal question on all points we gave our consent. † <note>Translation: Law in Social Networks Project (Warsaw)</note>

            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
