<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 3, 505</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">23689</idno>
            <idno type="TM">23689</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">23689</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;505</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 3</note>
              Ophelas also called Besas son of Sarapas and Apollonous, of Oxyrhynchus, appointed as a representative by Artemidorus son of Amenneus son of Artemas, his mother being Thakoris daughter of Amenneus, also of Oxyrhynchus, by the terms of a deed of representation drawn up through the registry-office at Oxyrhynchus in the present month, of which a copy is appended, to Eudaemonis also called Plutarche stated as the daughter of Sinthonis daughter of Pekusis, and her mother Sinthonis daughter of Pekusis and Teenkegous, both of Tanais, jointly, each with her guardian, in the case of Eudaemonis also called Plutarche, Ammonius also called Dionysius son of Ammonius and Harasis, of Oxyrhynchus, and in that of Sinthonis, her full brother Pachnubis, greeting. I acknowledge that I have sold to you of the paternal house and yard and adjoining court which belong to the aforesaid Artemidorus, whom I represent, at the said city in the quarter of Pammenes’ Garden, of the said court in the eastern portion of it 50 square cubits extending from north to south as far as the end of the whole court and from east to west as far as the said 50 square cubits reach. The adjacent areas of the portion of the court sold to you by me, by survey 50 cubits, are, on the south the land of Diogenes and others, on the north that of Sarapion stated as the son of Thaisous, on the east that of Lucius Herennius Crispus and others, on the west the remaining walls of the said court. The sum mutually agreed upon between us as the price of the said land sold to you by me, by survey 50 square cubits, namely 500 drachmae of Imperial silver coin, I have received on the spot from you from hand to hand in full...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
