<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 8, 1153</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">25927</idno>
            <idno type="TM">25927</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">25927</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;8;1153</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-31" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 8</note>
              Apollonius to his son Apollonius, greeting. I have received through Heraclas the boxes with the books, as you write, and the half-chous jar of oil which Nicanor writes that he has sent. Tell Nicanor that Heraclas the boatman ... to pay us the 600 drachmae for his freights; he was here to-day; I found the boat sailing down and I thought that I ought to let you know about what I have said. You will receive through Origas two variegated (?) wrist-bands, one scarlet and one purple, which your brother Pausanias went to the expense of having made some time ago and presented to you; write and acknowledge their receipt. If I can buy a cloak for you privately, I will send it at once, if not, I will have it made for you athome. The blankets have been cut out; the account of them, as you write, shall be sent by Diogas to Nicanor through Heraclas. A pattern of the colour of the dress that is being made is enclosed in this letter; give it to Nicanor to look at, in order that, if he likes it, he may write to us, for it has not yet been given out. We are going to use local purple. Good-bye. Mecheir 6. <note>Address on verso.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
