<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 3, 498</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">28356</idno>
            <idno type="TM">28356</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">28356</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;498</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 3</note>
              Copy. To Antonia Asclepias also called Cyria, through her guardian Apollonius, from Asclas son of Alexandrus and Apollonius son of Amois, his mother being Tauris, both of Oxyrhynchus. We undertake to cut the squared building-stones transportable by camel (?) from the northern quarry required for the house of you, Antonia, in the quarter of Pammenes’ Garden, the rate of wages for the stone-cutting being for the outer squared camel stones at 4 drachmae for 16, for the inner ones at 4 drachmae for 30, for ἀντιβλήματα at 3 drachmae for 100 squared camel stones, and for oblong corner-stones at 8 drachmae for 16 outer squared camel stones and at 8 drachmae for 30 inner squared camel stones, and for chipped squared camel stones at 4 drachmae for 50 and for chipped oblong squared camel corner-stones at 8 drachmae for 50. All the aforesaid stones we will cut, but no ornamentation shall be required of us. Each of us shall receive for each day that he works both a loaf and relish. If the builders have need of our services in stone-cutting, we or one of us will provide them, each of us receiving as wages for each day’s services 4 drachmae, and likewise each of us on each day a loaf and relish. Until the 22nd of the present month Epeiph you have the right to transfer to others this contract for cutting the aforesaid squared camel stones from the northern quarry...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
