<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 3, 522</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">28362</idno>
            <idno type="TM">28362</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">28362</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;3;522</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-18" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 3</note>
              Account :— for the vessel of Triadelphus 3400 artabae of wheat at 21 drachmae (per 100) 712 dr. To the same at 4 drachmae per 1000 12 dr. Carriage of 171 artabae of wheat transported ... the drying-place at 4 dr. per 100 6 dr. Price of a jar (of wine) sent to the assistants and soldier 8 dr. 1 obol. To the elders of Ophis for the wages of 11 workmen employed in lading 6 dr. 2 obols. To Aphunchis, guard of the granary, as his salary since Tubi 18 dr. more. Total of expenditure 762 dr. 3 obols, of which 1/2 is (381 dr. 1 1/2 obols). For the vessel of Horion son of Ammonius 1500 artabae and for the vessel of Pausiris son of Apollonius 500 artabae, total 2000 artabae, at 21 dr. (per 100) 420 dr. Payment to Horion, pilot, the sum given, 8 dr. Price of a jar sent to the assistants and the soldier 8 dr. 1 obol. Price of 2 more jars sent to the sailors 16 dr. 2 obols. Price of vegetables for the same, without bread, 4 obols. To the elders of Ophis for the wages of 7 workmen employed in lading 4 dr. To 1 workman assisting beyond (?) the 1/2 artaba and embarking (?) corn for 3 1/2 days 5 dr. Total of expenditure 466 dr., of which 1/2 is (233 dr.). Sum of the whole expenditure 1228 dr. 3 obols, of which 1/2 is 614 dr. 2 obols. To Dioscoras 3 obols, for which he shall render an account. Price of 2 jars expended upon us alone from Phamenoth 27 to Pharmouthi 15 16 dr. 2 obols. Expense of... together with the price of oil for the same period 8 dr. 4 obols.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
