<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 12, 1482</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">28994</idno>
            <idno type="TM">28994</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">28994</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;12;1482</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 12</note>
              Morus to my lord Epimachus, greeting. I write to inform you that we have winnowed the barley of the man from the Oasis on the 8th, and we never had so much trouble in winnowing it; for it rained and the wind was irresistible, and Panares knows how we worked to succeed in transferring all the rest with the help of the gods. The total result was 38 artabae 4 choenices; of these I have disposed beforehand of 12 1/2 art. 8 choen. I made inquiries about the price of annual grass: it was sold in the village at 7 drachmae the load, as Panares too knows. After many inquiries I found some that was dry, and not to be paid for in ready money, but after four months. You will examine the question how you are to transport it, and, if you please, write to me about this, and say what proportion I am to dispose of beforehand from the large holding, and whether you want me to mix what belongs to the man from the Oasis with the rest. I have stored my share in the room belonging to your father. I supplicate on behalf of you and al your children and all your brothers and ... I pray for your health, my lord.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
