<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Dion., 10</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">3093</idno>
            <idno type="TM">3093</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">3093</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.dion;;10</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-07-18T20:47:34-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp263–264)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T20:44:40-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp263–264)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T20:44:12-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp263–264)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T20:43:42-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Commit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp263–264)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T20:35:58-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> To Nikanor and the synphylakitai of Kirka, from Pasis, also known as ..ges, son of Kephalas, of the mercenary cavalry under Demetrios 
from Libyan Akoris. On the night of the 13th of Hathyr, year 9, certain individuals, breaking into my house in a thievish manner, 
on the same night (?) despoiled those inhabiting it and made off with not only the agricultural tools, but also the other items in the same location, 
of which an itemized list is appended. Since, therefore, I suspect that the attack was orchestrated by Konnos, a Kynopolite, as he happens 
to live in the house of Aithon, and others along with him, whose names I do not know, I submit to you this notification so that the guilty, 
having been hunted down, may be sent to the stratêgos, so that the lost items may be returned to me, and the guilty may meet with consequences. 
And if this occurs, I shall be…. Farewell. Year 9, Hathyr 16.
This is the itemized list:
Belonging to Sotionchis: a chiton and a himation and a sack.
Belonging to Plenis, his brother: a chiton, 1 plow, 1 yoke.
Belonging to Paptutis: a chiton and a sack.
And belonging to those who were visiting from out of town: himations.
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp263–264)
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
