<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 7, 1068</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">31315</idno>
            <idno type="TM">31315</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">31315</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;7;1068</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-24" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 7</note>
              Satornilus to my lord Apollonius, greeting. Finding no boat available in the Arsinoïte nome I wrote to my lord Clematius the chief priest that he might send me a boat and so I might be able to carry the body down to Alexandria; and he sent me a skiff of sixty artabae burden, The brethren who brought it received letters also from Clematius to the intent that no one in the neighbourhood should trouble them(?). So on going up to the Arsinoïte nome they found the body not yet ready to be buried, and I have a delay of some days. They therefore determined on account of a pressing need to go to Toou. So I urge you, my lord, to supply them with the marks of your good will, that on their return they may testify of it to me, and with anything else they may need from you for Simias’ sake (for you sent for the ass and they kept it), until I come to you. I beg you then, my lord, to give them a letter in order that no one may trouble them on the road, and so I may be able to bury the body and come to you. I pray for your lasting health. (Addressed) Deliver to Apollonius from Satornilus.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
