<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 7, 1070</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">31317</idno>
            <idno type="TM">31317</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">31317</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;7;1070</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-24" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 7</note>
              Aurelius Demareus to his sister Aurelia Arsinoë, greeting. The prayer which I previously made to all the gods for the preservation of yourself and our child and your brother and father and mother and all our friends now goes up to them with far greater force in the great Serapeum, and I beseech the great god Serapis for your life and that of all our friends and for the good hopes that are held by mankind. I think it superfluous to write to you about our business and affairs concerning which I have written to you often before in many letters and have equally given you instructions in person; for you yourself as the mother of our child will be more eager than I am that those affairs should be studied and advanced with unsurpassed sollicitude. But before all study the care and regard of yourself, as I have often written to you about this also, sparing nothing that we have. I send you by Dionysius, who ... either in ... or in the ... the neighbour of the house of Apollonius, six cotylae of Siretic (?) oil in a half-chous jar, and one basket full of sweetmeats. Two petitions which were presented by Xenophas from Apollonius son of Scopas and his son-in-law Stephanus, who is at the city, against your father and mother—of these too I send copies in the bundle of letters. If therefore you meet and come to any conclusion about them let me know quickly, and anything that I thought I could do, being here, I will not neglect (?). Nothing has happened up to now about our affairs, I pray for your health.... Do not at present send me any supplies until I let you know or write to you about this, Greet and salute all our friends severally. I thank you very much for this that, although I have often written to you, you have not written at all nor remembered me in regard to the safety of our house, as I often by notes and letters and when with you in person enjoined on you to do. Do not neglect this, lest indeed you choose to hand over the keeping of the whole house to Heraïs, who is unworthy, along with yourself, and, what heaven forbid, we find ourselves at sixes and sevens. The slave of Ptolemaeus, the brother of Hermogenes, has been journeying to Alexandria and has often come to me, but you have not been willing to give him letters and have not sent him to me at all, but Eudaemon parted with him saying “At present we are not at leisure and are visiting others.” (Addressed) Deliver to my sister Arsinoé from Demareus.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
