<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 7, 1069</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">31316</idno>
            <idno type="TM">31316</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">31316</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;7;1069</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-24" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 7</note>
              Troïlus to his sister Maz, greeting. You will do well to have my white tunic made quickly in order that I may find it made if I come to you. I have written to Heraclides also so that you may receive my tools(?) and the wages of the weavers; and I wish to know how you are hurrying on the making of it. The purple is put with the tools. Be careful to send the letter to Thermouthion at Alexandria, for we may be able to load two camels with wheat for you and to send them to you. Make my slave-girl be properly industrious; and if Tamoun bear a child make her be assiduous with it. Be careful to have my tunic made properly, and let them put good measure into it, and be large-handed in the colouring. Buy a donkey for Nicetes in order that he may be able to accomplish your business; and reply to me if you want anything. I salute Heras. I pray for your health. P.S. I have written to Heraclides to give Tamoun 3,000 drachmae. (Addressed) From Troïlus to his sister Maz.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
