<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 1, 41</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">31338</idno>
            <idno type="TM">31338</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">31338</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;1;41</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 1</note> ...When the assembly had met, (the people cried)-... “the Roman power for ever! lords Augusti! prosperous praefect, prosperity to our ruler! Hail, ... president, glory of the city, ... Dioscorus, chief of the citizens! under you our blessings increase evermore, source of our blessings, ... Prosperity to the patriot, prosperity to the lover of right! Source of our blessings, founder of the city! ... Let the president receive the vote on this great day! Many votes do you deserve, for many are the blessings which we enjoy through you, O president. This petition we make to our ruler about the president, with good wishes to our ruler, asking for the city’s president, beneficent ruler, for the city’s founder, lords Augusti for ever,—this petition to our ruler about the president, for the honest man’s governor, the equitable governor, the city’s governor, the city’s patron, the city’s benefactor, the city’s founder, prosperous praefect, prosperous ruler, beneficent ruler, beneficent praefect! We beseech you, ruler, concerning the president; let the president receive the vote, let the president receive the vote on this great day! This is the first necessity.” The president said:—“I acknowledge with great pleasure the honour which you do me, but I beg that these demonstrations be reserved for a legitimate occasion when you may make them with safety and I shall be justified in accepting them.” The people cried, “Many votes do you deserve ... the Roman power for ever! Prosperous praefect, protector of honest men, our ruler! We ask, ruler, for the city’s president, the city’s benefactor, the city’s founder! We beseech you, ruler, preserve the city for our lords! beneficent ruler, we beseech you for the city’s well-wisher, the city’s patriot!” Aristion the advocate said :—“We will refer this matter to the most high council.” The people:—“We ask, ruler, for the city’s patron, the city’s founder, upright general, peace of the city! O... Dioscorides, chief of the citizens! O... Seuthes, chief of the citizens, equitable governor, equitable citizen! True and upright advocates, true and upright assessors! Hurrah for all who love the city. Long live the lords Augusti !”’
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
