<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 1, 118</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">31345</idno>
            <idno type="TM">31345</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">31345</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;1;118</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 1</note> Saras and Eudaemon to Diogenes the younger, greeting. We have been advised by the most notable Ammonion to send for a ferry-boat on account of the uncertainty of the road. We accordingly send you this message, in order that, if they consent to send while you are there, you may procure what is necessary, and if not, that you may dispatch a report to the strategus and the guardians of the peace. You know what hospitality requires, so get a little .. . from the priests and buy some incense and... We hear that you have been two days at Heracleopolis. Make haste back to look after your charge, when you have obtained what you went for. It is no use if a person comes too late for what required his presence. Ammonas and Dioscorus the cooks have gone to the Oxyrhynchite nome on the understanding that they would return at once. As they are delaying, and might be wanted, please send them off immediately.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
