<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 1, 120</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">31346</idno>
            <idno type="TM">31346</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">31346</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;1;120</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 1</note>
               
               Recto.
               
               Hermias to his sister, greeting. What remains to write to you about I do not know, for I have told you of everything till I am tired, and yet you pay no attention. When a man finds himself in adversity he ought to give way and not fight stubbornly against fate. We fail to realize the inferiority and wretchedness to which we are born. Well, so far nothing at all has been done; make it your business to send some one to me, either Gunthus or Ammonius, to stay with me until I know the position of my affairs, Am I to be distracted and oppressed until Heaven takes pity on me? Hermias is anxious to come to you. I requested him to stay, but he refused, saying that he had pressing business and that he must go, and that his son Gennadius was unable to attend to the property, especially as he was a stranger to the place and was engaged at his post. See that matters are properly conducted on your own part, or our disasters will be complete. We are resolved not to continue in misfortune (?). Farewell; I wish you all prosperity.
               
               Verso.
               
               Hermias to his son Gunthus, greeting. Unless Ammonius comes to me at once, put off everything or let him do your work and come yourself. Whatever you do, do not fail me in my trouble. Let me know how it was with Didymus. Can time accomplish everything after all? I pray for your health.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
