<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 8, 1158</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">31724</idno>
            <idno type="TM">31724</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">31724</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;8;1158</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-31" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 8</note>
              To my brother Diodorus, many greetings from Lucius and Sarapion. Before all else we pray for your prosperity and that of your whole house. Many times in the day we expect you to come to us. It would be kind of you to go to Aretion the baker and obtain from him four talents which he had from us when he was at Alexandria. See that you do not neglect this. If you get the four talents from him, when you come to us, buy us some provisions for our use and obtain stores and send them to us. You must know that I have written to Aretion to give you the four talents. As you said that you wish for ..., I will send it you when it is brought. I got the Cnidian jar of vinegar from Ammonas, and I have sent you by him a basket of dainties anda... We greet our sister and her daughter Helenous and her daughter. Greet Aphunchis and Techosis and Ptolemaeus from us. If you learn that Aretion is going to accuse you about the copper, write to me and I will send him an addition. I pray for your lasting health. <note>Address.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
