<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 10, 1275</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">31729</idno>
            <idno type="TM">31729</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">31729</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;10;1275</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 10</note>
              The Aurelii Onnophris son of Ammonius and Thaisous, Aphunchis son of Heraclas and Tausiris, Hermogenes son of Dionysius and Heraclous, ...sis son of Philotas and Aristous, and ...son of Ammonius, all five presidents of the village of Souis, and Copreus son of Sarapammon, chief of a company of flute-players and musicians, mutually acknowledge that on the one hand Onnophris and his associates have engaged Copreus with his company to perform for the inhabitants of the aforesaid village for five festal days beginning on the tenth of Phamenoth of the present 2nd year at the daily pay of one hundred and forty drachmae, forty pairs of loaves, and eight cotylae of raphanus-oil, and for the whole five days one jar of wine and one jar of vinegar; and on the other hand Copreus forthwith acknowledges that he has received as earnest-money twenty-drachmae. Onnophris and his associates shall receive Copreus and his company from the Oxyrhynchite nome with ten asses, and shall transport them to the aforesaid village ...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
