<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 8, 1160</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">31726</idno>
            <idno type="TM">31726</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">31726</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;8;1160</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-31" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 8</note>
              To my revered father Origenes, many greetings from Trophimus. Before all else I send many salutations to you and your consort Copria and Isidorus and Phullon and Helene and all our friends severally. You wrote to me in your letter that my boastfulness earns me the name of “Gift of Zeus” because I sent you money; but I do not boast about what I sent you by Philoxenus. If you have sold the various things which I sent you, write to me in order that I may send you more. I have been idle here for two months, otherwise I would have sent you all some more. I am keeping for the trial the money that I have collected; for I am waiting for the memoranda. You wrote to me, “Petition against Polydeuces.” If the memoranda come to me, I will petition against him and against Sarapodorus. If it seems good to you, send me a pot of oil. You wrote to me “You are staying at Alexandria with your paramour”. Write and tell me, who is my paramour. I pray for your health. (Addressed) Deliver to Origenes from Trophimus.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
