<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 12, 1415</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">31740</idno>
            <idno type="TM">31740</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">31740</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;12;1415</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 12</note>
              The prytanis said, “... and it is read to you.” Two communications from the strategus having been read, one concerning the appointment of a substitute for Actiasion, senator (?), son of ..., convoying collectors of wine, who had absconded, the other concerning the appointment likewise of a substitute for Theon, senator, son of ..., convoying from Arabia (?) collectors of barley, who had absconded, after the reading the prytanis said, “... Appoint persons to do the duty, in order that the carriage of the annona for the most noble soldiers may not be hindered.” The senators said, “Let ... not be (nominated) beforehand ..., lest they run away.” The prytanis said, “On this point we will refer to his excellency the epistrategus, and we will also add a statement concerning ..., and concerning a collector of wine in place of Aristion, who has been released by his excellency the epistrategus in another memorandum.” The senators said, “... Aristion, when he comes, will prosper; a prosperous public servant was Aristion.” The prytanis said, “Appoint the persons to office, in order that there may be no delay ...” The senators said, “The surety of ... was already (?) deposited with the strategus, the sureties of Actiasion and Theon were deposited with the strategus.” The prytanis said, ...
              The prytanis said, “... and it is read to you.” A communication from the strategus having been read concerning ..., and one from the banker of public moneys concerning the appointment of a substitute for Pasion, who ..., after the reading the senators said, “Let the prytanis nominate a richer person.” The prytanis said, ...
              ... Communications from ...esus having been read concerning ..., after the reading the prytanis said, “... were appointed to a public office although they already held such offices.” The senators said, ... The prytanis said, “Fill up the office, appoint ..., nominate whom you will.” The members of the .. tribe said, ... Eudaemon, exegetes, said (?), “Ptolemaeus (cannot?) remain in the public office ...” Ptolemaeus son of Damarion, chief-priest, said, “I entreat you, I cannot serve. I am aman of moderate means, I live in my father’s house, ...” The prytanis said, “Ptolemaeus still requires to be pressed by you, for he too shrinks from so great an office...” Eudaemon, exegetes, said, “Ptolemaeus too is a man of moderate means and unable to bear the burden ...” Ptolemaeus son of Damarion,chief-priest, said, “The office is beyond my powers.” The prytanis said, “Even if Ptolemaeus ... in another office (?), he cannot refuse you with regard to the post of public banker. It is, however, clear that it is not permitted ...” The senators said, “Upright, faithful Ptolemaeus ...” Ptolemaeus son of Damarion, chief-priest, said, “I entreat you, I cannot undertake two public offices at one time...” Eudaemon, exegetes, said, “Ptolemaeus has often given an example of his loyalty.” The prytanis said, “... I propose him to you.” The senators said, “Ptolemaeus will not refuse his tribe...” Eudaemon, exegetes, said, “You elected him on account of his good faith.”
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
