<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Tyche 35 (2020) S. 196</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">321597</idno>
            <idno type="TM">321597</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">321597</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">tyche;35;196</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2023-05-11T18:28:06-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
<p><milestone n="1" unit="line"/> To Publius Calvisius Patrophilus, vir egregius, iuridicus, <milestone n="3" unit="line"/> from Pamphilos alias Sokrates and Soterichos alias Dioskourides and Anoubiaine alias Achillis, all
three children of Asklepiades, son of Pamphilos, of the Sosikosmian tribe and Althaean deme, through their dispatched friend Ptolemaios, son of Diodoros.
<milestone n="7" unit="line"/> Since we are young and, standing in need of your exceeding hatred-of-evil, our lord, we have sent you this petition reporting the events from the beginning.
For when he was still alive, our aforementioned father borrowed from Kapitolinos son of Diodoros three thousand and five hundred drachmas already in 
the fourth year of the deified Hadrian, <milestone n="14" unit="line"/> and later, in the ninth year, the same father returned out of the principal 1,700 drachmas and the interest of the entire
principal in full, so that out of the 3,500 drachmas he (Kapitolinos) was still owed 1,800 drachmas. And after that, as long as he was still alive, our said father
continued making payments on account of the interest bit by bit. <milestone n="19" unit="line"/> And after he had died, in the twentieth year, we too have regularly paid until now in as much as
it was possible. Since, then, the aforesaid Kapitolinos was also long dead, leaving as heir his brother Ptolemaios, we continued to make payments to that person
in the same manner as well, so that what our father has paid back on account of the interest of the aforementioned 1,800 drachmas, and what we have paid on
the same debt, totals on account of interest 4,900 drachmas and more. <milestone n="29" rend="break" unit="line"/> But Ptolemaios reckons fraudulently, and [not acknowledging the payment that was
discharged in the ninth year?] of the deified Hadrian...</p>
</div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
