<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Enteux., 25</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">3300</idno>
            <idno type="TM">3300</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">3300</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.enteux;;25</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-07-16T19:33:04-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp198–199)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-16T19:31:06-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp198–199)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-16T19:30:45-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp198–199)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-16T19:30:27-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Commit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp198–199)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-16T19:28:26-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> To king Ptolemy, greetings, Pappos. I am wronged by Strouthos, my son. For although I taught him… and grammar… 
when I became older… and not… for him to take care (of me?)… to Dioskourides, your agent… in Arsinoë… that he would provide me 
with an artaba of grain per month and 4 drachmas, in which I myself (?) also… he did not give me any of the agreed-upon things, but… 
whenever he meets me, he reviles me most shamefully, and abusing me (physically)… into my house, he always seizes a box of my things (?), 
looking down upon me because I am an old man and have poor eyesight. Therefore, I need you, king, to tell Diophanes, stratêgos, 
to write to the epistatês of Arsinoë of the Themistes meris, the one by the dyke, to send him (i.e., Strouthos) to Diophanes; 
and if the contents of my petition prove true, bring him to trial for the abuse and force him to supply guarantors for my pension, 
so that he may pay it to me in the future. For if this occurs, I shall meet with justice via your agency, king. Farewell.
(in a second hand) To Ptolemaios. By all means, reconcile his father with Strouthos. But if he (i.e., Strouthos) disputes something, 
send him to us. Take care that you do not do otherwise. Year 26, Daisios 23, Phaophi 5.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> (in a third hand) Year 26, Phaophi 4. Strouthos, appearing (at the mediation), said that he would provide to Pappos, 
his father, for his pension, 2 bronze drachmas per month; and Pappos, also present, was content with these terms, and said, 
‘If he pays me (my pension) for a year, I will not inscribe his name on the temple for (owing me) this same amount.’
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp198–199)
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
