<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 6, 903</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">33342</idno>
            <idno type="TM">33342</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">33342</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;6;903</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-20" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 6</note>
              Concerning all the insults uttered by him against me. He shut up his own slaves and mine with my foster-daughters and his agent and son for seven whole days in his cellars, having insulted his slaves and my slave Zoë and half killed them with blows, and he applied fire to my foster-daughters, having stripped them quite naked, which is contrary to the laws. He also said to the same foster-daughters, “Give up all that is hers,” and they said, “She has nothing with us”; and to the slaves when they were being beaten he said, “What did she take from my house?” and they under torture said, “She has taken nothing of yours, but all your property is safe.” Zoilus went to see him because he had shut up his foster-son, and he said to him, “Have you come on account of your foster-son or of such a woman, to talk about her?” He swore in the presence of the bishops and of his own brothers, “Hence-forward I will not hide all my keys from her (he trusted his slaves but would not trust me); I will stop and not insult her.” Whereupon a marriage deed was made, and after this agreement and his oaths, he again hid the keys from me; and when I had gone out to the church at Sambatho he had the outside doors shut on me, saying, “Why did you go to the church?” and using many terms of abuse to my face, and through his nose. There were 100 artabae of corn due to the State on my account of which he paid nothing, not a single artaba. He obtained possession of the books, and shut them up saying, “Pay the price of the hundred artabae” having himself paid nothing, as I stated before; and he said to his slaves, “Provide helpers, to shut her up also.” Choous his assistant was carried off to prison, and Euthalamus gave security for him which was insufficient, so I took a little more and gave it for the said Choous. When I met him at Antinoöpolis having my bathing-bag (?) with my ornaments, he said to me, “I shall take anything you have with you on account of the security which you gave to my assistant Choous for his dues to the State.” To all this his mother will bear witness. He also persisted in vexing my soul about his slave Anilla, both at Antinodpolis and here, saying, “Send away this slave, for she knows how much she has possessed herself of,” probably wanting to get me involved, and on this pretext to take away whatever I have myself. But I refused to send her away, and he kept saying, “A month hence I will take a mistress.” God knows this is true.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
