<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Enteux., 72</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">3347</idno>
            <idno type="TM">3347</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">3347</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.enteux;;72</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-07-13T14:54:58-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp105–106)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-13T14:52:48-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp105–106)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-13T14:52:25-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp105–106)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-13T14:52:06-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Commit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp105–106)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-13T14:47:05-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> Hermogenes, son of Phil[ --- ], Persian of the epigone, to king Ptolemy, greetings. I am wronged by Petosiris, 
the one who lives in Lagis of the Themistes meris of the Arsinoite nome. For in year 5, according to the financial calendar, 
Phamenoth 21, a disagreement having arisen between us in the aforementioned village, (he placed) his hands upon me… 
with beatings and stompings upon whatever part of my body he might strike, … those present. Therefore, I need you, king, 
to command Diophanes, stratêgos, to write to Agathokles, epistatês, and have him (i.e., Agathokles) send him (i.e., Petosiris) to Diophanes, 
so that he may be tried for me, and if the things I write prove to be true, he may be forced to pay 200 drachmas for the blows… 
Diophanes…. For if this occurs, I shall have found justice through you, king. Farewell.
(in a second hand) To Agathokles: By all means, settle their differences; but if you cannot, send (them).
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> Year 4, Dios 3, Phamenoth 27. Hermogenes against Petosiris concerning blows for 200 drachmas.
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp105–106)
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
