<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title type="main"/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <idno type="filename">33514</idno>
            <idno type="TM">33514</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">33514</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">pylon;6;8_1</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2024-12-13" who="HGV">Xwalk from Pylon</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
<p>
[To my lady sister Isidora, Gelasios] her brother, greetings. Before everything, I greet (you) warmly, praying that you be well for the longest time, along with my lady sister Charisia. I greet warmly my mother Eirene. I greet warmly my sister Tsamoun and my brother Psais. I greet warmly my brother. Please, my lady sister, have the great house of our landlord Perikles be swept and sprinkled before I come. Please send me two thousand talents of money by all means. For I know your sisterly kindness. I greet warmly my father Psenamounis and (?) Ammonios. I greet warmly my mother Tamoun. I greet warmly my sister Thasi. I greet warmly all those in the house of Psenplaeus son of Ammonios with you individually. (Deleted: My mother) Your sister Tbekis, I greet warmly my brother [ ]. Mother Tbekis, I warmly greet my lady sister Isidora and my daughter Charisia. I greet warmly my sister Eirene. I greet warmly my son. I greet warmly . . (Verso) . . . and Ammonios . . . and mother Tabaia.
To my lady sister Isidora, Gelasios her brother. 
</p></div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
