<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Enteux., 79</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">3354</idno>
            <idno type="TM">3354</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">3354</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.enteux;;79</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-07-16T18:58:29-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp161–162)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-16T18:55:52-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp161–162)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-16T18:55:21-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp161–162)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-16T18:55:05-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Commit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp161–162)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-16T18:52:21-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> To king Ptolemy, greetings, Herakleides, of those from Alexandrou Nesos, those living in Krokodilopolis in the Arsinoite nome.
                         I am wronged by Psenobastis, who lives in Psya in the aforementioned nome. For in year 5, according to the financial calendar, Phamenoth 21,
                         I travelled to Psya, in the same nome, on private business; and while I was passing through/by… a certain Egyptian woman,
                         whose name is said to be Psenobastis, leaned over and poured urine down upon my clothing, with the result that they were dripping (with urine).
                  <milestone n="5" unit="line"/> I was vexed and upbraided her, and she abused me; and when I told her off in return… Psenobastis, with her right hand,
                         yanked the part of my cloak that lay upon my shoulder—the himation I was wearing—and ripped and struck it with the result that my chest
                         was laid bare and she spat in my face in the presence of some bystanders whom I called to witness. The things of which I accuse her she did out of hubris, and she
                         herself put her hands on me first. She was upbraided by some of those present for the things which she had done (?) to me, and as a result,
                         she left me behind there and went inside, from where she had poured the urine on me. <milestone n="9" unit="line"/> I need you, king, if it seems best to you, to not overlook me,
                         having been treated with hubris so outrageously by an Egyptian woman—I, being a Greek and a foreigner—and to tell Diophanes, stratêgos, since…
                         by her… to write to Sogenes, epistatês, to send Psenobastis to him (i.e., Diophanes) so that she may appear at trial with me about these matters,
                         and if the things presented in my petition prove true, she may pay the penalty upon which the stratêgos decides. For if this occurs,
                         I shall find justice through you, king. Farewell.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> Year 4, Dios 3, Phamenoth 27. Herakleides against Psenobastis concerning hubris.
                         <note>Translation with modification: J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement (2013) 161-162</note>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
