<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.10/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
    <teiHeader type="text">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">P.Enteux. 82</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
                <idno type="filename">3357</idno>
                <idno type="TM">3357</idno>
                <idno type="HGV">3357</idno>
                <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.enteux;;82</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
                        a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="fr">French</language>
                <language ident="en">English</language>
                <language ident="de">German</language>
                <language ident="it">Italian</language>
                <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
                <language ident="la">Latin</language>
                <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2024-06-08T12:33:48-05:00"
                who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Added via github because the file was stuck in finalization in the editor.</change>
            <change when="2014-12-31T19:03:33.396-05:00"
                who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/Randy">added a translation</change>
            <change when="2014-12-31T12:57:43-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> To king Ptolemy, greetings, Philista, daughter of Lysias, of those living in Trikomia. I am wronged by Petechon. 
For as I was bathing at the bath, the one in the aforementioned village, in year 1, on Tybi 7, he was serving as attendant in the women’s bath; 
and when I exited, so as to clean myself off, he, bringing in the ladles for the women’s bath, scattered my … and burned my belly and my right thigh down to the knee, 
so as to put me in danger of my life. Finding him, I handed him over to Nechthosiris, police chief of the village, while Simon, epistates, was present.                   
<milestone n="6" unit="line"/> Therefore, since I have fled to you as a suppliant, I need you, king, if it seems right to you, to not overlook me, 
treated so unjustly, (as I am) surviving by means of my handiwork; but order Diophanes, the governor, to write to Simon the epistates and 
Nechthosiris the policeman to bring Petechon before him (Diophanes), so that Diophanes may make an examination about these matters, (and) so that I, 
having fled to you, king, the common benefactor of all, may find justice. Farewell.
                  <milestone n="12" unit="line"/> (in a second hand) To Simon: Send the accused. Year 1, Gorpiaios 28, Tybi 12.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> Year 1, Gorpiaios 28, Tybi 12. Philista against Petechon, attendant, concerning burning. 
                  <note>Translation: J. Bauschatz (via PN in 2014)</note>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
            <div xml:lang="fr" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> Au roi Ptolémée salut Philista, fille de Lysias, habitant les-Trois-Bourgs. Je suis lésée par Pétéchôn. 
Je me baignais aux bains du susdit village. l'an 1, le 7 Tybi, quand cet homme, garçon de bains dans l'étuve des femmes, alors que j'étais sortie pour me savonner, 
apporia les brocs pleins d'eau chaude et les vida sur moi […], me brulant le ventre et la suisse gauche jusqu'au genou, au point de mettre ma vie en danger. 
L'ayant retrouvé, je l'ai livré à Nechthosiris, l'archiphylacite du bourg, en présence de Simón l'épistate.  <milestone n="6" unit="line"/>Je te prie donc, ô roi, 
si bon te semble, réfugiée en suppliante auprès de toi. de ne pas me voir avec indifférence aussi indignement traitée, moi qui vis du travail de mes mains, 
mais d'ordonner à Diophanès le stratège d'écrire à Simon l’épistate et à Nechthosiris le phylacite qu'il amène devant lui Pétéchôn afin que Diophanès examine l'affaire. 
Ainsi, après avoir cherché refuge auprès de toi, ô ro1, commun bienfaiteur de lous, j'obtiendrai justice. Sois heureux.
                  <milestone n="12" unit="line"/> (in a second hand) A Simôn. Envoie l'inculpé. An 1, 28 Gorpiaios — 12 Tybi.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> An 1, 28 Gorpiaios — 12 Tybi. Philista contre Pétéchôn, garçon de bains, pour avoir été échaudée. 
                  <note>Translation: O. Gueraud, P.Enteux. 82</note>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
