<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Enteux., 83</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">3358</idno>
            <idno type="TM">3358</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">3358</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.enteux;;83</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-07-18T17:17:46-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp242–243)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T17:16:02-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp242–243)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T17:15:44-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp242–243)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T17:15:36-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Commit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp242–243)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T17:10:07-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> To king Ptolemy, greetings, Thamounis, Herakleopolitan. I am wronged by Thothortais, inhabitant of Oxyrhyncha in the Arsinoite nome. 
For in year 1, Hathyr, when I was visiting Oxyrhyncha and had gone into the baths, the accused, appearing on the scene and grabbing hold of me 
as I was bathing in a tub in the women’s room, cast me out of the tub. When I did not give way, she, disdaining me because I was a stranger, 
struck me a great deal on whatever part of my body she might hit, and took away from me my stone necklace. After this, when I called for help to 
Petosiris the kômarchês about these matters, Thothortais, after being summoned, addressed him when she chose; and the kômarchês, plotting with her, 
led me off to the phylakê and held me there for four days, before he stripped me of the himation which I was wearing, worth 30 drachmas, 
and which the accused now has. Thus was I released. I ask you, then, king, that you command Diophanes, stratêgos, to write to Moschion, epistatês, 
to send Thothortais to him and, these things being true, to force her to give me back my himation, the one worth 30 drachmas; and (that you command) 
Diophanes to pronounce judgment concerning the things that were done to me, so that through your agency, king, I may find justice. Farewell.
(in a second hand) To Moschion. By all means, reconcile them; but if you are unable, send them so that they may be judged before the laokritai. 
Year 1, Gorpiaios 28, Tybi 12.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> Year 1, Gorpiaios 28, Tybi 12. Thamounis against Thothortais concerning a himation.
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp242–243)
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
