<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 10, 1299</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">33637</idno>
            <idno type="TM">33637</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">33637</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;10;1299</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 10</note>
              To my lord and son Ision from Psaïs and Syra, many greetings. Before all else I pray to the Lord God for your health and prosperity; Thonis your brother sends you many salutations. Next, since the new year we have been very ill, but we give thanks to God that we have recovered; and up to the present time we have not sacrificed the pigs. We are expecting you to come. You know that on your account we have not salted any fish, but we have made the pickle yearly, and, if possible, I will prepare it for your coming. Do as I told you about the ... of knives and the pepper. Your brothers Horion and Heraiscus salute you, An...n and her children salute you, Tachosis and her husband salute you, Triadelphus and his wife and children salute you. I salute Kamokos and his household, I salute Hepsates and his wife with their children, I salute Hatres, Pseke, and all our friends by name. I pray for your long-continued health. Hathur 10. (Addressed) Deliver to Ision ... from his parents Syra and Psaïs.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
