<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 10, 1253</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">33634</idno>
            <idno type="TM">33634</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">33634</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;10;1253</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 10</note>
              To ..., the most illustrious praefect of Egypt. It should be made known that the members of the bodyguard and of the cohorts herein following have stayed in the city of Oxyrhynchus on account of the ... and have assembled the public magistrates next to yourself in rank and property-owners and received from them on account of travelling expenses the amounts herein written, namely: ... and Therius, centurions, who came for the adaeratio and the contribution (?), 50 solidi of gold and 2 .. ., paid to them through Sarapion son of Eudaemon, formerly banker; Zoïlus, adjutant, 20 rugs of 6 cubits, supplied to him through Sozon, rug-merchant; Tauriscus, member of the bodyguard, who came for the collection of corn and barley for the days from the 7th to the 11th, 80 solidi of gold, of which the collector (?) was Isidorus, assistant of the praepositus of the 7th pagus; Aquilinus, member of the bodyguard, colleague of the aforesaid Tauriscus, 30 solidi of gold, of which the collector was Gaianus, assistant of the praepositus of the 5th pagus. The account of what was provided by each, the praepositi and the others, is with Triadelphus the chief assistant of the strategus. We give this information in order that nothing may escape your highness, my lord praefect.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
