<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 10, 1280</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">33635</idno>
            <idno type="TM">33635</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">33635</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;10;1280</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-11-14" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 10</note>
              Aurelius Pamea son of Peter, of the illustrious and most illustrious city of Oxyrhynchus, to Aurelius Ammonianus son of Euporion, of the said city, greeting. I acknowledge that I have of my own free will covenanted with you to share with you in the arbour of the camel-shed, which you, Ammonianus, have leased, from the past month Pachon at the beginning of the twelfth indiction, and to pay you yearly on account of rent one thousand myriads of silver drachmae, total 1000 myriads of silver, which I will deliver yearly with no delay. This agreement, of which a single copy is made, is valid, and in answer to the formal question I have given my assent. (Signed) I, Aurelius Pamea son of Peter, the aforesaid, have made the agreement and consent to al therein written, as aforesaid. I. Aurelius Pagochis son of Ptollion, wrote for him, as he is illiterate. Drawn up by me, Ptol...
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
