<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>UPZ 1, 7</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">3398</idno>
            <idno type="TM">3398</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">3398</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">upz;1;7</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-08-08T06:02:41-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Finalized - Ready.</change>
         <change when="2022-08-08T04:56:11-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Fine</change>
         <change when="2016-07-16T19:49:14-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 211)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-16T19:47:32-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 211)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-16T19:47:11-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 211)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-16T19:47:01-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Commit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 211)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-16T19:40:53-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> To Dionysios, tôn philôn and stratêgos, from Ptolemaios, son of Glaukias, Macedonian of those in katochê in the great Sarapieion, 
now for the tenth year. I am wronged by those sweeping and the bakers, those who are now performing service at the temple and 
who are going down into the Anoubieion, and (also) by Archebis, the doctor, and Mus, the cloak-seller, and others whose names I don’t know. 
For in year 19, on Phaophi 11, being present at the Astartieion, in which temple I am now in katochê, they broke in, wishing to strip and insult me, 
just as previously they attempted to get rid of me (?), in spite of the fact that I am a Greek. Since, therefore, I realize that they have lost all sense, 
I have shut myself in; but they, finding Harmais, my agent, upon the public walk, they beat him with bronze files. I ask, therefore, that you please 
write to Menedemos, your agent in the Anoubieion, to force them to do me justice; but if they do not obey, to send them to you, so that you 
may treat them in accordance with your hatred of wrongdoing. Farewell.
(in a fourth hand) To Menedemos. See to it that he receives justice. Year 19, Phaophi 19.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="41" unit="line"/> (in a third hand) Year 19, Phaophi 18.
(Petition) of Ptolemaios. (in a fifth hand) To Menedemos.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v,md" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="42" unit="line"/> (in a second hand) (Concerning) those performing service.
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 211)
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
