<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 7, 1026</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">35307</idno>
            <idno type="TM">35307</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">35307</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;7;1026</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-24" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 7</note>
              We have mediated between Gerontius and John to this effect :— John shall take the cloaks and the linen with the veils and the kerchiefs to be sold, and shall pay the loan of the three solidi; and we have given them to Gerontius to be sold for their value, as to the amount of which an oath shall be taken(?); and the remainder shall be paid to John for the expenses of his children. The articles sold are as follows :— an onyx-coloured Dalmatian vest at 33,850,000 denarii; another likewise of the Xoïte kind at 30,000,000; a ... linen cloth with a common kerchief at 1 solidus; a kerchief at 7,500,000; a towel and a linen cloth at 13,000,000 denarii. The unsold articles are as follows :— 1 small hide, 1 onyx-coloured veil, 1 Xoïte veil, 1 ... veil, a woman's box, a little shrine to hold unguents; these are to be sold through Theodorus and Gerontius for their value. Expenses through Gerontius amount to 18,600,000 denarii. We, Andreas and Triadelphus, presbyters, are witnesses.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
