<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 8, 1126</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">35570</idno>
            <idno type="TM">35570</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">35570</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;8;1126</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-31" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 8</note>
              ... I undertake of my free will to lease from you, from the land belonging to your patronage in the fields of the said village in the holding called that of Tsabatoüs, four arourae, total 4 arourae, by the measure of a fair measuring-line, the boundaries being on the south the land of the people of Tale, on the north that in your said patronage, on the west ..., on the east ..., to be sown with any kind of crop we choose, for the sowing of the auspicious 14th indiction, at a fixed rent as agreed between us of 13 carats of gold on the private standard for each aroura, making together 52 carats of pure metal on the private standard; and we will pay the rent of these to you at the time of the collection of public taxes in the 14th indiction without delay or dispute of any kind, at the risk of all our property, which is pledged to you for this purpose. The lease is valid and guaranteed, and in answer to the question we have given our consent. <note>Signatures of the lessees, and endorsement on the verso.</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
