<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Cair. Masp. 2, 67168</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">36693</idno>
            <idno type="TM">36693</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">36693</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.cair.masp;2;67168</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-12-02T05:02:22-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="ctr,r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> and I acknowledge that I have no claim against neither your holy monastery nor your said most pious monks and secretaries Menas and Ioannes, 
who also presented this document here, nor against anyone else belonging to the same monastery, <milestone n="9" unit="line"/> nor with regard to the aforesaid sale document, 
i.e. the 1500 knidia of wine mentioned in it ... a certain note, document … nor regarding anything else in general, for that reason. 
<milestone n="19" unit="line"/> And I further acknowledge … to hand over to you the aforementioned document without any controversy, or delay or neglect, or rather (the document), staying with me, 
unreturned, to be worthless, pointless and invalid, produced either by me or any other person, in the court and outside of the court, 
<milestone n="29" unit="line"/> and to keep you free from penalty, undisturbed, blameless and unapproached – you and your holy monastery and everyone belonging to it;
for that reason Ι bond to this my heirs and successors of all kinds. 
<milestone n="38" unit="line"/> And for security and guarantee of yours and  holy monastery of Pouinkoreus, I have made this acknowledgement of security which is valid and firm wherever it is produced, 
both inside and outside of court, along with my signature on it and of those who acted as witnesses at my request. 
<milestone n="48" unit="line"/> Αnd to all and each of those that have been written above, I, the aforementioned Theodoros, bishop, having been asked the formal question by you, Ioannes, 
the most pious monk and secretary, in your presence I consented. <milestone n="54" unit="line"/> Written in a single copy as prescribed. 
<milestone n="55" rend="break" unit="line"/> [Hand 2] I, the abovewritten most piteous Theodoros, bishop of the holy church of Pentapolis, son of the blessed Ioannes, 
have made this acknowledgement of security for the holy Tabennesiotes monastery of Pouinkoreus, located in the great city of Hermopolis in the province Thebais, 
through you Ioannes the most pious monk and secretary of the most loved by God Anatolios, proestos of the same monastery,
<milestone n="61" unit="line"/> and I acknowledge that I, having received from you and been paid in full the 1500 knidia of wine owed to me according to a sale document composed and addressed to my name 
by Menas and Ioannes most pious monks and secretaries of the same monastery, that neither I nor my heirs have any claim or legal right either 
against the said holy monastery or against the most loved by God proestos or anyone belonging to the monastery on the pretence of said debt. 
<milestone n="69" unit="line"/> And since I happen to have dispatched the letter in the district of Thebais for the action for recovery of debt, I agree to recall the letter at your discretion, 
without any dispute and that it staying with me, is useless and invalid, produced by either me or any other person, and to keep unharmed you and your holy monastery 
in regard to that letter. I agree with everything written above and having been asked the formal question I consented. [...] 
<milestone n="77" unit="line"/> ☧ I, Aurelius Timotheos, son of the blessed … residing in the place called … in Asteriou, am witness to this acknowledgement at the request of the most pious bishop Theodoros, who set it.
<milestone n="80" unit="line"/> ☧ I, Aurelius Isak, son of the blessed … residing in the place called Tatianou Pylai in Pergamiou, am witness to this agreement at the request of the most pious bishop Theodoros, who set it.
<milestone n="82" unit="line"/> ☧ I, Aurelius Iulianus, son of the blessed Theonas residing in the place called Tria Hiera Asteriou am witness to this agreement at the request of the most pious bishop Theodoros, who set it. 
<milestone n="85" rend="break" unit="line"/> ☧ I, Menas, son of Ioannes, synallagmatographos, residing in Tatianou Pylai finished [...]
[fragments] <note>Translation: by Law in Social Networks Project (Warsaw)</note>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="ctr,v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Fr1" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Fr2" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Fr3" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Fr4" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Fr5" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
