<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Lond. 5, 1696 R</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">36921</idno>
            <idno type="TM">36921</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">36921</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.lond;5;1696r p.lond;5;1696</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-02-07T04:54:24-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="Fr,r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/>⳨ After the consulate of gloriosissimus Flavius Philoxenus, on the 29th of Phaophi of the fifth indiction. Aurelii Victor, son of Hermauos and Phoibammon, 
son of Psais, son of Lart... and Victor son of Psempnouthes, all of them field guards on the plain of the village of Aphrodite of the Antaiopolite nome, to Aurelius Apollos, 
son of Dioskoros, from the same village, greetings. 
We acknowledge that we have leased from you for a period of three years from the harvest of the sixth indiction including the current one, God willing, 
the half which belongs to you of the total of the unwatered arourae, held in common with the heirs of Mousaios, son of Syrion, who keep the other half, 
that is to say, the southern section, with all the rights within the limits of the mound all around just next to the desert, situated in the plain of the same village, 
so that we cultivate it; and we shall pay to you the fixed rent, in case of flood and flood deficiency, of six artabae of wheat and six artabae of barley according to your measure; 
However, if the Nile does not reach the above-mentioned kleros, you shall deduct three artabae of barley from the above-mentioned rent, without dispute. 
The misthosis is valid and secure and, having been asked the formal question, we gave our consent; to be precise, on the kleros of Thenestaue, 
north of the arourae belonging to me, Victor, son of Hermauos. (h2) We, Aurelii Victor, son of Hermauos, and Phoibammon, son of Psais, and Victor, 
son of Psempnouthes, the above-mentioned, have leased as above. I, Ioseph, son of Hermauos, presbyter, wrote for them on their request because they do not know letters.
(h1) ⳨ Written by me Abraham ...

               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Fr,v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="30" unit="line"/> [Misthosis] by Victor, son of Hermauos, and Phoibammon, son of Psais, and Victor, son of Psempnouthes.
<note>Translation: Law in Social Networks Project (Warsaw)</note>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="ctr" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
