<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Lond. 5, 1696 R</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">36921</idno>
            <idno type="TM">36921</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">36921</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.lond;5;1696r p.lond;5;1696</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2023-10-23T06:29:34-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Finalized - Ready.</change>
         <change when="2023-01-25T10:05:55-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Looks good</change>
         <change when="2022-02-07T04:54:24-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="Fr,r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> ⳨ After the consulate of gloriosissimus Flavius Philoxenus, on the 29th of Phaophi of the fifth indiction. Aurelii Victor, son of Hermauos and Phoibammon, 
son of Psais, son of Lart... and Victor son of Psempnouthes, all of them field guards on the plain of the village of Aphrodite of the Antaiopolite nome, to Aurelius Apollos, 
son of Dioskoros, from the same village, greetings. 
<milestone n="8" unit="line"/> We acknowledge that we have leased from you for a period of three years from the harvest of the sixth indiction including the current one, God willing, 
the half which belongs to you of the total of the unwatered arourae, held in common with the heirs of Mousaios, son of Syrion, who keep the other half, 
<milestone n="14" rend="break" unit="line"/> that is to say, the southern section, with all the rights within the limits of the mound all around just next to the desert, situated in the plain of the same village, 
so that we cultivate it; and we shall pay to you the fixed rent, in case of flood and flood deficiency, of six artabae of wheat and six artabae of barley according to your measure; 
<milestone n="20" unit="line"/> However, if the Nile does not reach the above-mentioned kleros, you shall deduct three artabae of barley from the above-mentioned rent, without dispute. 
The misthosis is valid and secure and, having been asked the formal question, we gave our consent; to be precise, on the kleros of Thenestaue, 
north of the arourae belonging to me, Victor, son of Hermauos. <milestone n="24" unit="line"/> (h2) We, Aurelii Victor, son of Hermauos, and Phoibammon, son of Psais, and Victor, 
son of Psempnouthes, the above-mentioned, have leased as above. I, Ioseph, son of Hermauos, presbyter, wrote for them on their request because they do not know letters.
(h1) ⳨ Written by me Abraham ...
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Fr,v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="30" unit="line"/> [Misthosis] by Victor, son of Hermauos, and Phoibammon, son of Psais, and Victor, son of Psempnouthes.
<note>Translation: Law in Social Networks Project (Warsaw)</note>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <div xml:lang="fr" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> Sous le post-consulat de Flavius Philoxenos le gloriosissime, 29 Phaôphi de la cinquième
                         indiction.
                         Les Aurelii Biktôr fils d’Hermaouôs, Phoibammôn fils de Psaïos, petit-fils de (?) Lart[- - -]
                         et Biktôr fils de Psempnouthês, tous gardes-champêtres dans la pedias du village d’Aphrodité
                         du nome Antaiopolite, à Aurelius Apollôs fils de Dioskoros du même village, bonjour.
                  <milestone n="8" unit="line"/> Nous reconnaissons t’avoir pris en location pour une période de trois ans à partir des
                         récoltes de la sixième indiction incluse – si Dieu le veut – la moitié que tu possèdes de la
                         totalité des aroures sans eau qui sont communes aux héritiers de Mousaios fils de Syriôn
                         (ceux-ci pour l’autre moitié), à savoir la parcelle méridionale, avec tous ses droits, selon son
                         bornage avec la butte tout autour du côté de la montagne, se trouvant dans le terroir du
                         même village afin que nous la cultivions, et nous te verserons le loyer fixé, en cas d’inondation
                         suffisante et insuffisante, à six artabes de blé et six artabes d’orge selon ta mesure. <milestone n="20" unit="line"/> Si
                         cependant le Nil en crue n’est pas allé jusqu’audit terrain, tu allègeras le montant sus-mentionné
                         de notre loyer de trois artabes d’orge, ceci sans contestation. La location sera
                         valide et assurée et, soumis à la question formelle, nous avons donné notre accord. À
                         préciser que le terrain fait partie du lot de Tkhênestaue, au nord des aroures qui m’appartiennent,
                         à moi Biktôr fils d’Herma(o)uôs.
                <milestone n="24" unit="line"/> Nous, les susmentionnés Aurelii Biktôr fils d’Herma(o)uôs, Phoibammôn fils de Psaïs et
                         Biktôr fils de Psempnouthês, nous avons pris la location selon les termes susmentionnés.
                         Moi, Iôsêphi(o)s fils d’Herma(o)uôs, prêtre, à leur demande, j’ai écrit pour eux qui ne savent
                         pas écrire.
                         Écrit par moi, Abraam [...].
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="30" unit="line"/> Location de Biktôr fils d’Hermaouôs, de Phoibammôn fils de Psaïos et de Biktôr fils de
                           Psempnouthês [...].
                           <note>Translation: J.-L. Fournet, CdE 95 (2020) 139</note>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
