<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 6, 922</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">37133</idno>
            <idno type="TM">37133</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">37133</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;6;922</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-20" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 6</note>
              The two horses from Asclou were delivered to the groom. The horse from Ophis was delivered to the upper stable. The horse of the magistrate was delivered to the same stable. The horse from Spania was delivered to the same stable. The horse from the Arsinoite nome was delivered to the same stable. The small white horse was delivered to the groom. I gave. Patricius(?) and the small ... for the bay horse of the upper stable. I gave the white mare and the ... for the small horse which died. I sold the ... and bought the small black one which is in the stable. I sold the horse called Pleb for 3 solidi, which the revered Philoxenus has. I sold the horse from Constantinople for 3 solidi, which the revered Philoxenus has. I sold the two asses (?) from Heracleopolis and the ass from Oureeiebt for 5 2/3 solidi, which were paid to the same. The ass of the magistrate and that of the water-carrier and its mate are dead. The mare which died belonged to Menas the official. Three asses were bought from Ophis for 8 1/3 solidi, and another from Pallosis for 3 solidi. The she-ass of the Karaneots is dead. The other she-ass of the said Karaneots and that belonging to the people from Lucii and the small one I sold, and received 4 solidi for them.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
