<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 1, 128</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">37140</idno>
            <idno type="TM">37140</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">37140</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;1;128</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 1</note> His honour Pamouthius the secretary on the plea of bodily infirmity has expressed the desire to retire from his duties and take rest. Learning this, we (for it happened that I, John, was then at Oxyrhynchus) visited him in his house and were very importunate with him to do no such thing and not to make any resolution without reference to the opinion and decision of your excellency. We could not however persuade him to listen to our request in any other way than by offering and pledging ourselves to refer his case by letter to your excellency. He insists that he is unable to bear such a strain, and begs to be bidden to come to your excellency’s feet in order that you may judge of his present condition. Let your excellency therefore be pleased to write back your wishes, either persuading his worship to stay at his post and do his regular work or ordering him to come to your excellency’s feet. In the forefront of this letter we would place our due and fitting obeisance to your excellency.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
