<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 8, 1164</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">37839</idno>
            <idno type="TM">37839</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">37839</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;8;1164</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-31" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 8</note>
              The letter-carriers came to me bringing me a letter from your paternal magnificence about a camel, and I was very grateful for the opportunity granting me to be deemed worthy after so long of your honoured words. I immediately brought in their opponents and they produced not a few persons testifying that the camel is theirs, while on the other hand the letter-carriers brought other persons testifying that the said camel belongs to them; and since both sides brought witnesses, I could not settle the point between them. But if it be your bidding, order them to come to an arbitration with my people before any one whom they shall both select, and to accept the results of the arbitration; for I will use every means to secure that my people abide by the judgement given them. God is my witness that Iam anxious in everything to perform your orders. I write this with many reverences and greetings to your paternal magnificence. (Addressed) To my master the most magnificent ... reverend ... comes Peter, from Theodosius.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
