<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>ZPE 194 (2015) S. 194 Nr. 1</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">397805</idno>
            <idno type="TM">397805</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">397805</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">zpe;194;194_1</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2020-07-31T10:07:57-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> Debt (?). <note>Column number</note>
                      30. In the nineteenth year of Emperor Caesar Nerva Traianus Optimus Augustus Germanicus Dacicus Parthicus,
                      on the twenty–fourth day of the month Kaisareios, in Theadelpheia in the Themistos division of the
                      Arsinoite nome. <milestone n="6" unit="line"/> Eirenaios, son of Aphrodisios, about forty-two years old, with a scar on the right calf of
                      his leg acknowledges to Heron, son of Hermas, about forty years old, with a scar in the middle of his forehead,
                      that he <note>sc. Eirenaios</note> has received back from him <note>sc. Heron</note> one hundred drachmas in silver which
                      Heron owed to Eirenaios, as he <note>sc. Heron?</note> says, according to a contract which is claimed to have been
                      lost <milestone n="14" unit="line"/> and Eirenaios admits that it <note>i.e. the contract</note> is invalid for him and for everyone who should bring it
                      forth and that Eirenaios neither makes nor will make any claim against Heron or his assigns either about
                      these things he has received, as stated above, or about the interest on them or about any other matter at
                      all, written or unwritten, up to the present day, in any manner. The contract is incontestable. <milestone n="25" unit="line"/> Subscriber for Heron <note>vacat</note>
                      ... of Aphrodisios. 
                      <note>Translation: A. Mirończuk, ZPE 194 (2015) 196</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
