<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
   <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>BASP 59 (2022) S. 86</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">397807</idno>
            <idno type="TM">397807</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">397807</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">basp;59;86</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-23T02:52:52-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> In the eighth year of Imperator Caesar Nerva Traianus (Trajan) Augustus
                      Germanicus Dacicus, on the fifteenth day of Phamenoth, in Theadelpheia
                      in the division of Themistos of the Arsinoite nome,
               <milestone n="5" unit="line"/> Heron, son of Hermas, a Persian by descent, ca. thirty years of age, with
                      a scar in the middle of his forehead, acknowledges to Heron, son of Deios,
                      ca. twenty-nine years old, with a scar on the right side of his forehead
                      under his hairline, <milestone n="10" unit="line"/> that he has received from him a hundred silver drachmas
                      as a loan bearing interest and that he will return them to the same
                      Heron, son of Deios, on the fifteenth of the month of Pharmouthi <milestone n="14" unit="line"/> of the
                      present eighth year of Imperator Caesar Nerva Traianus Augustus Germanicus
                      Dacicus without any delay or excuse. <milestone n="17" unit="line"/> And if he does not return
                      them in accordance with what is written, let him pay them back with a
                      50% penalty and with interest immediately, while the right of execution
                      (of the debt) belongs to Heron, son of Deios …
           <milestone n="21" rend="break" unit="line"/> (In the left margin) I, Heron, son of Deios, to Heron, son of Hermas:
                      I have received the 100(plus) drachmas (and I will not bring any charge
                      against you about anything) at all, written or unwritten. In the ninth year
                      of Imperator Caesar Nerva Traianus Augustus Germanicus Dacicus,
                      Epeiph 15.
                      <note>Translation: D. Sells, BASP 59 (2022) 88</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
