<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>SB 14, 12089</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">4308</idno>
            <idno type="TM">4308</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">4308</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;14;12089</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-07-18T20:53:05-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp265–266)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T20:50:43-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp265–266)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T20:50:18-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp265–266)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T20:50:02-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Commit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp265–266)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T20:46:50-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> Horenis to Sosibios, greetings. When Petesouchos, the man in charge of the phylakitai in Thmoiobastis, 
came to see us it was reported that there had been some thefts at the royal threshing-floor on the night of Pachon 4, 
and that the thieves had made off with 14 artabas of grain; and (it was reported that) after he had carried out a search 
with the phylakitai he discovered eight measures of the stolen grain in the house of Petesouchos, son of Horos, 
which he handed over to Agathis, phylakitês, while we ourselves were present. And similarly (it was reported that) 
he discovered at the threshing-floor of Kales that 6 measures of grain had been removed from their sacks; and applying a seal, 
we transferred (the grain) to the royal granary. Since, therefore, both Petesouchos (i.e., Petesouchos, son of Horos) and Kales, 
having had a hand in this business, have fled, I make this report so that you may know. Farewell. Year 40, Pachon 15.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> ... To Sosibios.
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp265–266)
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
