<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Hamb. 4, 238</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">43304</idno>
            <idno type="TM">43304</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">43304</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.hamb;4;238</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-07-16T19:40:47-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp205–206)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-16T19:38:54-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp205–206)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-16T19:38:31-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp205–206)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-16T19:38:19-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Commit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp205–206)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-16T19:35:28-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> To Dionysios, ho pros tais syntaxesi and hêgemôn, from Philina, daughter of Argaios, Macedonian. I am wronged by Leontiskos, my son. 
For as I have run away from (?) him, I have been forced to flee to you… having charged (?) me, on account of my being (?) a woman… in year 21, 
having gone to… the according… the plot of 10 arouras, me… in my name… other artabas of wheat… 5… and… of the Herakleopolite nome, 
via a purchase that took place at the Herakleopolis agoranomion. But he did not abide by these terms, but has fled in possession of the daughter 
of the aforementioned female slave of mine, supposing that he will sell her. I ask, therefore, if it seems best to you, acting in accordance with what 
is presented in my other petitions, to not overlook me, being deprived of my rights by my inconsiderate son, but to write immediately to Sogenes, 
epistatês, to send Leontiskos to you, before the maiden is sold, so that if I prove that the contents of my petition are true, you may force him to 
return to me the grain and the maiden, and the slave girl who has been sold may be deposited with a neutral party. For if this happens, 
I shall have met with [ --- ] through you. Farewell.
(in a second hand) To Sogenes: Tell Leontiskos to present himself before us immediately. But if he delays, do not allow it. Year 22, Phamenoth 20.
(in a third hand?) Year 22, Phamenoth 30. To Dionysios. Philina, daughter of Argaios, Macedonian, brought to us a petition against her son, 
bearing orders from you to tell him (i.e., Leontiskos) to appear before you immediately, and if he delays, not to allow him to. 
He was ordered to appear by Hermogenes, agent of Ptolemaios, the….
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> To Sogenes.
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp205–206)
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
