<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>SB 3, 7202</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">4403</idno>
            <idno type="TM">4403</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">4403</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;3;7202</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-07-19T15:37:18-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp100, 140)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-19T15:35:04-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp100, 140)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-19T15:34:39-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp100, 140)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-19T15:34:25-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Commit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp100, 140)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-19T14:56:23-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="FrA" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> (lines 1–20) … we sent to you Petoüs, son of Horos, the brewer, who owed the following sums for the brewing tax: for year 14, 
for the village of Arsinoë, 740 [...] drachmas, [y] obols; for year 15, 1866 drachmas, 4 obols; and for Pelousion, for year 16, 1092 drachmas, 5 obols; 
for year 17, 200 drachmas; and for year 18, 597 drachmas; all told, 4500 [...] drachmas [and z obols?].
Also, more of those who have dovecotes in the meris have notified us that their value has not been determined up to now. And (they say that) 
the time is running out and that certain (dovecotes) have been sealed up by Testeutonchis, the man who received (the contract for the tax on dovecotes?) 
for year 20.
And it has reached us that he (i.e., Testeutonchis?) was hauled off to the phylakê in Krokodilopolis. Therefore, if it seems right to you, you will 
do well to send the man to us, so that he may pay in full the remainder.
Pharmouthi 2, in Psinachis. While Asklepiades, the epistatês in Boukolon Kome, was present, as well as Horos, one of the phylakitai from the same village, 
and Marres, the desmophylax from Arsinoë, Marres the oil-dealer brought up to us a certain Petobastis, son of Sannesitheus, who had 2 gourds and a… 
oil-flask, in which….
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 100)
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="FrB,1" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="28" unit="line"/> (lines 34–37) To Onnophris, desmophylax. We handed Akmenis, son of Phanes, the man who has received the beer tax for Arsinoë, 
over to Marres, son of Petetris, the desmophylax in Arsinoe, so that he might present him at the phylakê in Krokodilopolis.
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 140)
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="FrB,2" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="38" unit="line"/>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="FrC" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="43" unit="line"/>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="FrD" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="61" unit="line"/>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="FrE" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="74" unit="line"/>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
