<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>BGU 6, 1244</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">4405</idno>
            <idno type="TM">4405</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">4405</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">bgu;6;1244</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-07-13T14:42:21-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - added translation from a printed volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp86–87)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-13T14:39:12-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - translation from a printed volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp86–87)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-13T14:38:35-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - added translation from a printed volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp86–87)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-13T14:38:17-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Commit - added translation from a printed volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp86–87)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-13T14:32:04-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="r,ms" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> (in a second hand) To Apollonios, epistatês phylakitôn. Let them be evicted (?) as regards what [we have received] from Tkollousis. Year 22, Hathyr 23.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="r,ctr" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="3" unit="line"/> To Aniketos, oikonomos, from Tkollousis, brewer from the village of Phnebieus and…. I had a trial against Pasis and …-thea, 
their mother, before the chrêmatistai who adjudicate in matters that concern the (royal) revenues, concerning the baseless charge of the 
murder of a slave fifteen days ago, (a charge) which they leveled against me and my agents. On account of this, the accused broke 
into my house, which I happen to have purchased from the people who bought it from them. And now they have moved a certain Isias 
into it through their own agency, so that perhaps somehow they may be able, through a similar pretext, to establish habitation. 
Wherefore, I ask that you please write to Agathokles to send Isias, so that she may… and give way to me by force. For if this happens, 
I will have met with your assistance. Farewell.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="35" unit="line"/> (in a second hand) To Apollonios.
(in a third hand) Year 22, Hathyr 24. From Apollonios. To Agathokles, epistatês of Phnebieus. 
Below lies a copy of the petition given to Aniketos and sent to us. Therefore, let… be sent to Isias, 
so that an investigation about the events recorded may be carried out by Aniketos.
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp86–87)
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
