<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Phrur. Diosk., 6</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">44722</idno>
            <idno type="TM">44722</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">44722</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.diosk;;6</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-07-16T19:09:36-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp168–169)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-16T19:06:09-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp168–169)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-16T19:05:35-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp168–169)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-16T19:05:17-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Commit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp168–169)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-16T18:58:44-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="1" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> To Dioskourides, hêgemôn and phrourarchos, from Artemidoros and Protarchos, sons of Artemidoros, both Dorians. 
Of the petition which we submitted to Teres, tôn philôn and stratêgos, we have appended a copy. We ask that you take heed of its contents. 
For if this occurs, we will benefit from your kindness. Farewell.
To Teres, tôn philôn and stratêgos, from Artemidoros and Protarchos, sons of Artemidoros, both Dorians. 
On the 6th of Phaophi, year 36, we were traveling along the path that leads from Herakleopolis to the harbor with others 
when we came to the gate that leads from the phrourion into the city. Someone sitting on a wagon, whose name we do not know, 
willfully attacked one of us, namely Artemidoros, in a manner defying all expectation. Artemidoros determinedly rebuked him, 
and we entered the gate of the ochyrôma. But then, a certain Koson and a certain Thymoleon and others, whose names we do not know, 
set upon us; and, drunk, they whipped Andronikos, who was travelling along with us. Some of them attacked us with bricks and rocks, 
while others employed hands and feet, and still others bit us. And we, in danger from such an attack, called out for help, and certain people 
who had arrived on account of the commotion assisted us. Koson and Thymoleon were consequently carted off to the phrourarchos, 
but after this a certain Ammonia set upon some of the cloaks we were wearing and mistreated them, and in the confusion she went off in 
possession of Andronikos’ cloak. Those who had accompanied Koson’s accomplices fled. After we had handed over the aforementioned to Epimachos, 
agent of the phrourarchos, a certain Nikodemos appeared, as did Asklepiades and many others. They were also drunk and had heard 
that we were within (the ochyrôma). They mistreated us, wishing to cause us harm; but those who had appeared on the scene 
because of the disturbance upbraided them and took us into a house, so they went away. We ourselves are in danger of our lives, 
and suspect that the attacks against us were orchestrated by Apollonios, son of Herakleides, an Ammonian, 
because of the present examination for one of us—namely Protarchos—before Nikanor and Archianax of his (i.e., Protarchos’) wife, 
Chrysous, and the aforementioned Apollonios, who has committed adultery with her.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="39" unit="line"/> We are unable to deliver the appropriate account against them in the area for the aforementioned reasons. 
We ask, then, if it seems right to you, to see to it that, on the one hand, the aforementioned men and Ammonia are guarded, 
and that, on the other hand, our petition be sent up to Nikanor and Archianax, so that we, setting out from this (place?), 
may deliver the appropriate account. If this occurs, we will receive assistance. Farewell.
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp168–169)
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
