<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Dime 3, 12</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">45636</idno>
            <idno type="TM">45636</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">45636</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;2;160 sb;1;5108</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-09-15T12:06:40.818-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-09-15T12:06:40.803-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:24:59.12-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from Rylands catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-22T14:24:14-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <p>
               <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> ‘I, Herieus daughter of Laousis and Tapetesouchus, acknowledge that I have sold to Hisarous daughter of Onnophris and Herieus the two parts belonging to me out of five parts of the two-storied house and court on the east side and of all appurtenances, being common and undivided, at Socnopaei Nesus in the division of Heraclides, of which the measurements and adjacent areas of the whole house and court are as aforesaid. Adjacent to the whole house and court are on the south the house of Tesenouphis son of Prales, which is in the possession of his children, and the house and court of Taesis, on the north the entrance and exit, on the east the house and court of Teses son of . . . nebis, which are in the possession of his children, on the west the house of Thases daughter of Panephrummis; and I have received in immediate and full payment the price agreed upon and I will guarantee the sale with every guarantee from the present day for ever and will fulfil the other provisions as aforesaid, and I have instructed the witnesses to sign and to pay the clerk of the record-office when he has endorsed the deed. Laousis son of Herieus wrote for her as she is illiterate. I, Hisarous daughter of Onnophris and Herieus, have purchased the aforesaid two parts out of five of the house and court as aforesaid. Stotoës son of … wrote for her as she is illiterate. Sale and cession of two parts out of five of the house and court and all appurtenances in Socnopaei Nesus in the division of Heraclides, of which the measurements and adjacent areas are as aforesaid, which sale and cession Herieus daughter of Onnophris and Tapetesouchus, aged about 25 years with a mole on the … forehead, concludes with Hisarous daughter of Onnophris and Herieus, aged about … years with a scar on the left … The subscribers are Laousis son of Herieus aged about 51 years with a scar on … and … The 15th year of Tiberius Caesar Augustus, the ... of the month … Drawn up through the record-office in Socnopaei Nesus.’
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
