<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
    <teiHeader type="text">
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title type="main">P.Ryl. 2 160 D</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
                <idno type="filename">45838</idno>
                <idno type="TM">45838</idno>
                <idno type="HGV">45838a 45838b</idno>
                <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;2;160D</idno>
                <availability>
                    <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
                        a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
                </availability>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <profileDesc>
            <langUsage>
                <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
                <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
                <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
                <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
                <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
                <language ident="la">Latein</language>
                <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
            </langUsage>
        </profileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2012-08-22T18:21:44.204-04:00"
                who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from John Rylands Papyri Catalogue, with permission.</change>
            <change when="2019-06-25T04:45:47-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
                <div n="1" type="textpart">
                   <p>
                       <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> I, Stotoétis son of Panephrumis and Tanephrumis, acknowledge that I have sold to 
Apunchis son of Panephrumis and Tanephrumis two shares belonging to me out of five shares 
of a two-storied house and court and two shares out of four shares of a fallen house, 
all common and undivided, and of all appurtenances, in Socnopaei Nesus in the division of Heraclides 
... and a twelfth share of a mill.., Adjacent to the whole first house are on the south 
...a vacant space , . .,on the north a public street, on the west its common entrance and exit, 
on the east the house of Satabous, while to the second house are adjacent on the south the house of Apunchis, 
on the north the house of Apunchis and his brothers, on the west the house of Stotoétis son of Horus, 
on the east a public street ; and I will guarantee the sale with every guarantee as aforesaid. Herieus
son of Herieus wrote on his behalf, as he was illiterate.
<milestone n="8" rend="break" unit="line"/> Date, demotic signature of Apunchis and docket of the record-office.
                   </p> 
                </div>
                <div n="2" type="textpart">
                    <p>
                        <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> The 2nd year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, 
16th of the month Epeiph, at Socnopaei Nesus in the division of Heraclides of the Arsinoitenome. 
Apunchis son of Panephrummis, aged about 25 years, with a scar on the right forearm, 
has lent to Stotoétis son of Panephrummis, a Persian of the Epigone, aged about 35 years, 
with a scar on the middle of the forehead, <milestone n="9" unit="line"/> (who acknowledges) that he has in loan from 
him the capital sum of 34 drachmae in coined silver currency and that he has received it 
from him forthwith from hand to hand out of the house at the interest of one drachma 
per mina per month, which sum the borrower shall repay to Apunchis in the month Epeiph 
of the coming third year of Tiberius Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator. 
<milestone n="17" rend="break" unit="line"/> If he fails to repay the loan and the interest as aforesaid, Apunchis shall have the right of execution 
upon the borrower and upon all his property, as if in accordance with a legal decision. 
The subscriber of the borrower is Herieus son of Herieus, aged about 35 years, 
with a scar on the left eyebrow. (The other) subscriber is the aforesaid Apunchis.
<milestone n="25" rend="break" unit="line"/>Subscriptions of Stotoétis and Apunchis, date and docket of the record-office.
<note>Translation: A.S. Hunt, P.Ryl. 2 160 C</note>
                    </p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
