<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>BGU 8, 1773</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">4854</idno>
            <idno type="TM">4854</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">4854</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">bgu;8;1773</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-07-19T14:24:17-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp323–324)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-19T14:22:16-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp323–324)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-19T14:21:56-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp323–324)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-19T14:21:48-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Commit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp323–324)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-19T14:19:27-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> (in a second hand) …. (in the first hand) Year 2[.], Phaophi 7, in Herakleopolis below Memphis, before [ --- ], syngenês and stratêgos and ho epi tôn prosodôn. 
Imouthes, the man who submitted the petition, guardian of [ --- ] and his sons, appeared in court. By Imouthes it was made clear that 
there belonged to the aforementioned around Bousiris a phylakitikos klêros from Phidon, 10 arouras, and that he himself (i.e., Imouthes) 
had paid the royal taxes on it for the twenty-first year. But around the month of Mesore in the same year he had been detained in the heirktê, 
and remained in detention until Epeiph, year 22. Themison, one of those who lived in Bousiris, having learned of this, came into possession 
of the aforementioned allotment by force in year 22 and sowed it and carried off the produce. When Imouthes was released, and when he 
attempted to settle the accounts about the rents, he stated that Themison, though he pledged that he would pay, made no attempt at payment, 
and even employed the same method as before and sowed the plot in year 23. Imouthes, since he was crippled by a bodily illness and since the 
seed was untouched, thought it best to write to Nearchos, archiphylakitês, to extract from Themison the rents for year [..] for the 10-artaba tax (?), 
in accordance with the law about those who come into possession of allotments… into the plots… to Themison….
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp323–324)
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
