<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Coll. Youtie 1, 16</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">5041</idno>
            <idno type="TM">5041</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">5041</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.coll.youtie;1;16</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-07-14T20:54:38-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 151)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-14T20:52:49-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 151)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-14T20:52:27-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 151)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-14T20:52:06-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Commit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 151)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-14T20:48:43-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> To Ptolemaios, syngenês and stratêgos, from Petermouthis, son of Peteësis, 7-aroura machimos of those under Chomenis, 
also a crippled cobbler of those from Tebtynis of the Polemon meris, but living in Oxyrhyncha of the same meris. 
On the first of the intercalary days of Mesore, year 8, Dionysios, archiphylakitês of the meris, arriving in the village and entering my workshop 
with Demetrios, and Apollonios the eisangeleus, and Teos and Nechthenibis and other ephodoi, seized me and led me through the village, 
with every form of mistreatment and insolence and blows, up to the middle street of the city. And they did not release me before shaking me 
down for 4 silver drachmas and 1300 bronze drachmas; and they forced Pnepheros, son of Horos, another machimos, to place at the bank 
in my name for him (i.e., Dionysios) a promissory note payable to Areios, epispoudastês of the meris, for 44 silver drachmas; and in 
addition they forced this same Areios to accept the aforementioned 44 silver drachmas from him (i.e., Dionysios), disdaining me because 
I am helpless and crippled. And they also carried of the clothes I was wearing. I ask that you not overlook me, but if it does not seem improper, 
please send…. And if this takes place, I shall receive succor from you. Year 8, Mesore intercalary day 1. Farewell.
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 151)
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
