<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Hels. 1, 2</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">5139</idno>
            <idno type="TM">5139</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">5139</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.hels;1;2</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-07-18T16:57:29-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - added translation from a published volume (Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 227)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T16:54:15-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 227)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T16:53:56-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 227)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T16:53:35-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Commit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 227)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T16:51:31-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> To Philon, archiphylakitês, from Dionysios, son of Zoilos, antigrapheus from the oikonomos for the apomoira for the districts around Theogonis. 
On the 18th of the present month, Phamenoth, when already the lamps were being kindled, I was bathing in the so-called new baths of Aristodemos. 
As I was using a gourd as a cup, I was stripped (of it?) by Philon, one of the soldiers, saying that… bath-attendant… me…. 
Leaping upon me, with others whose names I do not know, they beat me with blows and kicks against whatever part of my body might be available. 
Dragging me out of the bath, they led me up to the gate opposite the Samothrakion; and when some phylakitai appeared, they handed me over to them. 
Since, therefore, I am bedridden, I ask that you please guard Philon and his associates until a judgment has been given concerning my claims. For if this happens, ….
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 227)
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
