<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 2, 65</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">5284</idno>
            <idno type="TM">5284</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">5284</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;2;65</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2012-09-09T05:24:01.486-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-09-09T05:24:01.477-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-16T18:51:13.099-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from John Rylands Catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-16T16:19:22-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <div n="1" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> ... all the grave-diggers belonging to the association had made an Egyptian contract, registered in the 19th year, Phamenoth 9, through the record-office of the same city, concerning the division among them of the shares agreed upon, whereby it was provided that any person breaking the agreement or claiming the shares assigned to each should be compelled to pay to the association a fine of ... of copper and the same sum to the Treasury. These and other provisions being contained in the contract, and the petition declaring that Petosiris, Paris, and their supporters, taking no heed whatever of the fixed rules, carried off a number of corpses from them, the details of which will appear in the forthcoming inquiry, they asked that the accused should be ordered to be brought forward and compelled perforce to pay to them the fine fixed as well as the other sums due to the Treasury, and that they should receive also the proper penalty. In these circumstances, Petosiris and the others . . .
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="12"/> ... we, seeing (?) that the accused have deserted and are entirely triumphant (?), but those who brought the accusation are still further distracted by their opponents through a long-continued injury, have jointly decided that the provisions of the Egyptian contracts voluntarily made by the parties, and the other rules thereby fixed, shall remain as they are, valid and inviolate. Read: the 14th year, Mecheir 24.
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
