<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Ryl. 4, 583</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">5301</idno>
            <idno type="TM">5301</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">5301</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ryl;4;583</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2013-01-30T01:44:26.619-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2013-01-30T01:44:26.574-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/wgclaytor">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - ready</change>
         <change when="2012-08-23T18:52:33.458-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/James%20Corke-Webster">Translation added from Rylands catalogue, with permission.</change>
         <change when="2012-08-23T18:49:43-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <div n="Fr1,r,int" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> ‘In the first year of the reign of Ptolemy and Ptolemy the brother and Cleopatra, children of Ptolemy and Cleopatra, gods Epiphaneis, the priest at Alexandria of Alexander and the gods Soteres and the gods Adelphi and the gods Euergetae and the gods Philopatores and the gods Epiphaneis and the gods Philometores, the athlophorus of Berenice Euergetis, the canephorus of Arsinoe Philadelphus, the priestess of Arsinoe Philopater, being those in office at Alexandria, on the 9th of the month Xandikos, 9th Phaophi, at Philadelphia in the Arsinoite nome. Nicomachus, son of Ph ….. ades of Halicarnassus, successor to his father’s holding, has leased to Apollonius son of Apollonius, Persian of the Epigone, the somewhat sandy vineyard situated near the same Phildelphia, being of 6 arourae or such as it may be, belonging to Crates, son of Pheidimus of Arsinoe in Lycia, tactomisthus of the Pamphylians in their command, for the first year for a rent of two-thirds of all the fruits and produce that grow in this vineyard; viz., when all fruits have been turned into wine and deductions made for the apomoira due to the Treasury, wages for the treaders, hire of winepress and a contribution (in the mouth of the vintage?) of a half kados to the agricultural guild, the must remaining shall be divided into three portions, of which Nicomachus shall take two and Apollonius one. Each shall provide jars for himself and as required for the apomoira according to the proportions of his lease, and each shall carry down the jars for himself to the winepress, and carry up the must for himself, while the apomoira ….
<milestone unit="line" n="13"/> ‘monthly wages (?) are to be paid at his own expense by Apollonius from the time stated until termination of the lease, as is best for the land and the vine; Apollonius is to prune the vine moderately and exactly, to attend properly to the dressing of the young vines, to keep the ground of the property clear of weedy growth and rush and reed and quake grass and kinaios reed and all the other tangle of roots except for the dry ground inside the cross-trench, and is to maintain the cross-trenches dug and clean and the property fenced; he is to clear out the drains and fence the conduit facing to … and lead it through for the watering; and when the lease has expired, he is to deliver the ground of the property in clean condition and the cross-trenches clean, as is presently stated. If he fail to deliver it or to perform each of the tasks at the proper time, or if he abandon the lease, he is to pay the assessed wage with 50 percent. surcharge for every task he fails to perform, and a fine of two silver talents for any damage that may be due at the time of his abandoning the lease. Apollonius is to shift 50 rows of vines to the uncultivated ground at his own expense and to transplant in the same year at the proper (time) …’
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Fr2,r,ext" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="40"/>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="Fr1,v,int" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="1"/>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
