<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>SB 1, 5675</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">5641</idno>
            <idno type="TM">5641</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">5641</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;1;5675</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-07-12T17:36:04-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp80–81)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-12T17:31:05-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - translation from published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp80–81)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-12T17:21:10-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - added a translation from a  published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp80–81)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-12T17:20:48-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Commit - added a translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp80–81)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-12T17:18:53-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> King Ptolemy to Neon, greetings. We have subjoined to you a copy of the letter we sent to the epistatai phylakitôn.
See to it that you instruct those appointed by you, region by region, to act in accordance with our wishes, 
knowing that we will penalize those who transgress our orders, as is fitting. Farewell. Year 22, Daisios 26, Choiach 26.

King Ptolemy to Synnomos, greetings. It has come to our attention that….

Another ordinance: carry out your examinations in accordance with the regulations and the commandments from us, 
our father and our ancestors. Punish those who at random and without forethought bring people up for examination, 
as is right, but send to us immediately those who bring people up for examination because of a grudge or seeking illicit gain. 
And (act) in the same manner regarding those who make notifications in name against (?)…, 
but deliver to us immediately those who submit notifications covertly, even if you… with regard to one of these matters 
in compliance with the existing orders. But if a vow is made against certain individuals who are not present, 
then bring these people in/up, so that there may not be any… of wrongdoing before the trial. 
And in general, steadfastly provide for those who have been appointed by us, since we will punish those who transgress this ordinance, 
as is right. Year 22.
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp80–81)
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
