<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>SB 8, 9792</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">5794</idno>
            <idno type="TM">5794</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">5794</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;8;9792</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-06-13T13:41:26-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - Changed idnos to 5794.</change>
         <change when="2016-06-13T13:33:54-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - translation from published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 3)</change>
         <change when="2016-06-13T13:32:50-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - added translation from published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 3)</change>
         <change when="2016-06-13T13:23:49-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> To Mnaseas, of the diadochoi and epistatês phylakitôn, from Seos, son of Horos, of those from the Sarapieion in the desert opposite Hermoupolis. 
On the 24th of Choiach, year 6, I was away from the Oasis with others. A band of robbers set upon us as we were coming back and took off in possession 
of a male donkey of mine and a female one. With both of these they carried off the merchandise of which they stripped me. 
After submitting a notification to Dannos and the kômophylakitai about these matters at the very time when they occurred, 
I gave to you and Eumelos and Ptolemaios, who were stratêgoi then, the appropriate account, along with the other (officials?). 
Accordingly, Thortaios was sent out to seek the men by force. But now I have learned that my male donkey is in the possession of Asos, 
son of Seous, in the aforementioned Sarapieion, so I make this report to you, so that once Asos and my donkey are placed under guard, 
the necessary investigation may take place, and I may get back my donkey; and if any other of the things I lost is discovered, those 
responsible may meet with the fitting consequences. Farewell. Year 19, Epeiph 6.
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 3)
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
