<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.10/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>VBP 4, 48</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">5830</idno>
            <idno type="TM">5830</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">5830</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.bad;4;48</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2015-05-11T04:38:56.893-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/simoeis">Finalized - Ready</change>
         <change when="2015-05-11T04:38:56.887-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/simoeis">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Accept.  Change triple parentheses to double.</change>
         <change when="2015-04-30T10:55:05.456-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/simoeis">Translation added as part of the University of Heidelberg and Wuerzburg 2015 Ancient Letters Webinar.  Elizabeth Nabney kindly compiled the translation.</change>
         <change when="2015-04-30T10:46:21-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p> <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> Dionysia to her lord Theon, greetings and good health.  I myself am also well, and I continue to keep the best remembrance of you because of all the good (I received from you).  And I pray to the gods that I may hear you are healthy in many ways, because you both rescued us from enemies and left us again when you departed against the enemy.  Know therefore that as you instructed me to carry out and sell the excess goods, when I took out the mattress <milestone unit="line" n="5"/> Neon seized it in the marketplace and took it away, using no ordinary violence.  And so it was judged for me that I had the right to petition the presiding official in the city (o epi tes poleos), since you are away rather than present.  And when he appeared with me, having treated me in such a terrible way, it was decided that it should be sealed up and kept in the town hall (archeion) until the time when you are present.  For he was saying that you are not on military service and I am not part of a military household, but that you had sailed upriver due to <milestone unit="line" n="10"/> work and you are not under royal command.  And I have been distressed to no ordinary degree because Marsyas has sent a letter, but you have written nothing to me.  So you will give me pleasure even now if you write back with news of you, whatever there is, so that I may be free from anxiety, please.  Take care of yourself so that I may greet you in good health.  Greet Marsyas and Ammonios.  Aline and her children greet you.  <milestone unit="line" n="15"/> Farewell.  Year 44, Phaophi 5.  Above all I bid you remember how you left me behind alone like the dogs and you did not stand by the things you were exhorting.  Even now remember us.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p> Deliver to Theon from Dionysia.
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>