<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Eleph., 1</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">5836</idno>
            <idno type="TM">5836</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">5836</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.eleph;;1intdupl</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-04-28T09:09:10-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/simoeis">Finalized - Ready</change>
         <change when="2016-04-28T08:59:12-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/simoeis">Vote - Accept - Rowlandson does not number lines; thus it is probably better to remove them from here.  l. 8: --&gt; another; l. 17 Gelan: --&gt; Gelan.  See also Hoogendijk's comments.</change>
         <change when="2016-03-03T15:33:02-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/cisca.hoogendijk">Vote - AcceptWithModification - Make text identical with Rowlandson's:&#xD;
l. 1 month of Dios: delete of&#xD;
l. 4 1,000 remove comma&#xD;
l. 7 bur &gt; but&#xD;
 l. 9 nor &gt; or (twice)&#xD;
l. 11 1,000 &gt; 1000 (twice)&#xD;
l. 13 himself &gt; Herakleides himself&#xD;
l. 13 the property of Herakleides &gt; Herakleides' property&#xD;
l. 15 in the place &gt; in that place</change>
         <change when="2016-03-03T05:00:03-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/Lucia%20Langerak">Submit - Added translation.&#xD;
(in the preview the line numbers are invisible, although I entered them according to the Translation Help rules)</change>
         <change when="2016-03-03T04:54:34-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/users/Lucia%20Langerak">Commit - added English translation from Rowlandson, Women and Society</change>
         <change when="2016-03-03T04:46:58-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <note>Translation: Rowlandson, Women and Society (1998), Nr. 123</note>
<milestone n="1" rend="break" unit="line"/> In the reign of Alexander son of Alexander, in the seventh year, in the satrapship of Ptolemy, in the fourteenth year, in the month Dios. Marriage contract of Herakleides and Demetria. Herakleides (the Temnitan) takes as his lawful wife Demetria the Koan, a free man a free woman, from her father Leptines, Koan, and her mother Philotis, (Demetria) bringing clothing and ornaments to the value of 1000 drachmas, and Herakleides is to supply to Demetria all that is proper for a freeborn wife, and we shall live together wherever it seems best to Leptines and Herakleides consulting in common. <milestone n="6" rend="break" unit="line"/>If Demetria is discovered doing any evil to the shame of her husband Herakleides, she is to be deprived of all that she brought, but Herakleides shall prove whatever he alleges against Demetria before three men whom they both approve. <milestone n="8" rend="break" unit="line"/>It shall not be permitted for Herakleides to bring home another wife in insult of Demetria or to have children by another woman or to do evil against Demetria on any pretext. If Herakleides is discovered doing any of these things and Demetria proves it before three men whom they both approve, Herakleides shall give back to Demetria the dowry of 1000 drachmas which she brought and shall moreover forfeit 1000 drachmas of the silver coinage of Alexander. <milestone n="12" rend="break" unit="line"/>Demetria and those aiding Demetria to exact payment shall have the right to exact payment, as derived from a legally decided action, upon Herakleides himself and upon all Herakleides' property both on land and on water. <milestone n="13" rend="break" unit="line"/>This contract shall be normative in every respect, wherever Herakleides may produce it against Demetria, or Demetria and those aiding Demetria to exact payment may produce it against Herakleides, as if the agreement had been made in that place. <milestone n="15" rend="break" unit="line"/>Herakleides and Demetria shall have the right to keep the contracts severally in their own custody and to produce them against each other. <milestone n="17" rend="break" unit="line"/>Witnesses: Kleon, Gelan; Antikrates, Temnitan; Lysis, Temnitan; Dionysios, Temnitan; Aristomachos, Cyrenaean; Aristodikos, Koan.

            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
