<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 1, 9 Verso</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">64289a</idno>
            <idno type="TM">64289</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">64289a</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;1;9</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-10-13" who="http://papyri.info/users/rfbaumann">Add translation from print edition.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <note>Translation: from P.Oxy. 1</note> A copper drachma has 6 obols, and an obol 8 chalki, so that the copper drachma consists of 48 chalki. A drachma has seven, 7, obols, and an obol has 8 chalki, so that the drachma consists of 56 chalki. The talent has 60 minae, and the mina 25 staters or 100 drachmae, and the stater has 4 drachmae, so that the talent consists of 1500 staters or 6000 drachmae, or forty-two thousand obols. An artaba has 10 measures, and the measure has 4 choenices, so that the artaba consists of 40 choenices. A medimnus has 12 hemihekta and the hemihekton four choenices, so that the medimnus consists of forty-eight choenices. The ell has 6 palms, and the palm 4 digits, so that the ell consists of 24 digits. The metretes has 12 choës, and the chous 12 cotylae, so that the metretes consists of 144 cotylae. The mina-weight has sixteen, 16, quarters, and a quarter has....
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
