<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">65003</idno>
            <idno type="TM">18878</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">18878</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">chla;41;1197 p.cair.masp;2;67131</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2023-05-04T05:48:09-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="1" subtype="column" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  [...] debt amounting to fifteen solidi and ⅓  for the city exchange rate and no delay [...]
and I shall pay in full [...him?] [...] I have made the house free of any liability for her; and as proof of
these things I ask the same most distinguished Theodosios, the courier, to clarify in his own words that
he has indeed received whatever he was still owed by the most blessed Isidoros, <milestone n="7" unit="line"/> and that he has no claim
either against me or the aforementioned most noble (lady) Theus or this house, but also he will not on any
occasion use the minutes taken regarding this issue as actual proof of the delayed payment to him of the
fifteen and ⅓ golden solidi according to the city’s exchange rate to extinguish all the debt(?).
<milestone n="13" rend="break" unit="line"/> The defensor said: what was said by Psais (pap.: Psoios), the venerable numerarius of the assessment office,
was written in the minutes. And the present most distinguished Theodosius, courier, [says] <milestone n="16" unit="line"/> Theodosius, son of
Ioseph(?) [...] courier [...] I was paid the debt owed to me by Isidoros of blessed memory, who himself was
also a courier of the ducal office, through the venerable numerarius of the assessment office, present here;
<milestone n="20" rend="break" unit="line"/> and I have no claim against his venerableness, nor against any of the people of the most blessed Isidoros, 
nor against the most noble Theus nor against [...] of Isidoros [...nor?] against the aforementioned house, 
nor against her heirs or any other person [...] to not use these minutes regarding this [issue] [...] work I have received [...] in total [...]
<milestone n="28" rend="break" unit="line"/> The defensor said: add also these to the minutes accordingly [...]
Psais (pap.: Psoius), the venerable numerarius of the assessment office [...] of the wife and himself
[...I request] that the minutes of the proceedings be issued also to me.
<milestone n="32" rend="break" unit="line"/> The defensor said: it will be issued to your venerableness and anyone interested.
<note>Translation: Law in Social Networks Project (Warsaw)</note>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
