<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>ZPE 177 (2011) S. 172</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">694</idno>
            <idno type="TM">694</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">694</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">psi;4;435 p.cair.zen;1;59034 zpe;177;172 sb;3;6713</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2024-05-23T07:40:25-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/paulpeters">Finalized - Bereit.</change>
         <change when="2024-05-23T07:28:23-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/paulpeters">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Literaturverweis ergänzen. Zeilenzählung überarbeiten. In Z. 8 "on household" zu "on behalf of you (and your household", in Z. 10 "hi" zu "him" und in Z. 18 "Apollonius" zu "Apollonios" korrigieren.</change>
         <change when="2022-10-27T05:25:31-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> Zoilos of Aspendos, [from the entourage, military unit or association of?],
                         who was recommended to you by the Friends of the King, greets Apollonios. It happened to me
                         as I was paying worship to the god Sarapis on behalf of your health and success
                         with King Ptolemy that Sarapis instructed me again and again
                         in my sleep that I should sail over to you and inform you of this
                         oracle <milestone n="6" unit="line"/> that there must be constructed for him [a temple (?)]
                         and sacred precinct in the Greek (marketplace/ neighborhood ?) near the harbor and a priest must preside and
                         sacrifice at the altar on behalf of you (and your household?). Because I implored [the god Sarapis (?)]
                         that he excuse me from this work (?), he visited upon me an illness
                         so great that I was in danger of my life. <milestone n="10" unit="line"/> When I had offered up prayers to him, that if (?)
                         he should heal [me] I would perform this service and do what
                         had been ordered by him, and when I quickly had recovered, a certain individual from Knidos appeared
                         who undertook to build a Sarapieion in that place and brought
                         in stones; thereupon, however, the god forbade him from building, and he
                         left. <milestone n="15" unit="line"/> When I had come to Alexandria and hesitated
                         to talk to you concerning these matters instead of the business matters which you had agreed to with me,
                         once again I suffered a relapse that lasted for four months, on account of which I was unable to come
                         to you right away. Therefore, Apollonios, it would be good for you
                         to heed the god's commands so that Sarapis will be merciful to you and greatly
                         enhance your status with the king and give you good health.
                <milestone n="21" unit="line"/> So, do not be disheartened about the cost, as will arise from a great
                         expenditure by you - on the contrary, it will be altogether profitable for you, for I will jointly supervise
                         everything.
                         Farewell.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="25" unit="line"/> From Zoilos, concerning Sarapis. To Apollonios.
                           Year 28, Audnaios (February 12/13, 257 B.C.),
                           at Berenikes
                           Hormos.
                           <note>Translation: G.H. Renberg – W.S. Bubelis, ZPE 177 (2011) 173-174</note>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
