<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>BGU 6, 1252</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">7324</idno>
            <idno type="TM">7324</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">7324</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">bgu;6;1252</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-07-18T17:05:22-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - added a translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 230)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T17:01:49-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - added a translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 230)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T17:01:26-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - added a translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 230)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T17:00:53-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Commit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 230)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-18T16:58:10-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> [To X, greetings, from Y and Z], who have received the contract to hunt wild birds for year 7 in the aforementioned village and also Euhemeria. 
We had jointly left the areas in which it was required that we set out our hunting nets after we had hunted the birds living in them, so as to render 
the appropriate tax revenue. But on the night of Tybi 7, year 7, Gennaios, son of [.]otes, of those from the same village and our fellow-hunter, 
reported to us that he had, without our knowledge, entered the bird-lairs in which we had left him (?) remaining/behind (?) and hunted. 
Wherefore we rushed upon him at that very moment, and taking Harmais, phylakitês, and Pyrrhos, son of Petaus the phylakitês, 
we entered into the aforementioned areas and handed over Gennaios as well as the nets he had set up. Since, therefore, for this reason we have suffered 
the loss of 400 kerkereis, we are making this report to you so that he (i.e., Gennaios) may be brought before Helas, epistatês phylakitôn, 
and he may meet with the appropriate punishment, and the aforementioned loss may be extracted from him as a penalty, so that we may be able 
to pay what is due unhesitatingly. Year 7, Tybi [..].
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 230)
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
