<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title/>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">7434</idno>
            <idno type="TM">7434</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">7434b 7434a</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">chr.wilck;;166 p.petr;2;20</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-06-16T20:30:33-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - Added translation from a published volume (Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement pp69–70).</change>
         <change when="2016-06-16T20:19:05-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Translation is from a published volume (Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp69-70).</change>
         <change when="2016-06-16T20:15:48-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - Added a translation from a published volume (Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp69–80).</change>
         <change when="2016-06-16T18:23:24-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Commit - added translation from a printed volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp69–70)</change>
         <change when="2016-06-16T18:19:54-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="1+2rp" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> To Ptolemaios, epimelêtês, from Theophilos, agent of Antikles, the official in charge of royal grain export in the Arsinoite via boat.
Pinuris and Erianoupis, who are shipbuilders in the Arsinoite nome for the purpose of exporting the royal grain,
having received from Ptolemaios, agent (?) of Asklepiades, … for the purpose of constructing new ships…
for the purpose of the preparation of the things commanded by Antikles, travelled to Herakleopolis;
and Herakleides, the archiphylakitês, detained them. Ptolemaios, appealing to Herakleides the oikonomos,
and making the necessity (of their release) known, wrote to Herakleides (i.e. the archiphylakitês) to release them,
since I myself as well was unable to intervene. But now I hear that Herakleides (i.e. the archiphylakitês)
has not obeyed the letter of Herakleides, oikonomos, and will not (do so), unless either you or the dioikêtês write to him. 
Therefore, so that the export of grain may not be held up—since the ships are not being made ready and all this is happening
in spite of the fact that a very large amount of grain has accumulated from the market and the tribute—I ask that you,
if it seems best, please write to Herakleides, archiphylakitês in the Herakleopolite nome, to release them, 
so that they may be available for work and the ships may not be left unbuilt. For I know that you are not unaware
that... the grain on the... and in the cistern in Boukolon kome, but if it is carried out by donkeys... a difference... per 100 artabas of five drachmas. 
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp69–70)
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="3" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/>
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="4" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/>
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
