<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Tebt. 3, 797 .1</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">7856</idno>
            <idno type="TM">7856</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">7856</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.tebt;3.1;797</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-07-12T17:29:00-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - added translation from published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 72)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-12T17:12:41-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - translation from published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 72)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-12T17:10:35-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - added a translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 72)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-12T17:09:47-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Commit - added a translation from a published volume</change>
         <change when="2016-07-12T17:06:28-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> To [..…]esis, archiphylakitês of Berenikis Thesmophorou, and his phylakitai, from Poregebthis, priest and warden of the temple of Isis 
from the same village. On the 15th of the present month, while I was sacrificing in the temple of Isis there 
on behalf of the king and queen and their children and ancestors, totally innocent, … Perutis, son of Perutis, 
whipped (me?)… and took… and when I cried out for help, Papontos, my …, but they removed by force from the… (and) 
planted many blows on me, and wounded my shin, and beat me in my face and took off in possession of my honey and a linen garment 
worth 2000 drachmas, and a bag containing 328 bronze drachmas, and a bronze altar and a drinking vessel, 
(all of?) which I recovered from the wardens of the temple on the 15th. I am submitting a petition to you so that you may send 
the perpetrators to Meleagros, the epistatês phylakitôn, so that, once the examination of them has been held, 
they may meet with the fitting punishment and I may recover the things which I have described. For once this has happened, ….
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, p. 72)
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
