<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 69, 4756</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">80741</idno>
            <idno type="TM">80741</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">80741</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;69;4756</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2011-07-17T21:57:33.385-04:00" who="Joshua D. Sosin">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2011-07-17T21:57:33.382-04:00" who="Joshua D. Sosin">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Accept. No need for quotes.</change>
         <change when="2011-07-01T16:28:16.167-04:00" who="Nathan Gilbert">Translation copied from published version.</change>
         <change when="2011-07-01T16:22:30-04:00" who="SoSOL">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <p>
               <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> In the reign of our most godly and most pious master, greatest benefactor, Flavius Mauricius new Tiberius, the eternal Augustus, year 8, in the consulship of our same most pious master, year 7, 
Phamenoth 14, indiction eighth.
<milestone unit="line" n="5" rend="break"/> To Flavia Anastasia, gloriosissima illustria, daughter of Menas, son of Eudaemon, of glorious memory, 
landowner here in the splendid city of the Oxyrhynchites, through you, Flavius Victor, spectabilis comes 
and administrator of hers, Aurelius Abraam, son of Paulus, mother Thecla, originating from the village . . . 
of the Oxyrhynchite nome. I acknowledge by willing resolve and voluntary choice, swearing the divine and 
august oath, that I guarantee and receive from your glory through your dependants Aurelius Elias son of 
Phib, mother . . . , from the same village, on condition that he shall remain continuously and abide in the 
same village, and he shall on no account abandon it nor transfer to a another place . . . in the place 
where I have also received him, in the prison of this city. Or if I fail to do this, I acknowledge myself 
accountable to answer for all that is required of him. This deed of surety, written in a single copy, is binding, 
and in reply to the formal question I gave my assent. (2nd hand) I, Aurelius Abraam, son of Paulus, . . . (N. Gonis) 
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
