<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?oxygen RNGSchema="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/latest/tei-epidoc.rng" type="xml"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Oxy. 69, 4757</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">80742</idno>
            <idno type="TM">80742</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">80742</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.oxy;69;4757</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2011-07-17T21:54:39.067-04:00" who="Joshua D. Sosin">Finalized - ready</change>
         <change when="2011-07-17T21:54:39.063-04:00" who="Joshua D. Sosin">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Accept.</change>
         <change when="2011-07-01T16:30:58.456-04:00" who="Grant Adamson">Entered translation from copy provided by author. </change>
         <change when="2011-07-01T16:14:00-04:00" who="SoSOL">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation" xml:space="preserve">
            <div n="r" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="1"/> . . . the condition of the adscripticius. And he shall on no account leave the same village nor transfer to another place, but if he is 
required of me by your glory through your subordinates on any day, for any reason whatsoever, <milestone unit="line" n="5"/> I shall bring him forward and deliver him up in a 
public place without recourse to any place of refuge or letter of safe-conduct, in the place where I have also received him, in the public prison of the 
same city of the Oxyrhynchites. Or if I fail to do this, I acknowledge that I shall pay for his non-appearance twelve solidi of gold, actual payment of 
which is to be enforced. This deed of surety, written in a single copy, is binding, and in reply to the formal question I gave my assent. (2nd hand) I, 
Aurelius <milestone unit="line" n="10"/> Phoebammon, comarch, son of Pieus, the aforewritten, have made this surety and undertake responsibility for the same Macarius 
at my risk, as aforesaid. I, Anastasius, contract writer, wrote on his behalf, as requested, because he is illiterate.
<milestone unit="line" n="13" rend="break"/> Through me, Anastasius, the completion was made.
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="v" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone unit="line" n="14"/> Surety of Phoebammon, son of Pieus, from the village of (E)ieme, <milestone unit="line" n="15"/> undertaking responsibility for Macarius from the 
same village. (N. Gonis)
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
