<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>P.Hib. 1, 73</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">8222</idno>
            <idno type="TM">8222</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">8222</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.hib;1;73</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2016-07-14T20:00:04-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Finalized - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp108–109)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-14T19:53:14-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp108–109)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-14T19:52:30-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Submit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp108–109)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-14T19:52:00-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/users/Randy">Commit - added translation from a published volume (J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp108–109)</change>
         <change when="2016-07-14T19:49:25-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> Antigonos to Dorion, greetings. You wrote concerning Kallidromos: for me now, at last, to force him to give back the donkey 
or pay him (i.e., the donkey’s owner) its value. But Kallidromos… Dorion… to exact from him the value of the donkey, 20 drachmas. 
Therefore quietly, in accordance with the letter you wrote me, I led Kallidromos off to the desmôtêrion in Sinaru 
so that he might give the donkey back to Dorion; but Patron, the phylakitês, arriving at the desmôtêrion, 
released Kallidromos from the desmôtêrion, with the result that I could not exact the money. He led the donkey off to his 
house and is keeping it there, out of sight. If I had not been unwell, I would have taken it from him by means of a machairophoros. 
I have written to you concerning these matters so that you may know that the violence of Patron is responsible for the fact that the 
restoration to Dorion did not take place. Patron has continued to disobey your commands. Farewell. Year 4, ….
(J. Bauschatz, Law and Enforcement, pp108–109)
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
