<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Chr.Wilck. 389</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">8896</idno>
            <idno type="TM">8896</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">8896</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">chr.wilck;;389</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-08-08T08:02:35-04:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Commited directly to master repository.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="2" unit="line"/>(Inspection) of the rising of the most sacred Nile in the division of 
Themistes for the current 22nd year of our Lord Imperator Commodus 
Antoninus. <milestone n="5" unit="line"/>The inspection was made by me in conjunction with Demetrios 
when he was strategus of the divisions, and Hierakapollon, the present 
strategus, and Asclepinos, the royal scribe of the division of Themistes, <milestone n="9" unit="line"/>in 
accordance with the records of the inspectors of sowing in each district and 
of the overseers of embankments, and within the limits prescribed by the 
former prefect Flavius Piso, to Petronius, my predecessor as inspector, 
<milestone n="15" unit="line"/>whereby he desired him in company with the strategi and royal scribes to 
make the inspection of the work remaining to be done( ?) on embankments 
and canals; so that if each task was completed according to the norm of 
the nome —— in a special record there should be a comparison of the 
records given by the inspectors of sowing with that of my inspection —, 
<milestone n="21" rend="break" unit="line"/>in accordance with which we have made the survey with the concurrence of 
the inspectors of sowing and x also called Ptolemaios, former shore-warden, 
and Aurelios Areios, present shore-warden. <milestone n="25" unit="line"/>They themselves pointed out 
their own work and that of others wherever necessary. Theodoros, son of 
Soterichos, surveyor of the Heracleopolite nome, acted as surveyor and 
measures. <milestone n="28" unit="line"/>Beginning the inspection of the above division on Epiph 20 
in the past 21st year, we completed it on the 17th of Phaophi in the current 
22nd year with intervals. The number of days —— 
<note>Translation with minor modifications: A.C. Johnson, Roman Egypt to the reign of Diocletian, Nr. 8 p. 23</note>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
