<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>BGU 1, 19</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">8950</idno>
            <idno type="TM">8950</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">8950</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">chr.mitt;;85</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2021-02-23T11:26:47-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <div n="1" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> Copy. By delegation of Petronius Mamertinus, prefect of Egypt. Year
                         19 of Hadrian Caesar the lord, Mecheir 17, in the case of Chenalexas
                         versus Petesouchos and Dionysios. Menander the judge told the litigants:
                         “I postponed the present affair, because it was in the general interest, until
                         I should write to His Excellency the prefect to ask him if the inheritance
                         of the grandmother’s estate was given to the grandsons and to the
                         granddaughters of the Egyptians by virtue of a grant of the lord Hadrian
                         Caesar. So, the letter I wrote to His Excellency the prefect and the one
                         he sent me in response will be read.” He ordered that both of them be
                         read and inserted in the minutes, their content being verbatim as follows: 
                <milestone n="11" unit="line"/> “To His Excellency the prefect Petronius Mamertinus, Menander, former
                         royal scribe of the Arsinoite nome, greetings. At the last conventus,
                         Chenalexas daughter of Alexander, Egyptian, was involved in a lawsuit
                         with her paternal uncle Petesouchos and her cousin Dionysios before the
                         judge Herakleides, about the part of the inheritance of her grandmother
                         which she said had fallen to her father from his mother. As those
                         around Petesouchos confirmed that the latter had died before his mother
                         in the first year of the reign of Hadrian Caesar the lord (ad 117/8),
                         whereas (Chenalexas said he died) in the fifteenth year (AD 131/2), she
                         promised to prove it with documents. The judgment was deferred for
                         administration of proof. Now, all of them having been sent to me for
                         trial, she claimed to benefit by the grant of the god, the most illustrious
                         Emperor,
               </p>
            </div>
            <div n="2" type="textpart">
               <p>
                  <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> who allowed the Egyptians to inherit their grandmothers’
                         estate, and she brought a precedent of His Excellency the epistratêgos
                         Gellius Bassus, who had judged that the children’s children also inherit
                         the estate of the grandmother. After other things, his decision was written
                         as follows: ‘All the paternal estate that falls to the person in question
                         from the testament of Eudaimonis or in any other way, will come to his
                         children.’ The matter being also about the question whether with the
                         grandmother being dead intestate the ninth year before the Emperor’s
                         grant, the granddaughter will take the part of the succession of her father,
                         I write to you, my Prefect, so that you may command what in your
                         opinion is to be done. I pray for your health, Lord Prefect. Year 19 of the
                         Emperor Caesar Trajan Hadrian Augustus, Mecheir 14.”
                <milestone n="12" unit="line"/> To which letter it was answered:
                         “Petronius Mamertinus to Menander, former royal scribe of the
                         toparchy of Polemon, greeting. If no judgment has been pronounced
                         on the affair between Chenalexas and Petesouchos [...] paternal
                         uncle and Dionysios, cousin, concerning the estate of her grandmother,
                         it is advisable that, according to the letter of the lord, you allow
                         Chenalexas, through your judgment, to succeed to the part of the paternal
                         estate her father would have inherited if he had survived. Goodbye.
                         Year 19, Mecheir 14.”
                         He pronounced the following decision:
                         “It seems advisable, according to the letter of His Excellency the prefect,
                         that Chenalexas should succeed to the part of the paternal estate her
                         father would have inherited (from his mother) if he had survived.”
                         
               </p>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
