<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.stoa.org/epidoc/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title type="main"> HGVTITLE (DDBTITLE) </title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">hgv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="TM">gv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">hgv-TEMP</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">bgu;1;321rpdupl</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">Französisch</language>
            <language ident="en">Englisch</language>
            <language ident="de">Deutsch</language>
            <language ident="it">Italienisch</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanisch</language>
            <language ident="la">Latein</language>
            <language ident="el">Griechisch</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2021-05-04T10:39:47-04:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
               <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> To Aurelios Didymos strategus of the merides of Themistos and Polemon of the Arsinoite from Aurelios Pakysis son of Tesenouphis, priest and stolistes of the temple of the first rank of the village of Soknopaiou Nesos of the meris of Herakleides. I possess a place in the house of the wife of my son Aurelios Tesenouphis in the hamlet of Pisaïs in the meris of Themistos in which I keep in storage foodstuffs for our daily use. Just lately my relatives went into the place because I myself was away in Alexandria and it was discovered that the foodstuffs had been pilfered. The cause of the theft, as was clear, was that the crime had been committed when the place, which is on the upper floor, had been holed through the floor. When those who are living there were proved to have done this through malice aforethought, they undertook in the presence of both the archephodos of the village and others to give me seven artabas of grain against the amount of the theft. But since they have agreed to the undertaking but up until now have not complied with the restitution, of necessity I am making submission of a petition which I request be placed on record, so that my rights be secured for me against the accused, Panouphis son of Stotoetis and Pakysis son of Kanneis. Farewell. (2nd hand) I, Aureliou (sic) Pakysis, have submitted the petition. (1st hand) Year 24 of Marcus Aurelius Severus Antoninus Parthicus Maximus Britannicus Maximus Germanicus Maximus Pius Augustus, Pharmouthi 12.
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
