<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
  <teiHeader type="text">
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>CPR 1, 29</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>Duke Collaboratory for Classics Computing (DC3)</authority>
            <idno type="filename">9859</idno>
            <idno type="TM">9859</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">9859</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">cpr;1;29 chr.mitt;;335</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>© Heidelberger Gesamtverzeichnis der griechischen Papyrusurkunden Ägyptens. This work is licensed under 
            a <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/" type="license">Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 License</ref>.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>The contents of this document are generated from SOSOL.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="fr">French</language>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="de">German</language>
            <language ident="it">Italian</language>
            <language ident="es">Spanish</language>
            <language ident="la">Latin</language>
            <language ident="el">Modern Greek</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabisch</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2022-01-03T09:46:11-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Finalized - Ready.</change>
         <change when="2022-01-03T08:57:34-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/james.cowey">Vote - Accept-Straight-to-Finalization - Fine.</change>
         <change when="2022-01-01T17:07:11-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/chantalvanegdom">Submit - To add a translation to a papyrus that does not have one published yet.</change>
         <change when="2022-01-01T17:03:51-05:00"
                 who="http://papyri.info/editor/users/chantalvanegdom">Commit - Added English translation</change>
         <change when="2022-01-01T16:59:51-05:00" who="http://papyri.info/editor">Automated creation from template</change>
      </revisionDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" xml:space="preserve" type="translation">
            <p>
              <milestone n="1" unit="line"/> In the twenty-fourth year of Imperator Caesar Marcus Aurelius Commodus Antoninus Augustus Armeniacus Medicus Parthicus Sarmaticus Germanicus Maximus, in the month Dystros, Tybi 12, in Ptolemais Euergetis, 
in the Arsinoite nome. <milestone n="6" unit="line"/> Harpokration, son of Demetrios, grandson of Heron, from the metropolis, registered in the quarter of Phremei, about twenty years old with a scar on his right shin, acknowledges to Isidora, daughter of 
Epagathos, about eighteen years old, with a scar on the corner of her right eye, with her brother as her guardian, born from the same father and mother, about fourty years old without distinguishing marks: <milestone n="12" unit="line"/> that Harpokration, 
the acknowledging party, has received a deposit of eight hundred drachmas of silver, from Isidora, forthwith from hand to hand, free of all risk and subject to no claim of any reduction, <milestone n="16" unit="line"/> which he will give back to her whenever 
she chooses, without any delay and dispute and subterfuge, she having the right of execution on Harpokration, and all his property as if in accordance with a legal judgement. <milestone n="20" unit="line"/> Signatories: for Harpokration, who declares he 
does not know letters, Didymos, son of Heron, about thirty-six years old, without distinguishing marks, and for Isidora and her guardian, likewise illiterate, Ptollas, son of Didas, about 42 years old without distinguishing marks.
<milestone n="25" rend="break" unit="line"/> (Hand 2) I, Harpokration, son of Demetrios, acknowledge to have received the eight hundred and eight drachmas of the deposit from Isidora, and I will give them back whenever she chooses, without delay, as aforesaid. 
I, Didymos, son of Heron, have written this on his behalf, as he is illiterate.
<milestone n="28" unit="line"/> (Hand 3) I, Isidora, daughter of Epagathos, with her brother Theon as her guardian: the deposit was made in regard to me, as aforesaid. <milestone n="31" unit="line"/> I, Ptollas, son of Didas, have written on their behalf, as they are illiterate.
I have signed, Tybi 12. 

            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
