<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Declaration of children</title>
            <author>Marcus Aurelius Apion, son of Philip.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">michigan.apis.3465</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(MiU)3465</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20910</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20910</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.corn;;18dupl</idno>
            <idno type="filename">20910-2</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">P.Corn. Inv. I 80</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               
               
               
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      
      
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
         </langUsage>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change when="2025-12-05T09:21:28.232347-05:00"
                 who="https://papyri.info/editor/users/hcayless">Pull translation out of APIS record.</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div xml:lang="en" type="translation">
            <ab>"To Aurelius Diogenes also called Hermias, nominator of the glorious and most glorious city of Oxyrhinchus for the current 7th year and 6th year, from Marcus Aurelius Apion, son of Philip, his mother being Apias, daughter of Altheus. I wish that my sons, born to me from my former wife, who is dead, Tisois, daughter of Sarapammon, son of Eutychides also called Sarapion, her mother being Thatous, of the glorious and most glorious city of Oxyrhinchus, should for the first time be registered in the quarter of Thoeris Square - the Aurelii, Philip, who is in the same current 7th year and 6th year thirteen years of age, and Gaius likewise, who is in the same current 7th year and 6th year five years of age, both subject to the twelve drachma tax and members of the gymnasium; and Melanas also called Anubiaina, who is in the same 7th year and 6th year fifteen years of age, likewise Taeus, who is in the same current 7th year and 6th year seven years of age. Therefore I hand in the memorandum, requesting that they be enrolled in the class of their equals as is fitting. And I swear the customary oath of the Romans that I have made no false statement.;Year 7 of Imperator Caesar Marcus Aurelius Valerius Maximianus, Germanici, the Highest Pious and Fortunate Augusti, Epeiph 30. I, Aurelius Apion, son of Philip, have handed it in and I took the oath.;2nd hd. Thoeris Square. Philip aged 13. Gaius aged 5. Daughters: Melanas also called Anoubiaina, aged 15; Taeus aged 7. Children of Apion, son of Philip." Signed: "Noukekies, assistant official."</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Westermann WL - Kraemer CJ, PCorn, 18, 1926, Pl p 101 -- BL II.2, 49 on ll. 4, 25 and 28; BL VIII, 90.</bibl>
            </listBibl>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
