<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Contract of loan with mortgage</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">nyu.apis.4730</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNU)4730</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">26671</idno>
            <idno type="TM">26671</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.nyu;2;29</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">NYU inv. 12</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Bobst</note>
                     <note type="general">Source of description: R</note>
                     <note type="general">Verso: Worp, K. A. - Nielsen, B. "New Papyri from the New York University Collection: III". ZPE 140 (2002) p.141 (Nr. 30); nyu.apis.4731</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 6 x 9 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0100" notAfter="0125">Early II CE</origDate>
                     <origPlace>from Oxyrhynchite nome</origPlace>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Contracts</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Loans</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Mortgage</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>--- (at an interest of one drachma) per each mna for each month from the current month of --- (and) of necessity I shall pay back (the principal and the monthly interest) until the 10th of the month of Thoth of the coming nth year (without any delay); but if I fail to do so, I acknowledge that there remain with you, instead of the principal and the interest, the possession and ownership for ever of the nth part belonging to me of a house, situated in the Thoeris Street quarter, and an atrium and courtyard and the entrances and the exits and the appurtenances and all the annexes, the boundaries of which are: to the South: ---, to the North: property of Alia alias Diogenis, to the East: ---, to the West: (property) of (N.N., son/daughter of) Ptollarion and however (s)he is styled --- the aforementioned house and all the appurtenances --- and the power to use it and to dispose of it in whatever way you may choose, and neither I nor anyone else on my behalf shall have the right to make a claim upon it or any part of it in any way whatsoever, and I shall further deliver it to you guaranteed perpetually against all claims with every guarantee and free from persons' property returns and (the liability to) cultivate royal or estate domain land from every obligation or debt or lien of every kind public or private and from everything else whatsoever; I will of necessity and at once repel ever person who in any way whatsoever proceeds against or claims this property, whether whole or part, at my own costs, as if in consequence of a legal decision ---.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Worp, K. A. - Nielsen, B. "New Papyri from the New York University Collection: III". ZPE 140 (2002) 138-40 (Nr. 29) <note>Ethyle R. Wolfe, NYU Dissertation, 31-40, 1949</note>
               </bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
