<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Contract for a Parachoresis</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">nyu.apis.4742</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(NNU)4742</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.nyu.2.15a</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">121947</idno>
            <idno type="TM">121947</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.nyu;2;15</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">NYU inv. 22</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Location: Bobst</note>
                     <note type="general">15 lines, joins with PSI inv. 137.  See Bastianini, _Scrivere Leggere Interpretare: Studi di aniquità in onore di Sergio Daris_ and P.NYU II 15</note>
                     <note type="general">Source of description: R</note>
                     <note type="general">Verso blank</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus ; 13 x 16.5 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0068">AD 68, May 5</origDate>
                     <origPlace>From Oxyrhynchite nome</origPlace>
                  </origin>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Documentary</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Contract</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Land cession</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Parachoresis</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Year fourteen of Nero Claudius Caesar August Germanicus Imperator, on Pachon the tenth, in the city of Oxyrhynchoi.  N.N. daughter of N.N. son of Kephalas and of Tausarapis daughter of Horus, with as her guardian her husband (?) N.N. son of N.N. from --, acknowledges to Berenice, daughter of N.N. son of Dionysios and of Berenice daughter of Dio--, from ---, that she has ceded to her, in accordance with the administrative arrangements of those controlling cavalry affairs and on the basis of a memorandum submitted by her to the official in charge of the registry of military settlers' land grants, three arouras of catoicic land and land bought for conversion into catoicic land, belonging to her near Nesla in the Upper Toparchy in the kleros of N.N., together with the yearly rents thereof, of which the neighbors are: to the South --, to the North --, to the West --, to the East --, in order that the three arouras shall belong to Berenice and her offspring along with the other rights and benefits, irrefutably for all time,   in accordance with the ordinances and instructions, and the she, the acknowledging party, has received from Berenice the agreed upon among of cession money, i.e. n silver drachmas of imperial money, on the spot and in full, at the moments when this was urgent, and that regarding this cession N.N. will not violate the contract and will not attempt any fraud, in any way whatsoever, and that  the same (woman) will absolutely hand over to Berenice or to her representatives the three arouras fully guaranteed and free from all the public imposts and other dues, from previous years up to the 5th of the Epogomenai of Mesore of the past thirteenth year and including the thirteenth year of Nero Claudius Caesar August Germanicus Imperator.  If she violates any of these provisions in the contract her action will be invalid and she shall forfeit to Berenice or to her representatives for every specific breach both the damages and a fine of n silver drachmas and to the state the sum, and nevetheless the contract as drawn up in accordance with their mutual harmonious agreement, shall be binding.  (M. 2) In the 14th year of Nero Claudius Caesar Augustus Germanicus Imperator, on Pachon the tenth.  It has been registered through N.N., tax-farmer (representing his colleagues). (Translation of P.NYU II 15a)</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>Worp, K. A. - Nielsen, B. "New Papyri from the New York University Collection: II". ZPE 136 (2001) 132-4 (Nr. 15) P.NYU II 15a</bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.NYU:2:15a</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
