<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter Seeking Recruitment of Youths for Instruction in Crafts Related to Shipbuilding</title>
            <author>Kurrah ben Sharik</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">hermitage.apis.13</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(RU-SPGE)13</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.ross.georg.4.6</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0197;4;6</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ross.georg;4;6</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20491</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20491</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Hermitage inv. 13333f</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Letter from the governor of Egypt, Kurrah b. Sharik, to the pagarch, Basilius, ordering the recruitment of youths to be trained as ship carpenters and caulkers</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">Inv. 13333f has 9 lines (= right half of P.Ross.Georg. IV 6.6-14) written against the fibers; the back is blank; lines 15-29 of P.Ross.George. IV 6 have yet to be scanned. The papyrus joins with P.Lond. IV 1391</note>
                     <note type="general">German translation on p. 28-29 of ed.pr.</note>
                     <note type="general">For the date see BL VI 122</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus; 65.5 x 11.5 cm (taken from P.Ross.Georg.)</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0710">23 January, 710 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>kome Aphrodito</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>From the collection of N. Likhachov; once housed in the Paleographical Museum of the Academy of Science in St. Petersburg; now in the Hermitage Museum</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">letter</term>
               <term type="genre_form">order</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>In the name of God. Kurrah ben Sharik, the governor, to Basilius, the pagarch of kome Aphrodito.  We are constantly in need of carpenters and caulkers on account of maintenance of the small ships (carabi), light vessels (acatenaria), and messenger boats (dromonaria), and for various other services to the state.  For there is no way for such services to be completed without them, and they are also of use to those in the chora.  Thus, once you receive the present letter, order throughout the city and villages connected to it, and among the leading people of your district, youths to train in the crafts.  Entrust them to skilled and notable craftsmen who know suitably their craft, and observing and monitoring them each month, watch over their work that there is no carelessness and negligence, and write to us the name, patronymic, village and craft of each.  Preparing half of them to be cast for work in shipbuilding and half in caulking, send to us in the same way the names of the youths placed last year in the same kind of list.  Order those of your district to plant a multitude of trees, vines, acacias and other trees and do not neglect any of the orders included in the present letter, but go around and observe on your own all of these things, as has been said, and write to us how you have done.  Know well that we intend to send, God willing, one assigned to go around and look after these things and fully report to us whether you have followed our order or are somehow doing things otherwise.  This was written on the twenty-eighth of the month of Tybi in the eighth indiction.  Verso: Kurrah ben Sharik the governor to Basilius the pagarch of kome Aphrodito . . . of the eighth indiction for the . . . of craftsmen and caulkers.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Ross.Georg. IV 6 <note>BL II.2, 113; VI 122, BL XI 188; for discussion of the letters of Kurrah b. Sharik see H. Cadell, "Correspondance de Kurrah ben Sharik" Recherches de Papyrologie IV (1967), 107-160, esp. 133-160</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Ross.Georg.:4:6</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
