<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lease of Land</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">hermitage.apis.101</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(RU-SPGE)101</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.ross.georg.3.36</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0197;3;36</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ross.georg;3;36</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">17962</idno>
            <idno type="TM">17962</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Hermitage inv. 13428</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Aurelius Psaeus acknowledges a five year lease of land from Apollos, son of Dioscorus.</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">27 lines written along the fibers; 1 line on the back, along the fibers</note>
                     <note type="general">German translation on p. 151 of ed.pr.</note>
                     <note type="general">Belongs to Dioscorus archive</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">In Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus; 29.4x15 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0537">7 October, 537 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>from kome Aphrodito</origPlace>
                     <persName type="asn">Apollos</persName>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>From the collection of N. Likhachov; once housed in the Paleographical Museum of the Academy of Science in St. Petersburg; now in the Hermitage Museum</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">In Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">Papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Lease</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Following the consulship of the most illustrious Flavius Belisarius; Phaophi 10, first indiction.  To the most admirable Apollos, son of Dioscorus, son of Psimanobet, syntelestes from the village of Aphrodito in the Antaeopolite nome, from Aurelius Psaeus, son of Phunsius, son of Salatocus, from the same village in the same nome. Greetings. I acknowledge willingly and of my own choice to have leased from your virtuousness for a period of five years, counting inclusively from the crops, God willing, of the coming second indiction, the unirrigated aruras which belong to you and are called "the aruras of Casillas," on the farm of Thinestme, to the west of the road and to the north my own aruras, on condition that I provide for the land which I will be able to cultivate, whether inundated or uninundated, for each arura in accordance with a survey by the schoinion, 2 artabs wheat by your tax measure and without dispute.  The lease is authoritative and firm, and having been questioned, I agreed.  I the above-mentioned Aurelius Psaeus, son of Phunsius, have drawn up the lease in the way set out above.  I, Flavius Theotecnus, son of Psaeus, the former praepositus have written for him who does not know letters. Through me, Cyrus the notary, this has been written according to the will of god. (Verso) Lease of Psaeus, the aruras of Casillas.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Ross.Georg. III 36 <note>BL VIII, 291; IX, 226</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Ross.Georg.:3:36</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
