<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter of Instruction for the Recovery of Fugitives</title>
            <author>Kurrah ben Sharik</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">hermitage.apis.10</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(RU-SPGE)10</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.ross.georg.4.2</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0197;4;2</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ross.georg;4;2</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20488</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20488</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Hermitage inv. 13328f</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Letter from the governor of Egypt, Kurrah b. Sharik, to the pagarch, Basilius, ordering (and stipulating procedures for) the recovery of fugitives</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">18 lines against the fibers; text nearly complete, with all but first line surviving. On the back is an acknowledgement of receipt dated 29 June 710 and consisting of one line (the preceding line of the address is lost) written along the fibers</note>
                     <note type="general">cf. P.Lond. IV 1332, 1333, 1343, 1359, 1372</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus; 48.7 x 20.9 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0710">17 June, 710 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>kome Aphrodito</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>From the collection of N. Likhachov; once housed in the Paleographical Museum of the Academy of Science in St. Petersburg; now in the Hermitage Museum</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">letter</term>
               <term type="genre_form">order</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>In the name of God. Kurrah ben Sharik, the governor, to Basilius, the pagarch of kome Aphrodito. We give thanks to God.  And furthermore we have sent to the lower chora those who are assigned in your district to send back men of 20 years (of age) who have left it.  Thus as soon as you receive the present order, send three men who know the topoi well to which they are fleeing.  And place over them a trustworthy and capable man assigned to take (the fugitives) and record the number of those who are discovered and sent to you.  Order their fellow villagers to give each one his keep for one month, since we are going to order that their wages be given to them, by God's will.  But if there is anyone from your district who left in the preceding year and his fellow villagers know the place where he has been, write to us about him, making it clear to us whom he is with.  We are going to send this one right away to you to repay him who is discovered harboring him a repayment that is going to do him harm, God willing.  This was written on the twenty-third of Payni in the ninth indiction.  Verso: [Kurrah ben Sharik the governor to Basilius the pagarch of kome Aphrodito].  On the fifth of the month of Epeiph of the ninth indiction, this was delivered by NN the messenger, concerning fugitives.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Ross.Georg. IV 2 <note>BL VI, 121; BL VII, 171 (for date of verso); for discussion of the letters of Kurrah b. Sharik see H. Cadell, "Correspondance de Kurrah ben Sharik" Recherches de Papyrologie IV (1967), 107-160, esp. 133-160</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Ross.Georg.:4:2</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
