<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lease of Land</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">hermitage.apis.27</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(RU-SPGE)27</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.ross.georg.3.33</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0197;3;33</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ross.georg;3;33</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">17959</idno>
            <idno type="TM">17959</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Hermitage inv. 13424f</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Lease of a farm by Aurelius Abraamios for three years in the village of Aphrodito and holding of Nempketos</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">26 lines along the fibers; back is blank; papyrus is darkened; upper, right, and lower margins extant</note>
                     <note type="general">German translation on p. 140 of ed.pr.</note>
                     <note type="general">Belongs to Dioscorus archive</note>
                     <note type="general">Hand is same as P.Cair. Masp. I 67107</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>1 papyrus; 29 x 10 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate notBefore="0522" notAfter="0522">A.D. 522</origDate>
                     <origPlace>kome Aphrodito</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>From the collection of N. Likhachov; once housed in the Paleographical Museum of the Academy of Science in St. Petersburg; now in the Hermitage Museum</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">lease</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Following the consulship of Symmachus and Boethius, viri clarissimi, on the 8th of ? of the 1st indiction . . . To the most admirable . . . of the village of Aphrodito in the Antaeopolite nome . . . from Aurelius Abraamius son of NN whose mother is Sibylla from the farm of Psinsou . . . of the same village of Aphrodito of the same nome, greetings.  I acknowledge, willingly and of my own accord, to have leased from you, the aforementioned, for 3 years, from the harvest of the, with God's will, upcoming 2nd indiction and during the subsequent time, the farm, which belongs to you, of the priest Apa John Macarius . . . which is situated in the plain to the south of the same village of Aphrodito in the holding of Nempkes, along with a cistern, stopping station and all the legal property within the boundaries, on the condition that I perform all of the agriculture labor at my own expense.  For rent I will give you in return, without mistake or delay, in accordance with the strength of the previous lease?, conducted through the most pious . . . . The lease is valid, which I have issued to you in one copy and having been asked about everything, I have agreed.  I, Aurelius Abraamius, the aforementioned, am leasing . . . the farm, as mentioned above.  I, Apollo son of Isaac, having been deemed appropriate, have written on behalf of him, who is illiterate.  Written by me, Victor son of Apollo.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Ross.Georg. III 33 <note>BL IV, 72</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Ross.Georg.:3:33</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
