<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Order for Building Material for the Palace in Babylon</title>
            <author>Kurrah ben Sharik</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">hermitage.apis.14</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(RU-SPGE)14</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">p.ross.georg.4.7</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0197;4;7</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">p.ross.georg;4;7</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">20492</idno>
            <idno type="TM">20492</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Hermitage inv. 13334f</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Letter (entagion) from the governor of Egypt, Kurrah b. Sharik, to the pagarch, Basilius, ordering building material for the palace in Babylon</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">14 lines, against the fibers; on the back is an acknowledgement of receipt dated 20 Oct. 709, written along the fibers</note>
                     <note type="general">German translation on p. 32-33 of the ed.pr.</note>
                     <note type="general">For the date, see BL VI, 122</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc">Greek</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>41.5 x 13.5 cm (ed.pr.)</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0709">20 September, 709 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>kome Aphrodito</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>From the collection of N. Likhachov; once housed in the Paleographical Museum of the Academy of Science in St. Petersburg; now in the Hermitage Museum</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">letter</term>
               <term type="genre_form">order</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>Regarding split palm branches and palm-leafs.  In the name of God.  Kurrah ben Sharik, the governor, to Basilius, the pagarch of kome Aphrodito.  We have issued an assessment for provisions on account of the roofing of the buildings of the palace that is being built at the order of the Commander of the Faithful (i.e. the caliph) along the inner harbor at Phossato . . . under Ata, son of Abderaaman and Yahya, son of Andala, in the present eighth indiction and we have made an assessment through your pagarchy of provisions in accordance with the attached requisition notice, and after drawing up the orders (entagia) for these things we sent them to you.  Thus once you receive the present letter, work towards fulfillment of the orders and send the needed provisions to Babylon on account of the said palace, as has been described.  This was written on the twenty-third of the month of Thoth in the eighth indiction.  [Requisition list: split palm branchees and] palm-leafs, 1000, 1/2 solidus.  Verso: [Kurrah ben Sharik the governor to Basilius the pagarch of kome Aphrodito].  On the twenty-fourth of the month of Phaophi, in the eighth indiction, this was delivered by Szouseir, regarding split palm branches [and palm-leafs].  Abdella[</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>P.Ross.Georg. IV 7 <note>BL VI, 122; for discussion of the letters of Kurrah b. Sharik see H. Cadell, "Correspondance de Kurrah ben Sharik" Recherches de Papyrologie IV (1967), 107-160, esp. 133-160</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">P.Ross.Georg.:4:7</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
