<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://epidoc.stoa.org/schema/8.13/tei-epidoc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Requisition of Money to Cover Shipping</title>
            <author>Kurrah ben Sharik</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <authority>APIS</authority>
            <idno type="apisid">hermitage.apis.16</idno>
            <idno type="controlNo">(RU-SPGE)16</idno>
            <idno type="ddbdp">sb.20.15100</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-perseus-style">0239;20;15100</idno>
            <idno type="ddb-hybrid">sb;20;15100</idno>
            <idno type="HGV">23879</idno>
            <idno type="TM">23879</idno>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <idno type="invNo">Hermitage inv. 13337f</idno>
               </msIdentifier>
               <msContents>
                  <summary>Letter (entagion) from the governor of Egypt, Kurrah b. Sharik, to the pagarch, Basilius, requisitioning money</summary>
                  <msItemStruct>
                     <note type="general">14 lines, against the fibers; Arabic in line 1; on the back is an acknowledgement of receipt</note>
                     <note type="general">German translation of P.Ross.Georg. IV 10 on p. 43 of ed.pr.; Italian translation of full text, ZPE 85 (1991), 296-297; photograph in ZPE 85 (19976), Tafel X</note>
                     <note type="general">Hermitage papyrus joins with P.Lond. IV 1387 and Pap.Berol.inv. no. 25039(24.5 x 5.6 cm)</note>
                     <textLang mainLang="grc" otherLangs="ar">Greek; Arabic</textLang>
                  </msItemStruct>
               </msContents>
               <physDesc>
                  <objectDesc>
                     <supportDesc>
                        <support>41.8 x 14 cm</support>
                     </supportDesc>
                  </objectDesc>
               </physDesc>
               <history>
                  <origin>
                     <origDate when="0710">1 January, 710 A.D.</origDate>
                     <origPlace>kome Aphrodito</origPlace>
                  </origin>
                  <provenance>
                     <p>From the collection of N. Likhachov; once housed in the Paleographical Museum of the Academy of Science in St. Petersburg; now in the Hermitage Museum</p>
                  </provenance>
               </history>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <classDecl>
            <taxonomy xml:id="apis">
               <desc>APIS keywords are controlled locally at the institution level. They are not necessarily consistent.</desc>
            </taxonomy>
         </classDecl>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="en">English</language>
            <language ident="grc">Greek</language>
            <language ident="ar">Arabic</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="#apis">
               <term type="genre_form">papyri</term>
               <term type="genre_form">letter</term>
               <term type="genre_form">order</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="translation">
            <ab>(Arabic: To the head of Isqoh for the cost of shipping).  Regarding the cost of shipping.  In the name of God.  Kurrah ben Sharik, the governor, to Basilius, the pagarch of kome Aphrodito.  We have assessed in your district seven reckoned solidi for the shipping costs for the boats that are transporting the requisitions for the small ships (carabi), Clysma, the cursus, and other needs of the state in the present eighth indiction, and having drawn up the orders (entagia) for the people in the villages we sent them to you.  Thus, once you receive the present letter, obtain this money for fulfillment of the orders and send it with one of your men who is assigned to submit it.  And don't let it seem like a good idea to you to burden any village with the slightest shipping costs except with that of the wheat and barley delivery that is destined for the storehouses of Babylon.  This was written on the sixth of the month of Tybi in the eighth indiction.  Verso: [on the ? of the month of ? in the eighth indiction this was delivered by] Abu Thouma, the postal messenger, on account of shipping costs. Kurrah ben Sharik the governor to Basilius the pagarch of kome Aphrodito.</ab>
         </div>
         <div type="bibliography" subtype="citations">
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>SB XX 15100 P.Ross.Georg. IV 10 P.Lond. IV 1387 <note>BL VI, 122; R. Pintaudi - P.J. Sijpesteijn, ZPE 85 (1991), 296-297; for discussion of the letters of Kurrah b. Sharik see H. Cadell, "Correspondance de Kurrah ben Sharik" Recherches de Papyrologie IV (1967), 107-160, esp. 133-160</note>
               </bibl>
               <bibl type="ddbdp">SB:20:15100</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
